EU/ORGANIZATION leaders/O have/O spoken/O out/O against/O riots/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O that/O have/O claimed/O the/O lives/O of/O at/O least/O 150/O people/O ./O 
Authorities/O say/O the/O initially/O peaceful/O protest/O turned/O violent/O when/O police/O attempted/O to/O break/O it/O up/O ./O 
Hans-Gert/PERSON Poettering/PERSON ,/O president/O of/O the/O European/O parliament/O ,/O has/O expressed/O grave/O concern/O about/O the/O bloody/O clashes/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
In/O a/O statement/O released/O by/O his/O office/O ,/O Poettering/PERSON described/O reports/O about/O how/O the/O protests/O had/O been/O handled/O as/O ``/O deeply/O disturbing/O ./O ''/O 
He/O called/O on/O both/O sides/O to/O exercise/O calm/O and/O restraint/O and/O urged/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O to/O fully/O respect/O human/O rights/O ,/O ``/O especially/O the/O right/O to/O freedom/O of/O expression/O and/O peaceful/O demonstration/O ./O ''/O 
In/O an/O interview/O with/O <ORGANIZATION>DW-TV/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O German/O Human/O Rights/O Commissioner/O Guenther/PERSON Nooke/PERSON on/O Monday/O also/O spoke/O out/O against/O the/O eruption/O of/O violence/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O Uighurs/O in/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ./O 
Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION :/O How/O does/O the/O German/O government/O view/O the/O events/O in/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ?/O 
Guenther/PERSON Nooke/PERSON :/O We/O have/O not/O been/O in/O a/O position/O to/O come/O to/O an/O official/O assessment/O because/O not/O enough/O information/O has/O been/O made/O available/O yet/O ,/O but/O of/O course/O we/O know/O that/O there/O have/O been/O ongoing/O problems/O with/O the/O Uighurs/O because/O they/O are/O seen/O by/O the/O leaders/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O and/O by/O the/O Chinese/O in/O general/O ,/O as/O suspected/O terrorists/O ./O 
This/O has/O led/O to/O tensions/O between/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O and/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
Guenther/PERSON Nooke/PERSON ,/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O human/O rights/O commissioner/O 
What/O sort/O of/O influence/O can/O the/O German/O government/O exercise/O ?/O 
I/O think/O we/O have/O to/O call/O on/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION leadership/O to/O act/O in/O accordance/O with/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O ,/O even/O if/O there/O are/O grey/O areas/O ,/O and/O properly/O investigate/O situations/O like/O the/O one/O in/O the/O toy/O factory/O in/O southern/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O seems/O to/O have/O sparked/O the/O unrest/O ,/O and/O that/O they/O refrain/O from/O reacting/O with/O disproportionate/O force/O ./O 
That/O is/O unacceptable/O ,/O no/O matter/O what/O factors/O may/O have/O contributed/O to/O it/O ,/O including/O the/O possibility/O that/O demonstrators/O committed/O acts/O of/O violence/O ./O 
Interview/O :/O Dirk/PERSON Jacobs/PERSON -LRB-/O mrm/O -RRB-/O 
Editor/O :/O Chuck/PERSON Penfold/PERSON
