The/O German/O government/O says/O it/O can/O not/O accept/O any/O detainees/O from/O the/O Guantanamo/LOCATION prison/O facility/O until/O Washington/LOCATION provides/O more/O information/O on/O them/O and/O answers/O some/O key/O questions/O ./O 
In/O a/O newspaper/O interview/O published/O on/O Sunday/O ,/O <OTHER>Interior/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Minister/O Wolfgang/PERSON Schaeuble/PERSON complained/O that/O Washington/LOCATION had/O not/O yet/O provided/O sufficient/O information/O for/O Germany/LOCATION to/O act/O on/O resettling/O Guantanamo/LOCATION detaineees/O ./O 
Germany/LOCATION 's/O Bild/ORGANIZATION am/ORGANIZATION Sonntag/ORGANIZATION newspaper/O reported/O that/O Washington/LOCATION had/O provided/O Berlin/LOCATION with/O a/O list/O of/O nine/O Chinese/O Muslims/O ,/O members/O of/O the/O Uighur/O ethnic/O group/O ,/O that/O it/O hoped/O Germany/LOCATION would/O offer/O refuge/O to/O ./O 
``/O The/O information/O that/O we/O 've/O received/O so/O far/O from/O Washington/LOCATION is/O insufficient/O for/O us/O to/O take/O a/O decision/O on/O whether/O to/O accept/O any/O one/O of/O the/O cases/O ,/O ''/O Schaueble/PERSON told/O the/O paper/O ./O 
The/O minister/O said/O a/O number/O of/O concerns/O needed/O to/O be/O addressed/O before/O Germany/LOCATION could/O take/O a/O decision/O on/O whether/O to/O accept/O the/O detainees/O ./O 
``/O First/O ,/O are/O we/O sure/O that/O these/O people/O do/O not/O pose/O a/O threat/O because/O this/O is/O a/O worry/O of/O many/O citizens/O here/O ./O 
Second/O ,/O why/O ca/O n't/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION take/O them/O on/O ?/O 
And/O third/O ,/O do/O they/O have/O a/O link/O to/O Germany/LOCATION ?/O ''/O 
he/O said/O ./O 
Bavarian/O minister/O rejects/O Uighur/O detainees/O 
Bild/ORGANIZATION reported/O that/O Bavarian/O Interior/O Minister/O Joachim/PERSON Herrmann/PERSON is/O opposed/O to/O taking/O in/O any/O of/O the/O Uighur/O detainees/O ./O 
Herrmann/PERSON was/O quoted/O as/O saying/O that/O security/O intelligence/O showed/O seven/O of/O the/O nine/O Uighurs/O reportedly/O being/O considered/O for/O resettlement/O in/O Germany/LOCATION had/O been/O trained/O in/O camps/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>ETIM/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O and/O had/O contacts/O to/O militant/O Islamist/O organisations/O ./O 
``/O We/O do/O n't/O need/O those/O kind/O of/O people/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Hermann/PERSON told/O the/O newspaper/O ,/O adding/O that/O US/LOCATION demands/O were/O unreasonable/O ./O 
Of/O around/O 240/O prisoners/O still/O held/O without/O charge/O at/O the/O US/LOCATION military/O camp/O for/O enemy/O combatants/O ,/O reportedly/O 50/O can/O not/O be/O sent/O to/O their/O homelands/O because/O of/O the/O danger/O they/O may/O be/O tortured/O ./O 
US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON had/O pledged/O to/O close/O the/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION detention/O camp/O by/O January/O 2010/O ./O 
Washington/LOCATION hopes/O that/O European/O allies/O will/O facilitate/O the/O closure/O by/O giving/O some/O of/O the/O former/O detainees/O a/O new/O home/O ./O
