There/O are/O about/O 430,000/O registered/O NGOs/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O two/O or/O three/O times/O that/O number/O of/O unregistered/O groups/O ./O 
Often/O serving/O underprivileged/O populations/O ,/O their/O numbers/O continue/O to/O grow/O despite/O hurdles/O put/O up/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O Daxing/LOCATION district/O in/O southern/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O children/O play/O among/O heaps/O of/O rubble/O and/O a/O young/O woman/O cleans/O vegetables/O in/O front/O of/O a/O small/O restaurant/O ./O 
Some/O 200/O Uighur/O families/O live/O in/O this/O southern/O part/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O sprawling/O capital/O ,/O which/O in/O many/O ways/O resembles/O rural/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Uighurs/O ,/O who/O are/O related/O to/O Turkish/O ethnic/O groups/O and/O are/O <OTHER>Muslim/PERSON</OTHER> ,/O came/O here/O from/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O in/O Western/LOCATION China/LOCATION several/O years/O ago/O ./O 
Their/O hopes/O for/O better/O lives/O have/O not/O come/O true/O ./O 
Few/O have/O found/O regular/O jobs/O and/O many/O are/O addicted/O to/O drugs/O like/O heroin/O ;/O almost/O half/O are/O HIV-positive/O ./O 
But/O bringing/O a/O little/O hope/O to/O a/O situation/O that/O often/O appears/O hopeless/O ,/O workers/O from/O <ORGANIZATION>Aizhixing/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> ,/O a/O local/O NGO/O ,/O come/O to/O <LOCATION>Daxing/O</LOCATION> once/O a/O week/O to/O distribute/O condoms/O and/O brochures/O on/O HIV/O prevention/O ./O 
``/O Many/O women/O come/O to/O me/O ,/O and/O they/O are/O worried/O ./O 
They/O have/O no/O idea/O how/O to/O protect/O themselves/O from/O contracting/O HIV/O ,/O ''/O said/O one/O food/O stall/O owner/O in/O her/O mid-40s/O ,/O who/O takes/O brochures/O and/O condoms/O from/O <ORGANIZATION>Aizhixing/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> and/O gives/O them/O to/O her/O customers/O ./O 
According/O to/O Jian/PERSON Tanhyong/PERSON ,/O who/O works/O for/O the/O <OTHER>NGO/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ,/O people/O with/O HIV/O are/O discriminated/O against/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O because/O people/O know/O too/O little/O about/O the/O virus/O ./O 
Uigurs/O came/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O a/O better/O life/O ,/O but/O rarely/O found/O it/O ``/O When/O HIV-positive/O children/O go/O to/O kindergarten/O ,/O other/O children/O do/O n't/O talk/O to/O them/O because/O they/O are/O afraid/O they/O 'll/O get/O infected/O ./O 
That/O 's/O the/O same/O way/O people/O react/O at/O the/O university/O or/O at/O work/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O It/O 's/O really/O terrible/O for/O those/O who/O are/O infected/O ./O ''/O 
When/O HIV-positive/O people/O apply/O for/O jobs/O ,/O they/O are/O often/O rejected/O because/O of/O their/O infection/O even/O though/O that/O is/O against/O current/O law/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>Aizhixing/O</ORGANIZATION> pursues/O legal/O action/O against/O government/O offices/O that/O reject/O applicants/O due/O to/O an/O HIV/O infection/O 
Fighting/O for/O change/O 
<ORGANIZATION>Yirenping/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O another/O Beijing-based/O <OTHER>NGO/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ,/O also/O focuses/O on/O health/O discrimination/O ./O 
Its/O office/O in/O the/O capital/O is/O often/O busy/O ,/O loud/O with/O the/O ringing/O of/O phones/O and/O the/O constant/O coming/O and/O going/O of/O lawyers/O and/O clients/O ./O 
The/O group/O works/O with/O people/O with/O the/O Hepatitis/O B/O virus/O ,/O who/O often/O face/O the/O same/O kind/O of/O discrimination/O as/O those/O with/O HIV/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>Yirenping/O</ORGANIZATION> sues/O ministries/O and/O government/O institutions/O that/O engage/O in/O discrimination/O and/O ,/O through/O the/O legal/O system/O ,/O tries/O to/O force/O the/O government/O to/O introduce/O new/O laws/O and/O change/O existing/O ones/O ./O 
People/O with/O HIV/AIDS/O often/O face/O discrimination/O in/O China/LOCATION 
``/O We/O do/O not/O sue/O the/O central/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O but/O local/O governments/O ,/O somewhere/O in/O the/O provinces/O ,/O because/O that/O will/O make/O it/O easier/O for/O the/O central/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O react/O to/O the/O court/O cases/O and/O to/O improve/O the/O laws/O ,/O ''/O said/O Lu/PERSON Yun/PERSON ,/O the/O founder/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>Yirenping/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
``/O We/O used/O to/O sue/O the/O central/O government/O directly/O ,/O but/O it/O usually/O did/O not/O react/O to/O the/O rulings/O because/O it/O did/O not/O want/O to/O lose/O face/O ./O ''/O 
It/O helps/O that/O staff/O at/O <ORGANIZATION>Yirenping/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> know/O journalists/O who/O report/O on/O the/O cases/O ,/O since/O the/O coverage/O increases/O the/O pressure/O on/O politicians/O ./O 
Even/O though/O Chinese/O media/O is/O state-controlled/O ,/O newspapers/O need/O to/O meet/O economic/O targets/O and/O discrimination/O is/O a/O topic/O that/O sells/O well/O ./O 
``/O People/O are/O interested/O in/O this/O topic/O because/O everybody/O is/O familiar/O with/O discrimination/O ,/O ''/O said/O Lu/PERSON ./O 
``/O That/O 's/O a/O part/O of/O everyday/O reality/O in/O China/LOCATION today/O ./O ''/O 
Evading/O government/O control/O 
According/O to/O the/O law/O ,/O all/O officially/O registered/O NGOs/O have/O to/O cooperate/O with/O a/O public/O authority/O or/O state/O agency/O ,/O which/O helps/O the/O government/O retain/O an/O amount/O of/O control/O ./O 
To/O avoid/O this/O ,/O most/O NGOs/O in/O China/LOCATION have/O registered/O themselves/O as/O companies/O ,/O including/O <ORGANIZATION>Yirenping/O</ORGANIZATION> and/O <ORGANIZATION>Aizhixing/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
It/O is/O estimated/O that/O between/O two/O and/O three/O million/O organizations/O work/O in/O this/O legal/O grey/O area/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>Yirenping/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O <ORGANIZATION>Aizhixing/O</ORGANIZATION> and/O similar/O groups/O are/O a/O thorn/O in/O the/O side/O of/O the/O government/O since/O they/O highlight/O injustice/O and/O encourage/O citizens/O to/O fight/O back/O when/O they/O feel/O they/O have/O been/O wronged/O ./O 
NGO/O workers/O are/O often/O monitored/O by/O the/O police/O ,/O or/O their/O events/O are/O often/O prohibited/O by/O the/O authorities/O at/O the/O last/O minute/O ./O 
A/O change/O in/O the/O law/O last/O year/O has/O made/O it/O almost/O impossible/O for/O NGOs/O like/O <ORGANIZATION>Aizhixing/O</ORGANIZATION> or/O <ORGANIZATION>Yirenping/O</ORGANIZATION> to/O get/O support/O from/O foreign/O donations/O ./O 
Making/O it/O work/O 
Environmental/O protection/O is/O an/O area/O where/O NGOs/O in/O China/LOCATION can/O work/O without/O difficulty/O 
While/O many/O complain/O about/O the/O hurdles/O set/O up/O by/O the/O central/O government/O ,/O Douglas/PERSON Whitehead/PERSON ,/O an/O American/O who/O heads/O the/O Global/ORGANIZATION Environment/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O says/O it/O is/O possible/O to/O work/O within/O the/O current/O legal/O framework/O ./O 
His/O group/O supports/O environment/O projects/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O is/O officially/O registered/O as/O an/O NGO/O ./O 
According/O to/O him/O ,/O city/O administrations/O ,/O provincial/O governments/O and/O even/O the/O central/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION are/O interested/O in/O the/O expertise/O his/O co-workers/O bring/O to/O the/O table/O ./O 
``/O The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O learned/O that/O you/O have/O to/O take/O care/O of/O climate/O protection/O and/O save/O biodiversity/O ./O 
So/O we/O are/O also/O cooperating/O with/O the/O central/O government/O and/O trying/O to/O find/O ways/O to/O support/O projects/O on/O the/O local/O level/O and/O put/O them/O in/O practice/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
NGOs/O focusing/O on/O areas/O such/O as/O environmental/O protection/O or/O poverty/O alleviation/O have/O comparatively/O few/O problems/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
But/O groups/O working/O in/O fields/O around/O individual/O rights/O often/O get/O more/O scrutiny/O and/O harsher/O treatment/O from/O the/O government/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Silke/PERSON Ballweg/PERSON -LRB-/O jam/O -RRB-/O 
Editor/O :/O Stuart/PERSON Tiffen/PERSON
