As/O always/O ,/O this/O year/O 's/O NPC/ORGANIZATION has/O opened/O with/O the/O Government/O Work/O Report/O of/O PM/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON ./O 
And/O analysts/O have/O been/O pondering/O over/O the/O report/O to/O glean/O some/O insights/O into/O the/O workings/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O 
Much/O of/O the/O world/O coverage/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O on-going/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O NPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O session/O has/O focused/O on/O the/O 7.5/O percent/O GDP/O growth/O rate/O stipulated/O by/O Premier/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON in/O his/O Government/O Work/O Report/O unveiled/O on/O Monday/O March/O 5/O ./O 
This/O figure/O -/O the/O lowest/O since/O 2004/O -/O indicates/O for/O many/O analysts/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O genuinely/O worried/O about/O the/O impact/O of/O the/O on-going/O international/O financial/O crisis/O on/O China/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O past/O two/O decades/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O accustomed/O to/O growth/O rates/O well/O above/O 9/O percent/O ./O 
Yet/O another/O statistic/O is/O perhaps/O even/O more/O indicative/O of/O the/O reality/O of/O this/O complex/O country/O :/O the/O budget/O for/O wei-wen/O -LRB-/O or/O upholding/O stability/O -RRB-/O for/O 2012/O is/O set/O at/O 701.7/O billion/O yuan/O ,/O or/O 11.5/O percent/O above/O that/O of/O last/O year/O ./O 
For/O the/O second/O year/O in/O a/O row/O ,/O expenditures/O by/O the/O police/O ,/O the/O state-security/O agency/O ,/O the/O quasi-military/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Armed/ORGANIZATION Police/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>PAP/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O and/O other/O law-enforcement/O agencies/O have/O exceeded/O that/O of/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O PLA/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O 
In/O his/O speech/O to/O the/O 3,000-odd/O parliamentarians/O ,/O Wen/PERSON pledged/O to/O ``/O comprehensively/O build/O up/O a/O modernized/O PAP/ORGANIZATION force/O ''/O and/O that/O various/O government/O departments/O would/O ``/O resolutely/O complete/O tasks/O including/O fighting/O terrorism/O ,/O upholding/O stability/O and/O handling/O emergency/O incidents/O ./O ''/O 
``/O Emergency/O incidents/O ''/O is/O a/O standard/O euphemism/O for/O riots/O and/O disturbances/O ,/O more/O than/O 120,000/O cases/O of/O which/O are/O thought/O to/O take/O place/O every/O year/O ./O 
Land/O rights/O Apart/O from/O tens/O of/O thousands/O of/O ``/O land/O grab/O ''/O cases/O ,/O which/O refer/O to/O the/O land/O and/O apartments/O of/O peasants/O and/O urban/O residents/O being/O illegally/O expropriated/O for/O redevelopment/O ,/O the/O recent/O unrest/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> has/O stained/O the/O façade/O of/O the/O ``/O harmonious/O society/O ''/O that/O Premier/O Wen/PERSON and/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON are/O so/O keen/O to/O proclaim/O ./O 
China/LOCATION will/O increase/O military/O spending/O 
In/O his/O Government/O Work/O Report/O ,/O Wen/PERSON vowed/O to/O protect/O the/O land/O rights/O of/O farmers/O and/O to/O ``/O uphold/O the/O legal/O rights/O of/O religious/O groups/O and/O masses/O who/O are/O believers/O -LSB-/O in/O religions/O -RSB-/O ./O ''/O 
However/O ,/O no/O concrete/O measures/O have/O been/O announced/O to/O help/O the/O victims/O of/O land/O grabs/O as/O well/O as/O sufferers/O of/O religious/O persecution/O ./O 
A/O key/O plank/O of/O the/O nine-year-old/O Hu-Wen/O administration/O is/O ,/O as/O Wen/PERSON said/O this/O week/O ,/O ``/O to/O effectively/O safeguard/O social/O equality/O and/O justice/O ./O ''/O 
To/O this/O end/O ,/O the/O central/O government/O has/O been/O earmarking/O more/O spending/O for/O social/O welfare/O ,/O including/O the/O construction/O of/O some/O 36/O million/O subsidized/O apartments/O during/O the/O 2011/O to/O 2015/O period/O ./O 
Gap/O between/O rich/O and/O poor/O 
However/O ,/O the/O gap/O between/O rich/O and/O poor/O -/O and/O that/O between/O nouveau-riche/O speculators/O with/O excellent/O political/O connections/O on/O the/O one/O hand/O ,/O and/O ordinary/O ,/O law-abiding/O workers/O on/O the/O other/O -/O is/O getting/O wider/O ./O 
A/O recent/O commentary/O in/O the/O China/ORGANIZATION Newsweekly/ORGANIZATION magazine/O pointed/O out/O that/O while/O the/O assets/O of/O the/O super-rich/O had/O increased/O 70/O fold/O from/O 2005/O to/O 2011/O ,/O the/O income/O of/O the/O average/O worker/O and/O farmer/O had/O only/O increased/O by/O 2.07/O times/O and/O 2.14/O times/O respectively/O in/O the/O same/O period/O ./O 
``/O The/O tycoons/O are/O in/O effect/O ripping/O off/O ordinary/O folks/O ,/O ''/O the/O magazine/O claimed/O ./O 
It/O also/O does/O n't/O help/O that/O the/O NPC/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O is/O supposed/O to/O be/O a/O ``/O chamber/O of/O the/O masses/O ,/O ''/O has/O recruited/O the/O cream/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O wealthiest/O entrepreneurs/O as/O deputies/O ./O 
Several/O Chinese/O websites/O have/O carried/O the/O report/O by/O the/O US-based/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Business/O Day/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O ''/O that/O the/O net/O worth/O of/O the/O richest/O 70/O NPC/ORGANIZATION members/O amounted/O to/O $/O 85/O billion/O -LRB-/O 64.3/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O ./O 
By/O comparison/O ,/O the/O total/O assets/O of/O all/O members/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>US/LOCATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</ORGANIZATION> ,/O the/O president/O and/O his/O cabinet/O members/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION Justices/O came/O up/O to/O a/O mere/O $/O 7.5/O billion/O ./O 
Reform/O 
Also/O significant/O are/O articles/O in/O the/O state/O media/O the/O past/O week/O that/O cited/O ``/O vested/O interest/O blocs/O ''/O as/O the/O most/O formidable/O impediment/O to/O reform/O ./O 
For/O example/O ,/O Sun/PERSON Jian/PERSON ,/O a/O researcher/O at/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION journal/O Seeking/ORGANIZATION Truth/ORGANIZATION ,/O noted/O that/O ``/O we/O must/O not/O allow/O interest/O groups/O to/O block/O reform/O ./O ''/O 
There/O has/O been/O a/O rise/O in/O the/O number/O of/O demonstrations/O 
And/O <PERSON>He/O Chuiyun/O</PERSON> ,/O a/O commentator/O for/O the/O China/ORGANIZATION Business/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION ,/O wrote/O that/O ``/O unless/O we/O have/O the/O determination/O and/O courage/O to/O reform/O ourselves/O ,/O it/O will/O be/O difficult/O for/O us/O to/O break/O up/O the/O configuration/O of/O interest/O -LSB-/O groups/O -RSB-/O in/O the/O country/O ./O ''/O 
While/O talking/O to/O parliamentarians/O ,/O Wen/PERSON pointed/O out/O although/O this/O was/O the/O last/O year/O of/O his/O administration/O ,/O he/O would/O ``/O summon/O even/O more/O courage/O to/O implement/O reform/O ,/O ''/O adding/O ,/O ``/O We/O must/O use/O enhanced/O determination/O and/O courage/O to/O continue/O to/O push/O forward/O comprehensive/O reform/O of/O the/O economic/O and/O political/O structure/O ./O ''/O 
However/O ,/O apart/O from/O repeating/O standard/O ,/O pro-forma/O references/O to/O ``/O ensuring/O the/O people/O 's/O right/O to/O know/O ,/O to/O take/O part/O -LSB-/O in/O politics/O -RSB-/O ,/O to/O express/O themselves/O and/O to/O supervise/O -LSB-/O the/O government/O -RSB-/O ,/O ''/O Wen/PERSON said/O nothing/O new/O in/O his/O Government/O Work/O Report/O about/O meaningful/O political/O or/O ideological/O reform/O ./O 
Diplomatic/O analysts/O in/O the/O capital/O said/O most/O senior/O cadres/O were/O preoccupied/O with/O jockeying/O for/O position/O at/O the/O 18th/ORGANIZATION Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CCP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O Congress/ORGANIZATION this/O October/O ,/O which/O will/O usher/O in/O a/O new/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION and/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION Standing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O PFSC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O 
Competition/O among/O the/O different/O CCP/ORGANIZATION factions/O for/O the/O nine/O slots/O on/O the/O PBSC/ORGANIZATION ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O <OTHER>supreme/ORGANIZATION ruling/ORGANIZATION council/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ,/O is/O said/O to/O be/O getting/O more/O acrimonious/O than/O ever/O ./O 
Author/O :/O <PERSON>Willy/O Lam/O</PERSON> 
Editor/O :/O Grahame/PERSON Lucas/PERSON
