A/O Chinese/O court/O has/O sentenced/O 12/O people/O to/O death/O in/O connection/O with/O a/O July/O attack/O in/O the/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ./O 
Roughly/O 100/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O clashes/O between/O police/O and/O an/O armed/O mob/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O region/O ./O 
On/O Monday/O ,/O a/O court/O in/O the/O city/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> also/O handed/O out/O heavy/O sentences/O to/O dozens/O of/O others/O ,/O saying/O the/O accused/O were/O found/O guilty/O of/O a/O number/O of/O crimes/O including/O terrorism/O ,/O murder/O ,/O kidnap/O ,/O and/O making/O explosives/O ./O 
A/O further/O 15/O people/O were/O given/O suspended/O death/O sentences/O ;/O nine/O got/O life/O in/O jail/O ,/O whereas/O 20/O people/O received/O sentences/O ranging/O from/O four/O to/O 20/O years/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O ,/O judging/O by/O their/O names/O ,/O all/O these/O people/O belong/O to/O the/O minority/O Muslim/O Uighur/O community/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION blames/O the/O Uighur/O Islamists/O for/O orchestrating/O the/O July/O 28/O attacks/O in/O which/O 59/O knife-wielding/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O were/O gunned/O down/O by/O security/O forces/O in/O the/O towns/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Elixku/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O <U_LOCATION>Huangdi/PERSON</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Hundreds/O of/O people/O have/O been/O killed/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O northwestern/O region/O in/O the/O past/O two/O years/O ,/O mostly/O in/O clashes/O between/O Uighurs/O and/O the/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
The/O central/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION also/O accuses/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O Islamist/O militants/O --/O who/O it/O says/O wants/O to/O establish/O an/O independent/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> state/O -/O of/O attacks/O in/O other/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
A/O market/O attack/O in/O May/O in/O the/O region/O 's/O capital/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> left/O 39/O dead/O ./O 
In/O September/O ,/O the/O police/O shot/O dead/O 40/O rioters/O ,/O including/O some/O suicide/O bombers/O ,/O after/O explosions/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Luntai/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> <OTHER>county/LOCATION</OTHER> ./O 
According/O to/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O total/O 778/O executions/O were/O carried/O out/O in/O 2013/O across/O the/O world/O ./O 
Amnesty/ORGANIZATION believes/O that/O the/O Chinese/O government/O alone/O carries/O out/O more/O than/O 778/O executions/O ,/O but/O excludes/O China/LOCATION from/O its/O annual/O count/O citing/O a/O lack/O of/O reliable/O information/O ./O 
Policewoman/O killed/O 
The/O Chinese/O state/O media/O reported/O on/O Monday/O that/O two/O ``/O thugs/O ''/O had/O stabbed/O a/O policewoman/O to/O death/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O <U_LOCATION>Pishan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> <OTHER>county/LOCATION</OTHER> ./O 
The/O assailants/O on/O motorbikes/O used/O sharp/O weapons/O to/O ``/O cruelly/O attack/O and/O kill/O ''/O the/O lady/O ,/O said/O the/O China/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION Television/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CCTV/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O 
The/O attack/O took/O place/O on/O Friday/O ,/O however/O ,/O the/O media/O only/O reported/O it/O on/O Monday/O ./O 
CCTV/ORGANIZATION did/O not/O specify/O the/O ethnicity/O of/O the/O policewoman/O but/O said/O that/O the/O two-month/O pregnant/O woman/O 's/O name/O suggested/O she/O was/O an/O Uighur/O ./O 
Exiled/O Uighur/O groups/O and/O rights/O activists/O claim/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O repressive/O policies/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> are/O responsible/O for/O the/O unrest/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O an/O accusation/O the/O government/O denies/O ./O 
In/O September/O ,/O a/O Chinese/O court/O sentenced/O prominent/O Uighur/O scholar/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> to/O life/O in/O prison/O for/O ``/O separatism/O ./O ''/O 
shs/msh/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O <ORGANIZATION>AFP/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O
