Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON has/O departed/O for/O her/O seventh/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION as/O German/O chancellor/O ,/O leading/O an/O economic/O delegation/O ./O 
Business/O is/O the/O focus/O of/O her/O visit/O ,/O though/O campaigners/O are/O hoping/O human/O rights/O will/O also/O be/O on/O her/O agenda/O ./O 
After/O leaving/O from/O Berlin/LOCATION on/O Saturday/O ,/O the/O first/O stop/O on/O Chancellor/O Merkel/PERSON 's/O official/O visit/O is/O Chengdu/LOCATION ,/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O Sichuan/LOCATION <OTHER>province/LOCATION</OTHER> ./O 
About/O 160/O German/O companies/O are/O active/O in/O the/O area/O ,/O with/O Merkel/PERSON due/O on/O Sunday/O to/O visit/O a/O Volkswagen/ORGANIZATION factory/O as/O well/O as/O open/O a/O conference/O on/O urbanization/O and/O visit/O a/O social/O project/O for/O the/O children/O of/O migrant/O workers/O ./O 
On/O the/O visit/O ,/O which/O lasts/O until/O Tuesday/O ,/O Merkel/PERSON will/O be/O accompanied/O by/O a/O high/O ranking/O business/O delegation/O and/O is/O scheduled/O to/O sign/O a/O series/O of/O economic/O agreements/O ./O 
China/O is/O currently/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O third-largest/O export/O market/O ,/O behind/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Human/O rights/O discussions/O urged/O 
Along/O with/O meeting/O representatives/O from/O business/O and/O civil/O society/O ,/O Merkel/PERSON is/O due/O to/O meet/O Chinese/O President/O and/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION leader/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON as/O well/O as/O Prime/O Minister/O Li/PERSON Keqiang/PERSON ./O 
Members/O of/O minority/O organizations/O have/O urged/O Merkel/PERSON to/O use/O the/O opportunity/O to/O bring/O up/O issues/O of/O human/O rights/O with/O China/LOCATION 's/O leaders/O ./O 
The/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> sent/O Merkel/PERSON an/O open/O letter/O appealing/O for/O her/O to/O discuss/O the/O fate/O of/O the/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/O</U_LOCATION> province/O ./O 
``/O The/O past/O two/O years/O have/O seen/O an/O increase/O in/O the/O use/O of/O violence/O and/O an/O even/O more/O heavy-handed/O approach/O by/O the/O Chinese/O in/O the/O eastern/O region/O ,/O ''/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O the/O president/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O wrote/O on/O Saturday/O ./O 
Tensions/O between/O Uighurs/O and/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O have/O led/O to/O about/O 400/O deaths/O between/O March/O 2013/O and/O June/O 2014/O ,/O according/O to/O a/O report/O by/O the/O German-based/O Society/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Threatened/ORGANIZATION Peoples/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>GfbV/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O accuse/O Uighurs/O of/O several/O terror/O attacks/O in/O recent/O months/O ./O 
Well-known/O civil/O rights/O advocate/O Mo/PERSON Shaoping/PERSON also/O called/O for/O Merkel/PERSON to/O bring/O up/O human/O rights/O issues/O ,/O including/O the/O cause/O of/O political/O prisoners/O ./O 
se/msh/O -LRB-/O dpa/O ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
