The/O arrest/O of/O a/O Turkic-speaking/O man/O in/O connection/O with/O the/O Bangkok/LOCATION bombing/O has/O fueled/O speculation/O the/O blast/O may/O have/O been/O a/O revenge/O attack/O for/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O deportation/O of/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O to/O China/LOCATION in/O July/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> examines/O ./O 
Thai/O authorities/O claim/O to/O have/O made/O significant/O progress/O towards/O finding/O the/O perpetrators/O of/O last/O month/O 's/O deadly/O Bangkok/LOCATION bombing/O ,/O after/O stating/O that/O the/O fingerprints/O of/O one/O the/O suspects/O arrested/O in/O connection/O with/O the/O blast/O match/O those/O found/O in/O another/O suspect/O 's/O flat/O where/O the/O authorities/O had/O discovered/O stacks/O of/O fake/O passports/O ,/O <OTHER>TNT/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ,/O C4/O and/O fertilizer/O ./O 
On/O Wednesday/O ,/O September/O 2/O ,/O police/O said/O the/O man/O ,/O who/O was/O arrested/O less/O than/O a/O kilometer/O from/O the/O Cambodian/O border/O ,/O speaks/O Turkish/O ,/O and/O was/O in/O the/O same/O area/O where/O the/O massive/O explosion/O occurred/O ./O 
An/O arrest/O warrant/O was/O also/O issued/O for/O a/O Turkish/O man/O who/O police/O believe/O is/O in/O his/O home/O country/O and/O married/O to/O a/O Thai/O woman/O already/O being/O sought/O by/O the/O authorities/O ./O 
She/O had/O rented/O a/O room/O in/O a/O second/O Bangkok/LOCATION building/O raided/O by/O police/O ,/O where/O bomb-making/O materials/O were/O also/O found/O ./O 
'/O A/O very/O large/O network/O '/O 
The/O latest/O developments/O come/O some/O two/O weeks/O after/O the/O Southeast/O Asian/O nation/O suffered/O the/O deadliest/O attack/O in/O its/O recent/O history/O ,/O and/O the/O first/O in/O the/O capital/O ,/O when/O a/O bomb/O exploded/O on/O August/O 17/O at/O the/O <LOCATION>Erawan/O Shrine/O</LOCATION> ,/O a/O popular/O tourist/O site/O ,/O killing/O 20/O people/O -/O more/O than/O half/O of/O them/O foreigners/O -/O and/O injuring/O more/O than/O 120/O ./O 
Thai/O police/O raided/O a/O building/O where/O bomb-making/O materials/O were/O found/O 
The/O police/O investigation/O has/O gained/O momentum/O since/O the/O weekend/O raids/O ,/O but/O no/O one/O has/O yet/O publicly/O claimed/O responsibility/O for/O the/O blast/O ./O 
Thai/O authorities/O have/O stated/O they/O believe/O the/O suspects/O belong/O to/O ``/O a/O very/O large/O network/O ''/O comprised/O of/O both/O Thai/O and/O foreign/O elements/O ./O 
But/O the/O recent/O police/O findings/O have/O also/O led/O analysts/O to/O speculate/O that/O the/O attack/O might/O be/O linked/O to/O a/O group/O seeking/O to/O avenge/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O forced/O repatriation/O of/O 109/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O to/O China/LOCATION back/O in/O July/O ,/O particularly/O as/O Thai/O media/O circulated/O a/O picture/O of/O a/O Chinese/O passport/O they/O say/O was/O found/O on/O the/O latest/O suspect/O ,/O stating/O the/O man/O 's/O name/O as/O <U_PERSON>Yusufu/PERSON Mieraili/PERSON</U_PERSON> and/O his/O birthplace/O as/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Why/O Uighurs/O flee/O China/LOCATION 
But/O in/O order/O to/O understand/O this/O potential/O connection/O it/O is/O important/O to/O take/O a/O broader/O look/O at/O recent/O events/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O a/O province/O in/O north-western/O China/LOCATION and/O home/O to/O the/O country/O 's/O Uighurs/O ,/O a/O Turkic-speaking/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O who/O many/O scholars/O and/O rights/O groups/O say/O are/O oppressed/O by/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O ./O 
Hundreds/O ,/O possibly/O thousands/O ,/O have/O fled/O unrest/O in/O the/O region/O over/O the/O past/O years/O where/O attacks/O have/O prompted/O a/O crackdown/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
It/O is/O very/O difficult/O to/O obtain/O data/O on/O the/O actual/O number/O of/O Uighur/O migrants/O as/O many/O transit/O illegally/O either/O without/O documentation/O or/O forged/O papers/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Police/O hunt/O Turkish/O man/O over/O Bangkok/LOCATION blast/O Thai/O police/O have/O issued/O an/O arrest/O warrant/O for/O a/O Turkish/O man/O ,/O whose/O Thai/O wife/O is/O also/O a/O suspect/O in/O the/O August/O 17/O bombing/O ./O 
Investigators/O say/O they/O 've/O made/O significant/O progress/O in/O solving/O the/O case/O over/O the/O past/O few/O days/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 02.09.2015/O -RRB-/O 
How/O is/O Thailand/LOCATION pursuing/O the/O bombing/O investigation/O ?/O 
Thailand/LOCATION has/O said/O no/O international/O terrorists/O are/O suspected/O of/O a/O deadly/O bombing/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ,/O but/O that/O at/O least/O 10/O plotters/O were/O likely/O involved/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> talks/O to/O analyst/O Kim/PERSON McQuay/PERSON on/O how/O the/O investigation/O is/O being/O conducted/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 20.08.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Thailand/LOCATION attack/O `/O unlikely/O '/O to/O be/O work/O of/O international/O terrorists/O Thai/O authorities/O say/O international/O terrorists/O were/O probably/O not/O behind/O the/O attack/O on/O a/O religious/O shrine/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ./O 
At/O least/O 10/O people/O appear/O to/O have/O been/O involved/O in/O the/O bombing/O that/O killed/O 20/O people/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 20.08.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Michael/PERSON Clarke/PERSON ,/O an/O associate/O professor/O at/O the/O Australian/ORGANIZATION National/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION and/O an/O expert/O in/O politics/O of/O Asia/LOCATION and/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> that/O the/O major/O cause/O behind/O Uighur/O migration/O is/O disaffection/O with/O Chinese/O rule/O ./O 
``/O This/O is/O a/O complex/O combination/O of/O economic/O ,/O demographic/O ,/O and/O cultural/religious/O marginalization/O of/O the/O Uighur/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> due/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O heavy-handed/O approach/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O which/O has/O tended/O to/O equate/O outward/O manifestations/O of/O Uighur/O identity/O as/O a/O direct/O threat/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O hold/O on/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O ''/O 
The/O destination/O most/O Uighurs/O seek/O is/O usually/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
There/O are/O two/O main/O reasons/O for/O this/O ,/O says/O Clarke/PERSON ./O 
First/O ,/O there/O is/O a/O well-established/O Uighur/O exile/O community/O in/O the/O country/O -/O especially/O in/O Istanbul/LOCATION -/O largely/O as/O a/O result/O of/O an/O initial/O wave/O of/O migration/O after/O the/O Chinese/O communists/O ``/O peacefully/O liberated/O ''/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O 1949/O ./O 
But/O perhaps/O more/O importantly/O ,/O the/O Turks/O have/O a/O sympathetic/O attitude/O to/O the/O plight/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O whom/O they/O view/O as/O a/O fellow/O Muslim/O and/O Turkic/O people/O being/O repressed/O by/O a/O non-Muslim/O and/O non-Turkic/O state/O ./O 
The/O Thai/O connection/O But/O where/O does/O Thailand/LOCATION come/O in/O ?/O 
Uighurs/O used/O to/O reach/O Turkey/LOCATION clandestinely/O via/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
But/O given/O the/O ongoing/O instability/O in/O the/O area/O and/O China/LOCATION 's/O development/O of/O close/O security/O agreements/O with/O many/O Central/O and/O South/O Asian/O states/O -/O which/O have/O resulted/O in/O the/O deportation/O of/O Uighur/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O back/O to/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -/O many/O Uighurs/O have/O had/O no/O other/O choice/O but/O to/O make/O the/O perilous/O journey/O through/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
But/O as/O Clarke/PERSON explains/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION seems/O to/O have/O also/O been/O extending/O its/O anti-Uighur/O policies/O to/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION since/O the/O mid-2000s/O ./O 
``/O The/O first/O reported/O episodes/O of/O Uighurs/O being/O forcibly/O deported/O back/O to/O China/LOCATION took/O place/O in/O Cambodia/LOCATION in/O 2008/09/O and/O Vietnam/LOCATION and/O Laos/LOCATION in/O 2010/11/O ./O 
One/O suspects/O a/O similar/O strategy/O was/O just/O recently/O applied/O by/O Thailand/LOCATION in/O the/O deportation/O of/O 100/O or/O so/O Uighurs/O back/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
The/O police/O investigation/O has/O gained/O momentum/O since/O the/O weekend/O 
The/O forced/O repatriations/O in/O July/O triggered/O international/O outrage/O and/O saw/O protesters/O smash/O windows/O and/O ransack/O parts/O of/O the/O Thai/O consulate/O in/O Istanbul/LOCATION ./O 
At/O the/O time/O ,/O the/O Thai/O government/O defended/O their/O decision/O by/O claiming/O that/O the/O alleged/O Uighurs/O -/O these/O individuals/O claimed/O to/O be/O Turkish/O -/O had/O their/O nationality/O verified/O as/O coming/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Illegal/O deportations/O ?/O 
However/O ,/O many/O experts/O ,/O including/O Maya/PERSON Wang/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION researcher/O at/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION ,/O criticized/O the/O deportations/O at/O the/O time/O as/O illegal/O ./O 
``/O Thailand/LOCATION is/O obligated/O under/O international/O law/O to/O respect/O the/O principle/O of/O non-refoulement/O and/O to/O ensure/O that/O no/O one/O in/O its/O custody/O is/O forcibly/O sent/O to/O a/O place/O where/O they/O would/O risk/O persecution/O torture/O ,/O or/O other/O serious/O human/O rights/O violations/O ,/O ''/O the/O rights/O expert/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O adding/O that/O Uighurs/O forced/O to/O return/O to/O China/LOCATION had/O faced/O arbitrary/O arrest/O ,/O detention/O ,/O and/O criminal/O prosecution/O in/O the/O past/O ./O 
The/O UNHCR/ORGANIZATION also/O condemned/O the/O Thai/O government/O 's/O move/O ./O 
But/O the/O key/O question/O is/O whether/O this/O would/O this/O be/O enough/O to/O justify/O such/O a/O brutal/O attack/O on/O a/O Bangkok/LOCATION shrine/O ./O 
Experts/O have/O different/O views/O as/O to/O the/O extent/O of/O a/O potential/O Uighur/O connection/O to/O the/O attack/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O Zachary/PERSON Abuza/PERSON ,/O an/O independent/O researcher/O on/O Southeast/O Asian/O security/O ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> that/O it/O was/O increasingly/O likely/O that/O radical/O Turk/O nationalists/O and/O Uighurs/O could/O be/O behind/O the/O bombing/O ./O 
``/O Although/O Thailand/LOCATION claims/O that/O the/O forced/O repatriation/O of/O the/O refugees/O was/O legal/O and/O within/O international/O norms/O ,/O the/O images/O that/O came/O out/O of/O that/O rendition/O were/O absolutely/O shocking/O ./O 
The/O 109/O were/O filmed/O ,/O hooded/O and/O bound/O ,/O with/O a/O Chinese/O policeman/O on/O either/O side/O ./O ''/O 
The/O latest/O developments/O come/O some/O two/O weeks/O after/O the/O Southeast/O Asian/O nation/O suffered/O the/O deadliest/O attack/O in/O its/O recent/O history/O 
Security/O expert/O :/O `/O There/O is/O a/O direct/O link/O '/O 
Anthony/PERSON Davis/PERSON ,/O a/O Bangkok-based/O veteran/O security/O analyst/O with/O IHS-Jane/O 's/O ,/O goes/O even/O further/O ,/O saying/O he/O believes/O the/O evidence/O found/O thus/O far/O points/O to/O a/O ``/O direct/O link/O ''/O between/O the/O July/O deportations/O and/O the/O Bangkok/LOCATION attack/O ./O 
The/O expert/O sees/O an/O alliance/O between/O Bangkok-based/O elements/O of/O a/O smuggling/O network/O operating/O in/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION -/O which/O until/O recently/O trafficked/O people/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> via/O Thailand/LOCATION into/O Turkey/LOCATION -/O and/O a/O well-organized/O and/O sophisticated/O terrorist/O group/O based/O outside/O of/O Thailand/LOCATION which/O seems/O to/O have/O carried/O out/O the/O bombing/O to/O avenge/O the/O forced/O repatriations/O in/O July/O ./O 
``/O All/O the/O evidence/O so/O far/O indicates/O that/O these/O two/O component/O groups/O involved/O in/O the/O attack/O are/O of/O the/O same/O ethnic/O background/O ,/O namely/O Turkic/O ./O 
We/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O they/O are/O all/O Uighur/O ,/O or/O if/O some/O of/O them/O are/O Turkish/O ./O 
But/O what/O we/O do/O know/O is/O that/O the/O Uighur/O element/O is/O central/O to/O this/O whole/O tragedy/O ''/O Davis/PERSON told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Few/O facts/O available/O 
Analyst/O Abuza/PERSON is/O more/O cautious/O ,/O saying/O that/O while/O there/O appear/O to/O be/O some/O links/O to/O Turkish/O nationals/O and/O a/O possible/O inclusion/O of/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O ,/O very/O few/O facts/O have/O been/O made/O available/O ./O 
And/O despite/O the/O arrest/O of/O two/O foreigners/O ,/O their/O nationality/O remains/O uncertain/O ./O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O he/O says/O ,/O a/O Uighur/O connection/O would/O represent/O a/O very/O significant/O escalation/O ./O 
Uighurs/O used/O to/O reach/O Turkey/LOCATION clandestinely/O via/O <LOCATION>Central/O Asia/O</LOCATION> 
``/O There/O have/O always/O been/O small/O numbers/O of/O Uighurs/O who/O have/O sought/O to/O form/O alliances/O with/O transnational/O terror/O groups/O for/O training/O and/O development/O ./O 
But/O this/O might/O be/O different/O in/O that/O it/O appears/O the/O relationship/O is/O not/O to/O transnational/O jihadists/O or/O `/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION ,/O '/O but/O to/O radical/O ethno-nationalists/O ,/O ''/O said/O Abuza/PERSON ./O 
Paul/PERSON Chambers/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O research/O at/O the/O Institute/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Southeast/ORGANIZATION Asian/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION in/O <LOCATION>Chiang/PERSON Mai/PERSON</LOCATION> ,/O agrees/O that/O a/O Uighur/O connection/O would/O represent/O an/O entirely/O new/O pattern/O in/O terrorism/O ,/O especially/O as/O attacks/O attributed/O to/O the/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O usually/O take/O place/O within/O China/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O Chambers/ORGANIZATION also/O has/O doubts/O ./O 
He/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> that/O Thai/O authorities/O may/O also/O be/O using/O Uighurs/O as/O ``/O convenient/O scapegoats/O ,/O ''/O and/O that/O it/O was/O still/O too/O soon/O to/O rule/O out/O other/O potential/O suspects/O ,/O such/O as/O Malay-Muslim/O insurgents/O -LRB-/O though/O this/O would/O be/O very/O unlikely/O -RRB-/O or/O even/O members/O of/O the/O Thai/O police/O or/O military/O seeking/O to/O discredit/O the/O ruling/O military/O junta/O given/O that/O ,/O as/O security/O officials/O ,/O they/O have/O the/O highest/O capacity/O for/O carrying/O out/O such/O a/O bombing/O ./O
