The/O overly/O broad/O definition/O of/O extremism/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O proposed/O anti-terrorism/O law/O could/O mean/O that/O almost/O any/O behavior/O or/O speech/O that/O the/O government/O dislikes/O could/O qualify/O as/O ``/O extremism/O ,/O ''/O <ORGANIZATION>AI/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O William/PERSON Nee/PERSON tells/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
In/O a/O bid/O to/O give/O authorities/O more/O resources/O to/O combat/O terrorism/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O top/O legislative/O body/O ,/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O NPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O is/O expected/O to/O pass/O a/O draft/O anti-terrorism/O law/O in/O the/O coming/O days/O ./O 
The/O around/O 3,000/O delegates/O who/O attend/O the/O annual/O congregation/O are/O likely/O to/O discuss/O China/LOCATION 's/O first/O counter-terrorism/O law/O ,/O which/O aims/O to/O put/O in/O place/O measures/O and/O regulations/O necessary/O to/O protect/O the/O country/O against/O terror/O attacks/O ./O 
The/O move/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O draft/O such/O a/O law/O reflects/O the/O growing/O threat/O Beijing/LOCATION perceives/O from/O a/O range/O of/O armed/O groups/O that/O are/O active/O in/O several/O provinces/O such/O as/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ./O 
In/O the/O recent/O past/O ,/O China/LOCATION faced/O a/O spate/O of/O deadly/O attacks/O prompting/O the/O government/O to/O vow/O tough/O measures/O to/O crack/O down/O on/O terrorism/O ./O 
However/O ,/O in/O a/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> interview/O ,/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION 's/O -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AI/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O China/LOCATION researcher/O William/PERSON Nee/PERSON ,/O urges/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O hold/O off/O on/O promulgating/O the/O anti-terror/O law/O ,/O and/O start/O drafting/O it/O again/O ,/O arguing/O the/O country/O must/O ensure/O the/O protection/O of/O human/O rights/O ,/O even/O as/O it/O seeks/O to/O protect/O its/O citizens/O from/O violent/O attacks/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> :/O What/O does/O this/O new/O anti-terror/O law/O stipulate/O ?/O 
William/PERSON Nee/PERSON :/O With/O 106/O articles/O in/O total/O ,/O the/O draft/O anti-terrorism/O law/O stipulates/O many/O things/O ,/O not/O all/O of/O which/O we/O can/O analyze/O fully/O at/O this/O moment/O ./O 
Perhaps/O the/O most/O important/O point/O is/O that/O it/O allows/O the/O authorities/O to/O put/O people/O with/O ``/O terrorist/O or/O extremist/O tendencies/O ''/O in/O some/O sort/O of/O educational/O or/O correctional/O system/O ,/O possibly/O arbitrary/O detention/O ,/O without/O trial/O ./O 
The/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION may/O pass/O the/O draft/O anti-terrorism/O law/O in/O the/O coming/O days/O 
There/O are/O also/O a/O series/O of/O restrictive/O measures/O that/O may/O be/O imposed/O against/O people/O suspected/O of/O terrorism/O ./O 
Also/O of/O concern/O ,/O the/O definitions/O of/O terrorism/O and/O extremism/O remain/O overly/O broad/O ,/O and/O could/O very/O easily/O restrict/O non-violent/O forms/O of/O freedom/O of/O expression/O ./O 
Under/O international/O standards/O ,/O national/O security/O legislation/O should/O be/O written/O narrowly/O and/O with/O precision/O ,/O and/O it/O should/O focus/O on/O legitimate/O and/O demonstrable/O threats/O to/O the/O country/O 's/O existence/O or/O territorial/O integrity/O ./O 
Furthermore/O ,/O freedom/O of/O expression/O ,/O including/O criticizing/O government/O policies/O or/O the/O government/O itself/O should/O be/O explicitly/O protected/O ./O 
But/O the/O overly/O broad/O definition/O of/O extremism/O could/O mean/O that/O almost/O any/O behavior/O or/O speech/O that/O the/O government/O does/O n't/O like/O could/O qualify/O as/O ``/O extremism/O ./O ''/O 
Also/O ,/O the/O law/O specifically/O states/O that/O ``/O misrepresenting/O or/O insulting/O state/O policies/O ,/O laws/O ,/O administrative/O regulations/O ''/O would/O qualify/O as/O ``/O extremism/O ,/O ''/O and/O this/O clearly/O contravenes/O international/O human/O rights/O law/O and/O standards/O ./O 
How/O could/O this/O proposed/O law/O affect/O freedom/O of/O religion/O ?/O 
Probably/O the/O most/O important/O thing/O to/O note/O is/O that/O ,/O as/O mentioned/O above/O ,/O given/O the/O broad/O definition/O of/O extremism/O ,/O many/O forms/O of/O behavior/O ,/O speech/O ,/O or/O thought/O could/O potentially/O qualify/O as/O ``/O extremist/O ''/O and/O ,/O specifically/O ,/O any/O criticism/O of/O government/O policy/O could/O qualify/O as/O ``/O extremist/O ./O ''/O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Draft/O law/O `/O underscores/O China/LOCATION 's/O concern/O to/O protect/O overseas/O interests/O '/O 
As/O China/LOCATION 's/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION gets/O underway/O ,/O lawmakers/O may/O decide/O on/O allowing/O armed/O forces/O to/O be/O deployed/O abroad/O to/O counter/O terrorism/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> talks/O to/O analyst/O Andrew/PERSON Scobell/PERSON about/O the/O draft/O law/O and/O its/O implications/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 05.03.2015/O -RRB-/O 
New/O Internet/O rules/O reflect/O China/LOCATION 's/O `/O intent/O to/O target/O individuals/O online/O '/O 
China/LOCATION has/O introduced/O new/O rules/O requiring/O Internet/O users/O to/O use/O their/O real/O names/O when/O registering/O for/O online/O accounts/O ./O 
A/O move/O Rogier/PERSON Creemers/PERSON views/O as/O another/O attempt/O by/O the/O authorities/O to/O control/O the/O Chinese/O cyberspace/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 02.03.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Chinese/O loans/O helping/O Latin/LOCATION America/LOCATION amid/O oil/O price/O slump/O 
New/O data/O show/O that/O Chinese/O banks/O loaned/O billions/O of/O dollars/O to/O Latin/O American/O countries/O in/O 2014/O ./O 
The/O publication/O 's/O co-author/O talks/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> about/O the/O risks/O associated/O with/O these/O loans/O for/O both/O China/LOCATION and/O Latin/LOCATION America/LOCATION ./O 
-LRB-/O 27.02.2015/O -RRB-/O 
How/O China/LOCATION is/O transforming/O the/O <LOCATION>South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/O</LOCATION> 
New/O images/O reveal/O the/O extent/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O land/O reclamation/O and/O construction/O in/O the/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ./O 
Experts/O warn/O the/O new/O developments/O will/O make/O it/O increasingly/O difficult/O to/O counter/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O regional/O claims/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 20.02.2015/O -RRB-/O 
The/O law/O would/O further/O enable/O China/LOCATION 's/O crackdown/O on/O non-authorized/O forms/O of/O religious/O practice/O ,/O especially/O in/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Uighur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>XUAR/O</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O ./O 
Over/O the/O past/O year/O ,/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION has/O noted/O that/O numerous/O counties/O in/O the/O <U_LOCATION>XUAR/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> posted/O notices/O on/O their/O websites/O stating/O that/O students/O should/O not/O be/O permitted/O to/O observe/O Ramadan/O ,/O and/O many/O teachers/O gave/O food/O and/O sweets/O to/O children/O to/O ensure/O that/O they/O did/O not/O observe/O the/O fast/O ./O 
Prohibitions/O on/O government/O employees/O and/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION cadres/O adhering/O to/O a/O religion/O were/O reinforced/O and/O several/O Uighur/O cadres/O were/O punished/O for/O downloading/O religious/O materials/O from/O the/O Internet/O or/O ``/O worshipping/O openly/O ./O ''/O 
Outward/O signs/O of/O adherence/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>Islam/O</ORGANIZATION> such/O as/O beards/O or/O veils/O were/O often/O banned/O ./O 
Specifically/O ,/O Islam/ORGANIZATION ,/O like/O other/O permitted/O religions/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O is/O tightly/O controlled/O by/O the/O relevant/O government/O body/O ,/O the/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O any/O religious/O practice/O that/O deviates/O from/O the/O official/O teaching/O could/O be/O seen/O as/O a/O ``/O distortion/O ,/O ''/O thus/O qualifying/O as/O ``/O extremism/O ''/O ./O 
Further/O ,/O parents/O who/O want/O their/O children/O to/O take/O part/O in/O religious/O education/O or/O ceremonies/O could/O potentially/O be/O accused/O of/O participating/O in/O ``/O extremist/O conduct/O ./O ''/O 
The/O law/O allows/O for/O detention/O and/O fines/O for/O people/O who/O display/O ``/O items/O advocating/O terrorism/O or/O extremism/O or/O otherwise/O advertising/O extremism/O ,/O ''/O and/O in/O the/O <U_LOCATION>XUAR/O</U_LOCATION> context/O ,/O we/O know/O that/O this/O is/O often/O interpreted/O as/O women/O with/O veils/O or/O burqas/O ,/O men/O with/O long/O beards/O ,/O or/O people/O wearing/O other/O T-shirts/O with/O the/O Islamic/O crescent/O moon/O ./O 
What/O revisions/O have/O been/O made/O to/O the/O law/O ?/O 
What/O 's/O worth/O noting/O is/O that/O the/O revised/O draft/O claims/O to/O be/O striking/O a/O balance/O between/O anti-terrorism/O and/O human/O rights/O protections/O ,/O and/O in/O some/O ways/O ,/O it/O 's/O positive/O that/O the/O government/O is/O at/O least/O acknowledging/O the/O human/O rights/O concerns/O that/O have/O been/O expressed/O about/O this/O law/O ./O 
But/O at/O this/O moment/O ,/O it/O does/O n't/O seem/O like/O any/O of/O the/O revised/O sections/O -/O which/O mainly/O add/O layers/O of/O additional/O approval/O in/O conducting/O anti-terror/O measures/O -/O will/O significantly/O improve/O the/O situation/O ,/O or/O give/O people/O suspected/O of/O terrorism/O a/O chance/O to/O appeal/O their/O case/O to/O an/O independent/O or/O impartial/O body/O ./O 
How/O could/O this/O affect/O the/O government/O 's/O ``/O strike/O hard/O ''/O campaign/O ?/O 
This/O could/O potentially/O give/O the/O government/O many/O new/O ``/O tools/O ''/O in/O the/O ``/O strike/O hard/O ''/O campaign/O -/O such/O as/O greater/O access/O to/O users/O '/O electric/O communications/O ,/O restrictions/O on/O freedom/O of/O movement/O both/O locally/O ,/O and/O in/O terms/O of/O exiting/O and/O entering/O the/O country/O ,/O and/O greater/O leeway/O in/O making/O people/O targets/O of/O extremism/O or/O terrorism/O -/O and/O thus/O targets/O of/O electronic/O and/O on-the-ground/O surveillance/O ./O 
Nee/PERSON :/O `/O The/O law/O would/O further/O enable/O China/LOCATION 's/O crackdown/O on/O non-authorized/O forms/O of/O religious/O practice/O ,/O especially/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> '/O 
The/O government/O has/O repeatedly/O emphasized/O that/O its/O ``/O strike/O hard/O ''/O campaign/O is/O being/O conducted/O ``/O according/O to/O the/O law/O ./O ''/O 
So/O ,/O this/O new/O law/O ,/O with/O the/O many/O new/O tools/O it/O gives/O to/O the/O authorities/O ,/O could/O potentially/O give/O the/O government/O greater/O perceived/O legitimacy/O in/O conducting/O its/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O ``/O according/O to/O the/O law/O ,/O ''/O even/O when/O it/O is/O engaging/O in/O activities/O that/O violate/O internationally/O recognized/O human/O rights/O laws/O and/O standards/O ./O 
What/O do/O you/O urge/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O do/O in/O this/O regard/O ?/O 
The/O government/O must/O ensure/O that/O it/O is/O protecting/O human/O rights/O ,/O even/O as/O it/O takes/O measures/O to/O ensure/O the/O safety/O of/O its/O citizens/O from/O violent/O attacks/O ./O 
We/O 've/O seen/O that/O in/O previous/O ``/O strike/O hard/O ''/O campaigns/O there/O have/O been/O tragic/O miscarriages/O of/O justice/O -/O as/O in/O the/O wrongful/O execution/O of/O the/O Inner/O Mongolian/O boy/O Hugjiltu/PERSON ./O 
Violations/O of/O human/O rights/O tend/O to/O increase/O resentment/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O we/O urge/O the/O government/O to/O hold/O off/O on/O promulgating/O this/O law/O ,/O and/O just/O start/O again/O ./O 
The/O government/O should/O ensure/O that/O any/O such/O law/O is/O compatible/O with/O the/O ICCPR/O ,/O the/O Johannesburg/LOCATION <OTHER>Principles/LOCATION</OTHER> ,/O the/O <LOCATION>Rabat/O</LOCATION> Plan/O of/O Action/O ,/O and/O many/O other/O international/O laws/O and/O standards/O ./O 
The/O government/O has/O ,/O apparently/O ,/O taken/O lots/O of/O time/O and/O consulted/O with/O many/O international/O experts/O ,/O and/O other/O governments/O in/O making/O the/O draft/O Domestic/O Violence/O Law/O ,/O -LRB-/O which/O is/O not/O yet/O out/O -RRB-/O ./O 
The/O government/O could/O do/O a/O similar/O thing/O ,/O by/O consulting/O with/O international/O bodies/O ,/O international/O human/O rights/O experts/O ,/O other/O governments/O ,/O and/O by/O of/O course/O reaching/O out/O in/O a/O meaningful/O way/O to/O the/O communities/O that/O will/O be/O most/O affected/O by/O this/O law/O ./O 
William/PERSON Nee/PERSON is/O China/LOCATION Researcher/O at/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION ./O
