The/O leaders/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION and/O other/O countries/O will/O discuss/O the/O threat/O the/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O group/O poses/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION at/O a/O Eurasian/O security/O summit/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> spoke/O to/O analyst/O Borhan/PERSON Osman/PERSON about/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O concerns/O ./O 
Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O Russian/O President/O Vladimir/PERSON Putin/PERSON and/O other/O leaders/O will/O discuss/O about/O the/O security/O situation/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O the/O increasing/O threat/O posed/O by/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O in/O Eurasia/LOCATION at/O this/O year/O 's/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Organization/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SCO/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O to/O be/O held/O Russian/O city/O of/O Ufa/LOCATION on/O July/O 9-10/O ./O 
``/O Due/O to/O the/O spillover/O effect/O of/O the/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION terrorist/O activities/O ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION now/O faces/O a/O grim/O security/O situation/O ,/O ''/O Chinese/O vice/O foreign/O minister/O Cheng/PERSON Guoping/PERSON told/O reporters/O ./O 
SCO/ORGANIZATION leaders/O ``/O will/O certainly/O have/O in-depth/O discussions/O on/O the/O Afghan/O issue/O ''/O ,/O he/O added/O ./O 
``/O And/O they/O will/O talk/O further/O about/O how/O to/O respond/O to/O the/O security/O situation/O there/O ,/O ''/O Cheng/PERSON was/O quoted/O as/O saying/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O worried/O about/O own/O separatist/O groups/O in/O the/O far/O western/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> working/O with/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
In/O a/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> interview/O ,/O Borhan/PERSON Osman/PERSON a/O Kabul-based/O analyst/O with/O the/O Afghanistan/ORGANIZATION Analysts/ORGANIZATION Network/ORGANIZATION ,/O explains/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O concerned/O because/O a/O palpable/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> foothold/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION could/O be/O far/O more/O dangerous/O to/O Chinese/O interests/O than/O ,/O say/O ,/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Osman/PERSON :/O `/O It/O is/O difficult/O to/O imagine/O a/O popular/O base/O of/O support/O for/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION '/O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> :/O Chinese/O vice/O foreign/O minister/O Cheng/PERSON Guoping/PERSON recently/O said/O Afghanistan/LOCATION is/O facing/O a/O grim/O security/O situation/O due/O to/O the/O spillover/O effect/O of/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O terror/O activities/O ./O 
What/O is/O your/O take/O on/O this/O ?/O 
Borhan/PERSON Osman/PERSON :/O The/O overall/O security/O situation/O in/O the/O South/LOCATION Asian/LOCATION country/O is/O certainly/O deteriorating/O ,/O especially/O in/O many/O parts/O of/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
But/O that/O probably/O has/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O the/O presence/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> in/O the/O region/O ./O 
Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O northern/O neighbors/O and/O China/LOCATION worry/O too/O much/O about/O a/O possible/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> threat/O that/O makes/O them/O translate/O the/O security/O deterioration/O into/O an/O imminent/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> threat/O ./O 
Apart/O from/O financial/O fears/O ,/O what/O are/O China/LOCATION 's/O interests/O in/O fighting/O a/O possible/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> threat/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ?/O 
China/LOCATION is/O possibly/O more/O worried/O about/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkistan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>ETIM/O</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O turning/O into/O a/O greater/O threat/O ,/O and/O about/O more/O Uighur/O Muslims/O radicalizing/O and/O joining/O jihad-based/O separatism/O ,/O than/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> threat/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION per/O se/O ./O 
China/LOCATION sees/O a/O volatile/O Afghanistan/LOCATION as/O an/O easy/O stage/O for/O the/O resurrection/O of/O <U_ORGANIZATION>ETIM/O</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O although/O there/O is/O no/O credible/O data/O about/O how/O effective/O and/O big/O this/O grouping/O is/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
What/O to/O expect/O from/O the/O SCO/ORGANIZATION ,/O BRICS/ORGANIZATION summits/O in/O Russia/LOCATION Often/O portrayed/O as/O a/O challenge/O to/O a/O Western-led/O order/O ,/O this/O year/O 's/O simultaneous/O SCO/ORGANIZATION and/O BRICS/ORGANIZATION summits/O are/O set/O to/O reveal/O Chinese/O and/O Russian/O plans/O for/O closer/O political/O and/O economic/O engagement/O in/O Eurasia/LOCATION ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> examines/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 06.07.2015/O -RRB-/O 
`/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> '/O poses/O new/O terror/O dimension/O ,/O warns/O German/O agency/O 
Europe/LOCATION is/O facing/O a/O ``/O new/O dimension/O ''/O of/O terror/O stemming/O from/O the/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O '/O footholds/O in/O Syria/LOCATION and/O Iraq/LOCATION ,/O according/O to/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O domestic/O intelligence/O agency/O ./O 
Its/O also/O pointed/O to/O far-right/O wing/O violence/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
-LRB-/O 30.06.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Opinion/O :/O The/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O muscle-flexing/O 
By/O launching/O attacks/O on/O the/O Afghan/O parliament/O and/O the/O northern/O city/O of/O Kunduz/LOCATION ,/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION want/O to/O demonstrate/O their/O strength/O ,/O not/O just/O to/O the/O government/O but/O also/O to/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ,/O says/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Florian/PERSON Weigand/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O 22.06.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O a/O palpable/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> foothold/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION alarms/O China/LOCATION since/O the/O militant/O grouping/O could/O be/O a/O far/O more/O dangerous/O patron/O or/O partner/O for/O the/O Chinese/O militants/O than/O ,/O say/O ,/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
This/O is/O why/O China/LOCATION might/O be/O more/O interested/O in/O contributing/O to/O efforts/O aimed/O at/O stopping/O the/O emergence/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O the/O first/O place/O ./O 
The/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION recently/O warned/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> against/O waging/O a/O parallel/O insurgency/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
Do/O you/O see/O a/O possibility/O of/O increasing/O clashes/O between/O the/O two/O groups/O ?/O 
So/O far/O ,/O there/O are/O no/O indications/O of/O massive/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> -/O <ORGANIZATION>Taliban/O</ORGANIZATION> clashes/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O largest/O clashes/O which/O have/O taken/O place/O in/O recent/O weeks/O in/O Nangarhar/LOCATION ,/O in/O eastern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O have/O failed/O to/O mount/O a/O serious/O threat/O to/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O control/O in/O these/O areas/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> has/O lost/O battles/O and/O terrain/O in/O most/O of/O the/O districts/O it/O initially/O contested/O ./O 
So/O ,/O the/O prospect/O for/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> to/O challenge/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O hold/O remains/O weak/O ./O 
Recently/O ,/O former/O prime/O minister/O and/O leader/O of/O the/O insurgent/O group/O Hezb-e/ORGANIZATION Islami/ORGANIZATION ,/O Gulbuddin/PERSON Hekmatyar/PERSON ,/O called/O upon/O his/O supporters/O to/O join/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Which/O role/O does/O he/O play/O in/O this/O ?/O 
Hekmatyar/PERSON has/O talked/O about/O specific/O cases/O in/O which/O he/O recommended/O his/O supporters/O to/O back/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> fighting/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
There/O have/O been/O reports/O of/O militants/O in/O eastern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION with/O <ORGANIZATION>Hezb-e/O Islami/O</ORGANIZATION> background/O claiming/O to/O be/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> fighters/O ./O 
But/O these/O fighters/O do/O not/O seem/O to/O have/O joined/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> on/O Hekmatyar/PERSON 's/O orders/O ./O 
Hekmatyar/PERSON 's/O clout/O over/O active/O insurgents/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION appears/O to/O have/O remarkably/O shrunk/O in/O recent/O years/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O his/O call/O on/O supporters/O to/O back/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> in/O its/O fight/O against/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION will/O remain/O more/O of/O an/O angry/O statement/O by/O a/O desperate/O warlord/O who/O has/O always/O been/O striving/O to/O remain/O relevant/O ./O 
#/O Do/O the/O Afghan/O people/O approve/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> group/O ?/O 
China/LOCATION sees/O a/O volatile/O Afghanistan/LOCATION as/O an/O easy/O stage/O for/O the/O resurrection/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkistan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O says/O Osman/PERSON 
It/O is/O difficult/O to/O imagine/O a/O popular/O base/O of/O support/O for/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
So/O far/O ,/O small/O groups/O have/O emerged/O here/O and/O there/O trying/O to/O carve/O a/O place/O for/O themselves/O in/O society/O ./O 
But/O their/O call/O for/O a/O caliphate/O does/O not/O resonate/O with/O local/O communities/O ./O 
There/O might/O be/O members/O of/O a/O limited/O number/O of/O young/O people/O either/O radicalized/O or/O at/O the/O risk/O of/O being/O radicalized/O into/O global/O jihadism/O ./O 
But/O ,/O they/O mostly/O remain/O disconnected/O from/O local/O societies/O ./O 
In/O Nangarhar/LOCATION ,/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> fighters/O have/O published/O propaganda/O pictures/O of/O their/O interaction/O with/O local/O residents/O ./O 
Rather/O than/O showing/O a/O supportive/O population/O ,/O the/O pictures/O show/O a/O terrified/O people/O ./O 
Borhan/PERSON Osman/PERSON is/O a/O Kabul-based/O researcher/O and/O analyst/O with/O the/O Afghanistan/ORGANIZATION Analysts/ORGANIZATION Network/ORGANIZATION ./O
