European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION interior/O ministers/O have/O agreed/O to/O exchange/O information/O on/O any/O detainees/O they/O accept/O from/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ./O 
They/O hope/O the/O agreement/O will/O help/O speed/O efforts/O to/O close/O the/O notorious/O US/LOCATION prison/O camp/O ./O 
The/O information/O exchange/O crafted/O by/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION ministers/O is/O a/O compromise/O that/O obliges/O EU/ORGANIZATION states/O to/O conduct/O ``/O consultation/O and/O thorough/O information/O sharing/O ''/O with/O the/O other/O members/O of/O the/O bloc/O before/O accepting/O any/O inmates/O ./O 
This/O would/O include/O restricting/O detainees/O '/O movements/O and/O keeping/O them/O under/O surveillance/O ./O 
``/O It/O 's/O very/O important/O ,/O ''/O EU/ORGANIZATION counterterrorism/O coordinator/O Gilles/PERSON de/PERSON Kerchove/PERSON told/O news/O agency/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O It/O is/O materialized/O by/O a/O system/O of/O information-sharing/O ,/O politically/O confirmed/O at/O the/O highest/O level/O ./O 
That/O 's/O important/O because/O it/O reinforces/O trust/O ./O ''/O 
Kerchove/PERSON went/O on/O to/O say/O that/O the/O agreement/O would/O set/O an/O example/O to/O other/O countries/O and/O hopefully/O pave/O the/O way/O for/O others/O to/O take/O in/O detainees/O ./O 
The/O EU/ORGANIZATION hopes/O that/O with/O this/O agreement/O in/O place/O ,/O some/O of/O the/O 245/O detainees/O at/O the/O prison/O could/O start/O to/O be/O moved/O out/O ,/O enabling/O the/O US/LOCATION government/O to/O keep/O its/O deadline/O for/O closing/O Guantanmo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION by/O January/O 2010/O ./O 
One/O specific/O group/O of/O prisoners/O at/O issue/O consists/O of/O 18/O Uighurs/O --/O members/O of/O a/O Chinese/O minority/O that/O harbor/O separatist/O ambitions/O and/O whom/O China/LOCATION considers/O terrorists/O ./O 
The/O Obama/PERSON administration/O has/O declared/O the/O Uighurs/O posed/O no/O threat/O and/O could/O be/O released/O ./O 
However/O the/O US/LOCATION says/O the/O group/O can/O not/O be/O returned/O to/O China/LOCATION for/O fear/O of/O persecution/O ./O 
Opposition/O pipes/O up/O 
Schaeuble/PERSON still/O questions/O why/O former/O inmates/O ca/O n't/O be/O settled/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION 
But/O several/O groups/O ,/O notably/O from/O the/O right-wing/O of/O European/O politics/O ,/O have/O continued/O to/O voice/O their/O opposition/O to/O accepting/O any/O former/O Guantanamo/LOCATION inmates/O ./O 
``/O The/O Uighurs/O who/O we/O are/O supposed/O to/O take/O in/O ,/O we/O should/O note/O for/O the/O record/O ,/O were/O all/O in/O terror/O camps/O ,/O ''/O said/O Lower/LOCATION Saxony/LOCATION state/O Interior/O Minister/O Uwe/PERSON Schuenemann/PERSON in/O an/O interview/O with/O German/O newspaper/O Die/O Welt/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Austria/LOCATION ,/O Germany/LOCATION and/O Italy/LOCATION also/O voiced/O objections/O to/O any/O plan/O to/O resettle/O detainees/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O noting/O that/O the/O countries/O that/O are/O part/O of/O the/O <LOCATION>Schengen/O</LOCATION> zone/O have/O no/O passport/O controls/O ,/O which/O would/O allow/O detainees/O to/O travel/O freely/O throughout/O the/O 25-nation/O area/O ./O 
``/O If/O they/O do/O not/O pose/O any/O risk/O ,/O we/O need/O to/O clarify/O why/O they/O can/O not/O remain/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O German/O Interior/O Minister/O Wolfgang/PERSON Schaeuble/PERSON ./O 
``/O We/O can/O not/O permit/O ourselves/O the/O liberty/O of/O leaving/O people/O suspected/O of/O terrorism/O at/O liberty/O ,/O ''/O Italian/O Interior/O Minister/O Roberto/PERSON Marconi/PERSON said/O recently/O ./O 
Significant/O agreement/O 
European/O anti-terrorism/O co-ordinator/O Gilles/PERSON de/PERSON Kerchove/PERSON says/O its/O all/O about/O trust/O The/O cost/O of/O taking/O in/O detainees/O and/O monitoring/O their/O movements/O is/O also/O an/O issue/O as/O is/O the/O question/O of/O how/O to/O deal/O with/O the/O detainees/O '/O families/O ./O 
EU/ORGANIZATION asylum/O policies/O provide/O for/O family/O reunification/O and/O should/O the/O detainees/O request/O their/O families/O ,/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION would/O be/O obliged/O to/O allow/O the/O relatives/O to/O relocate/O to/O the/O then/O former/O prisoners/O '/O new/O homes/O ./O 
Negotiations/O are/O ongoing/O about/O how/O much/O the/O US/LOCATION will/O contribute/O to/O the/O transfer/O and/O integration/O of/O the/O detainees/O ,/O according/O to/O officials/O ./O 
av/O //O <ORGANIZATION>Reuters/O</ORGANIZATION> //O <ORGANIZATION>AFP/O</ORGANIZATION> 
Editor/O :/O Nancy/PERSON Isenson/PERSON
