Turkey/LOCATION seeks/O to/O develop/O ties/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O 
On/O the/O first/O visit/O of/O a/O Turkish/O prime/O minister/O in/O 27/O years/O ,/O Recep/PERSON Tayyip/PERSON Erdogan/PERSON will/O also/O try/O to/O convince/O Chinese/O leaders/O to/O pressure/O Syria/LOCATION to/O put/O an/O end/O to/O violence/O ./O 
Turkey/LOCATION 's/O Prime/O Minister/O Recep/PERSON Tayyip/PERSON Erdogan/PERSON starts/O out/O on/O a/O landmark/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION on/O Sunday/O ./O 
His/O first/O stop/O is/O expected/O to/O be/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O in/O western/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O dominated/O by/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O crackdown/O on/O this/O predominantly/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O during/O the/O riots/O in/O 2009/O damaged/O bilateral/O relations/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
Three/O years/O after/O the/O crisis/O ,/O Erdogan/PERSON 's/O visit/O is/O seen/O as/O a/O sign/O of/O stronger/O dialogue/O and/O growing/O confidence/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O ./O 
``/O Turkey/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION have/O recently/O adopted/O a/O new/O policy/O ./O 
They/O are/O making/O efforts/O to/O prevent/O the/O issue/O of/O Uighurs/O becoming/O a/O source/O of/O tension/O in/O their/O bilateral/O relations/O ,/O ''/O Selcuk/PERSON Colakoglu/PERSON ,/O of/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Strategic/ORGANIZATION Research/ORGANIZATION Organization/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>USAK/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O trying/O to/O convince/O public/O opinion/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION of/O its/O policies/O ,/O by/O opening/O up/O the/O region/O more/O and/O more/O to/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O Ankara/LOCATION is/O using/O direct/O communication/O channels/O with/O Chinese/O authorities/O ,/O without/O disclosing/O its/O concern/O to/O the/O public/O ,/O Colakoglu/PERSON added/O ./O 
``/O If/O there/O is/O no/O major/O outbreak/O of/O unrest/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O like/O the/O one/O in/O 2009/O ,/O closer/O relations/O between/O Turkey/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION are/O likely/O to/O contribute/O to/O an/O improvement/O of/O the/O political/O and/O economic/O situation/O of/O the/O Uighur/O minority/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
<LOCATION>Turkey/O</LOCATION> has/O long-standing/O ties/O to/O the/O Uighur/O minority/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
In/O 2009/O ,/O Erdogan/PERSON compared/O the/O actions/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O a/O ``/O genocide/O ./O ''/O 
Relations/O have/O improved/O since/O Turkish/O Foreign/O Minister/O Ahmet/PERSON Davutoglu/PERSON visited/O China/LOCATION in/O 2010/O ./O 
Turkey/LOCATION is/O emphasizing/O its/O support/O and/O respect/O for/O China/LOCATION 's/O sovereignty/O and/O territorial/O integrity/O ,/O but/O also/O raising/O the/O difficult/O issue/O of/O human/O rights/O in/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ./O 
First/O visit/O in/O 27/O years/O Erdogan/PERSON 's/O visit/O will/O be/O the/O first/O official/O visit/O of/O a/O Turkish/O prime/O minister/O to/O China/LOCATION in/O 27/O years/O ./O 
Erdogan/PERSON visited/O China/LOCATION in/O 2003/O as/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O ruling/O Justice/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AKP/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ./O 
``/O This/O visit/O comes/O shortly/O after/O the/O visit/O of/O Vice/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON to/O Turkey/LOCATION in/O February/O ./O 
It/O reflects/O the/O political/O will/O of/O both/O countries/O to/O expand/O relations/O to/O the/O highest/O level/O ,/O ''/O Turkish/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Selcuk/PERSON Unal/PERSON told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
The/O two/O countries/O established/O strategic/O relations/O in/O 2010/O ./O 
Since/O then/O ,/O they/O have/O held/O close/O dialogue/O on/O bilateral/O and/O international/O issues/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Turkey/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION are/O yet/O to/O settle/O their/O differences/O on/O issues/O like/O the/O situation/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
Turkey/LOCATION has/O recently/O adopted/O a/O more/O assertive/O and/O pro-active/O policy/O on/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
Ankara/LOCATION has/O put/O all/O its/O support/O behind/O the/O Syrian/O opposition/O and/O called/O upon/O Syrian/O President/O Bashar/PERSON al-Assad/PERSON to/O stop/O the/O violence/O and/O to/O step/O down/O and/O make/O way/O for/O a/O political/O transition/O to/O democracy/O ./O 
Turkish/O officials/O openly/O criticized/O China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION for/O their/O veto/O of/O a/O UN/ORGANIZATION resolution/O aimed/O at/O stopping/O the/O violence/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
Erdogan/PERSON seeks/O support/O for/O his/O policy/O in/O Syria/LOCATION Turkish/O diplomats/O say/O the/O situation/O in/O Syria/LOCATION and/O regional/O and/O global/O issues/O will/O be/O among/O the/O topics/O in/O Erdogan/PERSON 's/O meetings/O with/O key/O Chinese/O officials/O ./O 
Erdogan/PERSON is/O set/O to/O meet/O Chinese/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ,/O Vice/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON and/O Chairman/O of/O the/O Standing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION <OTHER>of/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> <OTHER>the/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION Wu/PERSON Bangguo/PERSON ./O 
Colakoglu/PERSON says/O Turkey/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION have/O different/O views/O on/O recent/O developments/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION and/O Africa/LOCATION ,/O but/O these/O differences/O are/O not/O unsolvable/O ./O 
``/O Before/O the/O Arab/O uprisings/O ,/O Turkey/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION had/O followed/O similar/O lines/O ./O 
They/O supported/O peaceful/O and/O diplomatic/O efforts/O to/O solve/O the/O region/O 's/O problems/O ,/O ''/O Colakoglu/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O But/O after/O the/O Arab/O Spring/O ,/O a/O clear/O distinction/O has/O emerged/O ./O 
Turkey/LOCATION supported/O the/O demands/O of/O the/O people/O against/O their/O authoritarian/O regimes/O ./O 
China/LOCATION ,/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O has/O stood/O against/O foreign/O interventions/O based/O on/O principles/O ,/O also/O stressing/O that/O these/O interventions/O bring/O no/O solution/O ./O ''/O 
Trade/O and/O tourism/O 
Erdogan/PERSON is/O expected/O to/O be/O accompanied/O by/O a/O large/O delegation/O of/O ministers/O ,/O deputies/O and/O businessmen/O on/O his/O visit/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O two/O countries/O are/O to/O sign/O several/O agreements/O to/O further/O develop/O political/O and/O economic/O cooperation/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O Turkey/LOCATION 's/O third/O largest/O trading/O partner/O after/O Russia/LOCATION and/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
Trade/O between/O Turkey/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION totaled/O about/O 18/O billion/O euros/O -LRB-/O $/O 24/O billion/O -RRB-/O in/O 2011/O ./O 
``/O During/O the/O visit/O of/O Chinese/O Prime/O Minister/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON to/O Turkey/LOCATION in/O 2010/O we/O set/O two/O targets/O for/O our/O bilateral/O trade/O ,/O ''/O Unal/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O Our/O target/O now/O is/O to/O increase/O our/O trade/O to/O $/O 50/O billion/O in/O 2015/O and/O 100/O billion/O dollars/O in/O 2020/O ./O ''/O 
Despite/O these/O close/O economic/O ties/O ,/O Turkey/LOCATION 's/O growing/O trade/O deficit/O with/O China/LOCATION is/O a/O major/O problem/O ./O 
Ankara/LOCATION wants/O Chinese/O officials/O to/O ease/O import/O ,/O trade/O and/O investment/O conditions/O for/O Turkish/O businesses/O ./O 
Ankara/LOCATION is/O also/O seeking/O Chinese/O support/O for/O a/O dramatic/O increase/O in/O Chinese/O tourism/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O year/O 2011/O ,/O the/O number/O of/O Chinese/O tourists/O visiting/O Turkey/LOCATION passed/O 100,000/O for/O the/O first/O time/O ,/O an/O increase/O of/O 66/O percent/O compared/O to/O 2009/O ./O 
As/O 2013/O will/O be/O the/O Year/O of/O Turkish/O Culture/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O Turkish/O tourism/O operators/O hope/O to/O bring/O even/O more/O Chinese/O visitors/O to/O their/O country/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Ayhan/PERSON Simsek/PERSON ,/O Istanbul/LOCATION 
Editor/O :/O Sean/PERSON Sinico/PERSON //O Matthias/PERSON von/PERSON Hein/PERSON //O sgb/O
