China/LOCATION might/O be/O prepared/O to/O join/O the/O US/LOCATION campaign/O against/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O but/O Washington/LOCATION should/O n't/O get/O its/O hopes/O up/O too/O high/O ,/O writes/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON ./O 
Exactly/O 13/O years/O after/O 9/11/O ,/O the/O US/LOCATION is/O once/O again/O seeking/O recruits/O for/O a/O coalition/O of/O the/O willing/O ./O 
This/O time/O ,/O the/O enemy/O is/O not/O <ORGANIZATION>Al-Qaeda/O</ORGANIZATION> but/O the/O even/O more/O radical/O extremists/O of/O the/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION that/O has/O established/O itself/O in/O Syria/LOCATION and/O Iraq/LOCATION ./O 
Three/O years/O after/O America/LOCATION pulled/O its/O last/O troops/O out/O of/O Iraq/LOCATION ,/O it/O is/O being/O forced/O back/O into/O combat/O by/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O for/O the/O simple/O reason/O that/O it/O is/O most/O suited/O to/O the/O job/O ./O 
But/O the/O Americans/O are/O less/O keen/O than/O ever/O on/O going/O it/O alone/O ./O 
And/O the/O more/O countries/O it/O can/O enlist/O ,/O the/O clearer/O it/O becomes/O that/O it/O is/O still/O a/O world/O power/O ./O 
Ten/O Arab/O states/O have/O already/O declared/O their/O intention/O to/O stand/O by/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O 
France/LOCATION and/O Britain/LOCATION are/O not/O ruling/O out/O air/O strikes/O and/O at/O first/O glance/O ,/O it/O seems/O that/O even/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O only/O serious/O rival/O to/O US/LOCATION global/O power/O ,/O is/O prepared/O to/O join/O the/O international/O campaign/O against/O the/O jihadist/O fighters/O ./O 
On/O her/O trip/O to/O China/LOCATION this/O week/O ,/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON 's/O national/O security/O adviser/O Susan/PERSON Rice/PERSON asked/O Beijing/LOCATION where/O it/O stood/O and/O was/O told/O on/O Thursday/O by/O the/O Chinese/O foreign/O minister/O that/O it/O was/O prepared/O to/O offer/O assistance/O --/O on/O condition/O that/O international/O law/O be/O respected/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O sovereignty/O ,/O autonomy/O and/O territorial/O integrity/O of/O the/O participating/O countries/O ./O 
Thereby/O ensuring/O it/O does/O n't/O need/O to/O get/O its/O fingers/O burnt/O if/O it/O does/O n't/O want/O to/O ./O 
Chinese/O economic/O interests/O in/O Iraq/LOCATION 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O a/O vested/O interest/O in/O the/O matter/O ./O 
On/O the/O one/O hand/O ,/O it/O has/O economic/O interests/O to/O protect/O ./O 
After/O the/O US/LOCATION helped/O free/O Iraq/LOCATION from/O Saddam/PERSON Hussein/PERSON 's/O dictatorship/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O snapped/O up/O oil/O drilling/O rights/O from/O under/O the/O Americans/O `/O noses/O and/O now/O control/O around/O 50/O percent/O of/O oil/O production/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
Its/O three/O largest/O oil/O fields/O -/O Rumaila/LOCATION ,/O Halfaya/LOCATION and/O West/LOCATION Qurna/LOCATION --/O are/O either/O operated/O by/O the/O Chinese/O outright/O or/O are/O joint/O ventures/O with/O non-American/O companies/O ./O 
But/O now/O that/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> troops/O have/O hoisted/O their/O black/O flag/O in/O various/O Iraqi/O cities/O and/O introduced/O Sharia/O law/O ,/O even/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O getting/O nervous/O --/O although/O most/O of/O its/O oil/O fields/O are/O in/O the/O south/O of/O the/O country/O ,/O which/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> has/O not/O yet/O reached/O ./O 
But/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O presumably/O more/O worried/O about/O the/O threat/O of/O domestic/O terrorism/O than/O its/O oil/O fields/O ./O 
Barely/O a/O month/O goes/O by/O without/O yet/O another/O act/O of/O terrorism/O shaking/O the/O troubled/O western/O Chinese/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
These/O might/O be/O merely/O harbingers/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> terror/O ,/O but/O the/O evidence/O is/O mounting/O that/O the/O militant/O Islamist/O group/O has/O every/O intention/O of/O expanding/O into/O China/LOCATION ./O 
It/O features/O in/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> statements/O ,/O with/O the/O group/O `/O s/O leadership/O placing/O China/LOCATION at/O the/O top/O of/O a/O list/O of/O countries/O where/O Muslims/O are/O persecuted/O ./O 
Chinese/O terrorism/O experts/O have/O also/O voiced/O concern/O about/O the/O risk/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION and/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION posed/O by/O jihadists/O returning/O from/O Arab/O countries/O ./O 
Rising/O tensions/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION 
Many/O of/O them/O could/O easily/O go/O underground/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O where/O the/O people/O share/O more/O common/O cultural/O ground/O with/O Ankara/LOCATION than/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
So/O China/LOCATION 's/O leadership/O can/O no/O longer/O afford/O to/O simply/O sit/O tight/O and/O wait/O and/O see/O what/O happens/O ./O 
Tensions/O are/O rising/O ,/O as/O illustrated/O by/O recent/O comments/O made/O by/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON such/O as/O ``/O We/O should/O .../O make/O terrorists/O as/O unpopular/O as/O the/O rats/O crossing/O the/O street/O that/O we/O would/O like/O to/O squish/O ./O ''/O 
He/O urged/O the/O country/O 's/O troops/O to/O expend/O more/O sweat/O in/O training/O since/O that/O was/O better/O than/O letting/O blood/O in/O battle/O ./O 
Terrorism/O is/O no/O longer/O a/O problem/O restricted/O to/O far-flung/O provinces/O ,/O but/O has/O long/O reached/O the/O cities/O in/O the/O east/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
Support/O for/O the/O extremist/O elements/O among/O the/O Uighurs/O has/O already/O filtered/O across/O the/O border/O from/O neighboring/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
But/O despite/O these/O very/O real/O threats/O ,/O China/LOCATION will/O never/O stand/O shoulder/O to/O shoulder/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION in/O a/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O ./O 
While/O the/O US/LOCATION has/O also/O pledged/O to/O widen/O its/O air/O strikes/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ,/O Beijng/LOCATION can/O not/O begin/O to/O contemplate/O a/O similar/O military/O deployment/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O always/O opposed/O intervention/O in/O the/O Syrian/O civil/O war/O and/O China/LOCATION now/O fears/O that/O Obama/PERSON will/O use/O the/O campaign/O against/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> to/O bolster/O opposition/O forces/O in/O their/O fight/O against/O Bashar/PERSON al-Assad/PERSON ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION was/O quick/O to/O note/O that/O western/O interventions/O in/O Iraq/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Libya/LOCATION and/O Egypt/LOCATION were/O not/O wholly/O successful/O ./O 
A/O commentary/O released/O this/O week/O by/O state/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION was/O ample/O proof/O that/O China/LOCATION has/O little/O interest/O in/O getting/O involved/O in/O military/O deployments/O ,/O specifically/O asking/O why/O international/O terrorism/O is/O on/O the/O rise/O even/O though/O the/O US/LOCATION has/O been/O fighting/O it/O for/O over/O a/O decade/O ./O 
China/LOCATION needs/O to/O take/O a/O stand/O The/O breeding/O grounds/O for/O terrorists/O have/O grown/O ,/O the/O commentary/O read/O ,/O because/O the/O US/LOCATION first/O took/O on/O the/O regime/O of/O Saddam/PERSON Hussein/PERSON in/O Iraq/LOCATION ,/O then/O that/O of/O Gaddafi/PERSON in/O Libya/LOCATION and/O is/O now/O in/O the/O midst/O of/O destabilizing/O Assad/PERSON in/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
It/O is/O an/O argument/O that/O can/O not/O be/O simply/O dismissed/O ,/O the/O article/O goes/O on/O :/O 13/O years/O after/O 9/11/O ,/O the/O US/LOCATION still/O appears/O unable/O to/O face/O up/O to/O the/O real/O cause/O of/O terrorism/O ./O 
It/O 's/O all/O too/O easy/O to/O pass/O judgment/O from/O afar/O ./O 
But/O China/LOCATION wo/O n't/O be/O able/O to/O avoid/O taking/O a/O stand/O for/O much/O longer/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O fallback/O option/O of/O solving/O conflicts/O with/O negotiations/O is/O unlikely/O to/O prove/O helpful/O this/O time/O --/O unless/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O special/O ties/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION is/O not/O in/O the/O least/O interested/O in/O joining/O forces/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION to/O launch/O military/O strikes/O ./O 
These/O would/O inevitably/O follow/O American/O rules/O --/O which/O China/LOCATION is/O no/O longer/O willing/O to/O play/O by/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON has/O lived/O in/O Beijng/LOCATION for/O 20/O years/O ./O
