Over/O 30/O people/O have/O died/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O in/O a/O pointless/O attack/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O ``/O iron/O fist/O ''/O politics/O have/O failed/O to/O put/O an/O end/O to/O such/O violence/O for/O a/O reason/O ,/O says/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Matthias/PERSON von/PERSON Hein/PERSON ./O 
So/O far/O no/O one/O has/O claimed/O responsibility/O for/O the/O latest/O terrorist/O attack/O in/O the/O northwest/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
That/O was/O also/O the/O case/O with/O the/O most/O recent/O attack/O which/O the/O Chinese/O government/O blamed/O on/O Uighur/O separatists/O ./O 
However/O ,/O should/O there/O be/O an/O organization/O behind/O the/O bloodbath/O that/O was/O carried/O out/O on/O May/O 22/O at/O a/O market/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ,/O it/O should/O know/O :/O nothing/O can/O justify/O such/O needless/O acts/O of/O brutality/O ./O 
The/O attack/O was/O not/O an/O act/O of/O heroism/O ,/O but/O an/O act/O of/O mindless/O violence/O against/O innocent/O people/O ./O 
Our/O thoughts/O are/O with/O the/O victims/O -/O people/O who/O early/O this/O Thursday/O were/O simply/O going/O about/O their/O business/O ,/O buying/O fruit/O ,/O vegetables/O ,/O meat/O or/O making/O a/O living/O selling/O items/O at/O the/O market/O ./O 
The/O terrorist/O attack/O shows/O that/O an/O increasing/O amount/O of/O repression/O alone/O will/O not/O be/O able/O to/O prevent/O such/O violent/O acts/O from/O occurring/O ./O 
In/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O as/O in/O other/O Turkic-majority/O cities/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O there/O is/O such/O a/O heavy/O security/O presence/O that/O an/O increase/O seems/O hardly/O possible/O ./O 
Activities/O carried/O out/O by/O secret/O services/O could/O also/O hardly/O be/O more/O extensive/O than/O now/O ./O 
Under/O suspicion/O 
In/O 2009/O Uighurs/O started/O attacking/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> after/O the/O death/O of/O two/O migrant/O Uighur/O workers/O in/O southern/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Under/O a/O stifling/O blanket/O of/O ``/O ethnic/O harmony/O ''/O -/O as/O ordered/O by/O China/LOCATION 's/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION -/O disquiet/O slowly/O sweltered/O and/O eventually/O led/O to/O an/O outbreak/O of/O violence/O ./O 
Since/O then/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O generally/O been/O suspicious/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uighur/O population/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Explosions/O at/O market/O in/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> capital/O claim/O lives/O 
Blasts/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O have/O claimed/O many/O lives/O ,/O according/O to/O Chinese/O state/O media/O ./O 
The/O attack/O was/O carried/O out/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O capital/O city/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
-LRB-/O 22.05.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Chinese/O courts/O jail/O dozens/O of/O Uighurs/O over/O terror/O charges/O 
Courts/O in/O the/O Chinese/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> have/O jailed/O 39/O people/O after/O a/O special/O operation/O to/O counter/O Uighur/O separatist/O terrorism/O ,/O say/O judicial/O sources/O ./O 
The/O offences/O included/O the/O spread/O of/O ``/O terrorism/O audios/O and/O videos/O ./O ''/O 
-LRB-/O 21.05.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION :/O A/O dangerous/O memory/O 
As/O the/O 25th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O crackdown/O on/O student-led/O protests/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION crackdown/O approaches/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O stepped/O up/O efforts/O to/O silence/O dissent/O by/O detaining/O lawyers/O ,/O activists/O and/O journalists/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 19.05.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Deadly/O attack/O at/O Chinese/O railway/O station/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 
An/O explosion/O followed/O by/O an/O attack/O by/O armed/O assailants/O has/O occurred/O at/O a/O train/O station/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ./O 
The/O incident/O coincided/O with/O a/O visit/O to/O the/O western/O province/O by/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O 01.05.2014/O -RRB-/O 
The/O violence/O resulted/O in/O the/O death/O of/O 200/O people/O ./O 
For/O every/O step/O Uighurs/O try/O to/O take/O towards/O their/O interests/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION sees/O the/O danger/O of/O separatism/O or/O Islamism/O ./O 
Moderates/O --/O people/O who/O aim/O to/O promote/O the/O exchange/O between/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O and/O Uighurs/O --/O are/O silenced/O ./O 
What/O is/O happening/O now/O is/O what/O a/O leading/O mind/O of/O the/O Central/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Nationalities/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O Minzu/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O lamented/O about/O Tibet/LOCATION :/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O iron/O fist/O policies/O are/O upsetting/O people/O who/O are/O not/O per/O se/O against/O Chinese/O rule/O ./O 
Those/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION are/O wondering/O why/O the/O Uighurs/O are/O not/O happy/O about/O the/O economic/O development/O of/O their/O region/O and/O do/O n't/O become/O ardent/O supporters/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
What/O officials/O seem/O to/O forget/O ,/O however/O ,/O is/O that/O it/O is/O mostly/O migrant/O Han/O Chinese/O who/O are/O profiting/O from/O these/O developments/O ./O 
The/O local/O Uighurs/O ,/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O are/O clearly/O disadvantaged/O ./O 
They/O do/O n't/O really/O have/O any/O say/O in/O economic/O or/O political/O affairs/O or/O in/O the/O region/O 's/O administration/O ./O 
And/O party/O cadres/O do/O n't/O understand/O that/O preserving/O a/O cultural/O identity/O is/O about/O more/O than/O just/O folklore/O ;/O while/O Uighurs/O are/O encouraged/O to/O greet/O tourists/O or/O make/O TV/O appearances/O in/O bright/O traditional/O costumes/O ,/O singing/O and/O dancing/O to/O traditional/O songs/O ,/O vast/O parts/O of/O the/O old/O town/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> are/O being/O torn/O down/O without/O any/O say/O from/O the/O people/O living/O there/O ./O 
And/O the/O fact/O that/O no/O public/O servant/O is/O allowed/O to/O wear/O a/O beard/O that/O has/O any/O religious/O significance/O reinforces/O the/O feeling/O that/O they/O are/O seen/O as/O foreigners/O in/O their/O own/O lands/O ./O 
Act/O of/O desperation/O ?/O 
It/O has/O happened/O before/O in/O China/LOCATION that/O individual/O perpetrators/O have/O blown/O off/O steam/O by/O running/O amok/O ./O 
A/O day/O before/O the/O attack/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O a/O man/O in/O the/O central/O province/O of/O Henan/LOCATION killed/O seven/O people/O with/O a/O knife/O ./O 
A/O number/O of/O attacks/O have/O been/O carried/O out/O at/O schools/O and/O kindergartens/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION ,/O of/O course/O ,/O will/O investigate/O the/O attack/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
But/O it/O would/O do/O well/O to/O not/O blame/O an/O entire/O population/O for/O something/O that/O might/O possibly/O have/O been/O carried/O out/O by/O someone/O acting/O alone/O ./O 
And/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O their/O ``/O iron/O fist/O ''/O politics/O :/O would/O a/O good/O doctor/O keep/O increasing/O doses/O of/O a/O certain/O medicine/O that/O does/O n't/O work/O ,/O but/O has/O a/O long/O list/O of/O harmful/O side/O effects/O ?/O
