A/O day/O after/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O suffered/O a/O major/O attack/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> from/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> tells/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> the/O area/O is/O witnessing/O a/O violent/O response/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O 65-year-long/O ``/O brutal/O repression/O ''/O of/O Uighurs/O ./O 
On/O May/O 22/O ,/O attackers/O ploughed/O two/O vehicles/O into/O an/O open/O market/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O the/O capital/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> <U_LOCATION>Uighur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O hurling/O explosives/O which/O killed/O 31/O people/O and/O wounded/O 95/O ,/O according/O to/O Chinese/O authorities/O ./O 
The/O incident/O comes/O after/O a/O series/O of/O violent/O episodes/O at/O transport/O hubs/O throughout/O China/LOCATION which/O Beijing/LOCATION blames/O on/O Islamists/O and/O separatists/O from/O the/O restive/O region/O where/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O -LRB-/O also/O spelled/O Uyghur/O -RRB-/O make/O up/O around/O 45/O percent/O of/O the/O population/O ./O 
Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON has/O vowed/O to/O follow/O a/O ``/O strike-first/O approach/O against/O terrorists/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O ''/O according/O to/O state/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O stating/O that/O long-term/O stability/O was/O ``/O vital/O to/O the/O whole/O country/O 's/O reform/O ./O ''/O 
But/O in/O a/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> interview/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O spokesperson/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>WUC/O</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O warns/O that/O China/LOCATION 's/O ``/O heavy-handed/O ''/O approach/O will/O only/O further/O alienate/O members/O of/O the/O ethnic/O group/O who/O already/O feel/O their/O rights/O to/O have/O their/O own/O language/O ,/O religion/O and/O identity/O are/O being/O violated/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> :/O No/O responsibility/O has/O been/O claimed/O for/O these/O attacks/O ./O 
In/O your/O view/O ,/O who/O is/O responsible/O for/O this/O ?/O 
<U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> :/O We/O 're/O not/O sure/O who/O is/O responsible/O for/O the/O attack/O either/O ./O 
It/O is/O simply/O too/O early/O to/O tell/O ./O 
However/O ,/O it/O is/O the/O Chinese/O government/O which/O is/O blaming/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
Every/O time/O something/O like/O this/O happens/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION almost/O immediately/O jumps/O to/O conclusions/O ,/O blaming/O the/O Uighur/O people/O and/O using/O it/O as/O an/O opportunity/O to/O justify/O its/O repression/O ./O 
``/O Both/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O Tibet/LOCATION are/O occupied/O and/O colonized/O not/O only/O by/O Chinese/O military/O forces/O ,/O but/O also/O by/O millions/O of/O settlers/O ,/O ''/O says/O <U_PERSON>Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O seen/O here/O -LRB-/O R/O -RRB-/O next/O to/O exiled/O Uighur/O leader/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> 
What/O is/O your/O opinion/O on/O the/O Chinese/O government/O 's/O view/O that/O these/O attacks/O are/O linked/O to/O separatist/O movements/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ?/O 
We/O are/O not/O sure/O this/O is/O about/O so-called/O separatism/O or/O terrorism/O ./O 
This/O is/O rather/O a/O response/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O 65-year-long/O brutal/O repression/O of/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policies/O have/O always/O been/O about/O ``/O attacking/O and/O striking/O hard/O ''/O at/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O instead/O of/O respecting/O their/O rights/O enshrined/O into/O China/LOCATION 's/O Constitution/O and/O regional/O ethnic/O autonomy/O laws/O ./O 
While/O the/O territory/O 's/O name/O ,/O ``/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O <U_LOCATION>Uyghur/O Autonomous/O Region/O</U_LOCATION> ,/O ''/O would/O indicate/O that/O Uighurs/O should/O have/O rights/O under/O an/O autonomy/O arrangement/O ,/O the/O reality/O is/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O never/O respected/O those/O rights/O and/O ,/O in/O fact/O ,/O has/O taken/O them/O away/O ./O 
This/O applies/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O to/O the/O Uighurs/O '/O rights/O to/O have/O their/O own/O Uighur/O language/O ,/O culture/O ,/O identity/O as/O well/O as/O religious/O beliefs/O and/O practices/O ./O 
When/O Uighurs/O complain/O about/O infringement/O ,/O they/O are/O then/O demonized/O by/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O ,/O harassed/O ,/O sent/O to/O prison/O and/O even/O killed/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O we/O are/O witnessing/O this/O violent/O opposition/O to/O the/O Chinese/O government/O 's/O heavy-handed/O approach/O to/O Uighur/O issues/O ./O 
Can/O you/O sympathize/O with/O the/O Chinese/O government/O 's/O position/O that/O it/O is/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O duty/O and/O responsibility/O to/O implement/O measures/O to/O keep/O citizens/O safe/O from/O such/O attacks/O ?/O 
That/O is/O what/O the/O Chinese/O government/O claims/O ./O 
According/O to/O its/O propaganda/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION respects/O the/O rights/O of/O all/O minority/O groups/O ./O 
But/O it/O is/O important/O to/O point/O out/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O not/O a/O democracy/O ./O 
It/O is/O ruled/O by/O an/O authoritarian/O one-party/O communist/O system/O and/O minorities/O such/O as/O Uighurs/O ,/O Mongols/O ,/O Tibetans/O and/O even/O the/O ethnic/O majority/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O have/O suffered/O tremendously/O under/O it/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Opinion/O :/O China/LOCATION 's/O iron/O fist/O comes/O down/O where/O it/O should/O n't/O 
Over/O 30/O people/O have/O died/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O in/O a/O pointless/O attack/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O ``/O iron/O fist/O ''/O politics/O have/O failed/O to/O put/O an/O end/O to/O such/O violence/O for/O a/O reason/O ,/O says/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Matthias/PERSON von/PERSON Hein/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O 22.05.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Uighur/O leader/O :/O `/O Highly/O suspicious/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O terror/O claim/O '/O 
After/O a/O fatal/O car/O crash/O at/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O Uighurs/O fear/O more/O restrictions/O by/O authorities/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Exiled/O leader/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> says/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O using/O the/O incident/O as/O an/O excuse/O to/O further/O oppress/O the/O ethnic/O minority/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 08.11.2013/O -RRB-/O 
Ethnic/O tensions/O escalating/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 
The/O latest/O incidents/O of/O deadly/O violence/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> indicate/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policies/O towards/O ethnic/O minorities/O have/O reached/O a/O dead/O end/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 05.07.2013/O -RRB-/O 
China/LOCATION flexes/O muscles/O at/O home/O and/O abroad/O China/LOCATION 's/O new/O leadership/O has/O to/O walk/O a/O fine/O line/O between/O keeping/O a/O balance/O at/O home/O and/O throwing/O its/O weight/O around/O abroad/O ./O 
The/O rest/O of/O the/O world/O will/O be/O watching/O closely/O ,/O writes/O Wenfang/PERSON Tang/PERSON for/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O <ORGANIZATION>Transatlantic/O Voices/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
-LRB-/O 15.11.2012/O -RRB-/O 
However/O ,/O there/O is/O an/O important/O aspect/O to/O this/O ./O 
Following/O China/LOCATION 's/O opening/O up/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION helped/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O improve/O their/O lives/O and/O make/O money/O ./O 
But/O instead/O of/O supporting/O the/O country/O 's/O minorities/O in/O a/O similar/O way/O ,/O the/O government/O tried/O to/O forcibly/O assimilate/O them/O and/O destroy/O all/O those/O who/O stood/O against/O its/O brutal/O rule/O ./O 
The/O reality/O is/O that/O Uighurs/O and/O Tibetans/O and/O other/O groups/O face/O brutal/O oppression/O from/O Chinese/O communists/O ./O 
Furthermore/O ,/O both/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O Tibet/LOCATION are/O occupied/O and/O colonized/O not/O only/O by/O Chinese/O military/O forces/O ,/O but/O also/O by/O millions/O of/O Chinese/O settlers/O who/O have/O come/O to/O our/O land/O to/O lead/O good/O lives/O with/O good/O jobs/O and/O a/O high/O standard/O of/O living/O guaranteed/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O Uighurs/O and/O indigenous/O populations/O live/O in/O poverty/O and/O are/O not/O allowed/O to/O speak/O their/O own/O language/O or/O practice/O their/O culture/O and/O religion/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O root/O cause/O of/O the/O problem/O ./O 
Do/O you/O believe/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O an/O understanding/O of/O the/O needs/O of/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ?/O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O a/O very/O good/O understanding/O of/O the/O needs/O and/O political/O demands/O of/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ./O 
But/O the/O problem/O is/O that/O the/O Chinese/O government/O does/O n't/O respect/O them/O ./O 
While/O the/O authorities/O understand/O what/O Uighurs/O want/O ,/O it/O is/O in/O the/O nature/O of/O this/O authoritarian/O colonial/O power/O to/O never/O want/O to/O grant/O legitimate/O rights/O to/O those/O occupied/O ./O 
It/O always/O finds/O a/O way/O to/O justify/O its/O occupation/O and/O that/O is/O what/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O doing/O ./O 
Over/O the/O years/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O rejected/O Uighur/O complaints/O about/O political/O ,/O social/O and/O economic/O repression/O ,/O saying/O it/O has/O poured/O money/O into/O the/O region/O to/O develop/O it/O ./O 
What/O is/O your/O view/O on/O this/O ?/O 
It/O is/O true/O that/O China/LOCATION has/O developed/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION and/O other/O historically/O non-Chinese/O territories/O ./O 
The/O government/O has/O invested/O a/O lot/O of/O money/O in/O these/O regions/O to/O build/O high-rise/O buildings/O ,/O highways/O ,/O airports/O and/O train/O stations/O ./O 
But/O this/O infrastructure/O is/O not/O meant/O for/O the/O benefit/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O Tibetans/O or/O other/O groups/O ./O 
The/O railways/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O have/O been/O constructed/O to/O transfer/O millions/O of/O Chinese/O people/O to/O occupy/O and/O colonize/O the/O land/O ./O 
As/O soon/O as/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O arrive/O ,/O they/O are/O given/O special/O treatment/O in/O terms/O of/O jobs/O ,/O housing/O ,/O health/O care/O and/O rights/O otherwise/O denied/O to/O Uighurs/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION 's/O attempts/O to/O crack/O down/O on/O our/O religious/O practices/O have/O been/O backfiring/O ,/O ''/O says/O <U_PERSON>Seytoff/O</U_PERSON> The/O development/O of/O infrastructure/O does/O n't/O justify/O this/O brutal/O treatment/O ./O 
There/O are/O similar/O examples/O in/O history/O :/O When/O the/O British/O occupied/O India/LOCATION ,/O they/O also/O built/O railways/O ,/O roads/O ,/O factories/O ,/O and/O schools/O ,/O but/O does/O that/O give/O them/O the/O right/O to/O occupy/O India/LOCATION ?/O 
No/O ./O 
Do/O you/O see/O any/O changes/O taking/O place/O in/O the/O religious/O attitude/O of/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ?/O 
The/O Uighur/O people/O have/O traditionally/O practiced/O a/O modern/O form/O of/O Sunni/O Islam/O ./O 
However/O ,/O after/O 65/O years/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O atheist/O and/O communist/O education/O system/O alongside/O its/O attempt/O to/O secularize/O and/O crack/O down/O on/O our/O religious/O practices/O have/O been/O backfiring/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O 's/O heavy-handed/O repression/O of/O Uighurs/O is/O backfiring/O and/O forcing/O an/O increasing/O number/O of/O them/O into/O clinging/O ever-more/O to/O their/O religious/O beliefs/O and/O practices/O ./O 
The/O last/O thing/O they/O can/O hold/O on/O to/O is/O their/O religion/O because/O every/O other/O aspect/O of/O their/O lives/O -/O their/O language/O and/O identity/O -/O is/O being/O attacked/O and/O criminalized/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> is/O spokesman/O for/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> in/O Washington/LOCATION DC/LOCATION ./O
