China/LOCATION has/O executed/O eight/O people/O for/O ``/O terrorist/O attacks/O ,/O ''/O media/O reports/O say/O ./O 
Among/O those/O killed/O were/O three/O men/O accused/O of/O having/O masterminded/O a/O suicide/O car/O crash/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Tianamen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION in/O 2013/O ./O 
The/O eight/O people/O executed/O were/O involved/O in/O ``/O terrorist/O ''/O attacks/O in/O the/O far/O western/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O state-run/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O said/O early/O on/O Sunday/O ./O 
It/O said/O three/O of/O the/O people/O had/O been/O ``/O deprived/O of/O political/O rights/O to/O life/O ''/O for/O ``/O masterminding/O ''/O an/O assault/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Tianamen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION in/O October/O 2013/O ,/O in/O which/O two/O tourists/O died/O along/O with/O three/O attackers/O ,/O after/O a/O car/O rammed/O into/O bystanders/O before/O bursting/O into/O flames/O ./O 
Some/O forty/O people/O were/O injured/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O the/O traditional/O home/O of/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O ,/O who/O speak/O a/O Turkic/O language/O ./O 
The/O other/O executions/O recently/O carried/O out/O were/O for/O crimes/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ranging/O from/O setting/O up/O a/O terrorist/O outfit/O and/O illegally/O making/O explosives/O to/O attacking/O police/O officers/O and/O killing/O government/O officials/O ,/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O 
Harsh/O crackdown/O 
The/O executions/O are/O part/O of/O a/O crackdown/O on/O violent/O crime/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> after/O a/O string/O of/O deadly/O attacks/O there/O ./O 
Thirteen/O people/O were/O executed/O in/O June/O ./O 
A/O suicide/O bombing/O in/O May/O killed/O 39/O people/O at/O a/O market/O in/O the/O regional/O capital/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O and/O 29/O were/O stabbed/O to/O death/O at/O a/O train/O station/O in/O the/O soutwestern/O city/O of/O Kunming/LOCATION ./O 
Exiled/O Uighur/O groups/O and/O human/O rights/O activists/O say/O the/O violence/O in/O the/O region/O results/O from/O the/O government/O 's/O own/O policies/O of/O cultural/O oppression/O and/O intrusive/O security/O measures/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O immigration/O to/O the/O region/O by/O China/LOCATION 's/O Han/O ethnic/O majority/O ,/O which/O they/O say/O has/O led/O to/O discrimination/O and/O economic/O equality/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION ,/O however/O ,/O insists/O that/O it/O has/O improved/O living/O standards/O and/O developed/O the/O economy/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION does/O not/O say/O how/O many/O people/O it/O executes/O each/O year/O ,/O but/O an/O independent/O estimate/O put/O the/O figure/O for/O 2012/O at/O 3,000/O ,/O which/O is/O higher/O than/O all/O other/O countries/O combined/O ./O 
tj/ksb/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O <ORGANIZATION>AFP/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O
