Members/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uighur/O minority/O have/O long/O complained/O they/O suffer/O cultural/O marginalization/O ./O 
Many/O now/O also/O say/O they/O are/O the/O victims/O of/O worsening/O repression/O ,/O with/O accusations/O of/O serious/O human/O rights/O abuses/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O a/O multiethnic/O state/O ./O 
In/O addition/O to/O the/O overwhelming/O majority/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O are/O another/O 55/O national/O minorities/O ,/O mostly/O living/O on/O the/O periphery/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
But/O some/O minorities/O also/O feel/O culturally/O and/O politically/O marginalized/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O would/O like/O to/O paint/O a/O picture/O of/O harmonious/O coexistence/O among/O the/O country/O 's/O various/O ethnicities/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O extent/O to/O which/O this/O is/O in/O doubt/O for/O some/O 10/O million/O people/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O <U_LOCATION>Xianjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O has/O been/O thrown/O into/O sharp/O focus/O once/O again/O ./O 
In/O the/O city/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Aksu/PERSON</U_LOCATION> earlier/O this/O month/O ,/O a/O 17-year-old/O motorcyclist/O was/O shot/O by/O police/O after/O riding/O past/O a/O red/O traffic/O light/O ./O 
The/O subsequent/O protests/O were/O brutally/O suppressed/O ,/O according/O to/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Free/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Chinese/O security/O forces/O are/O accused/O of/O killing/O Uighurs/O in/O extra-judicial/O killings/O 
At/O the/O direction/O of/O the/O state/O information/O office/O ,/O any/O kind/O of/O report/O about/O the/O death/O of/O the/O teenager/O was/O removed/O from/O Chinese/O websites/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O China/ORGANIZATION Digital/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION online/O news/O service/O ./O 
Ubiquitous/O :/O Pictures/O of/O the/O disappeared/O 
Many/O women/O are/O worried/O about/O their/O husbands/O who/O were/O taken/O away/O by/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O after/O unrest/O in/O July/O 2009/O ,/O in/O which/O more/O than/O 150/O people/O died/O ./O 
The/O tragic/O incident/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Aksu/PERSON</U_LOCATION> formed/O part/O of/O the/O background/O for/O a/O conference/O of/O exiled/O Uighurs/O ./O 
The/O event/O was/O held/O under/O the/O title/O ``/O Silenced/O Crimes/O Against/O Humanity/O :/O Enforced/O Disappearances/O ,/O Arbitrary/O Arrests/O ,/O and/O Extra-judicial/O Killings/O of/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/LOCATION</OTHER> in/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Uighur/O delegates/O from/O 25/O countries/O in/O met/O over/O three/O days/O in/O the/O conference/O room/O of/O Munich/LOCATION 's/O <ORGANIZATION>Hotel/O Regent/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
On/O the/O wall/O hang/O the/O pictures/O of/O many/O of/O those/O who/O have/O died/O or/O disappeared/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O spokesperson/O for/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/O Uyghur/O Conference/O</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>WUC/O</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> about/O the/O mass/O disappearances/O of/O Uighurs/O ,/O on/O which/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O so/O far/O refused/O to/O prove/O any/O information/O ./O 
Although/O only/O a/O moderate/O in/O his/O criticism/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> was/O still/O indicted/O for/O alleged/O separatism/O 
<U_PERSON>Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> complains/O that/O ,/O since/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON took/O office/O last/O year/O ,/O there/O have/O been/O around/O a/O dozen/O extra-judicial/O killings/O of/O Uighurs/O ./O 
``/O The/O security/O forces/O often/O shoot/O dead/O Uighurs/O without/O any/O kind/O of/O trial/O or/O hearing/O ./O 
In/O the/O aftermath/O they/O simply/O label/O the/O victims/O separatists/O ,/O terrorist/O or/O extremists/O ./O ''/O 
It/O is/O <U_PERSON>Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O wish/O that/O representatives/O of/O Western/O governments/O such/O as/O that/O of/O Germany/LOCATION or/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ,/O open/O up/O a/O dialogue/O with/O their/O Chinese/O counterparts/O ,/O possibly/O even/O during/O state/O visits/O ./O 
Ulrich/PERSON Delius/PERSON ,/O Asia/LOCATION consultant/O for/O the/O Society/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Threatened/ORGANIZATION Peoples/ORGANIZATION said/O the/O situation/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O had/O become/O progressively/O worse/O ./O 
``/O On/O a/O daily/O basis/O ,/O where/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION is/O concerned/O ,/O we/O have/O to/O contend/O with/O a/O repressive/O regime/O -/O one/O which/O uses/O all/O its/O might/O against/O not/O only/O Uighurs/O but/O also/O against/O Tibetans/O or/O Han/O Chinese/O who/O are/O asserting/O their/O human/O rights/O ,/O ''/O said/O Delius/PERSON ./O 
``/O We/O are/O dealing/O with/O an/O incredibly/O powerful/O opponent/O that/O has/O immense/O status/O -/O economically/O ,/O politically/O and/O militarily/O ./O 
That/O is/O what/O makes/O the/O situation/O so/O difficult/O ./O ''/O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O believes/O the/O solution/O is/O to/O be/O even/O more/O repressive/O ,/O according/O to/O Uighur/O spokesman/O <U_PERSON>Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> ./O 
The/O fact/O that/O even/O moderate/O critics/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O like/O the/O Uighur/O Professor/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> have/O found/O themselves/O indicted/O for/O alleged/O separatism/O appear/O to/O support/O this/O ./O 
The/O attack/O on/O a/O train/O station/O in/O southwestern/O China/LOCATION was/O unanimously/O condemned/O by/O Uighur/O delegates/O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O the/O delegates/O who/O gathered/O in/O Munich/LOCATION placed/O great/O emphasis/O on/O the/O rejection/O of/O violence/O ./O 
A/O terrorist/O stabbing/O attack/O at/O a/O train/O station/O in/O Kunming/LOCATION ,/O in/O which/O more/O than/O 30/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O March/O ,/O was/O unanimously/O condemned/O ./O 
As/O well/O as/O being/O a/O chance/O to/O exchange/O information/O and/O ideas/O ,/O the/O Munich/LOCATION meeting/O was/O also/O an/O opportunity/O to/O prepare/O for/O the/O fifth/O anniversary/O of/O the/O outbreak/O of/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> riots/O ./O 
At/O the/O gathering/O in/O Munich/LOCATION ,/O however/O ,/O witnesses/O reported/O that/O significantly/O more/O were/O killed/O ./O 
Munich/LOCATION -/O capital/O of/O Uighur/O exiles/O 
The/O Bavarian/O capital/O was/O chosen/O to/O host/O the/O event/O because/O it/O is/O houses/O the/O offices/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>WUC/O</U_ORGANIZATION> ./O 
There/O is/O a/O simple/O reason/O that/O the/O city/O became/O something/O of/O a/O capital/O for/O exiled/O Uighurs/O ,/O according/O to/O <U_ORGANIZATION>WUC/O</U_ORGANIZATION> General/O Secretary/O <U_PERSON>Dolkun/PERSON Isa/PERSON</U_PERSON> :/O During/O the/O Cold/O War/O ,/O the/O city/O was/O the/O base/O of/O the/O American/O foreign/O broadcaster/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Liberty/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O ,/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O had/O a/O dedicated/O Uighur/O program/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O the/O city/O attracted/O both/O Uighur/O journalists/O and/O activists/O ./O 
<OTHER>Although/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Radio/ORGANIZATION Liberty/ORGANIZATION later/O moved/O to/O Prague/LOCATION ,/O the/O Uighurs/O stayed/O in/O Munich/LOCATION ./O 
In/O May/O ,/O the/O city/O plans/O to/O host/O to/O another/O conference/O that/O will/O focus/O on/O the/O religious/O oppression/O of/O the/O majority/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O ./O
