China/LOCATION has/O topped/O the/O list/O as/O the/O world/O 's/O worst/O jailer/O of/O journalists/O ./O 
In/O numerous/O other/O countries/O -/O Egypt/LOCATION ,/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O Vietnam/LOCATION ,/O Ethiopia/LOCATION ,/O and/O Eritrea/LOCATION -/O a/O climate/O of/O fear/O and/O censorship/O persist/O ./O 
China/LOCATION won/O the/O dubious/O distinction/O of/O throwing/O the/O most/O journalists/O in/O prison/O for/O the/O second/O year/O in/O a/O row/O ,/O according/O to/O an/O annual/O report/O by/O the/O Committee/ORGANIZATION to/ORGANIZATION Protect/ORGANIZATION Journalists/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CPJ/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O 
By/O CPJ/ORGANIZATION figures/O ,/O China/LOCATION was/O holding/O about/O a/O quarter/O of/O the/O 199/O journalists/O languishing/O in/O cells/O around/O the/O world/O in/O 2015/O because/O of/O their/O reporting/O ./O 
The/O New/O York-based/O journalist/O rights/O group/O said/O China/LOCATION had/O 49/O journalists/O in/O jail/O -/O a/O record/O for/O the/O country/O -/O as/O journalists/O are/O increasingly/O rounded/O up/O for/O reporting/O on/O financial/O issues/O amid/O market/O turmoil/O and/O a/O crackdown/O on/O corruption/O ./O 
``/O As/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON continues/O his/O crackdown/O on/O corruption/O and/O as/O the/O country/O 's/O economic/O growth/O slows/O and/O its/O markets/O become/O more/O volatile/O ,/O reporting/O on/O financial/O issues/O has/O taken/O on/O new/O sensitivity/O ,/O ''/O the/O CPJ/ORGANIZATION said/O ,/O citing/O the/O case/O of/O Wang/PERSON Xiaolu/PERSON ,/O a/O business/O reporter/O who/O wrote/O on/O possible/O malfeasance/O of/O a/O regulator/O ./O 
Xiaolu/PERSON was/O arrested/O for/O ``/O colluding/O with/O others/O and/O fabricating/O and/O spreading/O false/O information/O about/O securities/O and/O futures/O trading/O ,/O ''/O and/O later/O confessed/O on/O state/O television/O ,/O a/O tactic/O authorities/O have/O increasingly/O employed/O ,/O the/O CPJ/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O 
Reporting/O on/O human/O rights/O and/O the/O country/O 's/O Uighur/O minority/O remained/O sensitive/O and/O in/O one/O case/O three/O family/O members/O of/O <U_PERSON>Shohret/ORGANIZATION Hoshur/ORGANIZATION</U_PERSON> -/O a/O <OTHER>Washington/LOCATION</OTHER> DC-based/O Uighur/O journalist/O for/O US/LOCATION government/O funded/O <ORGANIZATION>Radio/O Free/O Asia/O</ORGANIZATION> -/O were/O arrested/O in/O retaliation/O for/O his/O work/O ,/O the/O CPJ/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O 
Egypt/LOCATION ,/O Turkey/LOCATION go/O from/O bad/O to/O worse/O 
Coming/O in/O second/O place/O as/O the/O worst/O jailer/O of/O journalists/O ,/O Egypt/LOCATION has/O imprisoned/O 23/O journalists/O ,/O nearly/O double/O from/O a/O year/O ago/O ./O 
``/O Perhaps/O nowhere/O has/O the/O climate/O for/O the/O press/O deteriorated/O more/O rapidly/O than/O in/O Egypt/LOCATION ,/O ''/O the/O CPJ/ORGANIZATION said/O ,/O noting/O how/O President/O Abdel/PERSON Fattah/PERSON el-Sisi/PERSON used/O national/O security/O justifications/O to/O control/O and/O to/O clamp/O down/O on/O media/O ./O 
Turkey/LOCATION ,/O which/O for/O two/O consecutive/O years/O in/O 2012/O and/O 2013/O had/O the/O most/O journalists/O in/O prison/O before/O releasing/O dozens/O in/O 2014/O ,/O doubled/O the/O number/O of/O journalists/O in/O prison/O this/O year/O to/O 14/O ./O 
Turkey/LOCATION has/O been/O repeatedly/O cited/O by/O rights/O organization/O for/O the/O deterioration/O of/O media/O freedom/O and/O independence/O as/O President/O Recep/PERSON Tayyip/PERSON Erdogan/PERSON and/O his/O Justice/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION extend/O their/O wrath/O over/O critical/O voices/O through/O the/O judiciary/O ./O 
With/O two/O elections/O in/O 2015/O ,/O instability/O stemming/O from/O involvement/O in/O the/O Syrian/O civil/O war/O and/O the/O resumption/O of/O fighting/O with/O the/O Kurdistan/ORGANIZATION Workers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O PKK/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O the/O environment/O for/O journalists/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION has/O become/O more/O precarious/O ./O 
Most/O recently/O ,/O two/O prominent/O journalists/O with/O the/O opposition/O media/O <ORGANIZATION>Cumhuriyet/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O <PERSON>Can/O</PERSON> Dundar/PERSON and/O Erdem/PERSON Gul/PERSON ,/O were/O arrested/O on/O espionage/O charges/O for/O publishing/O stories/O on/O alleged/O weapons/O shipments/O by/O Turkey/LOCATION 's/O intelligence/O agency/O to/O Syrian/O rebels/O under/O the/O guise/O of/O humanitarian/O aid/O ./O 
Iran/LOCATION 's/O revolving/O door/O policy/O 
The/O number/O of/O journalists/O in/O prison/O in/O Iran/LOCATION dropped/O from/O 30/O last/O year/O to/O 19/O this/O year/O ,/O but/O a/O ``/O revolving/O door/O policy/O ''/O skewed/O the/O picture/O as/O the/O state/O released/O some/O prisoners/O temporarily/O while/O arresting/O others/O ,/O CPJ/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O 
``/O Anti-state/O charges/O remain/O the/O favored/O tool/O for/O jailing/O journalists/O in/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O ''/O the/O CPJ/ORGANIZATION said/O ,/O pointing/O to/O among/O others/O <ORGANIZATION>Washington/O Post/O</ORGANIZATION> journalists/O Jason/PERSON Rezaian/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O accused/O of/O espionage/O and/O other/O charges/O ./O 
He/O has/O reportedly/O been/O convicted/O and/O sentenced/O ,/O but/O there/O are/O few/O details/O on/O the/O charges/O ./O 
Vietnam/LOCATION ,/O Ethiopia/LOCATION ,/O Eritrea/LOCATION 
Although/O the/O number/O of/O journalists/O in/O jail/O decreased/O in/O Vietnam/LOCATION ,/O censorship/O there/O remains/O a/O major/O issue/O ,/O as/O does/O forced/O exile/O ./O 
In/O Ethiopia/LOCATION ,/O censorship/O is/O widespread/O and/O several/O journalists/O have/O been/O arrested/O and/O face/O travel/O restrictions/O ./O 
Repressive/O Eritrea/LOCATION ,/O meanwhile/O ,/O has/O 17/O journalists/O in/O prison/O ,/O making/O it/O the/O worst/O in/O sub-Saharan/O Africa/LOCATION ./O 
In/O a/O violation/O of/O not/O only/O media/O rights/O but/O due/O process/O ,/O all/O of/O the/O Eritrean/O journalists/O in/O prison/O have/O never/O been/O charged/O with/O a/O crime/O or/O faced/O a/O court/O ./O
