Officers/O in/O Shenyang/LOCATION have/O killed/O three/O Uighur/O men/O who/O they/O say/O were/O Islamist/O militants/O ./O 
Activists/O have/O said/O that/O Uighurs/O are/O merely/O being/O discriminated/O against/O by/O a/O ``/O hostile/O ''/O government/O ./O 
Police/O officers/O in/O the/O northeastern/O Chinese/O city/O of/O Shenyang/LOCATION shot/O and/O killed/O three/O Uighur/O men/O carrying/O knives/O and/O injured/O a/O fourth/O on/O Monday/O evening/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O local/O government/O and/O state/O media/O ./O 
They/O reported/O that/O the/O men/O were/O shouting/O about/O Islamic/O holy/O war/O ,/O but/O declined/O to/O give/O any/O further/O details/O of/O the/O incident/O ./O 
``/O When/O police/O pursued/O the/O terrorist/O suspects/O ,/O four/O terrorists/O armed/O with/O knives/O resisted/O arrest/O ./O 
Police/O fired/O shots/O only/O after/O the/O terrorists/O ignored/O warnings/O ,/O ''/O read/O an/O online/O statement/O from/O the/O Shenyang/LOCATION public/O security/O bureau/O before/O it/O was/O taken/O down/O without/O explanation/O ./O 
State-run/O Beijing/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION ,/O citing/O the/O provincial/O government/O ,/O said/O the/O police/O had/O killed/O the/O militants/O when/O they/O resisted/O them/O during/O a/O raid/O ./O 
``/O When/O the/O police/O tried/O to/O enter/O to/O investigate/O ,/O four/O terrorists/O wearing/O headgear/O ,/O holding/O knives/O and/O crying/O out/O `/O jihad/O '/O hacked/O at/O the/O police/O ,/O ''/O the/O Beijing/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O 
The/O news/O outlet/O reported/O that/O the/O men/O were/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/O</U_LOCATION> ,/O the/O primary/O homeland/O of/O the/O Muslim/O Uighur/O minority/O ,/O and/O that/O the/O ``/O accompanying/O children/O ''/O as/O well/O as/O one/O woman/O ,/O also/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O had/O been/O apprehended/O by/O authorities/O ./O 
Minority/O Uighurs/O targeted/O 
Activists/O say/O that/O Uighurs/O ,/O targeted/O as/O separatists/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ,/O are/O simply/O fleeing/O violence/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O where/O hundreds/O have/O died/O in/O recent/O years/O ./O 
The/O government/O blames/O the/O strife/O on/O Islamic/O militants/O and/O says/O Uighurs/O want/O to/O create/O their/O own/O breakaway/O state/O ./O 
In/O a/O statement/O about/O Monday/O 's/O incident/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O spokesman/O for/O the/O exile/O group/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> wrote/O :/O ``/O The/O accusation/O that/O they/O are/O suspected/O terrorists/O exposes/O China/LOCATION 's/O hostile/O and/O discriminatory/O attitude/O ./O ''/O 
``/O China/LOCATION 's/O barbarian/O policy/O of/O shooting/O people/O dead/O before/O judicial/O interrogation/O should/O be/O prevented/O by/O the/O international/O community/O ,/O ''/O said/O <U_PERSON>Raxit/PERSON</U_PERSON> ./O 
es/msh/O -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
