Concerned/O about/O an/O Islamic/O insurgency/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Province/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O China/LOCATION has/O offered/O to/O assist/O in/O the/O Afghan/O peace/O process/O ./O 
But/O experts/O say/O China/LOCATION lacks/O direct/O access/O to/O the/O Afghan/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O relies/O on/O its/O clout/O over/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O not/O been/O directly/O involved/O in/O Afghan/O politics/O since/O 2001/O when/O US-led/O international/O forces/O toppled/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION regime/O ./O 
Instead/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O focused/O on/O economic/O investments/O and/O strengthening/O trade/O ties/O with/O the/O war-torn/O country/O ./O 
However/O ,/O with/O the/O end/O of/O NATO/ORGANIZATION 's/O military/O mission/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION last/O year/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION now/O wants/O to/O play/O a/O more/O active/O role/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
On/O February/O 12/O ,/O Chinese/O Foreign/O Minister/O Wang/PERSON Yi/PERSON announced/O that/O his/O country/O was/O willing/O to/O mediate/O in/O efforts/O to/O engage/O the/O Afghan/O <ORGANIZATION>Taliban/O</ORGANIZATION> in/O peace/O negotiations/O ./O 
``/O We/O will/O support/O the/O Afghan/O government/O in/O realizing/O reconciliation/O with/O various/O political/O factions/O including/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O said/O Wang/PERSON during/O his/O two-day/O visit/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
No/O direct/O line/O 
Experts/O believe/O China/LOCATION lacks/O direct/O access/O to/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION leaders/O and/O relies/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O relations/O with/O the/O militant/O group/O ./O 
Still/O ,/O some/O experts/O are/O optimistic/O about/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O peace/O initiative/O as/O China/LOCATION has/O strong/O strategic/O ties/O with/O Islamabad/LOCATION and/O is/O trusted/O as/O a/O regional/O power/O by/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O even/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Experts/O say/O China/LOCATION has/O no/O direct/O access/O to/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION leaders/O 
``/O Given/O the/O mistrust/O between/O Kabul/LOCATION and/O Islamabad/LOCATION both/O countries/O want/O a/O regional/O power/O like/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O has/O their/O trust/O ,/O to/O play/O a/O facilitating/O role/O in/O peace/O talks/O ./O 
The/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O too/O ,/O trust/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O this/O all/O can/O help/O the/O Afghan/O peace/O process/O ,/O ''/O Haroon/PERSON Mir/PERSON ,/O analyst/O and/O a/O former/O member/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O Centre/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Research/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Policy/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION is/O in/O contact/O with/O some/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION members/O ,/O but/O when/O Beijing/LOCATION offers/O help/O with/O the/O peace/O process/O ,/O it/O actually/O means/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION that/O are/O in/O contact/O with/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Mir/PERSON added/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O a/O close/O strategic/O ally/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O was/O one/O of/O the/O first/O countries/O to/O recognize/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION regime/O when/O they/O seized/O power/O in/O late/O 1990s/O ./O 
The/O Afghan/O government/O has/O accused/O Islamabad/LOCATION of/O supporting/O the/O militant/O group/O 's/O guerilla/O war/O against/O Afghan/O and/O international/O forces/O since/O 2001/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O however/O ,/O has/O always/O officially/O denied/O the/O allegations/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O support/O for/O Afghan/O reconciliation/O `/O more/O of/O a/O burden/O than/O an/O opportunity/O '/O 
China/LOCATION has/O offered/O to/O support/O the/O Afghan/O government/O in/O reconciling/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
But/O while/O Beijing/LOCATION brings/O major/O diplomatic/O and/O economic/O weight/O to/O the/O table/O ,/O the/O prospects/O of/O success/O are/O slim/O ,/O as/O Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON tells/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
-LRB-/O 12.02.2015/O -RRB-/O 
The/O Sino-Pakistani/O axis/O :/O Asia/LOCATION 's/O `/O little/O understood/O '/O relationship/O 
China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION have/O been/O described/O as/O ``/O all/O weather/O friends/O ,/O ''/O but/O the/O nature/O of/O their/O ties/O remains/O secretive/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> talks/O to/O analyst/O Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON ,/O about/O some/O of/O the/O most/O sensitive/O aspects/O of/O this/O strategic/O relationship/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 15.01.2015/O -RRB-/O `/O 
Pakistan/LOCATION could/O have/O 200/O nuclear/O weapons/O by/O 2020/O '/O 
While/O many/O states/O are/O downsizing/O their/O nuclear/O stockpiles/O ,/O Asia/LOCATION is/O witnessing/O a/O buildup/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O located/O in/O a/O region/O ``/O most/O at/O risk/O of/O a/O breakdown/O ,/O ''/O has/O the/O fastest-growing/O nuclear/O program/O ,/O as/O Gregory/PERSON Koblentz/PERSON tells/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
-LRB-/O 02.12.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Assessing/O India/LOCATION 's/O position/O on/O NATO/ORGANIZATION 's/O Afghanistan/LOCATION pullout/O 
Just/O weeks/O before/O NATO/ORGANIZATION combat/O troops/O leave/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O neighboring/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION are/O vying/O for/O influence/O in/O the/O war-torn/O nation/O ./O 
Analyst/O Michael/PERSON Kugelman/PERSON talks/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> about/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION 's/O view/O of/O the/O impending/O pullout/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 24.11.2014/O -RRB-/O 
A/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION delegation/O recently/O visited/O China/LOCATION ,/O but/O the/O group/O 's/O spokesman/O said/O the/O visit/O was/O not/O to/O discuss/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O role/O in/O Afghan/O peace/O process/O ./O 
Zhu/PERSON Yongbiao/PERSON ,/O an/O associate/O professor/O at/O Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION Asian/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>ICAS/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O of/O Lanzhou/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O believes/O the/O visit/O was/O intended/O to/O establish/O initial/O contacts/O and/O build/O trust/O ./O 
``/O The/O current/O contact/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION is/O more/O like/O an/O initial/O attempt/O to/O establish/O a/O connection/O for/O the/O future/O and/O to/O prepare/O for/O a/O more/O active/O engagement/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O main/O purpose/O is/O not/O to/O act/O as/O a/O mediator/O right/O now/O ,/O ''/O he/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
The/O Chinese/O expert/O also/O believes/O China/LOCATION lacks/O direct/O and/O effective/O means/O of/O intervention/O and/O participation/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O peace/O process/O ,/O but/O could/O still/O play/O a/O supportive/O role/O as/O a/O ``/O provider/O of/O funds/O ''/O in/O the/O future/O ./O 
Concerns/O over/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 
But/O China/LOCATION 's/O interest/O in/O the/O Afghan/O peace/O process/O is/O not/O limited/O to/O its/O desire/O to/O increase/O its/O regional/O influence/O ./O 
Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON ,/O a/O fellow/O with/O the/O Asia/LOCATION program/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>German/O Marshall/O Fund/O</ORGANIZATION> of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> that/O China/LOCATION was/O worried/O about/O the/O implications/O of/O the/O <LOCATION>West/O</LOCATION> 's/O drawdown/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O its/O effect/O on/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ./O 
``/O Beijing/LOCATION fears/O that/O a/O deteriorating/O situation/O there/O -LSB-/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION -RSB-/O could/O have/O destabilizing/O implications/O for/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O northwestern/O province/O ,/O and/O for/O the/O wider/O region/O ,/O impacting/O on/O China/LOCATION 's/O ambitions/O for/O a/O `/O <U_LOCATION>Silk/O Road/O</U_LOCATION> economic/O belt/O '/O and/O risking/O a/O proxy/O war/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O <PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> said/O in/O a/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> interview/O ./O 
The/O Uyghur/O nationalist/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O active/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O used/O Afghanistan/LOCATION as/O a/O safe/O haven/O when/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION were/O in/O power/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
If/O faced/O with/O another/O civil/O war/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O fear/O that/O Afghanistan/LOCATION could/O once/O again/O become/O a/O safe/O haven/O for/O Uyghur/O insurgents/O ./O 
On/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O worried/O that/O an/O even/O longer/O war/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION will/O put/O its/O economic/O investments/O in/O the/O war-torn/O county/O in/O jeopardy/O ./O 
Protecting/O investments/O 
Ahmad/PERSON Saedi/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O on/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O said/O protecting/O its/O present/O or/O future/O investments/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION was/O one/O of/O the/O main/O factors/O behind/O China/LOCATION 's/O interest/O in/O Afghan/O peace/O process/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O increased/O its/O economic/O aid/O and/O investment/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION over/O the/O past/O years/O 
``/O China/LOCATION has/O huge/O economic/O interests/O in/O a/O safe/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O as/O some/O Chinese/O companies/O have/O signed/O big/O contracts/O with/O the/O Afghan/O government/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION is/O worried/O about/O the/O faith/O of/O these/O contracts/O as/O international/O troops/O leave/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Saedi/PERSON said/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O increased/O its/O economic/O aid/O and/O investment/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION over/O the/O past/O four/O years/O ./O 
Metallurgical/ORGANIZATION Corporation/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION has/O the/O biggest/O contract/O with/O Afghan/O government/O which/O amounts/O to/O 3.5/O billion/O dollars/O in/O order/O to/O develop/O Aynak/O Copper/O mines/O ./O 
The/O company/O is/O yet/O to/O start/O actual/O work/O as/O insecurity/O has/O been/O the/O main/O obstacle/O for/O the/O Chinese/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
