Chinese/O authorities/O have/O insisted/O that/O they/O will/O be/O able/O to/O hold/O a/O safe/O Olympics/O after/O foiling/O two/O terrorist/O plots/O ,/O including/O one/O targeting/O the/O event/O ./O 
The/O other/O plot/O was/O apparently/O an/O attempt/O to/O crash/O an/O airliner/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION on/O Friday/O ./O 
The/O incidents/O have/O sparked/O a/O debate/O about/O the/O security/O arrangements/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
The/O Olympics/O are/O almost/O five/O months/O away/O and/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O increasingly/O witnessing/O incidents/O ,/O which/O are/O raising/O concerns/O about/O its/O security/O arrangements/O ./O 
In/O January/O ,/O the/O police/O had/O shot/O two/O suspected/O terrorists/O and/O detained/O 15/O others/O ,/O who/O were/O allegedly/O planning/O to/O disrupt/O the/O Games/O ./O 
In/O early/O March/O ,/O an/O Australian/O travel/O group/O was/O caught/O up/O in/O a/O hostage/O drama/O in/O the/O tourist/O region/O of/O Xian/LOCATION ./O 
The/O kidnapper/O was/O shot/O dead/O by/O police/O after/O he/O released/O all/O but/O one/O of/O the/O hostages/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O officials/O have/O foiled/O a/O suspected/O terrorist/O plot/O to/O crash/O a/O Chinese/O passenger/O plane/O ./O 
The/O plane/O was/O on/O its/O way/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O capital/O of/O the/O northwest/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> to/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
These/O incidents/O demonstrate/O that/O China/LOCATION has/O to/O prepare/O itself/O well/O in/O the/O run-up/O to/O the/O Games/O ,/O says/O a/O terror/O expert/O Li/PERSON Wie/PERSON from/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Anti-Terror/ORGANIZATION centre/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION :/O ``/O Terrorist/O attacks/O have/O been/O planned/O for/O long/O ./O 
However/O the/O nature/O of/O the/O attacks/O is/O changing/O continuously/O ./O 
No/O country/O is/O 100/O percent/O safe/O ./O 
Terrorist/O networks/O ,/O such/O as/O Al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION ,/O are/O not/O weakened/O ./O 
They/O always/O find/O ways/O to/O plan/O attacks/O ./O 
``/O Interpol/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O FBI/ORGANIZATION have/O been/O assisting/O Beijing/LOCATION with/O the/O security/O arrangements/O ahead/O of/O the/O Olympic/O Games/O ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O the/O country/O has/O itself/O put/O many/O security/O measures/O in/O place/O ./O 
During/O the/O Games/O ,/O tens/O of/O thousands/O of/O troops/O of/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION will/O be/O on/O the/O alert/O ,/O an/O estimated/O 800,000/O security/O personnel/O with/O special/O training/O will/O be/O deployed/O to/O protect/O the/O venues/O ,/O and/O around/O 150,000/O employees/O of/O security/O companies/O along/O with/O over/O 600,000/O volunteers/O will/O be/O stationed/O ./O 
However/O expert/O Li/PERSON Wei/PERSON believes/O that/O despite/O this/O gigantic/O security/O arrangement/O ,/O the/O greatest/O danger/O is/O from/O within/O china/LOCATION :/O The/O greatest/O danger/O is/O from/O a/O group/O which/O is/O called/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ./O 
It/O has/O been/O classified/O as/O an/O international/O terrorist/O group/O ./O 
In/O 1990s/O ,/O the/O group/O had/O launched/O a/O series/O of/O attacks/O ./O 
Last/O year/O ,/O the/O police/O destroyed/O a/O terrorist/O training/O camp/O in/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Pamir/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ,/O which/O had/O been/O run/O by/O the/O group/O ./O 
So/O ,/O stopping/O this/O group/O is/O going/O to/O be/O the/O main/O aim/O of/O the/O anti-/O terror/O fight/O here/O ./O ''/O 
The/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> is/O largely/O active/O in/O Muslim/O populated/O regions/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O such/O as/O the/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
The/O separatists/O Uighurs/O in/O the/O region/O have/O waged/O an/O insurgency/O for/O many/O years/O and/O are/O demanding/O for/O autonomy/O ./O 
China/LOCATION sees/O them/O as/O a/O threat/O ,/O but/O many/O human/O rights/O groups/O believe/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O exaggerating/O the/O threat/O of/O violence/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O the/O interests/O of/O exerting/O greater/O control/O in/O the/O area/O ./O
