A/O day/O before/O the/O Olympics/O open/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O protestors/O demonstrating/O for/O human/O rights/O rallied/O in/O front/O of/O Chinese/O embassies/O in/O several/O European/O cities/O with/O the/O exception/O of/O France/LOCATION where/O authorities/O banned/O protests/O ./O 
In/O Berlin/LOCATION ,/O demonstrators/O representing/O Tibetan/O groups/O ,/O Uighurs/O ,/O Mongolians/O and/O the/O Falun/ORGANIZATION Gong/ORGANIZATION spiritual/O movement/O gathered/O in/O front/O of/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O on/O Thursday/O ,/O Aug/O 7/O ,/O waving/O flags/O and/O holding/O banners/O ./O 
The/O protest/O was/O one/O of/O a/O series/O of/O events/O planned/O in/O several/O European/O cities/O on/O the/O eve/O of/O the/O prestigious/O Olympic/O Games/O to/O draw/O world/O attention/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O continuing/O human/O rights/O violations/O ./O 
Protests/O were/O planned/O in/O Lisbon/LOCATION and/O in/O Porto/LOCATION in/O Portugal/LOCATION ,/O candle/O vigils/O were/O planned/O in/O several/O Swiss/O cities/O and/O one/O in/O Norway/LOCATION ,/O while/O in/O London/LOCATION the/O Free/O Tibet/O campaign/O was/O to/O hold/O a/O protest/O in/O front/O of/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O on/O Friday/O ./O 
In/O Paris/LOCATION ,/O authorities/O banned/O rights/O groups/O from/O demonstrating/O outside/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O on/O Thursday/O and/O Friday/O ./O 
News/O agency/O AFP/ORGANIZATION reported/O that/O a/O ruling/O ruling/O sent/O to/O media/O watchdog/O <ORGANIZATION>Reporters/O Without/O Borders/O</ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>RSF/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O bans/O ``/O all/O gatherings/O ''/O from/O Thursday/O at/O 7:00/O am/O -LRB-/O 0500/O GMT/O -RRB-/O to/O Friday/O at/O midnight/O -LRB-/O 2200/O GMT/O -RRB-/O within/O a/O fixed/O perimeter/O surrounding/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O and/O consulate/O ./O 
RSF/ORGANIZATION had/O called/O for/O a/O rally/O outside/O the/O embassy/O at/O 1:00/O pm/O Friday/O ,/O to/O coincide/O with/O French/O President/O Nicolas/PERSON Sarkozy/PERSON 's/O arrival/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O the/O three-hour-long/O Olympic/O opening/O ceremony/O ./O 
The/O media/O watchdog/O has/O challenged/O the/O ruling/O in/O court/O ,/O with/O a/O decision/O due/O Friday/O at/O 10:30/O am/O ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION reported/O ./O 
RSF/ORGANIZATION head/O Robert/PERSON Menard/PERSON voiced/O outrage/O at/O the/O demo/O ban/O ,/O saying/O similar/O rallies/O were/O allowed/O to/O go/O ahead/O in/O six/O other/O European/O countries/O ./O 
``/O Does/O this/O mean/O that/O it/O is/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O that/O decides/O who/O has/O the/O right/O to/O demonstrate/O in/O Paris/LOCATION ?/O ''/O he/O asked/O ./O 
Rowdy/O protests/O by/O activists/O angry/O at/O China/LOCATION 's/O crackdown/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION seriously/O disrupted/O the/O Olympic/O flame/O 's/O Paris/LOCATION leg/O in/O April/O ,/O with/O images/O of/O the/O chaotic/O event/O provoking/O a/O wave/O of/O anti-French/O protests/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
In/O Berlin/LOCATION ,/O demonstrators/O tried/O --/O and/O failed/O --/O on/O Thursday/O to/O hand/O over/O a/O petition/O signed/O by/O 10,000/O people/O calling/O for/O greater/O human/O rights/O in/O China/LOCATION organised/O by/O a/O local/O non-governmental/O organisation/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Goettingen-based/O human/O rights/O group/O ,/O Society/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Threatened/ORGANIZATION Peoples/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O diplomatic/O delegation/O would/O not/O grant/O an/O appointment/O ,/O despite/O multiple/O requests/O ./O 
By/O handing/O over/O the/O petition/O the/O organization/O wanted/O to/O once/O against/O demonstrate/O against/O the/O increasing/O persecution/O of/O ethnic/O groups/O and/O religious/O communities/O ./O 
The/O Society/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Threatened/ORGANIZATION Peoples/ORGANIZATION '/O secretary/O general/O ,/O Tilman/PERSON Zülch/PERSON ,/O told/O German/O news/O agency/O DPA/ORGANIZATION the/O Olympics/O would/O not/O be/O a/O ``/O Games/O of/O Peace/O ''/O for/O Tibetans/O ,/O Uighurs/O ,/O Mongolians/O and/O Falun/ORGANIZATION Gong/ORGANIZATION members/O ./O 
``/O They/O 've/O already/O suffered/O too/O much/O repression/O in/O the/O past/O months/O for/O that/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
Zülch/PERSON also/O told/O news/O agency/O DDP/ORGANIZATION that/O the/O Olympics/O in/O China/LOCATION were/O ``/O comparable/O with/O the/O games/O from/O 1936/O in/O Berlin/LOCATION ,/O ''/O when/O Nazi/O Germany/LOCATION hosted/O the/O sporting/O event/O ./O 
``/O These/O are/O n't/O the/O games/O of/O openness/O and/O friendship/O ,/O but/O rather/O the/O games/O of/O repression/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O China/LOCATION was/O a/O ruled/O by/O a/O totalitarian/O regime/O that/O committed/O human/O rights/O abuses/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O painted/O the/O Games/O as/O a/O celebration/O of/O three/O decades/O of/O economic/O reforms/O and/O hopes/O the/O event/O will/O showcase/O a/O rapidly/O modernizing/O country/O ./O 
Some/O 100/O participants/O took/O park/O in/O the/O demonstration/O in/O Berlin/LOCATION which/O could/O n't/O take/O place/O directly/O at/O the/O embassy/O due/O to/O police/O barriers/O ./O 
They/O held/O up/O banners/O with/O Chinese/O characters/O written/O on/O them/O ,/O expressing/O their/O hope/O for/O improvement/O of/O human/O rights/O ./O 
The/O protestors/O also/O took/O lit/O torches/O ,/O emblazoned/O with/O the/O Olympic/O rings/O ,/O and/O put/O them/O out/O in/O giant/O tubs/O of/O water/O ./O 
With/O this/O symbolic/O gesture/O ,/O the/O demonstrators/O wanted/O to/O make/O clear/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O failed/O to/O honor/O the/O promises/O made/O leading/O up/O to/O the/O games/O to/O better/O human/O rights/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
According/O to/O human/O rights/O organizations/O ,/O more/O than/O 1,000/O Tibetan/O were/O taken/O into/O custody/O during/O the/O unrest/O and/O mass/O arrests/O in/O March/O 2008/O and/O are/O still/O missing/O ./O 
More/O than/O 1,500/O Uighurs/O have/O been/O arrested/O in/O recent/O weeks/O for/O political/O reasons/O ,/O and/O members/O of/O the/O Falun/ORGANIZATION Gong/ORGANIZATION sects/O have/O been/O victims/O of/O torture/O and/O murder/O ./O 
3,160/O of/O them/O have/O meet/O grisly/O deaths/O while/O in/O the/O custody/O of/O the/O security/O forces/O ,/O they/O say/O ./O 
Pro-Tibet/O groups/O are/O planning/O to/O hold/O Germany-wide/O demonstrations/O in/O order/O to/O call/O attention/O to/O the/O constant/O violations/O of/O human/O rights/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Over/O the/O next/O 17/O days/O ,/O some/O 50/O campaigns/O are/O planned/O to/O take/O place/O in/O 30/O different/O cities/O ,/O including/O Berlin/LOCATION ,/O Munich/LOCATION and/O Frankfurt/LOCATION ./O 
One/O group/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION activists/O plan/O to/O hold/O a/O ``/O protestival/O ''/O at/O Berlin/LOCATION 's/O landmark/O Brandenburg/LOCATION Gate/LOCATION to/O call/O attention/O to/O the/O ``/O ongoing/O bad/O human/O rights/O situation/O ''/O in/O the/O Chinese-controlled/O province/O ./O 
Germany/LOCATION 's/O human/O rights/O commissioner/O ,/O Guenter/PERSON Nooke/PERSON who/O has/O been/O in/O the/O Chinese/O capital/O since/O Tuesday/O ,/O said/O on/O Thursday/O that/O the/O decision/O to/O let/O Beijing/LOCATION host/O the/O Games/O has/O failed/O to/O improve/O the/O human/O rights/O situation/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
Planning/O for/O the/O Games/O has/O improved/O the/O mood/O of/O the/O city/O and/O brought/O new/O construction/O but/O the/O ruling/O party/O still/O tolerates/O no/O criticism/O or/O press/O freedoms/O ,/O Nooke/PERSON told/O news/O agency/O AP/ORGANIZATION ./O
