On/O Oct./O 1/O 2009/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION was/O transformed/O into/O a/O stage/O to/O celebrate/O the/O founding/O of/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION 60/O years/O ago/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O large/O military/O parade/O to/O demonstrate/O China/LOCATION 's/O military/O might/O ./O 
Despite/O the/O country/O 's/O economic/O strengths/O ,/O it/O still/O has/O far/O to/O go/O in/O terms/O of/O human/O rights/O ./O 
President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON opened/O the/O 60th/O anniversary/O ceremony/O to/O firing/O canons/O ,/O wearing/O a/O suit/O like/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON 's/O ./O 
A/O two-hour/O parade/O ,/O which/O included/O tanks/O and/O missiles/O ,/O 8,000/O soldiers/O ,/O 60/O floats/O and/O 100,000/O well/O trained/O civilians/O symbolised/O the/O country/O 's/O growing/O military/O and/O economic/O might/O ./O 
But/O there/O was/O much/O criticism/O of/O China/LOCATION on/O the/O occasion/O ./O 
In/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O for/O example/O ,/O there/O were/O massive/O demonstrations/O against/O the/O lack/O of/O progress/O on/O human/O rights/O and/O democracy/O ./O 
Earlier/O on/O in/O 2009/O ,/O on/O the/O 50th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O failed/O Tibetan/O uprising/O in/O March/O ,/O people/O all/O over/O the/O world/O demonstrated/O for/O Tibet/LOCATION 's/O autonomy/O ./O 
After/O 50/O years/O in/O exile/O ,/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O has/O not/O given/O up/O the/O fight/O ./O 
``/O The/O problem/O with/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION is/O that/O they/O consider/O me/O a/O trouble/O maker/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O this/O year/O ./O 
``/O So/O it/O is/O my/O duty/O to/O create/O more/O trouble/O ./O ''/O 
There/O was/O also/O ``/O trouble/O ''/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O north-western/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O Uighurs/O and/O majority/O Han/O Chinese/O clashed/O in/O July/O ,/O causing/O some/O 200/O deaths/O ./O 
The/O mainly/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O complain/O --/O like/O many/O other/O minorities/O in/O China/LOCATION --/O of/O cultural/O and/O religious/O repression/O ./O 
2009/O also/O marked/O the/O 20th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O massacre/O on/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O which/O can/O arguably/O be/O considered/O the/O most/O potent/O symbol/O of/O Chinese/O repression/O in/O the/O country/O 's/O recent/O past/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O media/O were/O banned/O from/O discussing/O it/O ./O 
The/O British/O Human/O Rights/O Risk/O Atlas/O ranked/O China/LOCATION 12th/O ``/O most/O risky/O country/O ''/O overall/O for/O human/O rights/O this/O year/O ./O 
For/O child/O labour/O ,/O forced/O labour/O ,/O and/O violations/O of/O freedom/O of/O association/O ,/O discrimination/O and/O working/O conditions/O ,/O China/LOCATION ranked/O highest/O ./O 
Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON is/O one/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O most/O prominent/O dissidents/O and/O is/O currently/O awaiting/O sentencing/O on/O charges/O of/O subversion/O ./O 
``/O I/O have/O lost/O faith/O ,/O ''/O his/O wife/O Liu/PERSON Xia/PERSON said/O in/O August/O ./O 
``/O There/O is/O absolutely/O no/O transparency/O here/O ./O 
If/O you/O live/O in/O a/O country/O in/O which/O freedom/O of/O speech/O is/O n't/O worth/O a/O dime/O ,/O anyone/O can/O be/O convicted/O ./O ''/O 
``/O I/O am/O very/O worried/O ,/O ''/O she/O continued/O ./O 
``/O They/O have/O accused/O him/O of/O felonies/O ,/O for/O which/O he/O could/O receive/O up/O to/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O 
He/O did/O n't/O do/O anything/O ,/O aside/O from/O telling/O the/O truth/O and/O stating/O his/O opinion/O ./O 
Here/O in/O China/LOCATION they/O call/O that/O `/O breaking/O the/O law/O '/O ./O ''/O 
Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON 's/O sentence/O is/O expected/O to/O be/O handed/O down/O on/O Christmas/O day/O ./O 
Although/O China/LOCATION was/O criticised/O for/O its/O human/O rights/O record/O ,/O its/O economic/O situation/O in/O 2009/O gave/O rise/O to/O hope/O ./O 
Despite/O world/O recession/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O economy/O continued/O to/O grow/O at/O a/O rate/O of/O eight/O to/O 10/O percent/O ./O 
The/O optimism/O expressed/O by/O many/O economists/O at/O the/O beginning/O of/O the/O year/O seems/O to/O have/O been/O vindicated/O ./O 
``/O The/O statistics/O are/O showing/O recovery/O in/O many/O sectors/O of/O the/O economy/O ,/O ''/O the/O head/O of/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION ,/O Zhal/PERSON Xiaochuan/PERSON ,/O said/O in/O January/O ./O 
``/O This/O means/O that/O our/O economic/O stimulus/O programme/O is/O taking/O hold/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION has/O made/O it/O clear/O that/O our/O reaction/O to/O the/O crisis/O must/O be/O quick/O and/O resolute/O ./O ''/O 
The/O positive/O signs/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O economy/O have/O been/O attributed/O to/O an/O increase/O in/O Chinese/O consumerism/O and/O lending/O and/O investments/O abroad/O ./O 
With/O this/O strategy/O ,/O experts/O say/O China/LOCATION is/O leading/O the/O world/O out/O of/O the/O financial/O crisis/O and/O will/O continue/O to/O do/O so/O in/O 2010/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Sarah/PERSON BerningEditor/PERSON :/O Anne/PERSON Thomas/PERSON 
