The/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION has/O secured/O commitments/O from/O six/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION nations/O to/O take/O in/O detainees/O held/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ,/O bolstering/O efforts/O to/O close/O the/O prison/O ,/O the/O Washington/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION reported/O Thursday/O ./O 
Britain/LOCATION ,/O France/LOCATION ,/O Ireland/LOCATION ,/O Italy/LOCATION ,/O Portugal/LOCATION and/O Spain/LOCATION have/O accepted/O or/O publicly/O agreed/O to/O take/O detainees/O ./O 
In/O addition/O ,/O four/O EU/ORGANIZATION countries/O have/O privately/O told/O the/O administration/O that/O they/O are/O committed/O to/O resettling/O detainees/O ,/O and/O five/O other/O EU/ORGANIZATION nations/O are/O considering/O taking/O some/O ,/O according/O to/O officials/O in/O US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON 's/O administration/O ,/O who/O spoke/O to/O the/O newspaper/O on/O the/O condition/O of/O anonymity/O ./O 
There/O are/O still/O 229/O prisoners/O at/O the/O camp/O ,/O which/O was/O opened/O in/O January/O 2002/O by/O then/O president/O George/PERSON W./PERSON Bush/PERSON to/O hold/O ``/O enemy/O combatants/O ''/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION ``/O war/O on/O terror/O ./O ''/O 
Obama/PERSON has/O ordered/O the/O camp/O to/O be/O closed/O by/O January/O 22/O ,/O 2010/O ./O 
To/O meet/O that/O goal/O ,/O the/O administration/O has/O appointed/O Daniel/PERSON Fried/PERSON ,/O a/O longtime/O diplomat/O with/O deep/O ties/O to/O eastern/O Europe/LOCATION and/O parts/O of/O the/O former/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ,/O to/O lead/O negotiations/O with/O other/O countries/O ./O 
Some/O 80/O prisoners/O are/O ready/O for/O release/O ./O 
The/O Post/ORGANIZATION said/O that/O if/O resettling/O agreements/O could/O be/O made/O ,/O a/O reduced/O detainee/O population/O would/O likely/O ease/O the/O politically/O charged/O debate/O on/O moving/O remaining/O prisoners/O to/O a/O facility/O on/O US/LOCATION soil/O ./O 
Of/O the/O detainees/O cleared/O for/O release/O so/O far/O ,/O eleven/O have/O been/O transferred/O home/O or/O to/O third/O countries/O ,/O including/O Bermuda/LOCATION ,/O which/O accepted/O four/O Chinese/O Uighurs/O ./O 
The/O Pacific/LOCATION island/O of/O Palau/LOCATION has/O agreed/O to/O resettle/O the/O 13/O remaining/O Uighur/O detainees/O ,/O and/O more/O than/O half/O of/O them/O are/O willing/O to/O go/O or/O are/O seriously/O considering/O the/O offer/O ./O 
In/O addition/O ,/O the/O administration/O has/O held/O positive/O talks/O with/O Australia/LOCATION and/O Georgia/LOCATION ,/O and/O it/O has/O formally/O approached/O or/O is/O planning/O to/O hold/O talks/O with/O countries/O in/O South/LOCATION America/LOCATION ,/O the/O Persian/LOCATION Gulf/LOCATION ,/O the/O Balkans/LOCATION and/O the/O former/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ,/O the/O Post/ORGANIZATION wrote/O ./O 
Congress/ORGANIZATION has/O blocked/O the/O White/ORGANIZATION House/ORGANIZATION from/O resettling/O any/O detainees/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O a/O move/O that/O US/LOCATION and/O some/O European/O officials/O feared/O would/O lead/O other/O countries/O ,/O particularly/O in/O the/O EU/LOCATION ,/O to/O refuse/O to/O help/O close/O the/O military/O prison/O ./O 
But/O the/O issue/O has/O proved/O relatively/O unproblematic/O ,/O officials/O said/O ./O 
``/O Obama/PERSON has/O a/O lot/O of/O political/O capital/O ./O 
Countries/O want/O to/O do/O something/O for/O him/O ,/O and/O that/O allows/O us/O to/O say/O ,/O `/O This/O is/O it/O ,/O this/O is/O what/O we/O want/O you/O to/O do/O ,/O '/O ''/O said/O a/O senior/O administration/O official/O quoted/O in/O the/O report/O ./O 
``/O This/O is/O going/O a/O lot/O better/O than/O we/O might/O have/O thought/O ./O ''/O 
One/O senior/O administration/O official/O said/O negotiations/O in/O eastern/O Europe/LOCATION will/O intensify/O once/O detainees/O arrive/O in/O larger/O EU/LOCATION countries/O ,/O such/O as/O Italy/LOCATION and/O Spain/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Post/ORGANIZATION also/O reported/O that/O US/LOCATION and/O European/O officials/O believe/O stalled/O negotiations/O with/O Berlin/LOCATION can/O be/O rekindled/O after/O Germany/LOCATION holds/O national/O parliamentary/O elections/O next/O month/O ./O 
And/O there/O is/O some/O expectation/O that/O France/LOCATION ,/O which/O has/O taken/O one/O detainee/O ,/O may/O accept/O more/O ./O 
nda/AFPEditor/O :/O Nancy/PERSON Isenson/PERSON 
