In/O a/O speech/O in/O Dharamsala/LOCATION ,/O India/LOCATION on/O Wednesday/O ,/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON declared/O his/O solidarity/O with/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uighur/O minority/O and/O accused/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O wanting/O to/O ``/O annihilate/O ''/O Tibetan/O Buddhism/O ./O 
