On/O a/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ,/O Pakistani/O President/O Asif/PERSON Ali/PERSON Zardari/PERSON has/O promised/O to/O work/O more/O closely/O with/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O combat/O terrorism/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O president/O has/O promised/O to/O work/O more/O closely/O with/O China/LOCATION in/O the/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O ./O 
His/O comments/O came/O as/O he/O visited/O the/O restive/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O met/O officials/O ahead/O of/O a/O trade/O expo/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O the/O provincial/O capital/O where/O security/O was/O boosted/O ./O 
It/O was/O President/O Zardari/PERSON 's/O first/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION after/O two/O deadly/O attacks/O in/O the/O ancient/O Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION city/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION left/O 21/O people/O dead/O and/O led/O to/O some/O tension/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O ,/O as/O officials/O blamed/O members/O of/O the/O ``/O East/ORGANIZATION Turkmenistan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION ''/O for/O the/O violence/O and/O said/O they/O had/O been/O trained/O in/O Pakistani/O camps/O before/O being/O sent/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Some/O experts/O maintained/O that/O the/O Chinese/O government/O had/O not/O produced/O enough/O evidence/O to/O establish/O an/O organized/O terrorist/O threat/O ,/O saying/O that/O the/O violence/O stemmed/O from/O a/O long-standing/O ethnic/O enmity/O in/O the/O area/O ./O 
On/O Wednesday/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O official/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O reported/O that/O President/O Asif/PERSON Ali/PERSON Zardari/PERSON had/O met/O the/O head/O of/O the/O Xinjiang/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Zhang/PERSON Chunxian/PERSON the/O day/O before/O ./O 
``/O Zardari/PERSON stated/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION opposes/O any/O terrorist/O activities/O and/O will/O work/O more/O closely/O with/O China/LOCATION in/O combating/O terrorism/O ,/O ''/O the/O agency/O said/O in/O a/O statement/O ./O 
Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O which/O borders/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O has/O seen/O many/O violent/O outbreaks/O in/O the/O past/O ./O 
Some/O members/O of/O the/O ethnic/O Uighur/O community/O have/O even/O sought/O refuge/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O mainly/O Muslim/O Uighur/O community/O resents/O the/O immigration/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O into/O the/O area/O and/O accuses/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O oppression/O ./O 
In/O 2009/O ,/O riots/O between/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O killed/O almost/O 200/O people/O ./O 
Zardari/PERSON endorsed/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policies/O in/O the/O restive/O region/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION have/O always/O enjoyed/O smooth/O ties/O in/O the/O past/O and/O these/O have/O become/O more/O intense/O in/O recent/O months/O as/O Islamabad/LOCATION 's/O relationship/O with/O Washington/LOCATION has/O deteriorated/O ./O 
However/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O also/O expressed/O its/O concerns/O about/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O security/O situation/O and/O its/O vulnerability/O to/O terrorists/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Manasi/PERSON Gopalakrishnan/PERSON -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O Editor/O :/O Anne/PERSON Thomas/PERSON 
