Khom/PERSON Raj/PERSON Sharma/PERSON is/O n't/O letting/O social/O barriers/O in/O Nepal/LOCATION hold/O him/O back/O ./O 
He/O 's/O a/O social/O entrepreneur/O and/O runs/O an/O institute/O for/O the/O empowerment/O and/O inclusion/O of/O people/O who/O are/O blind/O ./O 
The/O Nepalese/O national/O anthem/O is/O played/O as/O hundreds/O of/O activists/O and/O experts/O gather/O for/O a/O conference/O on/O disability/O issues/O at/O Triebhuvan/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O country/O 's/O capital/O Kathmandu/LOCATION ./O 
They/O are/O here/O to/O discuss/O the/O challenges/O faced/O by/O disabled/O people/O and/O to/O dream/O up/O new/O projects/O to/O address/O the/O needs/O of/O their/O communities/O ./O 
Khom/PERSON Raj/PERSON Sharma/PERSON is/O blind/O and/O has/O taken/O part/O in/O this/O annual/O event/O for/O years/O ./O 
He/O is/O the/O founder/O of/O the/O ``/O Inclusion/O Empowerment/O Centre/O ,/O ''/O a/O continuing/O education/O institute/O ,/O in/O Pokhara/LOCATION ,/O central/O Nepal/LOCATION ./O 
The/O center/O provides/O blind/O students/O with/O computers/O and/O the/O technology/O they/O need/O to/O use/O them/O ./O 
They/O also/O offer/O English/O classes/O ./O 
``/O It/O 's/O not/O so/O easy/O to/O find/O a/O job/O in/O our/O society/O if/O one/O is/O blind/O ,/O ''/O Khom/PERSON Raj/PERSON Sharma/PERSON told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O That/O 's/O why/O my/O students/O always/O have/O to/O prove/O how/O good/O they/O are/O ./O 
That/O 's/O why/O we/O organize/O seminars/O to/O make/O clear/O how/O much/O potential/O blind/O people/O have/O ./O ''/O 
Khom/PERSON Raj/PERSON Sharma/PERSON opened/O his/O center/O for/O the/O blind/O a/O year/O ago/O ./O 
The/O classrooms/O are/O sparsely/O furnished/O but/O they/O are/O equipped/O with/O the/O latest/O technology/O ./O 
He/O teaches/O his/O 35/O students/O for/O free/O because/O he/O knows/O that/O their/O families/O are/O unable/O to/O afford/O fees/O ./O 
As/O Sharma/PERSON spoke/O about/O his/O work/O his/O face/O lit/O up/O ./O 
His/O enthusiasm/O and/O optimism/O are/O contagious/O ./O 
In/O Nepal/LOCATION ,/O it/O is/O difficult/O for/O visually/O impaired/O people/O to/O find/O employment/O ,/O as/O discrimination/O against/O those/O with/O disabilities/O is/O widespread/O ./O 
The/O 27-year-old/O said/O his/O goal/O is/O to/O get/O his/O students/O jobs/O as/O interpreters/O or/O tour/O guides/O ,/O jobs/O in/O which/O they/O can/O use/O their/O English/O skills/O ./O 
It/O is/O still/O unthinkable/O in/O Nepal/LOCATION for/O a/O blind/O or/O partially-sighted/O person/O to/O work/O in/O a/O bank/O ./O 
Sharma/PERSON has/O long/O been/O active/O in/O disability/O rights/O organizations/O and/O has/O become/O a/O vocal/O advocate/O for/O the/O rights/O of/O blind/O people/O in/O Nepal/LOCATION ./O 
In/O January/O 2009/O ,/O Sharma/PERSON was/O awarded/O a/O scholarship/O and/O invited/O to/O attend/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Social/ORGANIZATION Entrepreneurs/ORGANIZATION in/O Kerala/LOCATION ,/O India/LOCATION ./O 
He/O took/O an/O 11-month/O course/O to/O learn/O more/O about/O project/O management/O ,/O planning/O and/O fundraising/O ./O 
``/O It/O was/O a/O very/O good/O opportunity/O for/O me/O and/O made/O me/O become/O more/O self-confident/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O We/O were/O from/O 14/O different/O countries/O ./O 
It/O was/O wonderful/O to/O exchange/O our/O experiences/O ./O ''/O 
Sharma/PERSON is/O an/O important/O role/O model/O for/O students/O like/O Sabitri/PERSON Batrai/PERSON ./O 
Blind/O from/O birth/O ,/O she/O uses/O a/O computer/O equipped/O with/O specialized/O software/O that/O allows/O her/O to/O hear/O what/O she/O is/O typing/O ./O 
Despite/O the/O challenges/O ahead/O ,/O she/O has/O big/O plans/O for/O the/O future/O ./O 
``/O I/O would/O like/O to/O teach/O at/O a/O computer/O institute/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
``/O My/O friends/O want/O me/O to/O teach/O them/O basic/O computing/O skills/O ./O 
I/O want/O them/O to/O be/O able/O to/O stay/O in/O contact/O with/O the/O whole/O world/O ,/O even/O when/O they/O 're/O at/O home/O ./O ''/O 
Born/O in/O small/O village/O in/O western/O Nepal/LOCATION ,/O Sharma/PERSON lost/O his/O eyesight/O when/O he/O was/O just/O 11/O years/O old/O ./O 
He/O was/O born/O unable/O to/O see/O out/O of/O his/O left/O eye/O ,/O but/O had/O some/O vision/O in/O his/O right/O ./O 
He/O did/O n't/O have/O access/O to/O proper/O medical/O care/O and/O his/O condition/O worsened/O ./O 
Sharma/PERSON 's/O parents/O ,/O who/O were/O peasants/O and/O unable/O to/O read/O ,/O took/O him/O to/O a/O nearby/O temple/O in/O search/O of/O help/O ./O 
They/O were/O told/O Sharma/PERSON 's/O blindness/O was/O punishment/O for/O something/O bad/O he/O had/O done/O in/O a/O past/O life/O ./O 
Being/O blind/O in/O Nepal/LOCATION is/O considered/O by/O many/O to/O be/O a/O curse/O ./O 
When/O he/O was/O finally/O taken/O to/O see/O a/O doctor/O ,/O it/O was/O too/O late/O ./O 
He/O had/O lost/O the/O sight/O in/O both/O eyes/O forever/O ./O 
But/O Sharma/PERSON says/O he/O does/O n't/O blame/O his/O parents/O ./O 
``/O That/O 's/O what/O society/O was/O like/O ,/O ''/O he/O explained/O ./O 
``/O There/O was/O no/O hospital/O near/O my/O house/O ./O 
My/O parents/O had/O no/O money/O and/O they/O would/O n't/O have/O been/O able/O to/O do/O anything/O anyway/O ./O ''/O 
Sharma/PERSON was/O able/O to/O get/O into/O a/O school/O for/O the/O blind/O and/O continue/O his/O studies/O ./O 
That/O 's/O where/O he/O met/O the/O woman/O he/O wanted/O to/O marry/O ./O 
She/O was/O from/O a/O lower/O caste/O ,/O which/O means/O she/O was/O considered/O socially/O beneath/O him/O ,/O and/O again/O Sharma/PERSON found/O himself/O fighting/O against/O discrimination/O ./O 
``/O In/O Nepal/LOCATION ,/O social/O standing/O is/O everything/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O You/O 're/O not/O allowed/O to/O marry/O someone/O from/O another/O caste/O ./O 
I/O belong/O to/O the/O so-called/O `/O top/O caste/O ,/O '/O my/O wife/O -LRB-/O is/O from/O -RRB-/O a/O different/O ethnic/O minority/O ./O 
It/O was/O hard/O to/O convince/O my/O parents/O ./O ''/O 
But/O the/O couple/O did/O eventually/O get/O married/O and/O they/O had/O a/O son/O ,/O who/O is/O now/O three/O ./O 
They/O named/O him/O ``/O Vision/O ,/O ''/O because/O he/O is/O able/O to/O see/O ./O 
Sharma/PERSON gets/O inspiration/O from/O his/O homelands/O ,/O the/O foothills/O of/O the/O Himalayas/LOCATION ,/O near/O Mount/LOCATION Everest/LOCATION ./O 
He/O explained/O that/O the/O feeling/O of/O being/O on/O top/O of/O the/O mountain/O ranges/O helps/O him/O aim/O high/O ,/O and/O stand/O unshaken/O in/O the/O face/O of/O any/O challenge/O -/O that/O 's/O what/O he/O aims/O to/O teach/O others/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Isha/PERSON Bhatia/PERSON //O act/O Editor/O :/O Saroja/PERSON Coelho/PERSON 
