Pakistani/O development/O experts/O and/O activists/O say/O the/O massacre/O of/O Shiite/O Muslims/O in/O Gilgit-Baltistan/LOCATION and/O other/O northern/O parts/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O linked/O to/O ongoing/O development/O programs/O in/O the/O area/O and/O regional/O politics/O ./O 
Last/O week/O ,/O several/O gunmen/O ,/O who/O were/O in/O the/O guise/O of/O Pakistani/O security/O officials/O ,/O stopped/O a/O passenger/O bus/O travelling/O from/O Rawalpindi/LOCATION to/O the/O northwestern/O Gilgit/LOCATION region/O and/O dragged/O the/O travelers/O off/O the/O bus/O ./O 
The/O gunmen/O asked/O the/O passengers/O to/O show/O their/O identity/O cards/O ,/O after/O which/O they/O brutally/O killed/O 22/O of/O them/O at/O point/O blank/O range/O ,/O making/O sure/O that/O they/O belonged/O to/O the/O minority/O Shiite/O community/O ./O 
The/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O Sunni-Wahabi/O militant/O organization/O ,/O claimed/O responsibility/O of/O the/O attack/O ./O 
It/O was/O the/O third/O such/O incident/O in/O six/O months/O ./O 
Pakistani/O experts/O say/O that/O although/O Shiite/O Muslims/O are/O also/O murdered/O in/O other/O parts/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O the/O Shiites/O living/O in/O the/O northwestern/O Gilgit-Baltistan/LOCATION region/O ,/O a/O predominantly/O Shiite/ORGANIZATION area/O ,/O face/O a/O systematic/O onslaught/O by/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Some/O experts/O go/O to/O an/O extent/O of/O calling/O it/O ``/O sectarian/O cleansing/O ''/O of/O the/O Shiites/O ./O 
In/O a/O similar/O incident/O on/O February/O 28/O ,/O gunmen/O in/O military/O fatigues/O shot/O dead/O 18/O Shiite/O Muslims/O in/O the/O northern/O Kohistan/LOCATION district/O while/O they/O were/O travelling/O from/O Rawalpindi/LOCATION to/O Gilgit/LOCATION ./O 
On/O April/O 3/O ,/O a/O Sunni/O mob/O pulled/O nine/O Shiites/O out/O of/O buses/O and/O murdered/O them/O in/O the/O town/O of/O Chilas/LOCATION ,/O about/O 60/O miles/O south/O of/O Gilgit/LOCATION ./O 
Pakistani/O human/O rights/O groups/O accuse/O the/O country/O 's/O security/O agencies/O of/O backing/O Sunni/O militants/O and/O failing/O to/O protect/O the/O minority/O groups/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
``/O The/O killings/O are/O doubtless/O the/O work/O of/O those/O who/O want/O to/O destroy/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O but/O a/O failure/O to/O nab/O and/O punish/O the/O killers/O is/O also/O contributing/O to/O the/O same/O end/O .../O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O are/O -RRB-/O nobody/O 's/O friends/O and/O those/O who/O created/O this/O monster/O have/O taken/O Pakistan/LOCATION down/O the/O road/O to/O annihilation/O ,/O ''/O said/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O non-governmental/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION of/O Pakistan/LOCATION in/O a/O statement/O ,/O directly/O holding/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O state/O agencies/O responsible/O for/O the/O massacre/O ./O 
Gilgit-Baltistan/PERSON used/O to/O be/O a/O popular/O tourist/O destination/O but/O now/O not/O many/O people/O travel/O to/O these/O areas/O because/O of/O the/O unrest/O ./O 
Gilgit-Baltistan/LOCATION lies/O about/O 10/O kilometers/O off/O the/O Karakoram/LOCATION Highway/LOCATION ,/O which/O connects/O it/O to/O the/O Pakistani/O capital/O Islamabad/LOCATION in/O the/O south/O and/O to/O the/O Chinese/O cities/O of/O Tashkurgan/LOCATION ,/O Upal/O and/O Kashgar/LOCATION in/O the/O northern/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ./O 
To/O the/O west/O of/O Gilgit-Baltistan/LOCATION lies/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O on/O its/O southwest/O is/O Pakistani/LOCATION Administered/LOCATION Kashmir/LOCATION ./O 
Pakistani/O experts/O say/O the/O sectarian/O violence/O in/O Gilgit-Baltistan/LOCATION ,/O which/O was/O given/O the/O status/O of/O an/O administrative/O province/O by/O President/O Zardari/PERSON in/O 2009/O ,/O is/O also/O linked/O to/O regional/O politics/O and/O to/O ongoing/O and/O future/O development/O projects/O in/O the/O area/O ./O 
Maqsood/PERSON Ahmad/PERSON Jan/PERSON ,/O a/O development/O expert/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/O that/O the/O violence/O in/O Gilgit-Baltistan/LOCATION region/O increased/O considerably/O after/O the/O Pakistan/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION 's/O government/O elevated/O the/O status/O of/O the/O once-reclusive/O and/O semi-governed/O region/O ./O 
``/O Currently/O ,/O I/O am/O working/O with/O the/O Plan/O International/O organization/O and/O we/O are/O working/O to/O implement/O some/O projects/O in/O Gilgit/LOCATION ,/O but/O the/O continued/O violence/O has/O impeded/O the/O pace/O of/O our/O projects/O ./O 
Other/O development/O organizations/O working/O in/O this/O area/O also/O complain/O about/O the/O same/O ,/O ''/O Jan/PERSON said/O ./O 
Many/O development/O experts/O are/O of/O the/O view/O that/O militant/O Sunni/O groups/O are/O not/O in/O favor/O of/O a/O prosperous/O and/O autonomous/O Shiite-dominated/O Gilgit-Baltistan/LOCATION region/O so/O close/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION and/O Kashmir/LOCATION ./O 
Defense/O experts/O say/O that/O peace/O in/O Gilgit-Baltistan/LOCATION would/O also/O be/O a/O setback/O for/O hard-line/O Kashmiri/ORGANIZATION militant/O groups/O ,/O which/O claim/O that/O Gilgit-Baltistan/LOCATION is/O part/O of/O Kashmir/LOCATION ./O 
Gilgit-Baltistan/O Shiites/O have/O always/O opposed/O any/O move/O to/O annex/O their/O region/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION Administered/O Kashmir/LOCATION because/O they/O fear/O it/O would/O turn/O them/O into/O a/O minority/O ./O 
The/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O say/O experts/O ,/O see/O the/O majority/O Shiite/PERSON Gilgit-Baltistan/PERSON as/O a/O threat/O to/O their/O Wahabi/O political/O agenda/O and/O their/O influence/O in/O the/O Pakistani/O Khyber/O Pakhtunkhwa/O province/O which/O borders/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
But/O there/O are/O others/O who/O say/O that/O the/O Shiite/O massacre/O in/O Gilgit-Baltistan/LOCATION was/O actually/O a/O war/O of/O interests/O between/O regional/O players/O ./O 
``/O It/O is/O somehow/O linked/O to/O the/O `/O war/O on/O terror/O '/O and/O US/LOCATION policies/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O especially/O its/O policy/O towards/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Sartaj/PERSON Khan/PERSON ,/O an/O editor/O in/O Karachi/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O I/O think/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O Pakistani/O agencies/O ,/O with/O the/O backing/O of/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ,/O are/O arming/O militant/O Sunni/O groups/O to/O suppress/O the/O Shiites/O in/O the/O region/O to/O kill/O any/O possible/O support/O for/O Iran/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Khan/PERSON added/O that/O the/O Pakistani/O agencies/O had/O given/O a/O ``/O free/O hand/O ''/O to/O militant/O organizations/O like/O the/O Sipah-e-Sahaba/LOCATION ,/O a/O Sunni/O organization/O believed/O to/O be/O responsible/O for/O various/O attacks/O on/O Pakistani/O Shiites/O in/O the/O past/O ,/O to/O operate/O in/O Gilgit-Baltistan/LOCATION ./O 
Karachi-based/O Shiite/O activist/O Syed/PERSON Ali/PERSON Mujtaba/PERSON Zaidi/PERSON also/O blamed/O US/LOCATION policies/O in/O the/O region/O for/O the/O instability/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O northern/O areas/O and/O the/O conflict/O between/O the/O Shiites/O and/O Sunnis/O ./O 
``/O The/O US/LOCATION intends/O to/O demoralize/O us/O ,/O make/O us/O feel/O hopeless/O and/O helpless/O ,/O so/O that/O it/O can/O continue/O to/O play/O its/O politics/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
Its/O main/O motive/O is/O to/O counter/O China/LOCATION and/O Iran/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Zaidi/PERSON told/O DW/O ,/O adding/O that/O he/O believed/O extremists/O Sunni/O groups/O like/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION were/O working/O for/O the/O US/LOCATION '/O interests/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
On/O his/O part/O ,/O Hameed/PERSON Satti/PERSON ,/O a/O development/O consultant/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/O that/O Pakistanis/O had/O a/O habit/O of/O blaming/O foreign/O countries/O for/O their/O problems/O ,/O and/O that/O it/O was/O not/O surprising/O for/O him/O that/O the/O massacre/O of/O the/O Shiites/O ,/O which/O he/O believed/O was/O a/O result/O of/O state/O policies/O ,/O was/O blamed/O on/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O 
