Hada/PERSON ,/O a/O high-profile/O dissident/O from/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION ,/O has/O been/O detained/O by/O authorities/O for/O nearly/O two/O years/O after/O having/O spent/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O 
His/O wife/O hopes/O for/O change/O following/O the/O recent/O party/O congress/O ./O 
Inner/O Mongolia/LOCATION ,/O in/O northeast/O China/LOCATION ,/O is/O one/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O autonomous/O regions/O ,/O like/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O Tibet/LOCATION in/O the/O west/O ./O 
But/O unlike/O these/O two/O regions/O ,/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION is/O rarely/O in/O the/O public/O eye/O ,/O due/O largely/O to/O ethnic/O tensions/O and/O demands/O for/O greater/O independence/O ./O 
Its/O five/O million/O inhabitants/O are/O hugely/O unhappy/O with/O the/O cultural/O and/O economic/O dominance/O of/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
The/O most/O recent/O protest/O ,/O in/O the/O capital/O Hohhot/LOCATION ,/O was/O triggered/O in/O May/O 2012/O by/O the/O violent/O death/O of/O two/O Mongolian/O activists/O who/O had/O blocked/O Chinese/O mining/O activities/O ./O 
Many/O Mongols/O reject/O China/LOCATION 's/O intervention/O in/O their/O traditional/O way/O of/O life/O ./O 
Their/O best-known/O protagonist/O in/O the/O battle/O for/O greater/O independence/O is/O Hada/PERSON ,/O who/O ,/O in/O line/O with/O Mongolian/O tradition/O ,/O uses/O only/O one/O name/O ./O 
The/O activist/O ,/O author/O and/O bookseller/O was/O arrested/O in/O 1995/O after/O organizing/O an/O anti-Chinese/O demonstration/O in/O Hohhot/LOCATION ./O 
He/O was/O convicted/O of/O separatism/O and/O ,/O because/O of/O an/O interview/O with/O Voice/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION America/ORGANIZATION ,/O of/O espionage/O as/O well/O ,/O in/O addition/O to/O his/O role/O in/O the/O banned/O ``/O South/ORGANIZATION Mongolian/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Democracy/ORGANIZATION ./O ''/O 
He/O was/O sentenced/O to/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O 
After/O Hada/PERSON 's/O sentence/O expired/O on/O December/O 2010/O ,/O photos/O of/O him/O at/O a/O family/O reunion/O appeared/O on/O the/O Internet/O ./O 
The/O five/O photos/O ,/O uploaded/O anonymously/O to/O the/O website/O boxun.com/O ,/O show/O the/O gray-haired/O Hada/PERSON eating/O with/O his/O wife/O Xinna/PERSON and/O their/O son/O Uiles/PERSON ./O 
The/O normality/O depicted/O by/O the/O photos/O is/O false/O ,/O however/O ./O 
Hada/PERSON has/O not/O been/O seen/O in/O public/O since/O his/O arrest/O ./O 
Family/O members/O say/O he/O continues/O to/O be/O held/O at/O an/O undisclosed/O location/O ./O 
Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION is/O among/O the/O groups/O protesting/O his/O detention/O ./O 
Xinna/PERSON was/O also/O arrested/O for/O ``/O illegal/O business/O activities/O ''/O in/O connection/O with/O the/O Mongolian/O Academic/O bookstore/O in/O Hohhot/LOCATION which/O she/O inherited/O from/O her/O husband/O ./O 
After/O the/O 18th/ORGANIZATION Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION mid/O November/O ,/O she/O spoke/O with/O DW/O about/O the/O state/O of/O her/O husband/O ./O 
``/O He/O was/O physically/O weak/O then/O -LRB-/O in/O December/O 2010/O -RRB-/O because/O of/O the/O bad/O food/O in/O prison/O but/O his/O mind/O was/O alert/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
``/O After/O that/O visit/O ,/O we/O were/O separated/O again/O because/O both/O of/O us/O went/O on/O a/O hunger/O strike/O to/O protest/O our/O illegal/O detention/O ./O ''/O 
After/O seeing/O her/O husband/O a/O year/O later/O ,/O Xinna/PERSON said/O he/O looked/O depressed/O ./O 
``/O He/O sat/O there/O all/O day/O without/O moving/O ,/O ''/O she/O recalled/O ./O 
``/O His/O guards/O told/O me/O he/O was/O in/O that/O state/O for/O nearly/O a/O year/O ./O ''/O 
Among/O the/O harassments/O to/O which/O he/O was/O subjected/O ,/O she/O added/O ,/O was/O the/O denial/O of/O toilet/O paper/O ./O 
Today/O ,/O Xinna/PERSON and/O her/O son/O live/O in/O a/O rented/O warehouse/O in/O Hohhot/LOCATION ,/O under/O constant/O surveillance/O by/O authorities/O ./O 
She/O was/O sentenced/O to/O five/O years/O probation/O for/O the/O alleged/O business/O offense/O ,/O while/O her/O son/O was/O accused/O of/O drug/O possession/O without/O formal/O charges/O ./O 
Xi/PERSON Haiming/PERSON ,/O a/O Chinese/O dissident/O living/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/O that/O Hada/PERSON had/O been/O threatened/O with/O another/O four/O years/O of/O detention/O -/O the/O justification/O being/O that/O after/O 15/O years/O of/O imprisonment/O ,/O he/O had/O no/O legal/O rights/O for/O a/O period/O of/O four/O years/O anyway/O ./O 
Hu/PERSON Chunhua/PERSON ,/O secretary/O of/O the/O CPC/ORGANIZATION Inner/ORGANIZATION Mongolia/ORGANIZATION Autonomous/ORGANIZATION Region/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O Xinna/PERSON 's/O bookstore/O remained/O closed/O and/O the/O books/O had/O been/O confiscated/O ./O 
Since/O the/O beginning/O of/O the/O 18th/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O officials/O had/O been/O following/O Xinna/PERSON 's/O every/O step/O ,/O even/O her/O walks/O with/O the/O dog/O in/O the/O courtyard/O or/O trips/O with/O her/O son/O to/O go/O swimming/O ,/O according/O to/O Hu/O ./O 
Her/O telephone/O and/O Internet/O access/O did/O not/O work/O during/O the/O party/O congress/O ,/O he/O added/O ./O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O Xinna/PERSON continues/O to/O write/O assiduously/O to/O party/O leader/O Hu/PERSON and/O high-level/O security/O officials/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O demanding/O the/O release/O of/O her/O husband/O and/O an/O end/O to/O the/O prosecution/O of/O her/O family/O ./O 
She/O remains/O confident/O ,/O pointing/O to/O the/O 18th/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION where/O there/O was/O talk/O of/O transparency/O in/O the/O justice/O system/O ./O 
``/O I/O added/O this/O sentence/O from/O the/O congress/O -/O `/O put/O justice/O in/O the/O sunshine/O '/O -/O in/O my/O letter/O to/O the/O Minister/O for/O Public/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION and/O expressed/O my/O hope/O that/O these/O would/O not/O remain/O empty/O words/O ,/O ''/O Xinna/PERSON said/O ./O 
She/O hopes/O China/LOCATION 's/O new/O leadership/O will/O embrace/O more/O openness/O and/O take/O a/O new/O approach/O to/O minority/O issues/O ./O 
