China/LOCATION 's/O ruling/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION meets/O this/O week/O to/O discuss/O how/O to/O rule/O the/O country/O in/O accordance/O with/O the/O law/O ./O 
But/O experts/O do/O n't/O expect/O a/O substantial/O reform/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O judiciary/O ./O 
Early/O last/O week/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O southwestern/O Yunnan/LOCATION Province/LOCATION ,/O an/O angry/O group/O of/O villagers/O stormed/O a/O construction/O site/O and/O attacked/O the/O workers/O ./O 
By/O the/O time/O police/O used/O batons/O and/O tear/O gas/O to/O bring/O the/O crowd/O under/O control/O ,/O two/O villagers/O and/O six/O workers/O had/O been/O killed/O ;/O some/O of/O the/O workers/O had/O been/O burned/O to/O death/O by/O villagers/O ./O 
In/O total/O ,/O eighteen/O were/O injured/O ./O 
According/O to/O local/O media/O reports/O ,/O residents/O had/O complained/O that/O they/O had/O not/O been/O adequately/O compensated/O for/O their/O land/O ,/O which/O had/O been/O appropriated/O for/O the/O construction/O project/O ./O 
There/O are/O often/O such/O conflicts/O over/O land/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O even/O though/O in/O most/O instances/O people/O are/O well/O compensated/O ./O 
However/O ,/O many/O local/O governments/O are/O corrupt/O ,/O and/O the/O money/O often/O ends/O up/O in/O the/O wrong/O hands/O ./O 
Since/O local/O governments/O are/O able/O to/O easily/O influence/O the/O justice/O system/O ,/O there/O is/O a/O lack/O of/O confidence/O in/O the/O courts/O and/O people/O thus/O lack/O an/O effective/O means/O to/O resolve/O such/O conflicts/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O disputes/O often/O end/O in/O violence/O ./O 
But/O that/O could/O change/O ./O 
On/O Monday/O ,/O the/O elite/O Central/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION will/O kick/O off/O a/O key/O three-day/O meeting/O whose/O focus/O is/O on/O the/O country/O 's/O legal/O system/O ./O 
Observers/O speculate/O that/O judicial/O reforms/O could/O limit/O the/O influence/O of/O local/O governments/O on/O the/O legal/O system/O ./O 
``/O The/O government/O 's/O motivation/O for/O reform/O are/O the/O increasing/O conflicts/O taking/O place/O all/O over/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O Zhu/PERSON Yi/PERSON ,/O a/O research/O associate/O at/O the/O Mercator/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O Merics/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O 
``/O Former/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ,/O and/O his/O successor/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O have/O said/O that/O if/O reform/O measures/O are/O n't/O taken/O ,/O it/O could/O mean/O an/O end/O of/O their/O party/O ./O ''/O 
Zhu/PERSON told/O DW/O that/O the/O government/O was/O aware/O of/O the/O problem/O ./O 
``/O The/O question/O is/O :/O What/O measures/O will/O eventually/O be/O introduced/O to/O change/O arbitrariness/O and/O abuse/O of/O power/O at/O the/O local/O level/O ?/O ''/O 
According/O to/O Human/O Rights/O Watch/O ,/O between/O 300/O to/O 500/O protests/O take/O place/O in/O China/LOCATION every/O day/O ./O 
According/O to/O Zhu/PERSON ,/O these/O increasing/O conflicts/O are/O linked/O with/O the/O rise/O of/O private/O property/O and/O with/O China/LOCATION 's/O increasing/O globalization/O processes/O ./O 
``/O The/O legal/O consciousness/O of/O the/O Chinese/O population/O is/O increasing/O ,/O ''/O Zhu/PERSON said/O ,/O ``/O and/O people/O want/O to/O make/O use/O of/O justice/O and/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O to/O protect/O private/O rights/O from/O the/O state/O ./O ''/O 
So/O far/O ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION has/O not/O provided/O any/O details/O of/O any/O possible/O judicial/O reform/O ./O 
Official/O statements/O have/O merely/O mentioned/O that/O the/O ``/O rule/O of/O law/O ''/O would/O be/O discussed/O at/O the/O fourth/O plenum/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O country/O 's/O official/O news/O agency/O ,/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O principle/O of/O ``/O rule/O of/O law/O ''/O is/O ``/O a/O must/O if/O the/O country/O is/O to/O achieve/O economic/O development/O ,/O proper/O governance/O ,/O cultural/O flowering/O and/O a/O clean/O environment/O ./O ''/O 
However/O ,/O Zhang/PERSON Ming/PERSON ,/O a/O legal/O scholar/O at/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O emphasizes/O that/O the/O term/O ``/O rule/O of/O law/O ''/O should/O not/O be/O equated/O with/O the/O Western/O legal/O concept/O ./O 
``/O The/O rule/O of/O law/O is/O concerned/O with/O making/O sure/O the/O government/O follows/O the/O law/O ./O 
But/O in/O the/O Chinese/O tradition/O ,/O it/O was/O always/O the/O case/O that/O the/O judiciary/O mainly/O serves/O to/O control/O the/O people/O ,/O ''/O said/O Zhang/PERSON ,/O adding/O that/O judicial/O reform/O will/O not/O bring/O about/O such/O a/O drastic/O change/O ./O 
``/O There/O 's/O still/O a/O long/O way/O to/O go/O to/O change/O that/O ./O ''/O 
Zhu/PERSON Yi/PERSON of/PERSON Mercis/PERSON agrees/O ./O 
``/O It/O 's/O not/O about/O separation/O of/O powers/O ,/O it/O 's/O not/O about/O constitutional/O law/O ./O 
The/O goal/O is/O to/O strengthen/O the/O judiciary/O as/O an/O instrument/O of/O domination/O ./O ''/O 
Proof/O of/O this/O can/O be/O seen/O in/O numerous/O legal/O proceedings/O ,/O especially/O those/O against/O government/O opponents/O ./O 
Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O winner/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON was/O sentenced/O in/O 2009/O for/O alleged/O ``/O subversion/O of/O state/O power/O ''/O to/O 11/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O 
More/O recently/O ,/O the/O Uighur/O rights/O activist/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON was/O ./O 
Both/O trials/O drew/O international/O criticism/O ./O 
Zhu/PERSON believes/O that/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O possible/O judicial/O reform/O ,/O the/O political/O elite/O will/O likely/O only/O focus/O on/O technical/O measures/O ./O 
These/O measures/O could/O bring/O some/O improvements/O in/O certain/O areas/O ,/O ``/O but/O this/O wo/O n't/O be/O a/O substantial/O reform/O of/O the/O judiciary/O ./O ''/O 
