A/O US-based/O rights/O group/O says/O China/LOCATION executed/O 2,400/O convicts/O in/O 2013/O ,/O an/O annual/O toll/O that/O has/O declined/O over/O the/O past/O decade/O ./O 
China/LOCATION executes/O more/O people/O than/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O world/O combined/O ,/O according/O to/O estimates/O ./O 
The/O 2,400/O executions/O represented/O a/O 20/O percent/O drop/O in/O Chinese/O prisoner/O executions/O from/O 2012/O ,/O and/O made/O up/O only/O a/O fraction/O of/O the/O 12,000/O killings/O in/O 2002/O ,/O a/O report/O by/O the/O Dui/ORGANIZATION Hua/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION said/O on/O Tuesday/O ./O 
The/O San/O Francisco-based/O group/O ,/O which/O campaigns/O for/O prisoner/O rights/O and/O the/O reform/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O justice/O system/O ,/O said/O it/O had/O obtained/O the/O data/O from/O ``/O a/O judicial/O official/O with/O access/O to/O the/O number/O of/O executions/O carried/O out/O each/O year/O ./O ''/O 
Last/O year/O 's/O cases/O included/O the/O unusual/O live/O broadcast/O by/O state-run/O CCTV/O of/O four/O accused/O being/O led/O in/O -LRB-/O pictured/O -RRB-/O before/O execution/O in/O southwestern/O Yunnan/LOCATION province/LOCATION 's/O capital/O of/O Kunming/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION does/O not/O officially/O release/O figures/O on/O executions/O ,/O but/O is/O thought/O to/O have/O than/O all/O other/O countries/O put/O together/O with/O a/O record/O of/O 24,000/O in/O 1982/O ,/O according/O to/O Dui/PERSON Hua/PERSON ./O 
Rights/O group/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O releases/O an/O annual/O report/O on/O capital/O punishment/O ,/O excludes/O China/LOCATION from/O its/O tally/O due/O to/O lack/O of/O reliable/O information/O ,/O but/O in/O 2013/O it/O put/O the/O total/O number/O of/O executions/O for/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O world/O ,/O put/O at/O 778/O in/O 22/O countries/O ./O 
Despite/O the/O downward/O trend/O since/O 2002/O ,/O Dui/PERSON Hua/PERSON acknowledged/O the/O decline/O was/O likely/O to/O be/O ``/O offset/O ''/O this/O year/O ,/O amid/O a/O countrywide/O anti-corruption/O campaign/O and/O a/O in/O the/O largely/O Muslim/O northwestern/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Hundreds/O of/O people/O over/O a/O series/O of/O attacks/O in/O the/O restive/O region/O ./O 
Last/O week/O a/O court/O condemned/O 12/O people/O to/O death/O in/O connection/O with/O clashes/O in/O July/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O ruling/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION keeps/O tight/O control/O over/O the/O country/O 's/O legal/O system/O ,/O and/O courts/O have/O a/O near-100/O percent/O conviction/O rate/O in/O criminal/O cases/O ./O 
In/O 2007/O ,/O the/O power/O to/O review/O death/O sentences/O was/O handed/O over/O to/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION -/O a/O move/O that/O has/O contributed/O to/O ``/O far/O fewer/O ''/O executions/O ,/O according/O to/O Dui/PERSON Hua/PERSON ./O 
In/O examining/O cases/O in/O 2013/O ,/O the/O top/O court/O sent/O around/O 39/O percent/O of/O death/O sentences/O back/O to/O provincial/O courts/O with/O a/O request/O for/O further/O evidence/O ,/O the/O group/O said/O ./O 
The/O use/O of/O force/O to/O extract/O confessions/O is/O still/O commonplace/O ./O 
There/O have/O been/O instances/O of/O wrongful/O conviction/O ,/O and/O China/LOCATION has/O occasionally/O exonerated/O wrongfully/O executed/O convicts/O after/O others/O claimed/O responsibility/O for/O the/O crimes/O ,/O or/O in/O some/O cases/O because/O the/O supposed/O murder/O victim/O was/O found/O alive/O ./O 
In/O June/O ,/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION handed/O down/O a/O landmark/O decision/O ,/O overturning/O the/O death/O sentence/O for/O Li/PERSON Yan/PERSON ,/O who/O had/O been/O convicted/O in/O 2011/O for/O killing/O her/O abusive/O husband/O after/O suffering/O months/O of/O torture/O at/O his/O hands/O ./O 
On/O October/O 10/O ,/O the/O international/O day/O for/O the/O abolition/O of/O the/O death/O penalty/O ,/O an/O unprecedented/O worldwide/O abolition/O call/O was/O issued/O by/O the/O foreign/O ministers/O of/O 12/O nations/O ,/O including/O Switzerland/LOCATION ,/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O Mongolia/LOCATION and/O the/O Philippines/LOCATION ./O 
Modern/O justice/O systems/O must/O strive/O for/O more/O than/O just/O revenge/O ,/O they/O said/O ./O 
State-ordered/O killings/O led/O only/O to/O more/O hatred/O and/O violence/O ./O 
All/O parties/O in/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O Bundestag/ORGANIZATION parliament/O also/O voted/O on/O the/O same/O day/O for/O a/O similar/O worldwide/O abolition/O call/O ,/O drafted/O by/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON 's/O governing/O conservatives/O ./O 
Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION highlighted/O executions/O of/O persons/O with/O psychological/O handicaps/O ,/O saying/O this/O breached/O fundamental/O human/O rights/O ./O 
nm/ipj/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O dpa/O ,/O epd/O ,/O KNA/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 
