As/O the/O 25th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O crackdown/O on/O student-led/O protests/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION approaches/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O stepped/O up/O efforts/O to/O silence/O dissent/O by/O detaining/O lawyers/O ,/O activists/O and/O journalists/O ./O 
The/O Beijing-based/O activist/O has/O been/O under/O house/O arrest/O since/O January/O 17/O ./O 
On/O that/O same/O day/O nine/O years/O ago/O ,/O the/O then/O General/O Secretary/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O Zhao/PERSON Ziyang/PERSON ,/O was/O forced/O to/O step/O down/O for/O his/O involvement/O in/O the/O violent/O crackdown/O of/O student/O protests/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Ever/O since/O I/O laid/O flowers/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION in/O 2004/O for/O the/O victims/O of/O the/O massacre/O ,/O I/O have/O been/O either/O detained/O or/O put/O under/O house/O arrest/O every/O year/O ,/O ''/O Hu/PERSON adds/O ./O 
But/O Hu/PERSON is/O not/O the/O only/O one/O facing/O trouble/O with/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O :/O In/O recent/O weeks/O ,/O a/O number/O of/O dissidents/O and/O activists/O have/O been/O either/O arrested/O or/O detained/O ./O 
The/O latest/O case/O reported/O by/O the/O Western/O media/O is/O the/O arrest/O of/O 62-year-old/O blogger/O Xiang/PERSON Nanfu/PERSON accused/O of/O spreading/O ``/O false/O claims/O ''/O on/O the/O Boxun/O website/O ./O 
Xiang/PERSON 's/O confession/O was/O aired/O on/O state/O television/O ./O 
On/O May/O 8/O ,/O Chinese/O officials/O paraded/O journalist/O Gao/PERSON Yu/PERSON on/O TV/O in/O a/O similar/O way/O ./O 
The/O 70-year-old/O ,/O who/O was/O a/O regular/O contributor/O to/O DW/O ,/O was/O arrested/O on/O charges/O of/O ``/O leaking/O state/O secrets/O ./O ''/O 
That/O same/O week/O Hong/LOCATION Kong-based/LOCATION publisher/O ,/O Yao/PERSON Wentian/PERSON ,/O was/O sentenced/O to/O 10/O years/O in/O prison/O on/O ``/O smuggling/O ''/O charges/O ./O 
The/O 73-year-old/O wanted/O to/O publish/O a/O critical/O book/O about/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON titled/O ``/O China/LOCATION 's/O godfather/O ,/O ''/O written/O by/O Yu/PERSON Jie/PERSON ,/O an/O author/O in/O exile/O ./O 
Two/O days/O earlier/O ,/O prominent/O civil/O rights/O lawyer/O ,/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON ,/O and/O other/O Chinese/O intellectuals/O were/O arrested/O for/O attending/O a/O private/O memorial/O service/O for/O the/O victims/O of/O the/O 1989/O riots/O ./O 
Five/O years/O ago/O ,/O Teng/PERSON Biao/PERSON ,/O one/O of/O the/O most/O prominent/O Chinese/O civil/O rights/O lawyers/O ,/O participated/O in/O a/O similar/O ceremony/O ./O 
``/O I/O was/O banned/O from/O teaching/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Politics/ORGANIZATION and/O Law/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O but/O nothing/O else/O happened/O ,/O ''/O Teng/PERSON told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O But/O many/O arrests/O this/O year/O are/O extraordinary/O and/O shocking/O ./O 
They/O are/O aimed/O at/O intimidating/O the/O Chinese/O people/O ./O 
The/O arrests/O of/O the/O prominent/O figures/O show/O the/O CPC/ORGANIZATION does/O n't/O care/O much/O about/O international/O pressure/O and/O criticism/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O it/O demonstrates/O that/O the/O government/O is/O apprehensive/O of/O the/O situation/O prior/O to/O the/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION anniversary/O on/O June/O 4/O ,/O which/O it/O fears/O might/O get/O out/O of/O control/O ,/O ''/O Teng/PERSON added/O ./O 
Hu/PERSON Jia/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O also/O one/O of/O the/O organizers/O of/O the/O ``/O Back/O to/O Tiananmen/O ''/O event/O ,/O believes/O the/O suppress/O wants/O to/O suppress/O any/O sign/O of/O a/O commemoration/O of/O the/O anniversary/O ./O 
The/O organizers/O have/O asked/O people/O to/O wear/O black/O T/O -/O shirts/O and/O gather/O at/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Hu/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O making/O use/O of/O the/O Internet/O to/O mobilize/O citizens/O ,/O believes/O online/O activities/O are/O likely/O to/O be/O used/O as/O evidence/O of/O his/O ``/O crimes/O ./O ''/O 
Police/O have/O beefed/O up/O security/O measures/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION following/O a/O series/O of/O deadly/O attacks/O by/O alleged/O Uighur/O extremists/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O other/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
In/O recent/O weeks/O ,/O the/O security/O forces/O have/O conducted/O several/O ``/O anti-terror/O ''/O exercises/O and/O hundreds/O of/O armed/O vehicles/O have/O been/O deployed/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O various/O major/O intersections/O ./O 
``/O After/O the/O violent/O incidents/O ,/O the/O government/O can/O justify/O these/O security/O measures/O ,/O ''/O said/O Hu/PERSON Jia/PERSON ./O 
