A/O Chinese/O court/O has/O given/O prominent/O human/O rights/O lawyer/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON a/O suspended/O three-year/O sentence/O for/O making/O comments/O critical/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O ruling/O will/O likely/O keep/O him/O out/O of/O prison/O for/O now/O ./O 
A/O Beijing/LOCATION court/O found/O Pu/PERSON guilty/O of/O ``/O inciting/O ethnic/O hatred/O ''/O and/O ``/O picking/O quarrels/O and/O provoking/O trouble/O ''/O for/O over/O China/LOCATION 's/O ethnic/O policies/O and/O criticism/O of/O officials/O ./O 
Pu/O has/O been/O a/O and/O represented/O dissident/O artist/O Ai/O Weiwei/O ./O 
He/O has/O also/O represented/O labor/O camp/O victims/O and/O criticized/O government/O policies/O over/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O the/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O ./O 
``/O Today/O 's/O verdict/O also/O means/O ,/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON could/O not/O serve/O as/O a/O practicing/O lawyer/O ./O 
He/O ca/O n't/O provide/O legal/O services/O or/O assistance/O as/O a/O lawyer/O ,/O ''/O Shang/PERSON Baojun/PERSON ,/O one/O of/O Pu/PERSON 's/O lawyers/O ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O However/O ,/O the/O verdict/O was/O still/O a/O relief/O to/O us/O ./O 
At/O least/O ,/O it/O means/O he/O can/O be/O released/O quite/O soon/O after/O spending/O almost/O 19/O months/O in/O jail/O ,/O ''/O explained/O Shang/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O worried/O about/O the/O working/O environment/O of/O Chinese/O lawers/O after/O Pu/PERSON 's/O case/O ./O 
His/O supporters/O were/O relieved/O that/O the/O suspended/O sentence/O likely/O means/O the/O human/O rights/O lawyer/O will/O not/O have/O to/O spend/O time/O in/O prison/O ,/O but/O expressed/O outrage/O over/O the/O guilty/O verdict/O and/O a/O sentence/O that/O effectively/O silences/O him/O for/O the/O near/O future/O ./O 
Under/O the/O three-year/O sentence/O ,/O Pu/O will/O be/O monitored/O by/O police/O and/O can/O only/O leave/O Beijing/LOCATION with/O permission/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION Agency/ORGANIZATION ,/O Pu/PERSON decided/O not/O to/O lodge/O an/O appeal/O against/O the/O court/O 's/O decision/O ./O 
``/O Clearly/O it/O is/O positive/O that/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON is/O unlikely/O to/O spend/O another/O night/O in/O jail/O ,/O yet/O that/O can/O not/O hide/O the/O gross/O injustice/O against/O him/O ,/O ''/O said/O William/PERSON Nee/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION researcher/O at/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O He/O is/O no/O criminal/O and/O this/O guilty/O verdict/O effectively/O shackles/O one/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O bravest/O champions/O of/O human/O rights/O from/O practicing/O law/O ./O ''/O 
Pu/O was/O arrested/O in/O May/O 2014/O as/O part/O of/O a/O wider/O nationwide/O crackdown/O on/O dissidents/O after/O attending/O a/O meeting/O to/O discuss/O The/O case/O against/O him/O related/O to/O seven/O social/O media/O posts/O between/O 2011/O and/O 2014/O in/O what/O critics/O argue/O is/O a/O politically/O motivated/O attack/O on/O rights/O defenders/O ./O 
Pu/O 's/O case/O has/O drawn/O the/O attention/O of/O rights/O groups/O and/O foreign/O governments/O ,/O several/O of/O which/O said/O they/O were/O not/O allowed/O into/O the/O courtroom/O because/O officials/O said/O it/O was/O overcrowded/O ./O 
cw/jil/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O dpa/O -RRB-/O 
