Chinese/O authorities/O have/O reportedly/O ordered/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION shopkeepers/O in/O a/O Xinjiang/LOCATION village/O to/O sell/O alcohol/O and/O cigarettes/O in/O a/O bid/O to/O undermine/O Islam/ORGANIZATION 's/O hold/O on/O local/O residents/O ./O 
But/O will/O this/O work/O ?/O 
DW/O speaks/O to/O James/PERSON Millward/PERSON ./O 
Authorities/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O have/O ordered/O shop/O owners/O and/O restaurateurs/O in/O a/O mainly/O Muslim/O Uighur/O village/O to/O sell/O alcohol/O and/O cigarettes/O or/O face/O closure/O of/O their/O establishments/O ,/O despite/O a/O public/O backlash/O against/O the/O products/O discouraged/O by/O followers/O of/O Islam/ORGANIZATION ,/O an/O official/O source/O was/O quoted/O by/O -LRB-/O RFA/O -RRB-/O as/O saying/O ./O 
In/O addition/O to/O directing/O owners/O to/O create/O ``/O eye-catching/O displays/O ''/O to/O promote/O the/O products/O ,/O the/O April/O 29/O announcement/O stated/O that/O ``/O anybody/O who/O neglects/O this/O notice/O and/O fails/O to/O act/O will/O see/O their/O shops/O sealed/O off/O ,/O their/O business/O suspended/O ,/O and/O legal/O action/O pursued/O against/O them/O ,/O ''/O said/O the/O report/O ./O 
It/O comes/O after/O a/O series/O of/O violent/O episodes/O at/O transport/O hubs/O throughout/O China/LOCATION last/O year/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION blamed/O on/O Islamists/O and/O separatists/O from/O the/O restive/O region/O where/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O -LRB-/O also/O spelled/O Uyghur/O -RRB-/O make/O up/O around/O 45/O percent/O of/O the/O population/O ./O 
Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON has/O vowed/O to/O follow/O a/O ``/O strike-first/O approach/O against/O terrorists/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O ''/O stating/O that/O long-term/O stability/O was/O ``/O vital/O to/O the/O whole/O country/O 's/O reform/O ./O ''/O 
In/O a/O DW/O interview/O ,/O China/LOCATION expert/O and/O historian/O James/PERSON Millward/PERSON says/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policies/O targeting/O peaceful/O aspects/O of/O Islamic/O practice/O are/O counter-productive/O ,/O not/O only/O because/O they/O anger/O the/O broad/O population/O of/O Uighurs/O ,/O but/O also/O potentially/O undermine/O China/LOCATION 's/O vaunted/O new/O foreign/O policy/O initiative/O ,/O the/O New/O Silk/O Road/O Economic/O Belt/O ,/O which/O involves/O enhanced/O economic/O and/O diplomatic/O relations/O with/O South/O and/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION and/O East/LOCATION Africa/LOCATION -/O regions/O comprised/O of/O several/O Muslim-majority/LOCATION nations/O ./O 
James/PERSON Millward/PERSON :/O The/O RFA/ORGANIZATION report/O includes/O a/O document/O in/O Uighur/O that/O tells/O supermarkets/O and/O restaurants/O in/O Aktash/LOCATION village/LOCATION ,/O Laskuy/LOCATION township/O of/O the/O region/O around/O the/O city/O of/O Hotan/LOCATION -LRB-/O also/O spelled/O Hetian/LOCATION or/O Khotan/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O that/O they/O are/O required/O to/O sell/O at/O least/O five/O brands/O each/O of/O cigarettes/O and/O alcoholic/O beverages/O ./O 
This/O document/O seems/O to/O have/O been/O photographed/O and/O put/O out/O on/O Twitter/O by/O someone/O in/O the/O area/O ./O 
RFA/ORGANIZATION has/O been/O able/O to/O get/O confirmation/O from/O a/O local/O party/O secretary/O that/O the/O document/O is/O real/O and/O that/O such/O a/O policy/O has/O been/O implemented/O in/O this/O small/O area/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
RFA/ORGANIZATION reports/O that/O the/O local/O party/O secretary/O himself/O said/O -/O remarkably/O -/O that/O the/O explicit/O purpose/O of/O the/O alcohol/O //O tobacco/O policy/O is/O to/O weaken/O religion/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
This/O fits/O with/O what/O seems/O to/O be/O the/O general/O thrust/O of/O a/O range/O of/O rules/O and/O prohibitions/O introduced/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION over/O recent/O years/O :/O against/O full/O veils/O and/O sometimes/O even/O headscarves/O on/O women/O ;/O against/O beards/O on/O younger/O men/O ;/O against/O ``/O Islamic/O ''/O clothing/O or/O religious/O symbols/O on/O clothing/O ;/O against/O fasting/O during/O Ramadan/O for/O students/O and/O government/O employees/O ;/O and/O of/O course/O long-term/O and/O general/O prohibitions/O on/O religious/O meetings/O ,/O prayer/O meetings/O or/O other/O ceremonies/O not/O sanctioned/O and/O controlled/O by/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
These/O policies/O seem/O to/O be/O somewhat/O inconsistently/O imposed/O in/O different/O parts/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O as/O the/O local/O nature/O of/O these/O alcohol/O and/O tobacco/O rules/O show/O ./O 
This/O may/O be/O because/O of/O different/O ways/O local/O officials/O interpret/O a/O broader/O Party/ORGANIZATION directive/O -/O sometimes/O excessively/O -/O or/O may/O represent/O a/O program/O of/O first/O experimenting/O in/O some/O places/O with/O particular/O policies/O before/O applying/O them/O ,/O or/O not/O ,/O to/O the/O region/O as/O a/O whole/O ./O 
Though/O I/O personally/O have/O not/O seen/O an/O explicit/O Chinese/O official/O statement/O to/O this/O effect/O ,/O it/O seems/O clear/O that/O these/O policies/O about/O customs/O associated/O with/O Islam/ORGANIZATION are/O related/O to/O Party/ORGANIZATION and/O Government/O efforts/O to/O counter/O what/O they/O see/O as/O increasing/O influence/O by/O Jihadi/O or/O violent/O Islamist/O ideology/O from/O outside/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION ./O 
There/O is/O independent/O evidence/O that/O such/O propaganda/O in/O Uighur/O language/O media/O has/O become/O increasingly/O available/O in/O recent/O years/O ./O 
There/O have/O been/O a/O few/O prominent/O incidents/O of/O random/O attacks/O on/O civilians/O by/O Uighurs/O with/O apparent/O political/O purpose/O -/O i.e./O terrorist/O attacks/O -/O in/O recent/O years/O ./O 
However/O ,/O there/O have/O also/O been/O many/O other/O kinds/O of/O violent/O incidents/O ,/O especially/O confrontations/O of/O police/O and/O Uighur/O civilians/O ,/O which/O Chinese/O media/O and/O authorities/O call/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O but/O many/O outside/O of/O China/LOCATION might/O disagree/O as/O to/O their/O sources/O and/O nature/O ./O 
In/O addition/O to/O security/O measures/O ,/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION has/O ordered/O ,/O and/O the/O Xinjiang/LOCATION authorities/O are/O implementing/O ,/O a/O raft/O of/O cultural/O measures/O directed/O at/O religious/O practice/O ,/O no/O doubt/O in/O the/O belief/O that/O such/O measures/O can/O reduce/O Uighur/O people/O 's/O religiosity/O and/O thus/O dampen/O their/O discontent/O with/O Chinese/O government/O and/O Party/ORGANIZATION rule/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
It/O is/O difficult/O for/O an/O outsider/O without/O direct/O access/O to/O Xinjiang/LOCATION to/O comment/O on/O the/O impact/O of/O either/O ``/O strike/O hard/O ''/O security/O measures/O or/O the/O policies/O against/O ``/O Islamic/O ''/O customs/O ./O 
Certainly/O I/O and/O many/O other/O observers/O outside/O China/LOCATION -/O and/O some/O in/O China/LOCATION -/O feel/O that/O policies/O targeting/O peaceful/O aspects/O of/O Islamic/O practice/O such/O as/O fasts/O ,/O beards/O ,/O veils/O ,/O food/O taboos/O etc/O ,/O are/O counter-productive/O because/O they/O will/O anger/O the/O broad/O population/O of/O Uighurs/O ,/O the/O vast/O majority/O of/O whom/O are/O not/O engaged/O in/O and/O do/O n't/O support/O terrorism/O or/O even/O political/O Islam/O ./O 
These/O policies/O make/O it/O easier/O for/O critics/O -/O such/O as/O al/O Qaeda/O or/O ``/O Islamic/O State/O ''/O -/O to/O say/O that/O the/O Chinese/O state/O and/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION are/O anti-Islam/O ,/O and/O this/O could/O even/O help/O with/O such/O groups/O '/O recruiting/O efforts/O ./O 
Other/O countries/O have/O tried/O policies/O that/O target/O Islamic/O symbols/O -/O one/O thinks/O of/O France/LOCATION 's/O bans/O on/O the/O veil/O for/O Muslim/O women/O ,/O for/O example/O -/O and/O few/O would/O see/O those/O policies/O as/O successes/O ,/O given/O continually/O worsening/O tensions/O in/O those/O countries/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O policies/O targeting/O Islamic/O customs/O seem/O to/O reflect/O a/O misdiagnosis/O of/O the/O problem/O of/O Uighur/O discontent/O and/O separatism/O as/O entirely/O due/O to/O outside/O ideology/O sneaking/O in/O ,/O like/O a/O contagion/O ./O 
It/O is/O clear/O to/O many/O outside/O observers/O ,/O and/O stated/O resoundingly/O by/O Uighur/O exile/O groups/O ,/O that/O extremist/O religion/O is/O only/O one/O element/O in/O Uighur/O discontent/O ./O 
Other/O causes/O are/O historical/O ,/O relating/O to/O Xinjiang/LOCATION 's/O and/O the/O Uighurs/O '/O status/O in/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION -LRB-/O PRC/LOCATION -RRB-/O ;/O or/O they/O are/O ethno-nationalist/O ,/O arising/O from/O a/O sense/O of/O Uighur/O identity/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION has/O not/O been/O able/O to/O convincingly/O incorporate/O beneath/O an/O umbrella/O Chinese/O identity/O ;/O or/O they/O are/O owing/O to/O discontent/O with/O real/O and/O perceived/O anti-Uighur/O discrimination/O by/O government/O and/O businesses/O that/O makes/O economic/O development/O efforts/O seem/O to/O help/O only/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
Other/O reasons/O include/O the/O discontent/O with/O recent/O or/O current/O policies/O such/O as/O increased/O Han/O migration/O into/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O the/O tearing/O down/O of/O old/O and/O treasured/O Uighur/O architecture/O ,/O the/O environmental/O legacies/O of/O nuclear/O testing/O in/O the/O near-by/O Lop/O Nor/O desert/O ,/O excessive/O water/O use/O that/O has/O exhausted/O water/O tables/O ,/O continued/O poverty/O and/O under-development/O of/O Uighur/O rural/O areas/O -/O and/O so/O on/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION does/O try/O to/O address/O some/O of/O these/O concerns/O ,/O especially/O economic/O ones/O ./O 
However/O ,/O without/O direct/O polling/O of/O Uighur/O people/O we/O do/O n't/O know/O with/O any/O precision/O the/O extent/O of/O their/O good/O -/O or/O ill-will/O to/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION after/O decades/O of/O economic/O development/O and/O the/O recent/O campaign/O against/O Islamic/O customs/O ./O 
My/O guess/O is/O that/O ham-fisted/O in-your-face/O policies/O ,/O such/O as/O requiring/O devout/O Muslims/O to/O sell/O alcohol/O when/O they/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O ,/O or/O de-veiling/O women/O ,/O would/O tend/O to/O dissipate/O whatever/O good/O will/O the/O Chinese/O state/O and/O Party/ORGANIZATION earn/O from/O raising/O Uighurs/O '/O standards/O of/O living/O ./O 
Bans/O on/O religious/O expression/O ,/O especially/O the/O gratuitously/O insulting/O bans/O on/O beards/O ,/O veils/O ,/O fasting/O ,/O and/O the/O requirement/O to/O sell/O alcohol/O ,/O also/O hurt/O China/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O policy/O efforts/O ,/O not/O only/O attracting/O criticism/O from/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O EU/ORGANIZATION ,/O but/O potentially/O undermining/O China/LOCATION 's/O vaunted/O new/O foreign/O initiative/O ,/O the/O New/O Silk/O Road/O Economic/O Belt/O ,/O which/O involves/O enhanced/O economic/O and/O diplomatic/O relations/O with/O South/O and/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION and/O East/LOCATION Africa/LOCATION ./O 
Most/O of/O the/O countries/O in/O these/O regions/O have/O large/O Muslim/O populations/O or/O are/O explicit/O Islamic/O states/O themselves/O ./O 
China/LOCATION can/O not/O call/O Islamic/O customs/O ``/O evil/O ''/O at/O home/O ,/O and/O not/O expect/O word/O to/O get/O out/O ./O 
Such/O rules/O erode/O China/LOCATION 's/O soft/O power/O potential/O in/O Islamic/O lands/O ./O 
It/O is/O important/O to/O distinguish/O among/O these/O violent/O incidents/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O vehicular/O assault/O by/O a/O family/O in/O Tian/PERSON `/O anmen/O square/O ,/O an/O attack/O on/O the/O Kunming/LOCATION railway/O station/O ,/O an/O attack/O on/O the/O Urumqi/LOCATION railway/O station/O ,/O and/O a/O bombing/O and/O vehicular/O assault/O in/O an/O Urumqi/LOCATION market/O ./O 
These/O appalling/O incidents/O fit/O a/O model/O that/O resembles/O in/O some/O ways/O terrorist/O acts/O by/O Islamist/O groups/O outside/O of/O China/LOCATION -/O and/O as/O such/O ,/O they/O were/O an/O alarming/O new/O development/O starting/O in/O the/O fall/O of/O 2013/O ./O 
There/O has/O also/O been/O an/O on-going/O series/O of/O clashes/O between/O Uighur/O citizens/O and/O police/O or/O military/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O apparently/O sparked/O by/O local/O issues/O ./O 
In/O some/O of/O the/O most/O serious/O of/O these/O ,/O Uighur/O villages/O have/O taken/O up/O agricultural/O tools/O as/O weapons/O ,/O so/O they/O are/O technically/O ``/O armed/O ''/O attacks/O ./O 
But/O the/O high/O casualty/O numbers/O result/O from/O Chinese/O authorities/O '/O use/O of/O guns/O against/O demonstrators/O and/O rioters/O ./O 
It/O is/O worth/O noting/O that/O in/O local/O areas/O of/O southern/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O police/O forces/O and/O even/O local/O chiefs/O are/O often/O Uighurs/O themselves/O ,/O though/O higher/O responsible/O officials/O are/O Han/O ./O 
Thus/O there/O are/O multiple/O sources/O behind/O the/O violence/O ./O 
Extremist/O and/O violent/O ideology/O seems/O to/O have/O inspired/O a/O small/O number/O of/O people/O to/O commit/O terrorist/O acts/O ./O 
A/O larger/O number/O of/O people/O have/O come/O into/O conflict/O with/O the/O authorities/O for/O reasons/O that/O are/O not/O always/O clear/O ,/O but/O may/O involve/O discontent/O with/O those/O authorities/O ,/O with/O the/O implementation/O of/O prohibitions/O on/O Islamic/O customs/O ,/O possibly/O with/O corruption/O and/O collusion/O between/O authorities/O and/O business/O interests/O ./O 
There/O are/O ,/O by/O Chinese/O official/O admission/O ,/O tens/O of/O thousands/O of/O disturbances/O across/O China/LOCATION every/O year/O ,/O including/O demonstrations/O ,/O riots/O ,/O attacks/O on/O authorities/O ,/O kidnappings/O of/O government/O or/O business/O leaders/O ,/O and/O expulsions/O of/O authorities/O from/O whole/O townships/O ./O 
This/O has/O become/O a/O standard/O means/O by/O which/O people/O expose/O the/O malfeasance/O of/O local/O officials/O and/O get/O the/O attention/O of/O the/O central/O government/O to/O address/O the/O problems/O ./O 
For/O Uighurs/O and/O Tibetans/O ,/O however/O ,/O this/O safety/O valve/O is/O unavailable/O :/O their/O demonstrations/O are/O met/O with/O deadly/O force/O ,/O and/O not/O by/O delegations/O of/O sympathetic/O central/O government/O officials/O ./O 
There/O does/O not/O seem/O to/O have/O been/O a/O terrorist/O attack/O for/O a/O year/O or/O so/O ,/O and/O this/O is/O a/O good/O thing/O ./O 
But/O the/O question/O of/O whether/O any/O of/O the/O two/O sides/O are/O willing/O to/O compromise/O raises/O an/O issue/O :/O there/O are/O not/O two/O ``/O sides/O ''/O in/O this/O ./O 
Though/O there/O are/O exile/O Uighur/O groups/O ,/O they/O do/O not/O really/O speak/O for/O the/O Uighur/O people/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O PRC/LOCATION certainly/O does/O not/O speak/O with/O them/O ./O 
There/O is/O no/O organization/O behind/O the/O anti-state/O violence/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O no/O one/O that/O the/O Chinese/O ``/O side/O ''/O could/O talk/O to/O ./O 
When/O incidents/O arise/O ,/O it/O would/O be/O good/O to/O see/O more/O discussion/O and/O less/O repression/O between/O local/O ,/O Xinjiang/LOCATION regional/O and/O national/O authorities/O ,/O on/O the/O one/O hand/O ,/O and/O local/O people/O with/O grievances/O on/O the/O other/O ./O 
Currently/O ,/O the/O one-size-fits-all/O response/O to/O any/O unrest/O is/O that/O it/O is/O terrorism/O ,/O inspired/O by/O evil/O ideology/O from/O outside/O ,/O and/O is/O to/O be/O put/O down/O with/O force/O ./O 
This/O blanket/O explanation/O potentially/O allows/O local/O officials/O to/O get/O away/O with/O all/O sorts/O of/O things/O ,/O and/O blame/O popular/O unrest/O on/O terrorists/O ./O 
I/O wonder/O if/O the/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O really/O good/O information/O about/O what/O happens/O at/O the/O local/O level/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
It/O certainly/O lacks/O that/O in/O many/O places/O in/O the/O rest/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O admits/O that/O corruption/O is/O a/O widespread/O problem/O ./O 
Is/O there/O no/O corruption/O or/O mis-governance/O causing/O trouble/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O just/O as/O elsewhere/O in/O China/LOCATION ?/O ''/O 
./O ''/O 
