Beijing/LOCATION has/O approved/O a/O new/O counterterrorism/O law/O aimed/O primarily/O at/O controlling/O ethnic/O unrest/O domestically/O ./O 
But/O the/O law/O has/O drawn/O criticism/O from/O foreign/O governments/O who/O argue/O it/O violates/O human/O rights/O ./O 
The/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION approved/O its/O first/O anti-terrorism/O law/O on/O Sunday/O ,/O despite/O international/O criticism/O that/O it/O threatens/O freedom/O of/O speech/O and/O intellectual/O property/O ./O 
On/O the/O surface/O ,/O the/O seems/O aimed/O at/O curbing/O ethnic/O violence/O in/O the/O tumultuous/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O of/O western/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O largely/O Muslim/O and/O has/O experienced/O heavy/O crackdowns/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION over/O the/O years/O ./O 
But/O many/O observers/O argue/O it/O will/O also/O impact/O freedom/O of/O speech/O ,/O as/O the/O bill/O introduces/O measures/O meant/O to/O tighten/O political/O dissent/O online/O ./O 
Additionally/O ,/O it/O introduces/O provisions/O that/O could/O require/O tech/O firms/O to/O hand/O over/O valuable/O information/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O something/O many/O in/O the/O business/O world/O see/O as/O a/O violation/O of/O intellectual/O property/O rights/O ./O 
A/O spokesman/O for/O the/O Chinese/O foreign/O ministry/O assuaged/O international/O concerns/O ,/O saying/O it/O will/O not/O violate/O the/O rights/O of/O individuals/O or/O companies/O as/O long/O as/O they/O are/O acting/O within/O the/O law/O ./O 
On/O Saturday/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION drew/O for/O denying/O a/O French/O journalist/O her/O credentials/O after/O she/O published/O a/O controversial/O account/O of/O the/O government/O 's/O policies/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
blc/bk/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 
