What/O is/O driving/O the/O Uighur/O Muslims/O to/O increasingly/O join/O the/O ranks/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O al/O Qaeda/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ?/O 
Analyst/O Siegfried/PERSON O./PERSON Wolf/PERSON tells/O DW/O why/O the/O Uighur/O issue/O has/O expanded/O far/O beyond/O China/LOCATION 's/O borders/O ./O 
Uighur/O Muslims/O ,/O a/O Turkic-speaking/O minority/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ,/O have/O long/O faced/O persecution/O by/O the/O country/O 's/O communist/O authorities/O ./O 
They/O are/O a/O distinct/O and/O mostly/O Sunni/O Muslim/O community/O and/O one/O of/O the/O 55/O recognized/O ethnic/O minorities/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O Uighurs/O feel/O increasingly/O suppressed/O and/O view/O Beijing/LOCATION as/O a/O ``/O colonizing/O power/O ''/O attempting/O to/O undermine/O their/O cultural/O identity/O ,/O political/O rights/O ,/O religion/O and/O to/O exploit/O their/O region/O 's/O natural/O resources/O ./O 
In/O the/O past/O few/O years/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O acted/O strictly/O against/O the/O separatists/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
This/O has/O pushed/O many/O Uighurs/O towards/O radicalization/O and/O militancy/O ./O 
The/O situation/O is/O also/O becoming/O aggravated/O due/O to/O the/O fact/O that/O Uighur/O separatism/O is/O not/O only/O an/O ethnic/O movement/O but/O also/O has/O a/O religious/O dimension/O to/O it/O ./O 
The/O Uighur/O issue/O is/O generally/O viewed/O as/O an/O internal/O Chinese/O security/O problem/O but/O some/O experts/O argue/O that/O it/O should/O also/O be/O looked/O at/O in/O the/O context/O of/O the/O rising/O global/O jihad/O and/O Islamic/O fundamentalism/O ./O 
The/O crucial/O point/O ,/O the/O analysts/O say/O ,/O is/O that/O the/O Uighur/O case/O is/O getting/O increasingly/O hijacked/O by/O the/O jihadist/O movements/O ,/O particularly/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION where/O a/O number/O of/O Uighur/O militants/O are/O reportedly/O fighting/O alongside/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O al/O Qaeda/O ./O 
In/O a/O DW/O interview/O ,/O Siegfried/PERSON O./PERSON Wolf/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O research/O at/O the/O Brussels-based/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION Democratic/O Forum/O -LRB-/O SADF/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O and/O a/O researcher/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Heidelberg/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION South/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION ,/O explains/O what/O is/O driving/O Uighurs/O to/O join/O Islamists/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O what/O could/O be/O done/O to/O prevent/O this/O ./O 
Siegfried/PERSON O./PERSON Wolf/PERSON :/O Decision-makers/O also/O need/O to/O look/O at/O the/O Uighur/O conflict/O in/O the/O context/O of/O Islamic/O jihad/O and/O fundamentalism/O ./O 
It/O is/O important/O to/O investigate/O to/O what/O extent/O Uighur/O refugees/O and/O illegal/O migrants/O are/O getting/O involved/O in/O jihadist/O networks/O in/O and/O outside/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O are/O being/O used/O as/O potential/O recruits/O for/O terrorist/O organizations/O ./O 
According/O to/O Chinese/O sources/O ,/O Uighur/O militants/O use/O fake/O Turkish/O passports/O to/O enter/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O join/O extremist/O groups/O ./O 
In/O the/O Afghan/O and/O Pakistani/O camps/O ,/O which/O are/O heavily/O funded/O by/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ,/O Uighurs/O receive/O ideological/O indoctrination/O as/O well/O as/O military/O training/O ./O 
Many/O of/O the/O Uighur/O fighters/O are/O organized/O under/O an/O umbrella/O group/O called/O East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION or/O ETIM/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O ETIM/O was/O listed/O as/O one/O of/O the/O ``/O more/O extreme/O separatist/O groups/O ''/O and/O as/O a/O terrorist/O organization/O by/O the/O US/LOCATION in/O 2002/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O ETIM/O is/O associated/O with/O al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION and/O its/O fighters/O are/O believed/O to/O have/O fought/O alongside/O them/O and/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION against/O NATO/ORGANIZATION troops/O ./O 
Furthermore/O ,/O the/O Uighurs/O gained/O combat/O training/O in/O Chechnya/LOCATION and/O were/O involved/O in/O terrorist/O activities/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ./O 
Reportedly/O ,/O the/O ETIM/ORGANIZATION has/O also/O sent/O its/O members/O to/O fight/O for/O ``/O Islamic/O State/O ''/O -LRB-/O IS/O -RRB-/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
IS/O has/O declared/O jihad/O against/O China/LOCATION on/O the/O grounds/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O mistreating/O the/O Uighur/O Muslim/O population/O ./O 
This/O classic/O Sunni/O jihadist/O propaganda/O based/O on/O the/O persecution/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O is/O evident/O in/O videos/O and/O other/O jihadist/O material/O in/O which/O IS/O has/O called/O for/O global/O jihad/O and/O an/O uprising/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Uighurs/O identify/O themselves/O as/O the/O original/O inhabitants/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O which/O they/O describe/O as/O ``/O East/O Turkistan/O ./O ''/O 
Many/O of/O the/O Turkic-speaking/O Uighurs/O feel/O closer/O to/O Central/O Asian/O states/O and/O are/O in/O favor/O of/O separating/O from/O China/LOCATION or/O receiving/O greater/O autonomy/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O it/O does/O not/O come/O as/O a/O surprise/O that/O Chinese/O security/O officials/O are/O dealing/O with/O them/O very/O strictly/O and/O want/O to/O have/O Xinjiang/LOCATION under/O their/O tight/O control/O ,/O for/O both/O economic/O and/O geo-strategic/O reasons/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O enforced/O harsher/O regulations/O against/O the/O Uighurs/O and/O raised/O the/O security/O budget/O for/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O tensions/O between/O the/O Uighurs/O and/O the/O majority/O Han/O Chinese/O people/O have/O dramatically/O increased/O ./O 
Clashes/O and/O violent/O riots/O broke/O out/O between/O the/O two/O communities/O in/O July/O 2009/O ,/O which/O resulted/O in/O at/O least/O 197/O fatalities/O ./O 
Another/O wave/O of/O violence/O occurred/O in/O 2012/O ./O 
This/O has/O driven/O many/O Uighurs/O to/O flee/O China/LOCATION --/O both/O legally/O and/O illegally/O -/O to/O other/O countries/O ./O 
There/O is/O no/O doubt/O that/O the/O ``/O forced/O returnees/O ''/O have/O to/O face/O severe/O persecution/O ,/O torture/O ,/O abuse/O ,/O and/O even/O disappearances/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O executed/O several/O of/O them/O in/O the/O past/O ./O 
In/O the/O past/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION acted/O against/O militant/O groupings/O carrying/O out/O anti-Chinese/O activities/O ./O 
However/O ,/O this/O happened/O on/O Pakistani/O soil/O and/O did/O not/O include/O Afghanistan/LOCATION or/O the/O Afghan/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
When/O it/O comes/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION it/O seems/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION are/O not/O on/O the/O same/O page/O ./O 
Achieving/O peace/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION is/O not/O Islamabad/LOCATION 's/O main/O goal/O or/O concern/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Afghan/O policy/O is/O driven/O by/O its/O rivalry/O with/O India/LOCATION which/O is/O aimed/O at/O minimizing/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION 's/O influence/O over/O its/O western/O neighborhood/O and/O making/O sure/O that/O a/O Pakistan-friendly/O government/O is/O in/O power/O in/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O 
Even/O if/O Islamabad/LOCATION decides/O to/O use/O its/O influence/O to/O protect/O Chinese/O interests/O vis-a-vis/O Uighur/O militants/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O it/O can/O convince/O various/O Afghan/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION factions/O and/O affiliated/O groups/O to/O change/O their/O strategies/O ./O 
In/O the/O Af-Pak/O region/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uighurs/O have/O proven/O to/O be/O not/O only/O an/O unusual/O source/O of/O friction/O in/O China-Pakistan/O and/O Afghanistan-Pakistan/O ties/O but/O have/O also/O added/O to/O regional/O instability/O ./O 
In/O this/O context/O ,/O it/O is/O important/O to/O note/O that/O until/O the/O early/O 1990s/O ,/O Pakistani/O governments/O adopted/O a/O much/O lenient/O attitude/O towards/O the/O Uighur/O presence/O in/O its/O northwestern/O tribal/O areas/O and/O remained/O largely/O indifferent/O to/O their/O separatist/O cause/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
This/O policy/O changed/O in/O the/O late/O 1990s/O in/O order/O to/O mollify/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O which/O felt/O increasingly/O uncomfortable/O about/O the/O fact/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O lawless/O tribal/O region/O bordering/O Afghanistan/LOCATION had/O developed/O into/O a/O sanctuary/O for/O Uighur/O extremists/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O major/O concern/O remains/O that/O Uighurs/O are/O using/O the/O Pakistani/O territory/O to/O create/O unrest/O in/O western/O China/LOCATION ./O 
As/O such/O ,/O China/LOCATION expects/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION acts/O more/O aggressively/O against/O these/O militants/O ./O 
The/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION ,/O funded/O and/O most/O likely/O constructed/O exclusively/O by/O China/LOCATION ,/O could/O be/O a/O primary/O target/O of/O Uighur/O fighters/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
Islamabad/LOCATION needs/O to/O do/O something/O to/O prevent/O this/O from/O happening/O ./O 
Otherwise/O it/O could/O have/O a/O negative/O impact/O on/O its/O ties/O with/O China/LOCATION and/O its/O weak/O economy/O ./O 
