Afghan/O President/O Ghani/PERSON and/O Indian/O PM/O Modi/PERSON have/O lashed/O out/O at/O Pakistan/LOCATION for/O its/O ``/O lack/O of/O cooperation/O ''/O in/O the/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O ./O 
Ghani/PERSON also/O snubbed/O Islamabad/LOCATION 's/O 500-million-dollar/O aid/O at/O the/O Heart/O of/O Asia/LOCATION conference/O ./O 
Speaking/O at/O the/O sixth/O Heart/O of/O Asia/LOCATION ministerial/O conference/O in/O the/O Indian/O city/O of/O Amritsar/LOCATION ,/O Afghan/O President/O Ashraf/PERSON Ghani/PERSON urged/O Pakistani/O authorities/O to/O act/O against/O the/O militants/O '/O sanctuaries/O in/O their/O country/O 's/O northwestern/O tribal/O areas/O ./O 
Ghani/PERSON said/O the/O 500/O million/O dollars/O in/O aid/O that/O Islamabad/LOCATION pledged/O for/O the/O reconstruction/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION would/O be/O better/O spent/O on/O eradicating/O terrorists/O that/O continue/O to/O launch/O attacks/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION from/O Pakistani/O soil/O ./O 
``/O We/O must/O confront/O the/O specter/O in/O the/O room/O ,/O ''/O Ghani/PERSON said/O on/O Sunday/O ,/O referring/O to/O what/O he/O said/O was/O a/O fresh/O wave/O of/O terrorism/O and/O political/O violence/O affecting/O the/O region/O ./O 
``/O Responses/O of/O states/O on/O this/O has/O been/O significant/O ,/O but/O some/O states/O provide/O sanctuary/O and/O tolerate/O these/O networks/O ,/O ''/O Ghani/PERSON said/O ,/O adding/O that/O a/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION leader/O had/O said/O recently/O if/O the/O group/O did/O not/O have/O sanctuary/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O it/O would/O not/O last/O a/O month/O ./O 
It/O is/O not/O the/O first/O time/O the/O Afghan/O government/O has/O criticized/O Pakistan/LOCATION for/O its/O alleged/O lack/O of/O cooperation/O in/O the/O fight/O against/O terror/O ./O 
At/O last/O years/O '/O Heart/O of/O Asia/LOCATION conference/O ,/O Kabul/LOCATION made/O similar/O accusations/O against/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Heart/O of/O Asia/LOCATION Istanbul/LOCATION Ministerial/O Process/O was/O established/O in/O November/O 2011/O to/O provide/O a/O platform/O to/O discuss/O regional/O issues/O ,/O particularly/O regarding/O strengthening/O security/O and/O economic/O and/O political/O cooperation/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O among/O its/O neighbors/O ./O 
The/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O some/O 20/O other/O countries/O serve/O as/O ``/O supporting/O nations/O ''/O in/O the/O process/O ./O 
The/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O Britain/LOCATION ,/O Canada/LOCATION ,/O Australia/LOCATION ,/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O Norway/LOCATION and/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION are/O taking/O part/O in/O this/O year/O 's/O conference/O being/O held/O in/O the/O northwestern/O Indian/O city/O of/O Amritsar/LOCATION ./O 
As/O ties/O between/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION have/O deteriorated/O in/O the/O past/O few/O years/O ,/O Kabul/LOCATION has/O drifted/O towards/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O archrival/O ,/O India/LOCATION ./O 
Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION have/O increased/O trade/O and/O defense/O cooperation/O and/O have/O launched/O a/O number/O of/O development/O projects/O that/O involve/O Iran/LOCATION and/O some/O Central/O Asian/O nations/O ./O 
New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION ,/O too/O ,/O accuses/O Pakistan/LOCATION of/O backing/O Islamist/O militants/O in/O India-administered/O Kashmir/LOCATION ./O 
In/O his/O opening/O remarks/O at/O the/O Heart/O of/O Asia/LOCATION conference/O ,/O Indian/O Prime/O Minister/O Narendra/PERSON Modi/PERSON termed/O terrorism/O ``/O the/O biggest/O threat/O to/O the/O peace/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O the/O region/O ,/O ''/O according/O to/O Indian/O media/O ./O 
``/O We/O must/O counter/O terrorists/O and/O their/O masters/O ./O 
We/O must/O demonstrate/O strong/O collective/O will/O to/O defeat/O terror/O networks/O that/O cause/O bloodshed/O and/O spread/O fear/O ,/O ''/O Modi/PERSON told/O the/O conference/O participants/O in/O a/O veiled/O reference/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Silence/O and/O inaction/O on/O terror/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O the/O region/O will/O only/O embolden/O terrorists/O and/O masters/O and/O those/O fund/O them/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
The/O Indian/O premier/O reiterated/O his/O country/O 's/O commitment/O to/O ``/O durable/O peace/O ''/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O announced/O plans/O to/O connect/O India/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION via/O an/O air/O link/O ./O 
An/O adviser/O to/O the/O Pakistani/O Prime/O Minister/O on/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION ,/O Sartaj/PERSON Aziz/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O taking/O part/O in/O the/O conference/O ,/O rejected/O the/O claims/O that/O his/O country/O was/O not/O supporting/O the/O peace/O process/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O Radio/O Pakistan/LOCATION reported/O ./O 
``/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O ready/O to/O extend/O every/O kind/O of/O cooperation/O for/O lasting/O peace/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Aziz/PERSON said/O ,/O adding/O that/O Afghanistan/LOCATION should/O avoid/O blaming/O Pakistan/LOCATION for/O its/O domestic/O problems/O ./O 
The/O previous/O rounds/O of/O the/O Heart/O of/O Asia/LOCATION failed/O to/O achieve/O any/O of/O the/O objectives/O that/O the/O Istanbul/LOCATION Ministerial/O Process/O had/O set/O for/O itself/O ./O 
The/O Afghanistan/LOCATION peace/O process/O never/O really/O took/O off/O ,/O as/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION insurgents/O are/O not/O cooperating/O with/O the/O government/O in/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O 
Experts/O say/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O powerful/O military/O still/O considers/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION an/O important/O strategic/O ally/O and/O believes/O the/O group/O should/O be/O part/O of/O the/O Afghan/O government/O ./O 
Observers/O are/O of/O the/O view/O that/O the/O Pakistani/O military/O hopes/O to/O regain/O the/O influence/O it/O enjoyed/O in/O Kabul/LOCATION before/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O its/O allies/O toppled/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION government/O in/O 2001/O ./O 
Siegfried/PERSON O./PERSON Wolf/PERSON ,/O a/O political/O science/O expert/O at/O Heidelberg/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O is/O of/O the/O same/O view/O ./O 
He/O told/O DW/O he/O is/O convinced/O that/O several/O elements/O within/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O security/O apparatus/O still/O believe/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION could/O be/O used/O as/O a/O strategic/O tool/O to/O counter/O India/LOCATION 's/O influence/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION want/O stability/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O but/O both/O have/O conflicting/O interests/O in/O the/O war-torn/O country/O ./O 
After/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION surprisingly/O overtook/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O fifth-largest/O city/O of/O Kunduz/LOCATION in/O July/O 2015/O ,/O US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON revised/O his/O decision/O of/O complete/O troop/O withdrawal/O by/O 2017/O ./O 
More/O than/O 5,000/O US/O soldiers/O will/O now/O stay/O in/O the/O country/O to/O help/O the/O Afghan/O security/O forces/O for/O an/O indefinite/O period/O of/O time/O ./O 
But/O foreign/O and/O security/O affairs/O analysts/O say/O that/O President-elect/O Donald/PERSON Trump/PERSON could/O adopt/O a/O different/O policy/O on/O Afghanistan/LOCATION when/O he/O takes/O charge/O in/O January/O 2017/O ./O 
Experts/O also/O say/O the/O US/LOCATION wants/O to/O leave/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O but/O it/O wants/O its/O interests/O to/O be/O protected/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
For/O that/O reason/O ,/O the/O Obama/PERSON administration/O is/O seeking/O Islamabad/LOCATION 's/O help/O ./O 
It/O believes/O that/O the/O Pakistani/O military/O enjoys/O considerable/O influence/O on/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION leadership/O ./O 
China/LOCATION ,/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O is/O wary/O of/O the/O Islamists/O operating/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O their/O alliance/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O other/O Islamist/O groups/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
It/O also/O seeks/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O assistance/O -/O not/O only/O to/O help/O create/O peace/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O but/O also/O to/O keep/O regional/O rival/O India/LOCATION at/O bay/O ./O 
The/O Heart/O of/O Asia/LOCATION summit/O is/O taking/O place/O at/O a/O time/O when/O the/O Middle/O Eastern/O militant/O group/O ``/O Islamic/O State/O ''/O -LRB-/O IS/O -RRB-/O has/O made/O huge/O gains/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O is/O increasing/O its/O presence/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
The/O group/O has/O claimed/O responsibility/O for/O a/O number/O of/O terror/O attacks/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION in/O the/O past/O few/O months/O ./O 
Analyst/O Wolf/PERSON fears/O that/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION infighting/O could/O lead/O to/O more/O defections/O of/O frustrated/O militants/O to/O IS/O ./O 
He/O also/O thinks/O an/O impending/O IS/O defeat/O in/O Iraq/LOCATION and/O Syria/LOCATION could/O push/O its/O fighters/O towards/O the/O Afghanistan-Pakistan/O region/O ./O 
``/O The/O IS/O ideology/O finds/O resonance/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
There/O are/O many/O religious/O groups/O that/O openly/O endorse/O it/O ;/O however/O ,/O they/O are/O quite/O small/O in/O size/O ./O 
But/O I/O fear/O that/O IS/O could/O still/O count/O on/O their/O backing/O ,/O ''/O Peshawar-based/O expert/O Iqbal/PERSON Khattak/PERSON told/O DW/O ./O 
Khattak/PERSON says/O that/O military/O operations/O alone/O wo/O n't/O solve/O the/O problem/O ./O 
``/O It/O is/O extremely/O important/O for/O the/O Pakistani/O state/O to/O invest/O in/O the/O welfare/O of/O common/O people/O and/O launch/O development/O programs/O to/O eradicate/O poverty/O and/O discourage/O people/O from/O joining/O the/O ranks/O of/O extremist/O outfits/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O Until/O then/O ,/O anything/O is/O possible/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
