Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O China/LOCATION has/O admitted/O to/O a/O probable/O case/O of/O human/O infection/O of/O bird/O flu/O while/O the/O virus/O continues/O to/O invade/O new/O regions/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O first/O case/O since/O 2003/O ./O 
China/LOCATION ./O 
Preliminary/O testing/O reveals/O that/O He/PERSON Junyao/PERSON ,/O a/O nine-year-old/O boy/O from/O Wantang/LOCATION ,/O Xiangtan/LOCATION county/LOCATION in/O Hunan/LOCATION ,/O has/O contracted/O bird/O flu/O ./O 
Previous/O tests/O ,/O undertaken/O by/O the/O local/O health/O department/O ,/O ``/O were/O negative/O ''/O said/O Qi/PERSON Xiaoqiu/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O the/O health/O ministry/O 's/O department/O of/O disease/O control/O ./O 
``/O But/O the/O results/O from/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Chinese/O Centre/O for/O</ORGANIZATION> Disease/ORGANIZATION Control/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Prevention/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CDC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O are/O positive/O ''/O ,/O even/O if/O further/O testing/O is/O required/O to/O confirm/O the/O results/O ./O 
The/O World/ORGANIZATION Health/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION 's/O -LRB-/O WHO/ORGANIZATION 's/O -RRB-/O Beijing/LOCATION spokesman/O ,/O Roy/PERSON Wadia/PERSON ,/O said/O he/O was/O ``/O not/O surprised/O ''/O even/O if/O he/O is/O waiting/O for/O confirmation/O ,/O expected/O within/O days/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O <ORGANIZATION>WHO/O</ORGANIZATION> experts/O are/O currently/O in/O Xiangtan/LOCATION to/O conduct/O confirmatory/O tests/O while/O their/O colleagues/O study/O lab/O samples/O of/O suspect/O cases/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
The/O boy/O fell/O ill/O on/O 13/O October/O together/O with/O his/O sister/O He/PERSON Yin/PERSON at/O the/O same/O time/O as/O an/O infection/O outbreak/O among/O birds/O in/O the/O village/O ./O 
His/O sister/O died/O within/O a/O few/O days/O and/O her/O body/O was/O cremated/O before/O any/O accurate/O testing/O could/O be/O carried/O out/O ./O 
The/O official/O diagnosis/O for/O both/O cases/O was/O of/O ``/O pneumonia/O caused/O by/O unknown/O factors/O ''/O ,/O but/O 11/O days/O after/O the/O media/O raised/O doubts/O about/O this/O ,/O the/O Health/O Minister/O requested/O <ORGANIZATION>WHO/O</ORGANIZATION> intervention/O ./O 
The/O boy/O was/O discharged/O from/O hospital/O last/O week/O ./O 
Now/O Qi/PERSON admits/O that/O the/O previous/O tests/O ``/O may/O not/O have/O been/O appropriate/O ''/O even/O because/O ``/O it/O was/O the/O first/O time/O the/O local/O laboratory/O conducted/O such/O tests/O ,/O and/O their/O quality/O is/O limited/O ./O ''/O 
A/O 36-year-old/O teacher/O fell/O ill/O with/O identical/O symptoms/O at/O around/O the/O same/O time/O in/O a/O neighbouring/O village/O ,/O but/O official/O health/O sources/O excluded/O infection/O ,/O without/O giving/O any/O further/O explanations/O ./O 
Yesterday/O two/O outbreaks/O of/O infection/O were/O reported/O in/O the/O remote/O north-west/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> where/O more/O than/O 6,500/O birds/O were/O infected/O and/O 320,000/O culled/O in/O the/O capital/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O <U_LOCATION>Zepu/LOCATION county/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
The/O authorities/O have/O admitted/O to/O 11/O outbreaks/O since/O October/O -LRB-/O in/O Mongolia/LOCATION Interior/LOCATION ,/O Liaoning/LOCATION ,/O Anhui/LOCATION ,/O Hubei/LOCATION and/O Henan/LOCATION -RRB-/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O announced/O that/O it/O will/O vaccinate/O all/O poultry/O stocks/O ,/O more/O than/O 14/O billion/O animals/O ./O 
In/O Heishan/LOCATION county/LOCATION in/O Liaoning/LOCATION ,/O Zhao/PERSON Yonghe/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O Badaohao/ORGANIZATION Township/ORGANIZATION Animal/ORGANIZATION Husbandry/ORGANIZATION Station/ORGANIZATION ,/O was/O arrested/O for/O certifying/O infected/O chickens/O as/O healthy/O ./O 
Vietnam/LOCATION ./O 
The/O media/O has/O reported/O two/O other/O suspect/O cases/O of/O infection/O hospitalized/O in/O Hanoi/LOCATION with/O typical/O symptoms/O :/O a/O 15-year-old/O girl/O and/O a/O 71-year-old/O woman/O ./O 
Testing/O is/O under/O way/O ./O 
The/O Agriculture/O Minister/O reported/O new/O outbreaks/O of/O the/O H5N1/O virus/O in/O three/O other/O provinces/O ,/O the/O central/O <LOCATION>Quang/PERSON Ngai/PERSON</LOCATION> and/O the/O northern/O <LOCATION>Vinh/PERSON Phuc/PERSON</LOCATION> and/O <LOCATION>Bac/PERSON Ninh/PERSON</LOCATION> provinces/O ./O 
In/O a/O bid/O to/O contain/O the/O infection/O ,/O massive/O culling/O of/O poultry/O continues/O ./O 
Hanoi/LOCATION breeders/O said/O they/O receive/O 15,000/O dong/O -LRB-/O around/O 95/O cents/O of/O a/O US/LOCATION dollar/O -RRB-/O for/O every/O duck/O slaughtered/O but/O it/O costs/O 40,000/O dong/O to/O raise/O one/O ./O 
However/O in/O the/O city/O of/O Ho/LOCATION Chi/LOCATION Minh/LOCATION ,/O where/O a/O ban/O on/O poultry/O breeding/O is/O on/O ,/O animals/O found/O in/O people/O 's/O homes/O are/O culled/O and/O no/O compensation/O is/O given/O ./O 
Scientists/O in/O Vietnam/LOCATION are/O undertaking/O continuous/O testing/O on/O birds/O in/O which/O they/O have/O identified/O a/O type/O of/O influenza/O virus/O ,/O although/O it/O does/O not/O appear/O to/O be/O dangerous/O to/O man/O ./O 
The/O fear/O is/O that/O some/O strains/O could/O evolve/O into/O forms/O and/O pathogenes/O which/O endanger/O human/O beings/O ./O 
Today/O Vietnam/LOCATION announced/O it/O will/O produce/O its/O own/O vaccine/O to/O protect/O poultry/O ./O
