Young/O people/O and/O teachers/O are/O denied/O the/O right/O to/O worship/O ./O 
A/O mosque/O is/O torn/O down/O to/O leave/O space/O for/O a/O shopping/O mall/O ./O 
For/O experts/O the/O region/O 's/O energy/O resources/O are/O behind/O China/LOCATION 's/O policies/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O <ORGANIZATION>F18</ORGANIZATION>/O -RRB-/O --/O In/O China/LOCATION 's/O north-western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Uighur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O control/O over/O the/O Uighurs/O continues/O to/O be/O much/O stricter/O than/O over/O other/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ethnic/O groups/O and/O comes/O close/O to/O being/O persecution/O ./O 
For/O Beijing/LOCATION separatism/O is/O the/O reason/O ,/O but/O that/O has/O not/O stopped/O it/O from/O exploiting/O the/O region/O 's/O wealth/O for/O the/O benefit/O of/O its/O richer/O eastern/O provinces/O and/O keeping/O the/O Uighur/O population/O backward/O ./O 
According/O to/O Forum/O 18/O ,/O tight/O control/O is/O exerted/O on/O imams/O and/O the/O youth/O ./O 
The/O morning/O of/O every/O Friday/O ,/O the/O Muslim/O day/O of/O rest/O ,/O local/O imams/O are/O obliged/O to/O go/O to/O the/O local/O state/O Religious/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION to/O discuss/O the/O text/O of/O their/O Friday/O sermon/O with/O officials/O and/O receive/O ``/O general/O instructions/O ''/O ./O 
Every/O religious/O group/O must/O be/O registered/O with/O their/O Nation-Religious/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O appointment/O of/O leaders/O must/O be/O approved/O by/O the/O authorities/O ./O 
Religious/O leaders/O have/O to/O attend/O meetings/O of/O the/O national-religious/O committees/O ,/O where/O officials/O tell/O them/O what/O policy/O they/O must/O pursue/O with/O believers/O ./O 
Believers/O may/O not/O hold/O a/O senior/O position/O in/O a/O state/O organisation/O ,/O or/O be/O a/O school/O teacher/O ./O 
And/O young/O people/O under/O 18/O are/O not/O allowed/O to/O attend/O places/O of/O worship/O ./O 
Shi/PERSON Si/PERSON Shin/PERSON ,/O deputy/O head/O of/O the/O national/O religious/O committee/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O told/O Forum/ORGANIZATION <ORGANIZATION>18/O</ORGANIZATION> that/O minors/O are/O not/O allowed/O to/O attend/O places/O of/O worship/O because/O they/O ``/O need/O to/O finish/O their/O education/O and/O develop/O their/O personalities/O before/O they/O can/O make/O an/O informed/O decision/O as/O to/O whether/O they/O are/O believers/O or/O atheists/O ''/O ./O 
The/O ban/O is/O especially/O strict/O in/O the/O most/O religious/O districts/O like/O <U_LOCATION>Hotan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O where/O the/O police/O prevents/O young/O people/O and/O public/O servants/O from/O going/O to/O the/O mosque/O or/O attend/O madrassahs/O -LRB-/O Islamic/O religious/O schools/O -RRB-/O ./O 
During/O the/O Islamic/O fasting/O month/O of/O Ramadan/O ,/O the/O authorities/O even/O force/O Muslim/O schoolchildren/O to/O have/O lunch/O ./O 
Similarly/O ,/O <OTHER>Muslim/PERSON</OTHER> places/O of/O worship/O or/O buildings/O used/O by/O Muslims/O have/O been/O expropriated/O or/O demolished/O ./O 
Three/O years/O ago/O near/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O main/O Id-ha/O mosque/O ,/O the/O authorities/O tore/O down/O many/O small/O mud-built/O restaurants/O and/O tea/O houses/O where/O <OTHER>Muslims/PERSON</OTHER> met/O to/O talk/O after/O prayers/O ./O 
In/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> the/O old/O mosque/O was/O torn/O down/O and/O rebuilt/O as/O part/O of/O shopping/O mall/O ,/O located/O somewhere/O between/O a/O Kentucky/ORGANIZATION Fried/ORGANIZATION Chicken/ORGANIZATION restaurant/O and/O a/O Carrefour/ORGANIZATION supermarket/O ./O 
Worshipers/O complain/O that/O they/O can/O not/O hear/O their/O own/O prayers/O because/O of/O the/O music/O and/O singing/O from/O the/O bazaar/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O have/O also/O banned/O Sufism/O and/O Wahhabism/O and/O writers/O inspired/O by/O these/O Islamic/O movements/O ,/O concerned/O of/O their/O possible/O political/O connections/O ./O 
But/O according/O to/O Forum/ORGANIZATION <ORGANIZATION>18/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O other/O Chinese/O Muslim/O ethnic/O groups/O are/O not/O as/O tightly/O controlled/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O the/O authorities/O '/O power/O over/O mosques/O used/O by/O ethnic/O <OTHER>Dungans/PERSON</OTHER> ,/O who/O hail/O from/O central/O Asian/O states/O ,/O is/O less/O strict/O ./O 
The/O situation/O is/O such/O that/O many/O Uighur/O parents/O often/O take/O their/O children/O to/O other/O parts/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O where/O they/O can/O study/O freely/O at/O a/O madrassah/O ./O 
For/O some/O experts/O ,/O the/O anti-Uighur/O persecution/O is/O essentially/O economic/O in/O nature/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O want/O to/O wipe/O out/O the/O identity/O of/O the/O Uighur/O population/O in/O order/O to/O better/O take/O control/O of/O the/O region/O 's/O oil/O ad/O natural/O gas/O ./O 
To/O achieve/O this/O goal/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O for/O years/O encouraged/O the/O immigration/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
<OTHER>Hans/PERSON</OTHER> are/O now/O a/O slim/O majority/O among/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O 19.3/O million/O people/O ,/O but/O dominate/O in/O trade/O and/O the/O administration/O ./O 
Uighurs/O ,/O 42/O per/O cent/O of/O the/O population/O ,/O are/O largely/O farmers/O ./O 
Since/O January/O 2000/O ,/O the/O central/O government/O has/O been/O pursing/O a/O `/O Develop/O the/O West/O programme/O '/O to/O overcome/O the/O region/O 's/O relative/O backwardness/O compared/O to/O eastern/O regions/O ./O 
Building/O rail/O and/O roads/O ,/O hydroelectric/O dams/O ,/O and/O oil/O pipelines/O is/O part/O of/O the/O programme/O ./O 
``/O Among/O the/O key/O projects/O of/O the/O Develop/O the/O West/O programme/O ,/O the/O majority/O only/O benefits/O the/O east/O ,/O ''/O said/O Zhao/PERSON Baotong/PERSON ,/O who/O heads/O the/O Economics/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O Shaanxi/ORGANIZATION Academy/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Social/ORGANIZATION Sciences/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O western/O city/O of/O Xian/LOCATION ./O 
``/O These/O projects/O are/O transporting/O electricity/O ,/O natural/O gas/O and/O other/O resources/O from/O the/O west/O to/O the/O east/O to/O fuel/O development/O there/O ./O 
Almost/O none/O of/O these/O projects/O are/O aiming/O at/O developing/O local/O manufacturing/O industry/O in/O the/O west/O ./O ''/O 
-LRB-/O PB/O -RRB-/O
