Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O --/O China/LOCATION 's/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O ,/O Qin/PERSON Gang/PERSON ,/O yesterday/O accused/O an/O exiled/O politician/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O candidate/O for/O the/O 2006/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O ,/O of/O maintaining/O links/O with/O terrorist/O organisations/O and/O attempting/O to/O undermine/O China/LOCATION 's/O stability/O ./O 
Qin/PERSON said/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> --/O who/O belongs/O to/O the/O member/O of/O the/O Turkic-speaking/O <OTHER>Uighur/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O --/O was/O seeking/O to/O divide/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> from/O the/O rest/O of/O China/LOCATION together/O with/O ``/O known/O terrorist/O organizations/O ''/O ./O 
The/O spokesman/O said/O :/O ``/O She/O was/O arrested/O for/O endangering/O national/O security/O and/O sentenced/O ./O 
She/O connives/O with/O terrorist/O forces/O abroad/O and/O engages/O in/O anti-Chinese/O secessionist/O movements/O ./O ''/O 
<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> was/O released/O from/O imprisonment/O in/O China/LOCATION on/O 17/O March/O 2005/O ,/O whereupon/O she/O asked/O for/O and/O obtained/O refugee/O status/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O where/O she/O now/O lives/O ./O 
The/O 58-year-old/O woman/O was/O the/O director/O of/O an/O established/O trade/O company/O as/O well/O as/O member/O on/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Consultative/ORGANIZATION Conference/ORGANIZATION for/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
She/O was/O arrested/O in/O 1999/O for/O spreading/O news/O abroad/O that/O was/O defined/O by/O China/LOCATION as/O ``/O material/O containing/O state/O secrets/O ''/O ./O 
Condemned/O to/O eight/O years/O in/O prison/O ,/O she/O was/O released/O a/O few/O days/O before/O the/O visit/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>American/O Secretary/O of/O</ORGANIZATION> State/ORGANIZATION to/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O just/O when/O America/LOCATION declared/O it/O would/O not/O present/O a/O motion/O critical/O of/O China/LOCATION at/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION in/O Geneva/LOCATION ./O 
Although/O the/O prison/O guards/O never/O laid/O a/O finger/O on/O her/O ,/O she/O described/O the/O abuse/O of/O other/O political/O prisoners/O ,/O who/O were/O beaten/O until/O they/O were/O lame/O ./O 
After/O her/O release/O ,/O she/O recalled/O a/O 96-year-old/O Uighur/O woman/O who/O was/O in/O prison/O without/O knowing/O why/O ./O 
The/O guards/O would/O torture/O prisoners/O within/O earshot/O to/O frighten/O her/O ./O 
To/O hit/O back/O at/O the/O woman/O because/O of/O her/O continued/O denunciations/O from/O abroad/O ,/O on/O 11/O May/O last/O year/O ,/O Chinese/O police/O arrested/O two/O employees/O of/O her/O firm/O ,/O the/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> trade/O centre/O ,/O and/O a/O few/O days/O later/O ,/O one/O of/O her/O sons/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Ablikim/PERSON Abdiriyim/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O disappeared/O ./O 
He/O had/O already/O been/O imprisoned/O in/O a/O laogai/O from/O 1999/O to/O 2001/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> has/O 19/O million/O inhabitants/O ,/O including/O eight/O million/O Uighurs/O ./O 
They/O are/O calling/O for/O more/O autonomy/O but/O some/O groups/O want/O to/O restore/O the/O independence/O enjoyed/O by/O the/O region/O from/O 1938/O to/O 1949/O ,/O when/O it/O was/O called/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION cracks/O down/O on/O all/O separatist/O groups/O with/O implacable/O violence/O ,/O accusing/O them/O of/O collusion/O with/O Islamic/O fundamentalism/O coming/O from/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
