During/O Chen/PERSON Guancheng/PERSON 's/O retrial/O ,/O his/O lawyers/O complain/O key/O witnesses/O were/O kidnapped/O ./O 
Harsh/O sentences/O and/O beating/O inflicted/O on/O the/O sons/O of/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O defender/O of/O Uyghur/O minority/O rights/O ./O 
An/O anti-AIDS/O activist/O is/O arrested/O to/O prevent/O him/O from/O holding/O a/O public/O forum/O on/O the/O issue/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O China/LOCATION 's/O justice/O system/O continues/O to/O strike/O the/O country/O 's/O human/O rights/O activists/O ./O 
The/O trial/O of/O Chen/PERSON Guangcheng/PERSON -LRB-/O an/O activist/O against/O forced/O abortions/O -RRB-/O has/O seen/O witnesses/O disappear/O ./O 
In/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O two/O sons/O of/O dissident/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> were/O found/O guilty/O in/O tax/O evasion/O ./O 
In/O Beijing/LOCATION an/O AIDS/O activist/O is/O jailed/O for/O organising/O a/O public/O forum/O ./O 
The/O blind/O activist/O ,/O who/O focused/O world/O attention/O on/O coercive/O birth-control/O measures/O by/O village/O officials/O in/O Shandong/LOCATION <OTHER>province/LOCATION</OTHER> ,/O was/O given/O an/O unusually/O harsh/O sentence/O of/O four/O years/O and/O three/O months/O in/O jail/O in/O August/O for/O damaging/O property/O and/O organising/O a/O mob/O to/O disrupt/O traffic/O ./O 
But/O he/O was/O granted/O a/O surprise/O retrial/O late/O last/O month/O for/O irregularities/O -LRB-/O three/O of/O Mr/O Chen/PERSON 's/O lawyers/O were/O arrested/O and/O replaced/O with/O court-appointed/O counsel/O -RRB-/O ./O 
His/O retrial/O began/O yesterday/O with/O the/O disappearance/O of/O four/O witnesses/O and/O the/O brief/O detention/O of/O one/O of/O his/O lawyer/O ./O 
His/O current/O defence/O team/O said/O four/O key/O witnesses/O for/O the/O defendant/O were/O ``/O kidnapped/O ''/O on/O Sunday/O by/O local/O officials/O ,/O including/O villager/O Chen/PERSON Guanghe/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O taken/O away/O by/O several/O unidentified/O people/O in/O front/O of/O the/O lawyers/O on/O Sunday/O ./O 
More/O than/O 30/O people/O blocked/O defence/O lawyers/O from/O entering/O Chen/PERSON Guangcheng/PERSON 's/O home/O village/O of/O Dongshigu/LOCATION on/O Sunday/O when/O they/O were/O attempting/O to/O collect/O more/O evidence/O ./O 
Chen/PERSON 's/O lawyer/O ,/O Li/PERSON Jinsong/PERSON ,/O complained/O that/O the/O trial/O took/O place/O in/O an/O atmosphere/O of/O intimidation/O ./O 
After/O hearing/O other/O witness/O ,/O the/O court/O adjourned/O to/O deliberate/O ./O 
A/O verdict/O is/O expected/O in/O a/O few/O days/O ./O 
A/O court/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Tianshan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> district/O -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O sentenced/O <U_PERSON>Alimu/PERSON Ahbudurimu/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O son/O of/O Uygur/O rights/O activist/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O to/O seven/O year/O in/O jail/O and/O 500,000/O yuan/O in/O fines/O for/O tax/O evasion/O ./O 
Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> was/O detained/O in/O 1999/O ,/O tried/O and/O imprisoned/O for/O five/O years/O on/O charges/O of/O ``/O leaking/O state/O secrets/O ''/O ,/O having/O sent/O newspaper/O clippings/O abroad/O ./O 
Released/O after/O an/O international/O campaign/O ,/O she/O now/O lives/O in/O exile/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O but/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O taken/O various/O legal/O actions/O against/O her/O company/O and/O her/O children/O who/O are/O still/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
<U_PERSON>Alimu/PERSON Ahbudurimu/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O who/O is/O already/O in/O prison/O ,/O was/O convicted/O of/O evading/O taxes/O for/O 208,430/O yuan/O as/O the/O attorney/O for/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Ahkeda/ORGANIZATION Trading/ORGANIZATION Co./ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ./O 
His/O brother/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Kahaer/PERSON Ahbudurimu/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O was/O also/O found/O guilty/O of/O evading/O nearly/O 2.5/O million/O yuan/O in/O taxes/O but/O spared/O a/O jail/O term/O ./O 
Two/O of/O her/O other/O sons/O were/O beaten/O by/O police/O after/O being/O detained/O in/O June/O ;/O a/O third/O has/O gone/O missing/O after/O charges/O of/O subversion/O were/O levelled/O at/O him/O ./O 
A/O daughter/O is/O also/O under/O house/O arrest/O ./O 
All/O this/O ``/O is/O clear/O retribution/O for/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O advocacy/O on/O behalf/O of/O Uyghurs/O ,/O ''/O said/O Nicholas/PERSON Bequelin/PERSON ,/O a/O China/LOCATION researcher/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION for/O the/O New/O York-based/O group/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O We/O have/O great/O doubt/O about/O the/O fairness/O of/O the/O trial/O and/O they/O -LSB-/O Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O sons/O -RSB-/O have/O not/O been/O able/O to/O get/O meaningful/O legal/O representation/O ./O ''/O 
Yesterday/O instead/O police/O freed/O leading/O AIDS/O activist/O Wan/PERSON Yanhai/PERSON ,/O three/O days/O after/O he/O planned/O to/O hold/O a/O public/O forum/O on/O the/O disease/O on/O Sunday/O ,/O World/O Aids/O Day/O ./O 
Nothing/O is/O known/O about/O the/O charges/O ,/O but/O Mr/O <PERSON>Wan/O</PERSON> was/O detained/O by/O officials/O from/O the/O Public/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION to/O ``/O discuss/O ''/O the/O workshop/O ,/O the/O Aids/ORGANIZATION Action/ORGANIZATION Project/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O 
The/O group/O wants/O health/O authorities/O to/O provide/O help/O ,/O including/O compensation/O ,/O drugs/O and/O medical/O care/O ,/O to/O the/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O ,/O perhaps/O millions/O of/O people/O who/O received/O tainted/O blood/O ./O 
-LRB-/O PB/O -RRB-/O
