Arrested/O in/O January/O for/O suspected/O links/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>Al-Qaeda/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O the/O proof/O of/O charges/O against/O them/O has/O yet/O to/O be/O revealed/O ./O 
Authorities/O insist/O on/O the/O terrorist/O threat/O ,/O but/O refuse/O to/O provide/O any/O explanation/O pertaining/O to/O activities/O against/O the/O Uyghur/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O It/O will/O possibly/O be/O a/O public/O trial/O against/O the/O 17/O Uyghur/O ,/O presumed/O to/O be/O terrorists/O ,/O who/O were/O arrested/O in/O January/O during/O a/O police/O raid/O on/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Pamir/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> highlands/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O near/O the/O Pakistan/LOCATION border/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O insist/O they/O represent/O a/O terrorist/O threat/O but/O refuse/O to/O supply/O explanations/O regarding/O their/O actions/O against/O the/O local/O population/O ./O 
Shi/PERSON Dagang/PERSON ,/O party/O secretary/O of/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> district/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O was/O unclear/O when/O the/O trials/O would/O be/O held/O and/O who/O would/O be/O allowed/O to/O attend/O ,/O but/O <OTHER>Mr/PERSON</OTHER> Shi/PERSON described/O them/O as/O ``/O open/O ''/O ./O 
Speaking/O to/O the/O press/O ,/O Shi/PERSON said/O the/O suspects/O were/O arrested/O in/O a/O training/O camp/O of/O the/O eastern/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Etim/O</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ,/O that/O they/O were/O being/O trained/O by/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O in/O contact/O with/O <U_ORGANIZATION>al-Qaeda/O</U_ORGANIZATION> in/O view/O of/O a/O terrorist/O attack/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Despite/O this/O not/O a/O single/O foreigner/O was/O found/O by/O police/O during/O their/O raid/O ,/O which/O resulted/O in/O the/O death/O of/O 18/O presumed/O terrorists/O and/O one/O officer/O ./O 
According/O to/O Shi/PERSON ,/O more/O than/O 1,500/O partly/O assembled/O grenades/O and/O a/O large/O amount/O of/O explosives/O and/O weapons/O were/O seized/O from/O the/O camp/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O long/O accused/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Etim/O</U_ORGANIZATION> of/O links/O to/O Islamic/O terrorism/O ./O 
This/O notwithstanding/O <U_PERSON>Ismail/PERSON Tiliwaldi/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O chairman/O of/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Uygur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O said/O there/O was/O increasingly/O less/O room/O for/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> militants/O to/O operate/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Speaking/O to/O journalists/O from/O the/O South/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Morning/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION ,/O he/O failed/O to/O clarify/O the/O position/O of/O <U_PERSON>Ablikim/PERSON Abdiriyim/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O son/O of/O well/O known/O activist/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O who/O is/O in/O forced/O exile/O following/O years/O of/O incarceration/O for/O his/O defence/O of/O Uygur/O rights/O ./O 
Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION has/O denounced/O that/O he/O is/O suffering/O serious/O ill/O health/O and/O that/O he/O is/O being/O denied/O medical/O care/O ,/O following/O his/O sentencing/O on/O charges/O of/O ``/O subversion/O ''/O in/O a/O closet/O door/O trial/O ./O 
Various/O sources/O ,/O including/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION accuse/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O using/O terrorism/O as/O a/O pretext/O for/O persecuting/O the/O Uygur/O ethnic/O population/O ./O 
The/O regional/O Office/O for/O Religious/O affairs/O limits/O the/O population/O 's/O religious/O practice/O and/O bans/O women/O and/O children/O from/O Mosque/O attendance/O ./O 
Islamic/O schools/O are/O also/O banned/O ./O 
According/O to/O a/O local/O daily/O paper/O ,/O in/O 2005/O China/LOCATION arrested/O over/O 18,227/O Uyghur/O on/O charges/O of/O representing/O ``/O a/O threat/O to/O national/O security/O ''/O ./O
