The/O police/O arrested/O six/O protesters/O outside/O the/O Blue/LOCATION Mosque/LOCATION ./O 
A/O further/O 70/O Uighurs/O arrested/O in/O recent/O days/O ,/O all/O belonging/O to/O the/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ethnic/O group/O forcibly/O annexed/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Passage/O of/O torch/O through/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> at/O risk/O ./O 
Istanbul/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O --/O Police/O detained/O at/O least/O six/O Uighur/O Muslims/O on/O Thursday/O at/O an/O anti-China/O protest/O during/O the/O Olympic/O torch/O ceremony/O ./O 
The/O demonstrators/O were/O detained/O after/O they/O broke/O away/O from/O a/O larger/O group/O of/O protesters/O and/O shouted/O slogans/O just/O feet/O away/O from/O <PERSON>Tugba/LOCATION Karademir/LOCATION</PERSON> ,/O a/O Turkish/O figure/O skater/O and/O Olympic/O athlete/O who/O had/O just/O started/O to/O run/O with/O the/O torch/O through/O the/O city/O ./O 
The/O arrest/O took/O place/O close/O to/O the/O <LOCATION>Blue/O Mosque/O</LOCATION> one/O of/O the/O most/O important/O tourist/O sites/O in/O the/O city/O ./O ''/O 
Turkey/LOCATION ,/O stand/O by/O your/O brothers/O ,/O ''/O read/O a/O banner/O at/O the/O protest/O in/O Istanbul/LOCATION ./O 
Hayrullah/PERSON Efendigil/PERSON ,/O one/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O involved/O in/O the/O demonstration/O ,/O says/O :/O ``/O We/O do/O n't/O want/O a/O country/O like/O China/LOCATION ,/O with/O a/O bad/O human/O rights/O record/O ,/O to/O hold/O the/O Olympics/O ,/O which/O symbolize/O humanity/O ,/O peace/O and/O brotherhood/O ''/O ./O 
The/O Uigher/O ethnic/O group/O ,/O which/O boasts/O its/O own/O language/O and/O traditions/O ,/O counts/O for/O at/O least/O half/O og/O the/O 19/O million/O inhabitants/O of/O the/O petrol/O rich/O northern/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O which/O was/O known/O as/O eastern/O <U_LOCATION>Turkistan/O</U_LOCATION> until/O 1949/O ./O 
In/O October/O 2005/O to/O celebrate/O the/O 50th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O autonomous/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O decreed/O by/O China/LOCATION in/O 1955/O ,/O 18,227/O Uighurs/O were/O arrested/O ``/O for/O having/O threatened/O national/O security/O ''/O ./O 
Every/O year/O hundreds/O of/O death/O sentences/O are/O carried/O out/O ,/O while/O there/O is/O blanket/O control/O over/O the/O mosques/O and/O Islamic/O schools/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O claims/O that/O separatist/O terrorist/O groups/O are/O hiding/O in/O the/O region/O and/O quotes/O over/O 250/O episodes/O of/O separatist/O violence/O in/O the/O area/O over/O the/O last/O 20/O years/O ,/O causing/O 160/O deaths/O and/O over/O 440/O injured/O ./O 
Less/O then/O a/O month/O ago/O Beijing/LOCATION ordered/O a/O raid/O against/O suspected/O Islamic/O Uighur/O terrorists/O :/O unconfirmed/O tolls/O report/O at/O least/O 30/O victims/O ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O authorities/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O ancient/O oasis/O on/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Silk/O Route/O</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O have/O arrested/O at/O least/O 70/O Uighurs/O suspected/O of/O preparing/O anti/O Chinese/O protests/O during/O the/O passage/O of/O the/O Olympic/O torch/O through/O their/O land/O ,/O due/O to/O take/O place/O in/O June/O ./O 
The/O government/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> denies/O the/O arrests/O ,/O confirmed/O however/O by/O inhabitants/O in/O the/O area/O and/O by/O the/O family/O 's/O o/O the/O suspected/O activists/O ./O 
In/O any/O case/O ,/O the/O number/O of/O soldiers/O guarding/O critical/O points/O of/O across/O the/O territory/O ,/O restrictions/O on/O freedom/O of/O movement/O and/O freedom/O to/O gather/O ,/O have/O all/O increased/O ./O
