Official/O sources/O say/O that/O Sichuan/LOCATION quake/O has/O led/O to/O change/O in/O schedule/O ./O 
Experts/O suggest/O instead/O that/O fear/O of/O protests/O in/O the/O region/O closed/O to/O the/O press/O might/O be/O the/O reason/O ./O 
`/O Return/O March/O ''/O is/O set/O to/O reach/O the/O border/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O Tibet/LOCATION by/O tomorrow/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O The/O arrival/O of/O the/O Olympic/O torch/O relay/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION set/O for/O tomorrow/O has/O been/O postponed/O as/O Tibetans/O on/O their/O `/O Return/O March/O '/O in/O northern/O India/LOCATION are/O getting/O ready/O to/O reach/O the/O border/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
The/O torch/O was/O due/O to/O reach/O Tibet/LOCATION tomorrow/O after/O completing/O its/O journey/O in/O Chongqing/LOCATION today/O ,/O but/O will/O now/O head/O directly/O to/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> where/O it/O will/O be/O carried/O by/O 624/O torch-bearers/O through/O the/O cities/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O <U_LOCATION>Shihezi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O <U_LOCATION>Congjin/O</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Official/O sources/O said/O that/O the/O change/O was/O due/O to/O the/O Sichuan/LOCATION quake/O ./O 
``/O We/O will/O decide/O on/O the/O next/O stop/O only/O after/O the/O torch/O arrives/O in/O one/O province/O ,/O ''/O an/O official/O said/O ./O 
``/O We/O are/O only/O able/O to/O confirm/O all/O the/O details/O of/O certain/O stops/O within/O the/O next/O 10/O days/O ./O 
Beyond/O that/O time/O frame/O a/O lot/O of/O things/O are/O up/O in/O the/O air/O ,/O ''/O said/O Shao/PERSON Shiwei/PERSON ,/O a/O deputy/O director/O of/O Beijing/ORGANIZATION Organizing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>BOCOG/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ./O 
Experts/O note/O that/O this/O decision/O runs/O counter/O to/O the/O efficiency/O and/O the/O tight/O if/O somewhat/O smug/O planning/O shown/O by/O Games/O organisers/O ./O 
The/O change/O to/O the/O Tibetan/O leg/O may/O have/O been/O prompted/O by/O concerns/O over/O ``/O security/O abnormalities/O ,/O ''/O this/O according/O to/O the/O Information/ORGANIZATION Centre/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Democracy/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O crackdown/O that/O followed/O protests/O on/O 14/O March/O has/O led/O to/O greater/O security/O concerns/O in/O the/O province/O ,/O even/O though/O <ORGANIZATION>BOCOG/O</ORGANIZATION> has/O insisted/O since/O 19/O March/O that/O there/O were/O not/O problems/O on/O the/O torch/O 's/O path/O ./O 
Tibet/LOCATION itself/O remains/O however/O a/O no-go/O zone/O for/O journalists/O ./O 
Some/O 50/O Tibetans/O participating/O in/O the/O `/O Return/O March/O '/O planned/O to/O arrive/O in/O Dharcula/LOCATION ,/O the/O last/O Indian/O town/O before/O the/O Tibetan/O border/O ,/O tomorrow/O to/O coincide/O with/O the/O arrival/O of/O the/O torch/O in/O their/O homeland/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O deployed/O troops/O along/O the/O border/O with/O the/O order/O to/O shoot/O anyone/O who/O crosses/O it/O ./O 
The/O march/O is/O designed/O to/O draw/O attention/O to/O the/O ongoing/O anti-Tibetan/O crackdown/O ./O 
``/O In/O 1959/O ,/O Tibetan/O refugees/O escaping/O Chinese/O brutalities/O came/O this/O way/O and/O we/O gave/O them/O shelter/O ,/O ''/O said/O Rajwar/PERSON Sahib/PERSON Bham/PERSON Raj/PERSON Singh/PERSON Pal/PERSON -LRB-/O photo/O -RRB-/O ,/O <OTHER>King/PERSON of/PERSON</OTHER> <LOCATION>Askote/PERSON</LOCATION> ,/O who/O welcomed/O the/O marchers/O on/O 14/O June/O ./O 
``/O It/O is/O our/O honour/O now/O to/O host/O this/O group/O of/O Tibetans/O making/O their/O journey/O home/O ./O 
No/O matter/O how/O long/O it/O takes/O ,/O the/O Tibetan/O people/O will/O eventually/O win/O out/O against/O oppression/O ./O ''/O 
Still/O the/O popularity/O of/O the/O Games/O is/O high/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
More/O than/O 4,000/O children/O have/O in/O fact/O been/O given/O the/O name/O <PERSON>Aoyun/LOCATION</PERSON> ,/O meaning/O Olympic/O Games/O ./O
