This/O morning/O two/O grenades/O hit/O a/O check/O point/O on/O the/O <OTHER>North/LOCATION West/LOCATION</OTHER> frontier/O ,/O a/O majority/O Muslim/O area/O theatre/O of/O violence/O in/O the/O past/O weeks/O ./O 
The/O news/O was/O reported/O by/O the/O state/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O but/O AFP/ORGANIZATION sources/O fail/O to/O confirm/O the/O episode/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O --/O The/O death/O toll/O from/O a/O morning/O attack/O on/O a/O border/O crossing/O in/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> majority/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O North/LOCATION West/LOCATION China/LOCATION ,/O is/O 16/O dead/O and/O a/O further/O 16/O wounded/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O state/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O New/LOCATION China/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O at/O 8/O am/O local/O time/O two/O attackers/O drove/O their/O truck/O into/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> border/O crossing/O ,/O exploding/O two/O grenades/O ./O 
Xinhua/ORGANIZATION sources/O report/O that/O the/O attackers/O were/O arrested/O and/O have/O confirmed/O that/O this/O mornings/O attack/O was/O of/O a/O terrorist/O nature/O ./O 
Initially/O the/O official/O agency/O reported/O two/O trucks/O involved/O in/O the/O episode/O ,/O later/O confirming/O that/O one/O truck/O was/O used/O ,/O but/O no/O further/O details/O have/O since/O been/O provided/O regarding/O the/O motives/O for/O the/O attack/O ./O 
French/O press/O agency/O AFP/ORGANIZATION reports/O that/O a/O police/O spokesperson/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> --/O the/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> autonomous/O region/O --/O has/O stated/O that/O they/O are/O ``/O unaware/O of/O an/O explosion/O having/O taken/O place/O in/O the/O zone/O ''/O ,/O refusing/O to/O confirm/O <ORGANIZATION>Xinhua/O</ORGANIZATION> reports/O ./O 
The/O presumed/O episode/O took/O place/O just/O four/O days/O ahead/O of/O the/O official/O opening/O ceremonies/O for/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympic/O Games/O ,/O ahead/O of/O which/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O repeatedly/O warned/O of/O possible/O attacks/O :/O a/O move/O that/O has/O allowed/O authorities/O to/O crack/O down/O even/O further/O on/O security/O across/O the/O country/O ./O 
According/O to/O colonel/O Tian/PERSON Yixiang/PERSON ,/O chief/O of/O security/O for/O the/O Games/O ,/O the/O greatest/O threat/O is/O presented/O by/O the/O Muslim/O separatists/O headed/O by/O a/O terrorist/O organisation/O from/O <U_LOCATION>East/O Turkestan/O</U_LOCATION> ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O called/O in/O reinforcements/O to/O ensure/O security/O throughout/O the/O Olympics/O :/O joining/O the/O police/O who/O patrol/O the/O territory/O on/O a/O daily/O basis/O are/O 34/O thousand/O soldiers/O ,/O 121/O planes/O and/O helicopters/O and/O 33/O naval/O vessels/O along/O the/O coast/O ./O
