The/O repression/O of/O the/O Ughurs/O is/O not/O an/O isolated/O case/O ./O 
Protestant/O are/O in/O jail/O and/O bishops/O have/O disappeared/O ./O 
The/O oppression/O of/O human/O rights/O is/O endemic/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O created/O the/O basis/O for/O revolts/O and/O clashes/O that/O can/O provoke/O unease/O and/O war/O everywhere/O ./O 
Benedict/PERSON XVI/PERSON and/O John/PERSON Paul/PERSON <PERSON>II/O</PERSON> :/O Human/O rights/O are/O the/O foundation/O of/O peace/O ./O 
Rome/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O In/O today/O 's/O meeting/O with/O his/O Chinese/O counterpart/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ,/O the/O Italian/O president/O Giorgio/PERSON Napolitano/PERSON mentioned/O the/O issue/O of/O human/O rights/O ./O 
Both/O of/O the/O two/O heads/O of/O state/O agreed/O that/O ``/O economic/O development/O in/O China/LOCATION has/O created/O new/O opportunities/O and/O poses/O new/O demands/O in/O the/O field/O of/O human/O rights/O ./O ''/O 
Napolitano/PERSON 's/O words/O echo/O those/O of/O Charter/O 08/O ,/O a/O document/O drafted/O and/O signed/O by/O intellectuals/O ,/O academics/O ,/O activists/O and/O members/O of/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION who/O seek/O -/O in/O a/O non-violent/O way/O -/O democratic/O reforms/O throughout/O country/O to/O stop/O the/O violence/O and/O injustice/O caused/O by/O the/O success/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O development/O and/O its/O complete/O lack/O of/O respect/O for/O human/O dignity/O ./O 
``/O The/O crazed/O results/O -/O states/O Charter/O 08/O -/O are/O endemic/O corruption/O of/O political/O leaders/O ,/O an/O undermining/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O ,/O lack/O of/O protection/O of/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O population/O ,/O a/O loss/O of/O ethics/O ,/O vulgar/O capitalism/O ,/O the/O polarization/O of/O society/O between/O rich/O and/O poor/O ,/O the/O exploitation/O and/O abuse/O of/O the/O natural/O ,/O human/O and/O cultural/O environment/O ,/O the/O aggravation/O of/O a/O long/O list/O of/O social/O conflict/O ,/O most/O notably/O a/O hardening/O of/O animosity/O between/O official/O representatives/O and/O ordinary/O people/O ''/O ./O 
Charter/O 08/O also/O says/O that/O ``/O conflicts/O and/O crises/O are/O growing/O in/O intensity/O ''/O day/O by/O day/O ./O 
As/O if/O to/O confirm/O this/O ,/O last/O night/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> bloody/O clashes/O broke/O out/O between/O local/O people/O and/O police/O ./O 
Although/O China/LOCATION continues/O to/O accuse/O groups/O of/O Uygurs/O in/O exile/O ,/O everyone/O knows/O that/O the/O problem/O is/O internal/O and/O has/O been/O simmering/O for/O decades/O ./O 
With/O the/O excuse/O of/O ``/O fighting/O Islamic/O terrorism/O ''/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O colonizing/O and/O oppressing/O the/O population/O and/O its/O religiosity/O in/O the/O region/O with/O emergency/O legislation/O ./O 
Every/O Friday/O Uygur/O imams/O must/O submit/O to/O the/O government/O the/O text/O of/O their/O sermons/O ,/O religious/O education/O of/O young/O people/O up/O to/O 18/O years/O is/O prohibited/O ,/O Islamic/O schools/O and/O mosques/O have/O been/O destroyed/O -LRB-/O in/O favour/O of/O ``/O economic/O development/O ''/O -RRB-/O ;/O boys/O in/O schools/O are/O forced/O by/O teachers/O to/O eat/O during/O Ramadan/O ./O 
The/O social/O and/O political/O marginalization/O that/O the/O Uygurs/O are/O submitted/O to/O in/O their/O own/O land/O is/O only/O equal/O to/O the/O accusations/O and/O marginalization/O suffered/O by/O Tibetans/O in/O Qinghai/LOCATION ,/O or/O in/O ``/O autonomous/O ''/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
Indeed/O ,/O one/O can/O say/O that/O the/O pattern/O of/O recent/O days/O closely/O follows/O the/O facts/O and/O theories/O of/O the/O Tibetan/O revolt/O before/O the/O Olympics/O in/O March/O 2008/O ./O 
Then/O too/O ,/O a/O peaceful/O demonstration/O turned/O into/O a/O violent/O confrontation/O with/O the/O army/O resulting/O in/O dozens/O of/O deaths/O ,/O followed/O by/O thousands/O of/O arrests/O and/O martial/O law/O ./O 
Violence/O toward/O the/O Uygur/O and/O Tibetan/O minorities/O is/O no/O different/O from/O that/O suffered/O by/O other/O groups/O ./O 
Human/O rights/O activists/O ,/O lawyers/O who/O defend/O the/O poor/O against/O the/O thieving/O of/O Party/ORGANIZATION members/O ;/O peasants/O demonstrating/O against/O the/O expropriation/O of/O their/O land/O and/O homes/O meet/O with/O the/O exact/O same/O response/O from/O the/O government/O :/O suffocation/O and/O repression/O ./O 
Even/O religious/O communities/O ,/O who/O -/O like/O the/O Uygurs/O and/O Tibetans/O --/O have/O no/O territorial/O claims/O ,/O suffer/O the/O same/O violence/O against/O their/O dignity/O and/O freedom/O ./O 
For/O the/O past/O 2/O years/O there/O has/O been/O a/O campaign/O to/O eliminate/O the/O entire/O underground/O Protestant/O community/O and/O their/O so-called/O domestic/O churches/O in/O act/O ;/O the/O destruction/O of/O churches/O ,/O the/O arrest/O of/O pastors/O ,/O the/O faithful/O ,/O beaten/O ,/O the/O dissemination/O of/O the/O Bible/O prohibited/O ./O 
The/O Catholic/O community/O is/O no/O better/O off/O ./O 
Official/O bishops/O -/O about/O 70/O ,/O approved/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION -/O are/O now/O under/O stringent/O control/O because/O secretly/O reconciled/O with/O the/O pope/O ./O 
All/O underground/O bishops/O -LRB-/O approximately/O 40/O -RRB-/O -/O not/O recognized/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION --/O are/O under/O house/O arrest/O ./O 
It/O is/O worth/O remembering/O that/O some/O of/O them/O have/O been/O missing/O for/O some/O time/O :/O Mgr/O ./O 
James/PERSON Su/PERSON Zhimin/PERSON -LRB-/O diocese/O of/O Baoding/LOCATION ,/O Hebei/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O 75/O ,/O arrested/O and/O disappeared/O since/O 1996/O ,/O Msgr./O Cosma/PERSON Shi/PERSON Enxiang/PERSON -LRB-/O diocese/O of/O Yixian/LOCATION ,/O Hebei/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O 86/O years/O ,/O arrested/O and/O disappeared/O on/O April/O 13th/O 2001/O ,/O Msgr./O Julius/PERSON Jia/PERSON Zhiguo/PERSON ,/O who/O disappeared/O for/O the/O umpteenth/O time/O March/O 30th/O last/O ./O 
If/O we/O add/O the/O unemployed/O and/O migrants/O ,/O those/O disgruntled/O by/O the/O current/O economic/O crisis/O to/O the/O Uygurs/O ,/O Tibetans/O ,/O democracy/O activists/O ,/O Protestants/O and/O Catholics/O ,/O it/O becomes/O all/O too/O clear/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O sitting/O on/O a/O powder/O keg/O that/O can/O explode/O at/O any/O moment/O and/O in/O fact/O is/O already/O giving/O rise/O to/O continuous/O revolts/O and/O clashes/O with/O the/O army/O and/O police/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O implosion/O into/O disorder/O would/O have/O global/O repercussions/O ./O 
Never/O before/O has/O the/O nexus/O between/O human/O rights/O and/O peace/O as/O stated/O by/O both/O Benedict/PERSON XVI/PERSON -LRB-/O Message/O to/O UNESCO/ORGANIZATION in/O 2005/O -RRB-/O and/O John/PERSON Paul/PERSON II/PERSON -LRB-/O see/O Message/O for/O World/O Day/O of/O Peace/O 1999/O -RRB-/O been/O more/O evident/O ./O 
By/O not/O respecting/O human/O rights/O ,/O China/LOCATION edges/O the/O world/O closer/O to/O war/O ./O 
The/O Quirinale/O communiqué/O hastened/O to/O state/O that/O any/O steps/O taken/O by/O Italy/LOCATION against/O Beijing/LOCATION regarding/O human/O rights/O will/O be/O made/O in/O ``/O the/O utmost/O respect/O for/O the/O autonomy/O of/O Chinese/O Institutions/O and/O their/O motivations/O ''/O ./O 
Maybe/O ,/O it/O is/O far/O too/O little/O ./O
