Accusations/O of/O separatism/O against/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON and/O the/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
Soldiers/O ,/O policemen/O ,/O security/O personnel/O on/O the/O increase/O to/O prevent/O any/O attempts/O at/O uprising/O ./O 
The/O foreign/O minister/O criticizes/O countries/O that/O welcome/O the/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> ,/O seen/O as/O merely/O ``/O a/O political/O leader/O ./O ''/O 
The/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> is/O asking/O only/O for/O autonomy/O in/O order/O to/O save/O the/O Tibetans/O from/O cultural/O genocide/O ./O 
An/O Uyghur/O academic/O asks/O for/O more/O help/O for/O the/O Muslim/O group/O ,/O in/O the/O grip/O of/O unemployment/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O The/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O deployed/O troops/O and/O strategies/O to/O prevent/O any/O revolts/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O both/O of/O them/O guilty/O ,/O together/O with/O ``/O hostile/O forces/O ,/O ''/O of/O wanting/O to/O destroy/O ``/O national/O unity/O ./O ''/O 
The/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON says/O he/O is/O concerned/O about/O the/O tension/O ;/O moderate/O Uyghurs/O accuse/O the/O government/O of/O impoverishing/O the/O population/O ./O 
In/O a/O study/O group/O connected/O to/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O NPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O underway/O at/O the/O capital/O ,/O the/O governor/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O Qiangba/PERSON Puncog/PERSON ,/O stated/O yesterday/O that/O his/O government/O has/O implemented/O preventive/O measures/O to/O monitor/O any/O threat/O against/O security/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
``/O There/O wo/O n't/O be/O another/O riot/O as/O big/O as/O what/O happened/O on/O March/O 14/O last/O year/O .../O That/O said/O ,/O it/O is/O still/O likely/O that/O some/O individual/O supporters/O of/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O may/O take/O the/O risk/O of/O making/O reckless/O moves/O ./O ''/O 
<PERSON>Qiangba/LOCATION Puncong/LOCATION</PERSON> has/O continued/O to/O criticize/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON and/O his/O government/O in/O exile/O ,/O saying/O that/O they/O constitute/O a/O threat/O to/O stability/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
Today/O ,/O foreign/O minister/O Yang/PERSON Jiechi/PERSON also/O accused/O the/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> of/O not/O being/O ``/O by/O any/O means/O a/O religious/O leader/O ,/O but/O political/O ,/O ''/O who/O is/O seeking/O to/O ``/O separate/O Tibet/LOCATION from/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Yang/PERSON also/O criticized/O those/O countries/O that/O invite/O the/O Tibetan/O religious/O leader/O ./O 
``/O Other/O nations/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ,/O ``/O should/O not/O permit/O visits/O by/O the/O <PERSON>Dalai/O</PERSON> ,/O and/O should/O not/O permit/O him/O to/O use/O their/O territory/O for/O secessionist/O activities/O ./O ''/O 
For/O years/O ,/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON has/O reiterated/O his/O desire/O to/O return/O to/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O asking/O only/O for/O cultural/O and/O religious/O autonomy/O in/O order/O to/O save/O the/O Tibetans/O from/O cultural/O genocide/O ,/O but/O Beijing/LOCATION accuses/O him/O of/O separatist/O activities/O ./O 
In/O recent/O weeks/O ,/O the/O Tibetan/O religious/O leader/O has/O often/O said/O that/O he/O is/O concerned/O about/O the/O increasing/O tension/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O which/O could/O lead/O to/O clashes/O and/O more/O deaths/O and/O arrests/O ,/O as/O happened/O last/O year/O ./O 
This/O year/O is/O also/O the/O 50th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O Tibetan/O revolt/O in/O 1959/O ,/O which/O was/O suffocated/O with/O military/O repression/O and/O led/O to/O the/O exile/O of/O the/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> ./O 
``/O It/O 's/O necessary/O to/O increase/O the/O number/O of/O the/O armed/O police/O ,/O police/O ,/O firemen/O ,/O border/O forces/O and/O public/O security/O ,/O ''/O Qiangba/PERSON Puncong/PERSON says/O ./O 
In/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> as/O well/O ,/O where/O the/O Uyghur/O community/O is/O asking/O for/O greater/O autonomy/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O providing/O extra/O military/O control/O ./O 
This/O year/O ,/O China/LOCATION wants/O to/O celebrate/O the/O 60th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O ``/O peaceful/O liberation/O ''/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O with/O the/O entry/O of/O the/O Chinese/O army/O into/O the/O region/O ./O 
But/O many/O Uyghurs/O see/O this/O as/O an/O invasion/O ./O 
Yesterday/O ,/O again/O during/O a/O study/O group/O at/O the/O NPC/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O governor/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O <U_PERSON>Nur/PERSON Bekri/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O said/O that/O ``/O the/O task/O of/O security/O will/O be/O more/O arduous/O ,/O and/O the/O struggle/O more/O fierce/O in/O the/O region/O this/O year/O .../O It/O 's/O a/O time/O of/O celebration/O for/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> people/O ,/O but/O hostile/O forces/O will/O not/O pass/O on/O such/O an/O opportunity/O to/O destroy/O it/O ./O ''/O 
Last/O year/O ,/O in/O order/O to/O prevent/O ``/O terrorist/O attacks/O ''/O at/O the/O Olympics/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION arrested/O more/O than/O 1,000/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
But/O personalities/O of/O this/O Muslim/O ethnicity/O accuse/O the/O Chinese/O government/O of/O being/O insensitive/O to/O the/O group/O 's/O basic/O economic/O necessities/O ./O 
According/O to/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O professor/O of/O economics/O at/O the/O central/O university/O for/O the/O nationalities/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O the/O most/O serious/O problem/O for/O the/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/LOCATION</OTHER> is/O unemployment/O ./O 
This/O is/O due/O to/O the/O marginalization/O of/O the/O group/O from/O administrative/O structures/O and/O state/O industries/O ,/O and/O to/O the/O policy/O of/O colonization/O ,/O which/O every/O year/O transfers/O thousands/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O to/O the/O region/O ./O 
In/O an/O interview/O with/O <ORGANIZATION>Radio/O Free/O Asia/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> ,/O Tohti/PERSON accused/O Governor/O Behkri/PERSON of/O insensitivity/O toward/O the/O Uyghurs/O :/O ``/O He/O 's/O always/O stressed/O the/O stability/O and/O security/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O threatened/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> has/O developed/O ,/O but/O the/O people/O are/O living/O in/O poverty/O ,/O especially/O Uyghurs/O ./O ''/O
