Exiled/O leader/O will/O hold/O a/O press/O conference/O and/O might/O meet/O lawmakers/O from/O Japan/LOCATION 's/O ruling/O party/O ./O 
China/LOCATION responds/O by/O saying/O that/O visit/O could/O jeopardise/O bilateral/O relations/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O internet/O is/O restored/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> but/O only/O for/O government/O sites/O ./O 
Tokyo/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O Exiled/O Uyghur/O leader/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> has/O arrived/O in/O Japan/LOCATION despite/O China/LOCATION 's/O displeasure/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION had/O called/O on/O Japan/LOCATION to/O deny/O her/O a/O visa/O ./O 
In/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O which/O is/O still/O under/O martial/O law/O ,/O internet/O access/O has/O been/O restored/O but/O only/O for/O pro-China/O sites/O ./O 
Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> came/O from/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O where/O she/O lives/O in/O exile/O ,/O on/O a/O five-day/O visit/O and/O is/O expected/O to/O hold/O a/O much/O awaited/O press/O conference/O tomorrow/O ./O 
She/O is/O likely/O to/O talk/O about/O the/O unrest/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> earlier/O this/O month/O ./O 
China/LOCATION claims/O that/O almost/O 200/O people/O ,/O mostly/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O died/O ;/O Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> said/O that/O thousands/O have/O died/O ,/O killed/O on/O masse/O by/O police/O ./O 
She/O is/O also/O expected/O to/O meet/O members/O of/O Prime/O Minister/O Taro/PERSON Aso/PERSON 's/O party/O ,/O but/O the/O contact/O will/O be/O unofficial/O for/O security/O reasons/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION had/O called/O on/O Tokyo/LOCATION to/O deny/O Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> the/O entry/O visa/O ./O 
Through/O its/O spokesman/O Qin/PERSON Gang/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION expressed/O its/O dissatisfaction/O with/O the/O trip/O ./O 
For/O Beijing/LOCATION Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> is/O a/O dangerous/O terrorist/O ,/O involved/O in/O separatist/O activities/O who/O masterminded/O this/O month/O 's/O violent/O protests/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Because/O of/O similar/O charges/O she/O spent/O around/O six/O years/O in/O a/O Chinese/O prison/O before/O being/O released/O under/O international/O pressure/O in/O 2005/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O ambassador/O to/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O Cui/PERSON Tiankai/PERSON ,/O also/O warned/O that/O a/O visit/O by/O this/O ``/O criminal/O ''/O would/O damage/O relations/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O ./O 
By/O contrast/O ,/O in/O recent/O weeks/O Japan/LOCATION criticised/O China/LOCATION 's/O bloody/O crackdown/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O calling/O on/O Chinese/O authorities/O to/O protect/O the/O human/O rights/O of/O Uyghur/O people/O ./O 
In/O the/O meantime/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> access/O to/O the/O internet/O and/O text/O messaging/O has/O been/O restored/O only/O today/O ./O 
Yang/PERSON Guoqing/PERSON ,/O a/O spokesperson/O for/O the/O provincial/O government/O news/O center/O ,/O said/O the/O government/O is/O now/O sending/O text/O messages/O to/O citizens/O to/O inform/O them/O ``/O about/O the/O latest/O situation/O ''/O ./O 
Internet/O has/O been/O restored/O as/O well/O but/O only/O to/O a/O few/O select/O government/O and/O business-related/O Web/O sites/O ;/O all/O the/O other/O are/O still/O being/O blocked/O ./O 
Well-known/O social/O networking/O sites/O like/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION and/O <ORGANIZATION>Twitter/O</ORGANIZATION> have/O been/O blocked/O nationwide/O for/O weeks/O ./O
