Women/O and/O girls/O seeking/O the/O release/O of/O their/O relatives/O detained/O in/O recent/O days/O ./O 
Demonstrations/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O <U_LOCATION>Y覺l覺/PERSON</U_LOCATION> ,/O <U_LOCATION>Dawan/PERSON</U_LOCATION> and/O <U_LOCATION>Tianshan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_LOCATION> :/O The/O violence/O reveals/O deep/O problems/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O never/O wanted/O to/O deal/O with/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O <OTHER>Agencies/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> -RRB-/O -/O Several/O hundred/O people/O ,/O mostly/O women/O and/O girls/O ,/O are/O challenging/O the/O cordons/O of/O police/O on/O the/O streets/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> :/O protesting/O against/O Chinese/O repression/O and/O demanding/O the/O release/O of/O their/O relatives/O ,/O who/O were/O arrested/O after/O the/O revolts/O of/O July/O 5/O ./O 
This/O morning/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION updated/O the/O number/O of/O victims/O and/O of/O those/O arrested/O :/O in/O the/O clashes/O with/O the/O police/O ,/O there/O were/O 156/O deaths/O and/O 1434/O arrests/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O continues/O to/O discharge/O the/O responsibilities/O of/O violence/O against/O the/O demonstrators/O ,/O but/O the/O population/O accuses/O the/O police/O of/O having/O fired/O on/O defenceless/O people/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O yesterday/O the/O demonstrations/O spread/O to/O other/O cities/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
In/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> more/O than/O 200/O people/O tried/O to/O gather/O at/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Id/LOCATION Kah/LOCATION</U_ORGANIZATION> mosque/O ,/O but/O were/O dispersed/O by/O police/O ./O 
The/O police/O have/O made/O arrests/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Y覺l覺/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O <U_LOCATION>Dawan/PERSON</U_LOCATION> and/O <U_LOCATION>Tianshan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
In/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O women/O and/O girls/O seeking/O the/O release/O of/O their/O loved/O ones/O ,/O have/O challenged/O the/O control/O of/O the/O city/O and/O the/O roads/O patrolled/O by/O tanks/O and/O scores/O of/O police/O officers/O wearing/O camouflage/O ./O 
Shouting/O ``/O Give/O us/O back/O our/O freedom/O !/O 
Give/O us/O back/O our/O men/O ./O ''/O 
The/O demonstration/O was/O witnessed/O by/O a/O group/O of/O foreign/O journalists/O who/O were/O being/O brought/O on/O a/O tour/O organized/O by/O the/O government/O to/O show/O the/O destruction/O caused/O by/O the/O demonstrators/O two/O days/O ago/O ./O 
The/O police/O surrounded/O the/O group/O and/O then/O dispersed/O them/O ./O 
But/O other/O groups/O of/O protesters/O are/O gathering/O in/O the/O city/O centre/O ./O 
Tens/O of/O thousands/O of/O policemen/O and/O soldiers/O were/O hired/O to/O maintain/O control/O of/O the/O situation/O and/O to/O carry/O out/O a/O series/O of/O indiscriminate/O arrests/O and/O destruction/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION continues/O to/O accuse/O groups/O of/O exiled/O Uygurs/O of/O organizing/O and/O fomenting/O the/O uprisings/O ./O 
But/O the/O same/O groups/O deny/O any/O influence/O ,/O and/O accuse/O China/LOCATION of/O doing/O nothing/O to/O prevent/O the/O degeneration/O of/O the/O non-violent/O demonstrations/O into/O carnage/O ./O 
Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AI/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O has/O asked/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O investigate/O the/O deaths/O and/O violence/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O demand/O the/O international/O community/O put/O pressure/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O respect/O human/O rights/O ./O 
``/O Beyond/O the/O immediate/O violence/O -/O AI/O says/O --/O a/O systematic/O violation/O of/O human/O rights/O has/O been/O inflicted/O on/O the/O Uighurs/O ''/O since/O the/O 80s/O ./O 
For/O decades/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O colonizing/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O which/O is/O rich/O in/O oil/O and/O gas/O ,/O importing/O many/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O who/O have/O now/O become/O the/O majority/O in/O the/O region/O and/O hold/O all/O political/O and/O economic/O power/O ./O 
To/O justify/O its/O iron/O fist/O Beijing/LOCATION accuses/O the/O Uygurs/O of/O separatists/O aspirations/O and/O terrorist/O attacks/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O the/O exiled/O Uygurs/O who/O China/LOCATION accuses/O of/O being/O behind/O the/O riots/O ,/O speaking/O in/O Washington/LOCATION said/O yesterday/O that/O the/O violence/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ``/O reveals/O deep/O ,/O serious/O problems/O that/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O not/O wanted/O to/O tackle/O or/O mitigate/O ''/O ./O
