The/O places/O of/O worship/O and/O the/O main/O roads/O of/O the/O city/O are/O patrolled/O by/O tens/O of/O thousands/O of/O soldiers/O ./O 
The/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION has/O announced/O a/O hard/O line/O against/O ``/O extremists/O ,/O separatists/O ,/O terrorists/O ./O ''/O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/<ORGANIZATION>O AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O The/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> government/O has/O ordered/O the/O closure/O of/O mosques/O for/O Friday/O prayer/O ./O 
The/O official/O reason/O is/O for/O the/O safety/O of/O the/O inhabitants/O ,/O still/O fearful/O of/O finding/O itself/O caught/O between/O belligerent/O groups/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O or/O Uyghurs/O but/O in/O reality/O the/O suspicion/O is/O that/O the/O places/O of/O prayer/O are/O used/O to/O instigate/O the/O revolt/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> mosques/O are/O guarded/O by/O soldiers/O and/O signs/O inviting/O the/O faithful/O to/O pray/O at/O home/O have/O been/O hung/O on/O the/O buildings/O ./O 
Despite/O this/O ,/O a/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> government/O spokesman/O has/O said/O that/O ``/O all/O religious/O activities/O should/O carry/O on/O as/O normal/O ./O ''/O 
The/O city/O is/O quiet/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O being/O patrolled/O by/O tens/O of/O thousands/O of/O armed/O soldiers/O ./O 
The/O reason/O given/O is/O ``/O for/O traffic/O control/O ,/O ''/O but/O in/O fact/O the/O deployment/O of/O armed/O forces/O is/O to/O prevent/O demonstrations/O and/O riots/O as/O seen/O in/O recent/O days/O ,/O with/O clashes/O between/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/LOCATION</OTHER> and/O thousands/O of/O police/O and/O violence/O between/O groups/O of/O Han/O and/O Muslim/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
The/O situation/O is/O so/O tense/O that/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON rushed/O back/O to/O China/LOCATION from/O the/O G8/O summit/O in/O Italy/LOCATION ./O 
The/O inter-ethnic/O conflict/O ,/O which/O could/O spread/O to/O other/O regions/O of/O the/O country/O ,/O has/O drawn/O a/O hard/O line/O response/O from/O the/O Leadership/O ./O 
Yesterday/O ,/O a/O communiqué/O was/O released/O at/O the/O conclusion/O of/O an/O emergency/O meeting/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Politburo/ORGANIZATION ,/O presided/O over/O by/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O stated/O that/O ``/O The/O planners/O of/O the/O incident/O ,/O the/O organisers/O ,/O key/O members/O and/O the/O serious/O violent/O criminals/O must/O be/O severely/O punished/O ./O ''/O 
Previously/O ,/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> Party/ORGANIZATION secretary/O had/O threatened/O the/O death/O penalty/O for/O all/O those/O who/O were/O responsible/O for/O killings/O in/O recent/O days/O ./O 
After/O this/O week/O 's/O incidents/O ,/O which/O killed/O 156/O people/O ,/O injuring/O nearly/O a/O thousand/O ,/O there/O were/O at/O least/O 1400/O arrests/O ./O 
While/O telephone/O lines/O have/O been/O cut/O and/O the/O Internet/O does/O not/O work/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O media/O continues/O to/O proclaim/O that/O the/O riots/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O other/O cities/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> are/O part/O of/O a/O subversive/O Islamic/O extremism/O ./O 
Yesterday/O ,/O Qin/PERSON Gang/PERSON ,/O a/O spokesman/O of/O the/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION said/O that/O there/O is/O ``/O much/O evidence/O ''/O that/O some/O of/O those/O involved/O in/O the/O violence/O ``/O have/O been/O trained/O by/O terrorist/O groups/O including/O <ORGANIZATION>al/O Qaeda/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O ''/O 
Qin/PERSON did/O not/O mention/O what/O that/O evidence/O was/O ,/O but/O said/O that/O the/O groups/O are/O ``/O closely/O linked/O with/O three/O evil/O forces/O abroad/O ./O ''/O 
The/O ``/O three/O forces/O ''/O being/O extremists/O ,/O separatists/O and/O terrorists/O ./O 
Among/O the/O Uyghurs/O there/O are/O groups/O that/O are/O inspired/O by/O Islamic/O extremism/O ,/O but/O most/O of/O them/O only/O seek/O greater/O autonomy/O and/O religious/O freedom/O in/O the/O face/O of/O a/O forced/O colonization/O of/O the/O region/O ./O 
To/O combat/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O Beijing/LOCATION controls/O every/O aspect/O of/O life/O of/O the/O Uyghurs/O and/O their/O religion/O ./O 
Every/O Friday/O morning/O ,/O the/O Muslim/O holy/O day/O ,/O the/O imams/O have/O to/O present/O themselves/O at/O the/O local/O Office/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Religious/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION to/O explain/O the/O text/O of/O the/O sermons/O that/O they/O will/O give/O and/O receive/O ``/O general/O indications/O ''/O ./O 
Every/O religious/O group/O must/O be/O registered/O with/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION Religious/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O appointment/O of/O leaders/O must/O be/O approved/O by/O the/O authorities/O ./O 
Parents/O '/O are/O not/O permitted/O to/O give/O religious/O education/O to/O their/O children/O ./O 
Children/O under/O 18/O are/O forbidden/O to/O attend/O mosques/O ./O 
During/O the/O fasting/O month/O of/O Ramadan/O ,/O the/O school/O authorities/O force/O Muslim/O students/O and/O teachers/O to/O eat/O ,/O breaking/O the/O fast/O ./O 
In/O many/O cities/O --/O also/O thanks/O to/O a/O rampant/O modernization/O -/O mosques/O ,/O Islamic/O schools/O and/O houses/O have/O been/O expropriated/O and/O destroyed/O to/O make/O room/O for/O banks/O ,/O buildings/O and/O offices/O ./O
