New/O trial/O might/O also/O end/O with/O death/O penalty/O ./O 
For/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O executions/O will/O increase/O poplar/O anger/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O The/O trial/O of/O 14/O people/O accused/O of/O involvement/O in/O ethnic/O unrest/O that/O shook/O China/LOCATION 's/O far/O western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O in/O July/O opened/O today/O ,/O authorities/O said/O ,/O two/O days/O after/O six/O Uyghur/O men/O were/O sentenced/O to/O death/O for/O the/O same/O offences/O ./O 
The/O defendants/O are/O charged/O with/O murder/O ,/O robbery/O ,/O arson/O and/O vandalism/O ,/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O reported/O ,/O in/O connection/O with/O the/O violence/O that/O broke/O out/O after/O a/O peaceful/O demonstration/O got/O out/O of/O hand/O and/O turned/O into/O a/O race/O riot/O between/O Muslim/O Uyghurs/O and/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
A/O late/O intervention/O by/O police/O and/O the/O military/O ended/O the/O unrest/O that/O left/O almost/O 200/O people/O dead/O and/O led/O to/O a/O thousand/O arrests/O ./O 
For/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O demonstrations/O and/O clashes/O were/O orchestrated/O by/O the/O Uyghur/O Diaspora/O ,/O led/O by/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ./O 
For/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O exiled/O Uyghur/O leader/O is/O a/O terrorist/O ./O 
The/O 14/O were/O part/O of/O a/O group/O of/O 21/O people/O charged/O with/O offenses/O relating/O to/O the/O unrest/O ./O 
Six/O have/O already/O been/O given/O the/O death/O penalty/O ;/O a/O seventh/O was/O sentenced/O to/O life/O in/O prison/O ./O 
In/O criticising/O the/O court/O 's/O decision/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> said/O ,/O ``/O This/O is/O not/O going/O to/O create/O peace/O and/O stability/O in/O the/O region/O ;/O this/O will/O further/O enrage/O the/O Uyghur/O people/O ./O ''/O 
Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O who/O an/O important/O leader/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O also/O said/O she/O feared/O that/O many/O of/O the/O arrested/O -LRB-/O in/O addition/O to/O those/O who/O were/O sentenced/O to/O death/O -RRB-/O were/O tortured/O and/O that/O others/O simply/O disappeared/O ./O 
For/O more/O than/O half/O a/O century/O ,/O Uyghurs/O have/O been/O demanding/O greater/O autonomy/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O central/O government/O ./O 
Some/O groups/O in/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Islamic/LOCATION Movement/LOCATION of/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION</U_ORGANIZATION> have/O successfully/O carried/O out/O terrorist/O attacks/O against/O China/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O wielded/O an/O iron/O fist/O in/O the/O province/O ,/O arresting/O and/O sentencing/O hundreds/O to/O death/O per/O year/O ./O 
On/O the/O pretext/O of/O stopping/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O also/O placed/O the/O Uyghurs/O '/O religious/O life/O under/O tight/O control/O ./O 
This/O includes/O monitoring/O imams/O '/O speeches/O ,/O banning/O young/O people/O from/O attending/O Friday/O prayers/O in/O mosques/O ,/O and/O demolishing/O mosques/O and/O Islamic/O schools/O ./O
