<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O the/O exiled/O Uyghur/O leader/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O protests/O :/O ``/O There/O is/O more/O attention/O ,/O but/O the/O economic/O power/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION prevents/O nations/O from/O doing/O anything/O concrete/O for/O us/O ''/O ./O 
Thousands/O of/O Uyghur/O arrested/O during/O the/O riots/O of/O July/O 5/O still/O imprisoned/O were/O ./O 
Worldwide/O event/O for/O the/O first/O anniversary/O of/O the/O massacre/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O The/O world/O ``/O shows/O more/O attention/O to/O the/O Uyghur/O cause/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O but/O could/O do/O much/O more/O for/O us/O ''/O ,/O says/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O the/O Uyghur/O leader/O exiled/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION to/O commemorate/O the/O first/O anniversary/O of/O one/O of/O the/O bloodiest/O ethnic/O riots/O to/O take/O place/O in/O the/O Asian/O country/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O to/O control/O the/O situation/O ,/O the/O central/O government/O has/O installed/O 40/O thousand/O cameras/O in/O the/O provincial/O capital/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
A/O year/O ago/O ,/O in/O fact/O ,/O an/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O Muslim/O community/O residing/O in/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> challenged/O the/O domination/O of/O central/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
During/O the/O clashes/O ,/O according/O to/O official/O sources/O ,/O 200/O people/O were/O killed/O ./O 
A/O further/O 1,700/O were/O wounded/O ,/O while/O the/O number/O of/O arrests/O is/O unknown/O :/O according/O to/O dissident/O leader/O ,/O there/O are/O tens/O of/O thousands/O detained/O ./O 
The/O Uyghur/O are/O not/O asking/O for/O independence/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O but/O demand/O greater/O autonomy/O ./O 
Although/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -/O the/O dissidents/O call/O the/O region/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -/O is/O one/O of/O the/O provinces/O with/O special/O status/O created/O by/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON ,/O residents/O accuse/O the/O authorities/O of/O banning/O education/O in/O the/O local/O language/O and/O customs/O ,/O in/O favour/O of/O the/O dominant/O Chinese/O Han/O ethnicity/O ./O 
The/O latter/O ,/O supported/O by/O authorities/O ,/O also/O enact/O a/O kind/O of/O ``/O economic/O racism/O ''/O which/O tends/O to/O keep/O the/O natives/O of/O the/O region/O far/O from/O the/O centres/O of/O power/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O 63/O year/O old/O mother/O of/O 11/O children/O ,/O spent/O many/O years/O in/O prison/O because/O of/O her/O opposition/O to/O the/O Chinese/O regime/O but/O -/O before/O the/O confrontation/O -/O tried/O to/O use/O the/O ``/O institutional/O ''/O channels/O to/O advance/O the/O cause/O of/O her/O people/O ./O 
She/O was/O a/O deputy/O at/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Assembly/ORGANIZATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O was/O a/O successful/O business/O woman/O ./O 
Today/O ,/O in/O exile/O in/O the/O U.S./LOCATION ,/O she/O says/O :/O ``/O I/O 'm/O just/O an/O ordinary/O woman/O ,/O but/O I/O fear/O the/O government. This/O shows/O that/O my/O demands/O are/O just/O ./O ''/O 
China/LOCATION ``/O accuses/O the/O Uyghur/O of/O being/O Islamic/O extremists/O ,/O but/O has/O no/O evidence/O to/O support/O these/O false/O accusations/O ./O 
What/O it/O does/O have/O is/O an/O enormous/O economic/O power/O ,/O which/O allows/O it/O to/O silence/O the/O protests/O of/O Western/O governments/O and/O the/O Muslims/O ''/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION announced/O it/O would/O invest/O about/O 10/O billion/O Yuan/O -LRB-/O 1/O billion/O -RRB-/O in/O the/O region/O by/O 2011/O ,/O to/O ``/O improve/O the/O Uyghur/O 's/O living/O conditions/O ''/O ./O 
According/O to/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O this/O announcement/O ``/O is/O part/O of/O Chinese/O trade/O policy/O ./O 
If/O they/O really/O want/O to/O change/O things/O ,/O they/O must/O release/O the/O innocent/O people/O they/O have/O detained/O and/O apologized/O for/O what/O they/O have/O done/O not/O only/O to/O the/O Uyghur/O ,/O but/O all/O the/O people/O of/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ''/O ./O 
In/O any/O case/O ,/O it/O seems/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O attitude/O is/O not/O destined/O to/O change/O ./O 
On/O the/O anniversary/O of/O the/O massacre/O ,/O which/O falls/O on/O 5/O July/O ,/O the/O police/O have/O locked/O down/O the/O capital/O ./O 
Forty/O thousand/O cameras/O have/O been/O installed/O on/O public/O buses/O ,/O stations/O ,/O along/O 4/O thousand/O streets/O ,/O 270/O schools/O and/O 100/O supermarkets/O ./O 
According/O to/O authorities/O ,/O the/O electronic/O eyes/O are/O ``/O to/O ensure/O safety/O in/O most/O important/O public/O places/O and/O allow/O all/O people/O of/O all/O ethnic/O groups/O ,/O to/O enjoy/O government/O services/O ''/O ./O 
Against/O Chinese/O repression/O ,/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O Association/O which/O gathers/O dissidents/O '/O from/O the/O ethnic/O group/O from/O around/O the/O world/O -RRB-/O has/O organized/O an/O international/O event/O for/O the/O anniversary/O ./O 
Protest/O marches/O are/O planned/O in/O front/O of/O Chinese/O embassies/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O Britain/LOCATION and/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O
