Chinese/O military/O expenditures/O are/O second/O only/O to/O those/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O twice/O higher/O than/O India/LOCATION 's/O ./O 
Many/O experts/O believe/O that/O the/O actual/O defence/O budget/O is/O much/O higher/O ./O 
National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O criticises/O Obama/PERSON for/O meeting/O the/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> and/O world/O leaders/O for/O using/O Taiwan/LOCATION to/O interfere/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O internal/O affairs/O ./O 
He/O claims/O `/O solidarity/O and/O harmony/O ''/O reign/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O --/O China/LOCATION announced/O that/O its/O military/O budget/O would/O increase/O by/O 7.5/O per/O cent/O in/O 2010/O ,/O the/O lowest/O jump/O in/O the/O past/O ten/O years/O ./O 
It/O will/O spend/O 532.1/O billion/O yuan/O -LRB-/O US$/O 78/O billion/O -RRB-/O over/O the/O year/O ./O 
Last/O year/O 's/O growth/O was/O 14.9/O per/O cent/O and/O ranged/O between/O 10/O and/O 14/O per/O cent/O in/O previous/O years/O ./O 
In/O today/O 's/O press/O conference/O ,/O Li/PERSON Zhaoxing/PERSON -LRB-/O pictured/O -RRB-/O ,/O spokesman/O for/O the/O annual/O session/O of/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O NPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O said/O that/O China/LOCATION has/O always/O pursued/O a/O path/O of/O peaceful/O development/O ./O 
He/O noted/O that/O its/O ``/O defence/O expenditure/O in/O recent/O years/O accounted/O for/O about/O 1.4/O per/O cent/O of/O its/O GDP/O ,/O ''/O compared/O to/O 4/O per/O cent/O for/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O and/O more/O than/O 2/O per/O cent/O for/O the/O United/LOCATION Kingdom/LOCATION ,/O France/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O military/O spending/O is/O second/O only/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O which/O aims/O to/O spend/O US$/O 636.3/O billion/O this/O year/O ,/O and/O is/O more/O than/O double/O India/LOCATION 's/O budget/O of/O US$/O 32.1/O billion/O ./O 
Wen/PERSON Bing/PERSON ,/O a/O researcher/O with/O the/O Military/ORGANIZATION Science/ORGANIZATION Academy/ORGANIZATION <OTHER>of/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> <OTHER>the/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Chinese/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O the/O slowdown/O in/O defence/O budget/O increase/O is/O due/O to/O the/O lingering/O global/O financial/O crisis/O and/O the/O world/O 's/O improving/O security/O environment/O ./O 
However/O ,/O many/O experts/O note/O that/O other/O governments/O in/O the/O region/O have/O either/O cut/O or/O held/O expenditure/O steady/O ,/O raising/O concerns/O that/O a/O power/O imbalance/O was/O building/O ./O 
As/O to/O allay/O such/O fears/O ,/O Li/PERSON said/O that/O the/O country/O 's/O limited/O military/O force/O was/O only/O designed/O to/O safeguard/O its/O sovereignty/O and/O territorial/O integrity/O ./O 
In/O reality/O ,/O many/O observers/O believe/O that/O China/LOCATION underestimates/O its/O military/O expenditures/O ./O 
For/O example/O ,/O China/LOCATION budgeted/O 480.7/O billion/O yuan/O for/O defence/O last/O year/O but/O actually/O spent/O 495/O billion/O ./O 
In/O addition/O ,/O it/O does/O not/O include/O certain/O items/O in/O its/O defence/O budget/O ./O 
The/O Pentagon/ORGANIZATION estimates/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION actually/O spends/O at/O least/O twice/O as/O much/O as/O it/O claims/O ./O 
Whatever/O the/O case/O may/O be/O ,/O ``/O China/LOCATION will/O adhere/O to/O a/O path/O of/O peaceful/O development/O and/O defensive/O military/O policies/O ,/O ''/O Li/PERSON insisted/O ./O 
In/O an/O obvious/O reference/O to/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON ,/O he/O criticised/O some/O countries/O during/O the/O press/O conference/O for/O interfering/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O internal/O affairs/O ./O 
He/O also/O said/O that/O Chinese/O people/O were/O angry/O with/O the/O meeting/O between/O certain/O foreign/O leaders/O and/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ,/O and/O that/O using/O the/O Taiwan/LOCATION issue/O to/O interfere/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O internal/O affairs/O was/O ``/O unacceptable/O ''/O ./O 
By/O contrast/O ,/O the/O situation/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O remote/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Uygur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> was/O ``/O stable/O ''/O ,/O he/O said/O ,/O and/O that/O ``/O solidarity/O ,/O mutual/O assistance/O and/O harmony/O are/O being/O consolidated/O and/O developed/O ''/O ./O 
In/O July/O of/O last/O year/O ,/O a/O peaceful/O demonstration/O by/O indigenous/O Uyghurs/PERSON turned/O into/O unrest/O against/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O who/O reacted/O by/O going/O on/O a/O violent/O rampage/O ./O 
During/O the/O civil/O strife/O that/O ensued/O ,/O 197/O were/O killed/O ,/O thousands/O were/O arrested/O and/O tens/O of/O people/O were/O sentenced/O to/O death/O ./O
