Uyghur/O intellectual/O <U_PERSON>Hailie/PERSON Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O who/O works/O for/O the/O ethnic/O understanding/O ,/O sentenced/O to/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O ,/O 51/O lawyers/O and/O professors/O write/O to/O the/O Chinese/O government/O :/O ``/O respect/O freedom/O of/O expression/O and/O human/O rights/O ,/O or/O the/O nation/O will/O collapse/O ''/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O A/O group/O of/O 51/O Chinese/O Han/O lawyers/O and/O professors/O has/O published/O an/O open/O letter/O expressing/O their/O concern/O about/O the/O ``/O criminalization/O of/O free/O speech/O ''/O that/O occured/O in/O the/O case/O of/O journalist/O imagine/O <U_PERSON>Hailie/PERSON Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O sentenced/O last/O July/O 23/O to/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O endangering/O state/O security/O ./O 
The/O letter/O ,/O which/O we/O publish/O in/O full/O ,/O was/O posted/O on/O the/O Internet/O by/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Defender/ORGANIZATION and/O has/O been/O circulated/O on/O mainland/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Respect/ORGANIZATION Freedom/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Expression/ORGANIZATION ,/O Release/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> Journalist/O <U_PERSON>Hailaite/PERSON Niyaz/PERSON</U_PERSON> We/O have/O learned/O that/O 51-year/O old/O Uyghur/O journalist/O and/O author/O <U_PERSON>Hailaite/PERSON Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> -LRB-/O whose/O name/O also/O appears/O as/O <U_PERSON>Hairat/O</U_PERSON> or/O <U_PERSON>Gheyret/PERSON Niyaz/PERSON</U_PERSON> or/O <U_PERSON>Niyaze/O</U_PERSON> -RRB-/O was/O recently/O sentenced/O to/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O by/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Urumqi/ORGANIZATION Intermediate/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Uyghur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>XUAR/O</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O for/O ``/O leaking/O state/O secrets/O ./O ''/O 
Born/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Qoqek/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>Tacheng/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>XUAR/O</U_LOCATION> ,/O <U_PERSON>Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> graduated/O from/O the/O Minzu/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O has/O previously/O held/O the/O positions/O of/O Chief/O Editorial/O Director/O of/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Xinjiang/O Legal/O Daily/O</U_ORGANIZATION> and/O Deputy/O Director/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Perspectives/O on/O the/O Rule/O of/O Law/O</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Fazhi/PERSON Zongheng/PERSON</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O magazine/O publishing/O house/O ./O 
A/O former/O editor/O and/O director/O of/O the/O website/O Uighurbiz.net/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O manager/O of/O the/O site/O 's/O discussion/O forum/O ,/O for/O a/O long/O time/O <U_PERSON>Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> has/O written/O online/O essays/O in/O Chinese/O ,/O gradually/O building/O a/O wide/O following/O among/O China/LOCATION 's/O netizens/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> combined/O his/O personal/O experiences/O facing/O problems/O affecting/O the/O Uyghur/O community/O with/O systematic/O research/O ./O 
According/O to/O an/O <LOCATION>Asia/O</LOCATION> Weekly/O report/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> carefully/O tracked/O Uyghur/O netizen/O reactions/O to/O the/O 2009/O Shaoguan/LOCATION incident/O in/O Guangdong/LOCATION Province/LOCATION and/O came/O to/O the/O conclusion/O that/O a/O major/O incident/O was/O likely/O to/O take/O place/O on/O July/O 5/O ,/O 2009/O ./O 
Around/O eight/O o'clock/O on/O the/O evening/O of/O July/O 4/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> contacted/O government/O officials/O to/O warn/O them/O of/O his/O findings/O ;/O the/O next/O morning/O ,/O at/O 10/O am/O ,/O he/O personally/O met/O with/O top/O officials/O of/O the/O <U_LOCATION>XUAR/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> to/O offer/O three/O specific/O recommendations/O ./O 
However/O ,/O officials/O did/O not/O act/O on/O his/O recommendations/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> believed/O that/O the/O July/O incident/O 's/O causes/O could/O be/O traced/O to/O dissatisfaction/O with/O bilingual/O education/O initiatives/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O government-organized/O efforts/O to/O send/O Uyghurs/O to/O other/O provinces/O to/O work/O as/O industrial/O laborers/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> expressed/O the/O above/O opinions/O in/O media/O interviews/O ,/O and/O soon/O thereafter/O published/O an/O article/O regarding/O the/O September/O 3rd/O incident/O -LSB-/O a/O demonstration/O by/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> demanding/O the/O removal/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> Chief/O Wang/PERSON Lequan/PERSON for/O mishandling/O the/O July/O 5/O violence/O -RSB-/O ./O 
His/O articles/O pointed/O out/O that/O Uyghurs/O have/O not/O received/O tangible/O economic/O benefits/O despite/O living/O in/O a/O resource-rich/O region/O ,/O and/O have/O been/O gradually/O marginalized/O and/O pushed/O into/O poverty/O ./O 
Furthermore/O ,/O as/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> government/O has/O expanded/O anti-terrorism/O policies/O and/O anti-splittist/O ideological/O campaigns/O in/O the/O past/O 20/O years/O and/O set/O up/O checkpoints/O around/O the/O <U_LOCATION>XUAR/O</U_LOCATION> ,/O Uyghurs/O in/O many/O areas/O have/O been/O subjected/O to/O dehumanizing/O searches/O and/O inspections/O which/O have/O heightened/O anxieties/O in/O the/O Uyghur/O community/O and/O aggravated/O ethnic/O conflict/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> is/O a/O Uyghur/O intellectual/O who/O upholds/O the/O spirit/O of/O independence/O ,/O and/O who/O for/O a/O long/O time/O has/O been/O greatly/O concerned/O about/O the/O fate/O of/O China/LOCATION and/O its/O ethnic/O minorities/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O with/O problems/O affecting/O citizens/O '/O civil/O rights/O and/O livelihood/O ./O 
He/O promoted/O increasing/O mutual/O understanding/O between/O Uyghurs/O and/O Han/O and/O his/O views/O about/O politics/O and/O culture/O are/O moderate/O and/O rational/O ,/O to/O the/O point/O that/O some/O believed/O he/O was/O sympathetic/O to/O the/O regime/O ./O 
This/O kind/O of/O intellectual/O is/O extremely/O important/O in/O advancing/O communication/O and/O reconciliation/O between/O ethnic/O groups/O ./O 
The/O groundless/O charges/O brought/O against/O <U_PERSON>Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O and/O the/O severe/O sentence/O he/O has/O received/O ,/O are/O bound/O to/O foment/O extremist/O thoughts/O and/O actions/O and/O deepen/O ethnic/O tensions/O ./O 
Chinese/O citizens/O of/O all/O ethnicities/O ,/O including/O Han/O and/O Uyghur/O ,/O are/O affected/O negatively/O by/O this/O sentence/O ./O 
Additionally/O ,/O we/O have/O learned/O that/O more/O Uyghur/O website/O managers/O and/O journalists/O have/O been/O arrested/O or/O imprisoned/O for/O expressing/O their/O opinions/O ./O 
We/O are/O deeply/O troubled/O by/O this/O news/O ./O 
We/O believe/O that/O the/O thoughts/O and/O opinions/O of/O every/O person/O ,/O regardless/O of/O their/O background/O ,/O ethnicity/O ,/O or/O beliefs/O ,/O deserve/O full/O and/O equal/O respect/O ./O 
We/O believe/O that/O charging/O <U_PERSON>Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> and/O others/O with/O speech/O crimes/O violates/O the/O constitutional/O promise/O that/O ``/O the/O state/O respects/O and/O guarantees/O human/O rights/O ,/O ''/O contradicts/O explicit/O constitutional/O protections/O for/O citizens/O '/O freedom/O of/O speech/O ,/O and/O runs/O counter/O to/O provisions/O in/O the/O Universal/O Declaration/O of/O Human/O Rights/O and/O other/O international/O human/O rights/O treaties/O which/O China/LOCATION has/O signed/O ./O 
We/O hope/O that/O the/O relevant/O authorities/O are/O able/O to/O respect/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O ,/O and/O wisely/O and/O courageously/O act/O to/O ensure/O citizens/O are/O guaranteed/O their/O freedom/O and/O dignity/O ./O 
This/O will/O form/O a/O solid/O foundation/O for/O the/O easing/O of/O ethnic/O tensions/O ,/O safeguarding/O of/O social/O peace/O ,/O and/O unity/O of/O the/O country/O ./O
