He/O used/O his/O power/O to/O hire/O his/O mistresses/O ,/O two/O twin/O sisters/O ,/O as/O police/O officers/O despite/O their/O lack/O of/O experience/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O the/O ``/O fight/O against/O corruption/O ''/O continues/O inside/O the/O party/O ,/O which/O extols/O a/O moral/O conscience/O and/O integrity/O it/O does/O not/O have/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O Despite/O the/O great/O firewall/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O internet/O users/O appear/O more/O apt/O at/O uncovering/O corrupt/O Communist/O officials/O than/O the/O party/O itself/O ./O 
Following/O the/O cases/O of/O abuses/O of/O power/O in/O Chongqing/LOCATION and/O Henan/LOCATION ,/O the/O police/O chief/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Usu/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O the/O western/O autonomous/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O was/O sacked/O days/O after/O he/O was/O accused/O online/O of/O keeping/O twin/O sisters/O -LRB-/O pictured/O -RRB-/O as/O mistresses/O ./O 
Qi/PERSON Fang/PERSON was/O removed/O as/O head/O of/O the/O Public/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION in/O <U_LOCATION>Usu/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> on/O Saturday/O ./O 
This/O came/O after/O the/O nation/O 's/O new/O leadership/O vowed/O last/O month/O to/O implement/O tougher/O anti-graft/O measures/O ,/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION reported/O ./O 
However/O ,/O it/O took/O someone/O posting/O details/O of/O the/O case/O on/O news/O portal/O Iyaxin.com/O to/O launch/O the/O investigation/O ./O 
The/O post/O said/O the/O twins/O ,/O 31/O ,/O were/O hired/O by/O the/O bureau/O five/O months/O after/O Qi/PERSON was/O promoted/O to/O police/O chief/O in/O June/O last/O year/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O women/O was/O made/O vice-captain/O of/O special/O operations/O ,/O whilst/O the/O other/O was/O made/O an/O assistant/O police/O officer/O in/O the/O traffic/O department/O ./O 
Nothing/O indicated/O that/O either/O had/O any/O previous/O work/O experience/O with/O the/O police/O ./O 
The/O post/O also/O alleged/O that/O Qi/PERSON was/O renting/O a/O luxury/O apartment/O in/O the/O city/O 's/O high-end/O area/O ,/O paid/O for/O by/O the/O bureau/O ./O 
Qi/PERSON is/O the/O latest/O high-ranking/O official/O accused/O online/O of/O corruption/O in/O the/O past/O month/O to/O be/O promptly/O investigated/O ./O 
Lanzhou/LOCATION Mayor/O Yuan/PERSON Zhanting/PERSON was/O accused/O of/O buying/O at/O least/O five/O luxury/O watches/O with/O public/O funds/O ./O 
In/O Taiyuan/LOCATION ,/O Shanxi/LOCATION ,/O the/O police/O chief/O was/O suspended/O and/O placed/O under/O investigation/O a/O day/O after/O a/O video/O circulated/O showing/O his/O drunken/O son/O ,/O who/O is/O also/O a/O policeman/O ,/O attacking/O a/O colleague/O after/O being/O caught/O drink-driving/O ./O 
Li/PERSON Chuncheng/PERSON ,/O a/O former/O deputy/O party/O secretary/O of/O Sichuan/LOCATION ,/O fell/O from/O grace/O because/O of/O corruption/O allegations/O ./O 
For/O some/O analysts/O ,/O the/O crackdown/O has/O two/O purposes/O ./O 
On/O the/O one/O hand/O ,/O the/O new/O leadership/O can/O project/O an/O image/O of/O moral/O integrity/O that/O it/O does/O not/O have/O since/O they/O have/O some/O skeletons/O in/O their/O own/O closets/O -LRB-/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O family/O has/O accumulated/O wealth/O estimated/O to/O be/O around/O a/O billion/O dollars/O -RRB-/O ./O 
On/O the/O other/O ,/O as/O the/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON 's/O administration/O winds/O down/O ,/O people/O are/O likely/O to/O be/O targeted/O to/O enable/O the/O new/O rulers/O to/O flex/O their/O muscles/O against/O the/O party/O 's/O fractious/O factions/O and/O gain/O the/O most/O from/O the/O new/O balance/O of/O power/O ./O
