The/O authorities/O have/O removed/O Yong/PERSON Peng/PERSON from/O official/O duties/O ./O 
The/O decision/O after/O the/O terrorist/O attack/O on/O the/O heart/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O which/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION claims/O is/O the/O work/O of/O Uyghurs/O from/O the/O western/O province/O ./O 
Analysts/O in/O agreement/O that/O the/O only/O independence/O movement/O left/O ``/O unable/O to/O plan/O such/O attacks/O ./O ''/O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O removed/O Yong/PERSON Peng/PERSON from/O office/O ./O 
The/O communist/O General/O represents/O the/O highest/O military/O authority/O in/O the/O western/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Although/O the/O decision/O does/O not/O explicitly/O mention/O it/O ,/O the/O removal/O is/O linked/O to/O the/O terrorist/O attackwhich/O took/O place/O on/O 28/O October/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O during/O which/O 5/O people/O were/O killed/O and/O another/O 38/O were/O injured/O ./O 
The/O central/O authorities/O have/O referred/O to/O the/O instigators/O and/O perpetrators/O of/O the/O act/O as/O some/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O ``/O pro-independence/O militants/O ''/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
In/O the/O attack/O ,/O carried/O out/O with/O an/O SUV/O that/O was/O detonated/O at/O the/O front/O door/O of/O the/O Forbidden/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O the/O bomber/O ,/O his/O wife/O and/O mother/O died/O ./O 
General/O Peng/PERSON Yong/PERSON -LRB-/O see/O photo/O -RRB-/O ,/O writes/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>People/O 's/O Daily/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O has/O been/O removed/O from/O the/O Provincial/ORGANIZATION Standing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION :/O in/O short/O ,/O he/O no/O longer/O has/O any/O authority/O ./O 
In/O any/O case/O ,/O the/O spotlight/O remains/O focused/O on/O the/O province/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
It/O is/O home/O to/O the/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O ,/O Turkic/O speaking/O peoples/O of/O Islamic/O religion/O ,/O who/O have/O always/O sought/O to/O gain/O independence/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
The/O central/O government/O ,/O for/O its/O part/O ,/O planted/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O the/O region/O to/O try/O to/O make/O them/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
It/O also/O imposes/O serious/O restrictions/O on/O freedom/O of/O religion/O ,/O the/O practice/O of/O <OTHER>Islam/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ,/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O language/O and/O the/O local/O culture/O ./O 
Even/O from/O the/O economic/O point/O of/O view/O there/O are/O various/O forms/O of/O discrimination/O ./O 
The/O average/O wage/O for/O rural/O workers/O is/O 6,400/O yuan/O per/O year/O -LRB-/O about/O 550/O Euros/O -RRB-/O :/O This/O is/O an/O increase/O compared/O to/O previous/O years/O ,/O but/O is/O still/O less/O than/O the/O national/O average/O 1,500/O yuan/O ./O 
The/O social/O situation/O also/O affects/O the/O labor/O market/O in/O the/O province/O ,/O it/O is/O not/O hard/O to/O find/O job/O postings/O that/O specify/O ``/O Uyghurs/O will/O not/O be/O accepted/O ./O ''/O 
Since/O 2009/O a/O special/O police/O and/O military/O system/O of/O control/O are/O in/O place/O ,/O imposed/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION after/O the/O riots/O in/O which/O nearly/O 200/O people/O lost/O their/O lives/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O the/O violence/O hundreds/O of/O custodial/O sentences/O and/O dozens/O of/O death/O sentences/O were/O inflicted/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O authorities/O believe/O that/O the/O perpetrators/O of/O violence/O are/O Muslim/O extremists/O ,/O but/O the/O exiles/O claim/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION ``/O is/O exaggerating/O ''/O the/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O to/O justify/O the/O repression/O against/O the/O Uyghur/O population/O ./O 
Over/O the/O years/O ,/O a/O single/O movement/O has/O really/O distinguished/O itself/O for/O its/O independence/O activities/O ./O 
However/O ,/O as/O pointed/O out/O by/O analysts/O and/O experts/O ,/O the/O ``/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkistan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Etim/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O no/O longer/O has/O the/O ability/O to/O bring/O about/O attacks/O even/O remotely/O similar/O to/O those/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ./O 
According/O to/O a/O local/O expert/O ,/O who/O requested/O anonymity/O ,/O ''/O the/O invasion/O NATO/ORGANIZATION of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION has/O stopped/O the/O past/O relations/O between/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Etim/LOCATION</U_ORGANIZATION> and/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Its/O impossible/O to/O think/O that/O they/O are/O able/O to/O strike/O 2/O thousand/O miles/O away/O from/O their/O home/O bases/O ''/O ./O 
The/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O an/O organization/O based/O in/O Germany/LOCATION that/O brings/O together/O the/O diaspora/O ,/O has/O asked/O for/O ``/O honesty/O and/O transparency/O ''/O in/O the/O inquiry/O into/O the/O attack/O several/O times/O in/O recent/O days/O ./O 
After/O condemning/O the/O incident/O ,/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION leader/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> expressed/O the/O fear/O that/O ``/O what/O happened/O could/O lead/O to/O a/O new/O ,/O fierce/O persecution/O against/O the/O ethnic/O group/O ,/O increasingly/O targeted/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION policies/O ''/O ./O
