The/O authorities/O in/O the/O western/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> release/O the/O lawyer/O ,/O committed/O to/O the/O defence/O of/O religious/O freedom/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O but/O continue/O to/O keep/O him/O under/O control/O ./O 
Contact/O with/O his/O family/O still/O denied/O ,/O now/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
His/O teeth/O are/O ruined/O and/O he/O is/O seeking/O medical/O care/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O Authorities/O in/O the/O western/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> have/O released/O the/O Christian/O lawyer/O and/O human/O rights/O activist/O Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON ,/O one/O of/O the/O most/O critical/O and/O best/O known/O throughout/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Despite/O having/O been/O released/O from/O prison/O -/O after/O 3/O years/O -/O after/O serving/O his/O full/O sentence/O ,/O the/O dissident/O is/O not/O really/O free/O ./O 
Since/O leaving/O prison/O ,/O yesterday/O ,/O he/O has/O been/O under/O the/O constant/O escort/O of/O provincial/O security/O agents/O ;/O Moreover/O ,/O it/O is/O not/O yet/O able/O to/O talk/O on/O the/O phone/O with/O his/O family/O and/O friends/O ./O 
His/O older/O brother/O Gao/PERSON Zhiyi/PERSON went/O to/O pick/O him/O up/O at/O the/O prison/O ,/O but/O since/O then/O -/O according/O to/O his/O wife/O Geng/PERSON He/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O currently/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION -/O ``/O it/O is/O impossible/O to/O talk/O to/O him/O ./O ''/O 
The/O well-known/O activist/O Hu/PERSON Jia/PERSON ,/O a/O family/O friend/O ,/O said/O he/O had/O spoken/O to/O his/O brother/O :/O ``/O He/O explained/O that/O Gao/PERSON 's/O teeth/O are/O ruined/O and/O he/O is/O now/O looking/O for/O treatment/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LSB-/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ed/O ./O -RSB-/O 
Once/O he/O has/O been/O seen/O ,/O they/O want/O to/O return/O in/O their/O native/O village/O of/O Yulin/LOCATION ,/O Shaanxi/LOCATION province/LOCATION ''/O ./O 
Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O respected/O human/O rights/O lawyers/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O for/O a/O long/O time/O -/O before/O his/O conversion/O -/O was/O one/O of/O the/O ``/O Ten/O best/O lawyers/O in/O the/O country/O ''/O chosen/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
After/O this/O first/O successful/O phase/O of/O his/O life/O ,/O in/O 2005/O ,/O he/O sought/O to/O compile/O a/O huge/O dossier/O on/O the/O persecution/O of/O non-official/O Christians/O and/O members/O of/O the/O Falun/ORGANIZATION Gong/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Moved/O by/O these/O testimonies/O ,/O Gao/PERSON embraced/O the/O Christian/O faith/O ./O 
Since/O then/O he/O took/O up/O the/O defense/O of/O persecuted/O believers/O and/O congregations/O and/O churches/O whose/O land/O and/O property/O had/O been/O expropriated/O free/O of/O charge/O ,/O which/O led/O to/O his/O being/O targeted/O by/O the/O authorities/O ./O 
He/O has/O been/O the/O victim/O of/O harassment/O and/O physical/O threats/O for/O many/O years/O ./O 
In/O December/O 2006he/O was/O sentenced/O to/O 3/O years/O imprisonment/O ,/O suspended/O from/O practicing/O for/O five/O years/O on/O charges/O of/O ``/O inciting/O subversion/O ''/O ./O 
At/O first/O he/O was/O allowed/O to/O return/O home/O ,/O but/O in/O reality/O was/O placed/O under/O illegal/O under/O house/O arrest/O with/O his/O wife/O and/O children/O ./O 
In/O 2009/O ,/O his/O family/O managed/O to/O escape/O from/O China/LOCATION because/O of/O the/O constant/O harassment/O by/O the/O authorities/O ./O 
On/O 4/O February/O 2009/O the/O police/O took/O Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON from/O his/O home/O ./O 
For/O over/O a/O year/O there/O was/O no/O news/O of/O his/O whereabouts/O until/O the/O end/O of/O March/O 2010/O ,/O when/O he/O gave/O an/O interview/O in/O which/O he/O describes/O his/O odyssey/O ,/O including/O torture/O ./O 
He/O described/O having/O been/O beaten/O so/O violently/O that/O once/O ``/O my/O life/O was/O hanging/O by/O a/O thread/O for/O forty-eight/O hours/O ./O ''/O 
A/O few/O days/O after/O the/O interview/O ,/O he/O disappeared/O again/O ./O 
In/O December/O 2011/O ,/O after/O twenty/O months/O ,/O the/O state/O press/O announced/O that/O he/O had/O been/O jailed/O for/O violating/O bail/O conditions/O ./O 
Family/O and/O friends/O ,/O who/O did/O not/O know/O whether/O Gao/PERSON was/O alive/O or/O dead/O ,/O were/O not/O informed/O until/O the/O final/O sentence/O ./O
