The/O burqa/O ,/O a/O garment/O worn/O by/O Muslim/O woman/O to/O cover/O themselves/O from/O head-to-toe/O ,/O is/O considered/O a/O symbol/O of/O religious/O extremism/O by/O the/O local/O authorities/O ./O 
Authorities/O already/O said/O they/O would/O ban/O the/O practice/O of/O religion/O in/O government/O workplaces/O ,/O public/O schools/O and/O state-owned/O enterprises/O from/O next/O year/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O A/O proposed/O burqa/O ban/O in/O the/O capital/O city/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O could/O spark/O further/O unrest/O in/O the/O troubled/O region/O ,/O experts/O warn/O ./O 
The/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION Standing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION voted/O yesterday/O in/O favour/O of/O banning/O people/O from/O wearing/O the/O garment/O in/O public/O ,/O the/O local/O news/O website/O Tianshan.net/O reported/O ./O 
The/O proposal/O must/O now/O be/O reviewed/O by/O the/O regional/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION Standing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION before/O it/O is/O implemented/O ,/O though/O the/O report/O -/O later/O deleted/O from/O the/O site/O -/O did/O not/O specify/O when/O this/O would/O happen/O ./O 
The/O burqa/O ,/O a/O garment/O worn/O by/O Muslim/O woman/O to/O cover/O themselves/O from/O head-to-toe/O ,/O is/O considered/O a/O symbol/O of/O religious/O extremism/O by/O the/O local/O authorities/O ./O 
``/O Burqas/O are/O not/O a/O traditional/O Muslim/O garment/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O ''/O said/O Jiang/PERSON Zhaoyong/PERSON ,/O a/O Beijing-based/O expert/O on/O ethnic/O affairs/O ./O 
``/O The/O ban/O has/O been/O issued/O following/O public/O security/O concerns/O ./O 
Some/O people/O are/O wearing/O it/O not/O because/O of/O their/O religion/O ,/O but/O to/O act/O out/O their/O resentments/O against/O society/O ./O ''/O 
Beijing/LOCATION blames/O religious/O extremists/O for/O a/O series/O of/O attacks/O that/O have/O killed/O hundreds/O of/O people/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> over/O the/O past/O few/O years/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> launched/O a/O ``/O beautifying/O project/O ''/O in/O 2011/O to/O discourage/O women/O from/O covering/O their/O faces/O and/O wearing/O the/O burqa/O ./O 
Several/O campaigns/O against/O producing/O ,/O selling/O or/O wearing/O the/O garments/O have/O been/O mounted/O by/O county/O and/O district-level/O governments/O in/O the/O province/O ./O 
Last/O month/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> said/O it/O would/O ban/O the/O practice/O of/O religion/O in/O government/O workplaces/O ,/O public/O schools/O and/O state-owned/O enterprises/O from/O next/O year/O ./O 
The/O province/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Its/O Uighur/O Muslim/O minority/O ,/O who/O number/O about/O nine/O million/O ,/O have/O long/O sought/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O central/O government/O ,/O for/O its/O part/O ,/O has/O brought/O in/O millions/O of/O settlers/O to/O make/O Han/O Chinese/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O it/O has/O severely/O curtailed/O Muslim/O religious/O worship/O as/O well/O as/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O local/O language/O and/O culture/O ./O 
Since/O 2009/O Chinese/O police/O and/O the/O military/O have/O held/O the/O region/O under/O a/O special/O regime/O ,/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION imposed/O following/O clashes/O that/O left/O nearly/O 200/O people/O dead/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O various/O episodes/O of/O violence/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O long/O prison/O sentences/O were/O imposed/O and/O dozens/O of/O death/O penalties/O were/O carried/O out/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O blame/O Muslim/O extremists/O for/O the/O wave/O of/O violence/O ./O 
Uighur/O exiles/O claim/O instead/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O ``/O exaggerating/O ''/O the/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O to/O justify/O repression/O against/O indigenous/O Uighurs/O ./O
