The/O government/O announces/O the/O results/O of/O the/O raid/O launched/O after/O Thursday/O 's/O attack/O at/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION Railway/LOCATION Station/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Some/O 23/O extremist/O groups/O have/O been/O broken/O up/O and/O more/O than/O 200/O explosive/O devices/O seized/O ./O 
Islamist/O ideology/O is/O spreading/O to/O the/O province/O through/O the/O internet/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O More/O than/O 200/O people/O were/O arrested/O and/O 23/O extremist/O groups/O broken/O ,/O state/O media/O report/O after/O Chinese/O authorities/O launched/O a/O massive/O campaign/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ,/O following/O an/O attack/O at/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> railway/O station/O on/O Thursday/O that/O left/O 34/O people/O dead/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O ,/O police/O arrested/O many/O suspects/O in/O their/O 20s/O and/O 30s/O since/O Friday/O ./O 
They/O learnt/O how/O to/O make/O explosives/O through/O the/O internet/O and/O undertook/O physical/O training/O by/O watching/O online/O videos/O ./O 
Equally/O ,/O they/O used/O text/O messages/O and/O social/O media/O to/O chat/O about/O how/O to/O make/O explosives/O and/O spread/O ``/O jihad/O ''/O ./O 
During/O their/O crackdown/O ,/O police/O also/O seized/O more/O than/O 200/O explosive/O devices/O ./O 
For/O the/O authorities/O ,/O those/O responsible/O for/O the/O spread/O of/O Islamic/O extremism/O are/O all/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O ,/O with/O contacts/O in/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION ./O 
All/O those/O arrested/O were/O also/O Uighurs/O ./O 
For/O years/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O a/O region/O inhabited/O by/O the/O Uyghur/O ,/O a/O Turkic/O Muslim/O ethnic/O minority/O ,/O has/O been/O rocked/O by/O riots/O and/O tensions/O ./O 
The/O Uighurs/O accuse/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O colonising/O their/O homeland/O and/O demand/O greater/O autonomy/O ./O 
The/O government/O ,/O which/O has/O moved/O millions/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O settlers/O to/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O boosted/O its/O military/O presence/O ,/O has/O accuses/O Uighurs/O of/O separatism/O and/O Islamic/O terrorism/O ./O 
In/O order/O to/O end/O the/O violence/O ,/O the/O authorities/O have/O been/O quick/O to/O impose/O the/O death/O penalty/O and/O have/O denied/O local/O Muslims/O their/O religious/O freedom/O ./O 
In/O a/O previous/O incident/O at/O the/O end/O of/O April/O ,/O two/O suspected/O suicide/O bombers/O detonated/O explosives/O at/O the/O exit/O to/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> train/O station/O ,/O killing/O themselves/O and/O one/O other/O person/O ./O 
Another/O eight/O people/O attacked/O passengers/O with/O knives/O ,/O leaving/O 79/O injured/O ./O 
The/O violence/O came/O just/O a/O few/O hours/O after/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ended/O his/O visit/O to/O the/O region/O ./O 
In/O recent/O months/O ,/O attacks/O with/O bombs/O and/O knives/O have/O also/O occurred/O in/O Guangzhou/LOCATION and/O Kunming/LOCATION ,/O which/O the/O government/O don/O Islamic/O separatists/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O
