The/O group/O had/O disappeared/O into/O thin/O air/O in/O January/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O claims/O they/O are/O guilty/O of/O aiding/O the/O Uighur/O professor/O to/O ``/O foment/O separatism/O ''/O through/O a/O website/O ./O 
Lawyer/O :/O ``/O It/O was/O a/O platform/O for/O debate/O among/O China/LOCATION 's/O ethnic/O minorities/O ''/O ./O 
They/O now/O risk/O from/O five/O to/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O Authorities/O in/O the/O northwestern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> have/O put/O seven/O ethnic/O Uighur/O college/O students/O on/O trial/O for/O being/O ``/O connected/O ''/O with/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ./O 
The/O professor/O ,/O who/O is/O also/O Uighur/O ,/O was/O sentenced/O to/O life/O imprisonment/O in/O September/O 2014/O on/O charges/O of/O separatism/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> has/O always/O rejected/O this/O ruling/O ,/O and/O the/O final/O communiqué/O read/O in/O the/O courts/O reaffirmed/O his/O love/O for/O China/LOCATION and/O belief/O that/O the/O ethnic/O issue/O can/O only/O be/O resolved/O through/O dialogue/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> was/O arrested/O last/O January/O ,/O after/O criticizing/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policy/O following/O the/O attack/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O in/O October/O 2013/O ,/O attributed/O to/O some/O Uighurs/O ./O 
The/O government/O 's/O response/O to/O the/O attack/O was/O the/O increase/O in/O the/O repression/O of/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ./O 
For/O years/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O calls/O on/O the/O government/O to/O open/O a/O real/O dialogue/O with/O the/O Uighurs/O to/O understand/O their/O difficulties/O and/O in/O 2005/O opened/O on/O the/O internet/O website/O Uighur/ORGANIZATION Online/ORGANIZATION ,/O to/O meet/O Uighurs/O and/O Han/O -LRB-/O Chinese/O -RRB-/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O accusers/O is/O this/O site/O the/O test/O of/O ``/O separatism/O ''/O academician/O ./O 
The/O arrested/O university/O students/O are/O charged/O with/O being/O ``/O collaborators/O ''/O on/O the/O website/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O lawyer/O Li/PERSON Fangping/PERSON ,/O confirms/O the/O facts/O but/O stresses/O that/O Uighur/O Online/O ``/O promotes/O dialogue/O and/O confrontation/O between/O the/O ethnic/O Muslim/O Chinese/O and/O other/O ethnic/O groups/O ''/O ./O 
The/O students/O ,/O who/O disappeared/O after/O being/O taken/O into/O custody/O last/O January/O ,/O now/O face/O five/O to/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O 
The/O province/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Its/O Uighur/O Muslim/O minority/O ,/O who/O number/O about/O nine/O million/O ,/O have/O long/O sought/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O central/O government/O ,/O for/O its/O part/O ,/O has/O brought/O in/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O settlers/O to/O make/O Han/O Chinese/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O it/O has/O severely/O curtailed/O Muslim/O religious/O worship/O as/O well/O as/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O local/O language/O and/O culture/O ./O 
Since/O 2009/O Chinese/O police/O and/O the/O military/O have/O held/O the/O region/O under/O a/O special/O regime/O ,/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION imposed/O following/O clashes/O that/O left/O nearly/O 200/O people/O dead/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O various/O episodes/O of/O violence/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O long/O prison/O sentences/O were/O imposed/O and/O dozens/O of/O death/O penalties/O were/O carried/O out/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O blame/O Muslim/O extremists/O for/O the/O wave/O of/O violence/O ./O 
Uighur/O exiles/O claim/O instead/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O ``/O exaggerating/O ''/O the/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O to/O justify/O repression/O against/O indigenous/O Uighurs/O ./O 
For/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Uighurs/O are/O responsible/O for/O the/O recent/O spate/O of/O violent/O attacks/O ,/O including/O the/O 1/O March/O 2014attack/O at/O the/O Kunming/LOCATION railway/O station/O by/O knives-wielding/O men/O that/O left/O 29/O people/O dead/O and/O more/O than/O 150/O wounded/O ,/O and/O the/O 28/O October/O 2013/O incident/O when/O an/O SUV/O plunged/O into/O a/O crowd/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O then/O burst/O into/O flames/O ,/O killing/O three/O people/O ./O 
The/O government/O believes/O that/O separatists/O from/O the/O ethnic/O minority/O are/O behind/O the/O attack/O :/O following/O investigations/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> and/O his/O students/O were/O put/O on/O trial/O ./O
