The/O Global/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION comes/O out/O against/O today/O 's/O vote/O because/O of/O its/O ``/O potential/O impact/O on/O developments/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
For/O the/O Chinese/O paper/O ,/O ``/O China/LOCATION can/O not/O afford/O to/O play/O this/O British/O game/O ''/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O Scottish/O independence/O is/O ``/O seen/O as/O a/O disruptive/O force/O that/O threatens/O unity/O and/O stability/O ,/O to/O be/O condemned/O ,/O ''/O this/O according/O to/O an/O editorial/O in/O The/O Global/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION that/O appeared/O on/O the/O day/O 4/O million/O Scottish/O voters/O are/O set/O to/O cast/O their/O ballot/O to/O decide/O whether/O to/O separate/O from/O the/O United/LOCATION Kingdom/LOCATION after/O more/O than/O 300/O years/O ./O 
The/O thrust/O of/O the/O opinion/O is/O not/O its/O rejection/O of/O Scottish/O independence/O ,/O but/O its/O rejection/O of/O British-style/O referendums/O per/O se/O ./O 
in/O fact/O ,/O for/O The/O Global/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O Scottish/O independence/O referendum/O has/O pushed/O the/O union/O to/O the/O cliff/O 's/O edge/O ./O 
If/O Scotland/LOCATION became/O independent/O ,/O David/PERSON Cameron/PERSON would/O go/O down/O in/O history/O as/O a/O ``/O criminal/O ''/O who/O presided/O over/O a/O break-up/O ./O 
Conversely/O ,/O if/O the/O bid/O is/O rejected/O ,/O Cameron/PERSON 's/O government/O has/O to/O stop/O the/O independence/O movement/O and/O prevent/O its/O serious/O consequences/O ./O 
For/O the/O Beijing-based/O newspaper/O ,/O the/O democratic/O choice/O of/O the/O referendum/O is/O like/O a/O baby/O tantrum/O ,/O warning/O that/O ``/O if/O a/O child/O knew/O it/O could/O get/O milk/O by/O crying/O ''/O ,/O this/O could/O became/O normal/O behaviour/O in/O British/O politics/O ./O 
Thus/O ,/O the/O country/O would/O ``/O never/O have/O peace/O ''/O ./O 
Going/O a/O step/O further/O ,/O the/O paper/O clearly/O indicated/O not/O only/O its/O support/O for/O British/O union/O over/O Scottish/O independence/O ,/O but/O also/O stressed/O its/O rejection/O of/O the/O referendum/O per/O se/O ./O 
Deploying/O the/O same/O terms/O and/O expressions/O that/O the/O Chinese/O communist/O government/O often/O trots/O out/O in/O its/O propaganda/O on/O national/O unity/O ,/O the/O editorial/O warned/O of/O the/O poll/O 's/O potential/O impact/O on/O developments/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O insisting/O that/O ``/O With/O its/O complex/O history/O and/O ethnic/O diversity/O ,/O China/LOCATION can/O not/O afford/O to/O play/O this/O British/O game/O -LSB-/O of/O independence/O -RSB-/O ''/O ./O
