Considered/O a/O prisoner/O of/O conscience/O by/O major/O human/O rights/O groups/O ,/O he/O slams/O Chinese/O authorities/O for/O torturing/O him/O and/O for/O persecuting/O his/O family/O ./O 
He/O said/O he/O would/O ``/O continue/O to/O fight/O against/O the/O oppression/O of/O the/O Mongolian/O nationality/O ''/O ./O 
Like/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION has/O suffered/O for/O decades/O from/O the/O arrival/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O settlers/O ,/O whose/O immigration/O is/O undermining/O local/O traditions/O and/O beliefs/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O Hada/PERSON ,/O an/O ethnic/O Mongol/O dissident/O and/O one/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O longest-serving/O political/O prisoners/O ,/O was/O released/O last/O week/O ./O 
During/O his/O time/O in/O jail/O ,/O he/O was/O tortured/O ;/O since/O he/O was/O let/O out/O ,/O he/O has/O been/O threatened/O ./O 
The/O Mongolian/O activist/O has/O spent/O much/O of/O the/O last/O two/O decades/O behind/O bars/O ,/O including/O the/O last/O four/O years/O in/O an/O extrajudicial/O ``/O black/O jail/O ''/O ,/O a/O detention/O facility/O in/O which/O people/O are/O held/O incommunicado/O under/O police/O custody/O without/O a/O court/O order/O ./O 
Hada/PERSON was/O first/O arrested/O in/O in/O 1996/O ./O 
After/O his/O trial/O ,/O he/O was/O sentenced/O to/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O separatism/O ,/O spying/O and/O supporting/O the/O Southern/ORGANIZATION Mongolian/ORGANIZATION Democratic/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION ,/O an/O organisation/O that/O seeks/O greater/O rights/O for/O ethnic/O Mongolians/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O but/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION considers/O a/O ``/O terrorist/O ''/O group/O ''/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O dissident/O ,/O the/O charges/O against/O him/O were/O trumped/O up/O ./O 
For/O various/O NGOs/O and/O international/O organisations/O ,/O he/O was/O and/O remains/O a/O ``/O prisoner/O of/O conscience/O ''/O ./O 
In/O his/O native/O province/O ,/O decades/O of/O migration/O by/O China/LOCATION 's/O dominant/O Han/O community/O have/O left/O Chinese/O Mongolians/O a/O minority/O in/O their/O own/O land/O ./O 
Officially/O ,/O they/O now/O make/O up/O less/O than/O a/O fifth/O of/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION 's/O almost/O 24/O million/O people/O ./O 
In/O view/O of/O the/O situation/O ,/O the/O Mongolian/O community/O has/O been/O demanding/O greater/O rights/O and/O protection/O for/O its/O traditions/O ,/O something/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O regularly/O ignored/O ,/O like/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Despite/O ongoing/O threats/O ,/O Hada/PERSON plans/O to/O continue/O his/O struggle/O ./O 
``/O During/O these/O 19/O years/O ,/O in/O an/O effort/O to/O force/O me/O to/O abandon/O my/O beliefs/O ,/O I/O was/O cruelly/O mistreated/O and/O subjected/O to/O various/O forms/O of/O tortures/O and/O ploys/O ,/O ''/O Hada/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O In/O particular/O ,/O my/O wife/O and/O son/O have/O been/O subjected/O to/O false/O accusations/O ,/O enormous/O persecution/O and/O suffering/O ./O 
I/O myself/O have/O been/O disabled/O as/O a/O result/O of/O torture/O and/O brutality/O ''/O ./O 
Yet/O ,/O ``/O My/O next/O step/O is/O to/O arrange/O my/O life/O and/O study/O ,/O to/O continue/O to/O fight/O against/O the/O oppression/O of/O the/O Mongolian/O nationality/O ./O ''/O
