The/O man/O ,/O 25/O and/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O was/O stopped/O at/O a/O checkpoint/O on/O the/O eastern/O border/O ./O 
Three/O suspects/O are/O still/O on/O the/O loose/O ./O 
The/O Thai/O police/O punishes/O 22/O officials/O for/O negligence/O ./O 
Bangkok/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O Thai/O police/O have/O arrested/O a/O second/O suspect/O in/O the/O bomb/O attack/O two/O weeks/O ago/O in/O central/O Bangkok/LOCATION ./O 
It/O is/O the/O second/O arrest/O after/O that/O of/O August/O 29/O ./O 
According/O to/O Thai/O authorities/O ,/O the/O man/O would/O have/O a/O key/O role/O in/O the/O terrorist/O act/O ,/O even/O if/O they/O have/O not/O revealed/O whether/O he/O placed/O the/O bomb/O that/O killed/O 20/O people/O and/O injured/O more/O than/O 100/O ./O 
Three/O other/O suspects/O ,/O including/O a/O woman/O <OTHER>Muslim/PERSON</OTHER> ,/O are/O still/O at/O large/O ./O 
Prime/O Minister/O Prayut/PERSON Chan/PERSON o-cha/PERSON said/O the/O arrested/O man/O ``/O is/O not/O an/O ethnic/O Thai/O and/O was/O stopped/O at/O the/O checkpoint/O in/O Sa/LOCATION Kaeo/LOCATION ''/O ,/O on/O the/O eastern/O border/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
Probably/O added/O the/O former/O general/O ,/O ``/O he/O was/O trying/O to/O escape/O ./O ''/O 
Local/O media/O reported/O that/O the/O man/O is/O a/O 25/O year-old/O Chinese/O national/O ,/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Uyghur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
This/O has/O once/O again/O led/O to/O suspicions/O that/O the/O attack/O is/O Muslims/O revenge/O against/O the/O government/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ./O 
At/O the/O beginning/O of/O July/O ,/O nearly/O 100/O Uyghurs/O were/O repatriated/O to/O China/LOCATION by/O force/O by/O the/O Thai/O authorities/O ./O 
The/O man/O stopped/O had/O a/O passport/O with/O the/O name/O <U_PERSON>Yusufu/PERSON Mieraili/PERSON</U_PERSON> ./O 
Just/O one/O day/O after/O a/O number/O of/O police/O pocketed/O the/O ransom/O for/O progress/O made/O in/O the/O investigation/O ,/O Thai/O police/O officers/O transferred/O 22/O agents/O from/O checkpoints/O on/O the/O borders/O accused/O of/O negligence/O ./O 
Six/O of/O the/O transferred/O worked/O in/O Sa/LOCATION Kaeo/LOCATION ./O 
``/O It/O was/O my/O decision/O -/O said/O Somyot/PERSON Pumpanmuang/PERSON police/O chief/O -/O because/O foreigners/O have/O been/O able/O to/O illegally/O enter/O ,/O without/O strict/O controls/O ''/O ./O
