Beijing/LOCATION is/O investing/O in/O the/O manufacturing/O sector/O in/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ./O 
Tajikistan/LOCATION receives/O $/O 200/O million/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O for/O lead/O extraction/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O goal/O is/O to/O limit/O Russian/O influence/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
Experts/O say/O China/LOCATION wants/O to/O infiltrate/O the/O vast/O market/O of/O the/O Eurasian/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION and/O contain/O the/O threat/O of/O terrorism/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O In/O recent/O months/O China/LOCATION has/O signed/O a/O series/O of/O trade/O agreements/O with/O the/O countries/O of/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION and/O Tajikistan/LOCATION in/O the/O lead/O ,/O with/O the/O main/O aim/O of/O counterbalancing/O Russian/O influence/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
This/O has/O been/O confirmed/O by/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>East/O Asia/O Forum/O</ORGANIZATION> website/O which/O has/O published/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O future/O investments/O plans/O for/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ./O 
Visiting/O the/O Kazakh/O capital/O on/O December/O 14/O ,/O 2014/O ,/O for/O the/O first/O meeting/O of/O the/O Council/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Heads/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Government/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Organization/ORGANIZATION ,/O Chinese/O Premier/O Li/PERSON Keqiang/PERSON announced/O a/O new/O economic/O agreement/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O ,/O which/O is/O an/O investment/O of/O 14/O billion/O dollars/O ./O 
This/O was/O followed/O in/O January/O 2015/O by/O an/O agreement/O between/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O Astana/LOCATION to/O enter/O into/O joint/O ventures/O in/O manufacturing/O and/O other/O key/O industries/O ,/O such/O as/O mining/O ,/O petroleum/O ,/O chemical/O ,/O gas/O and/O transport/O ./O 
Kazakhstan/LOCATION is/O the/O largest/O recipient/O of/O Chinese/O investment/O among/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION 's/O former/O Soviet/O bloc/O nations/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O between/O 1991/O and/O 2013/O ,/O the/O country/O received/O a/O total/O of/O $/O 22/O billion/O ./O 
According/O to/O experts/O ,/O these/O agreements/O come/O at/O a/O crucial/O time/O for/O the/O Kazakh/O economy/O ,/O which/O has/O recently/O suffered/O a/O slowdown/O ./O 
Because/O of/O the/O political/O situation/O in/O Russia/LOCATION and/O the/O fall/O in/O oil/O prices/O ,/O growth/O forecasts/O in/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION the/O have/O fallen/O from/O 5.1/O to/O 1.5/O %/O ./O 
What/O 's/O more/O ,/O the/O slowdown/O of/O the/O Chinese/O economy/O has/O caused/O a/O decrease/O in/O demand/O for/O metals/O and/O other/O raw/O materials/O ,/O resulting/O in/O falling/O prices/O ./O 
During/O the/O first/O half/O of/O 2014/O exports/O of/O iron/O ore/O to/O China/LOCATION fell/O by/O 41/O %/O ./O 
All/O of/O this/O has/O led/O the/O Astana/LOCATION government/O to/O announce/O a/O new/O program/O of/O infrastructure/O investment/O to/O attract/O Chinese/O investment/O in/O the/O manufacturing/O sector/O ,/O as/O was/O the/O case/O with/O the/O January/O agreement/O ./O 
In/O addition/O to/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION has/O decided/O to/O invest/O in/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ./O 
On/O February/O 25/O ,/O 2015/O ,/O the/O Tajik/O parliament/O ratified/O an/O agreement/O between/O the/O government/O and/O the/O -LRB-/O Chinese-owned/O -RRB-/O Sino-Tajik/ORGANIZATION Mining/ORGANIZATION Company/ORGANIZATION that/O provides/O for/O the/O development/O of/O the/O mineral/O deposit/O of/O Zarnisori/PERSON Shimoli/PERSON ./O 
Lochin/PERSON Fayzullozoda/PERSON ,/O vice-president/O of/O the/O State/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION on/O investment/O and/O management/O of/O state/O property/O ,/O said/O that/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION government/O has/O allocated/O $/O 200/O million/O for/O the/O the/O project/O ./O 
Under/O the/O new/O plan/O ,/O the/O mineral/O deposit/O -/O located/O in/O the/O administrative/O region/O of/O Sughd/LOCATION -LRB-/O in/O the/O northeast/O of/O the/O country/O -RRB-/O ,/O currently/O slated/O to/O receive/O World/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION funds/O for/O a/O project/O to/O upgrade/O the/O roads/O -/O will/O generate/O two/O million/O tons/O of/O ore/O and/O 20/O thousand/O tons/O of/O lead/O will/O be/O produced/O per/O year/O ./O 
Fayzullozoda/PERSON added/O ,/O moreover/O ,/O that/O the/O project/O will/O create/O more/O than/O 2/O thousand/O new/O jobs/O in/O the/O area/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O main/O aim/O is/O to/O increase/O Chinese/O influence/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O taking/O advantage/O of/O the/O opportunities/O offered/O by/O the/O Russian/O recession/O and/O the/O diplomatic/O isolation/O of/O Moscow/LOCATION caused/O by/O the/O war/O in/O Ukraine/LOCATION ./O 
By/O increasing/O investment/O and/O establishing/O joint/O ventures/O with/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION may/O also/O gain/O access/O to/O the/O immense/O market/O of/O the/O Eurasian/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O EEU/O -RRB-/O ,/O which/O came/O into/O force/O on/O January/O 1/O ,/O 2015/O ./O 
Some/O critics/O of/O this/O economic/O integration/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O foreign/O countries/O argue/O that/O Chinese/O investment/O could/O be/O very/O risky/O ./O 
For/O example/O ,/O China/LOCATION could/O transfer/O obsolete/O and/O highly/O polluting/O industries/O that/O it/O has/O decided/O to/O close/O in/O its/O own/O territory/O to/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ,/O causing/O serious/O environmental/O problems/O ./O 
Other/O experts/O claim/O that/O the/O strengthening/O of/O economic/O cooperation/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O neighboring/O nations/O will/O complicate/O emigration/O for/O the/O ethnic/O Uighur/O Muslim/O minority/O from/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ./O 
Incorporated/O into/O the/O territory/O of/O communist/O China/LOCATION in/O 1949/O ,/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O is/O inhabited/O by/O ethnic/O Uighur/O ,/O who/O speak/O a/O Turkish/O dialect/O ,/O profess/O <OTHER>Islam/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> and/O identify/O with/O the/O populations/O of/O <LOCATION>Central/O</LOCATION> Asia/LOCATION rather/O than/O the/O cultural/O traditions/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O ethnic/O group/O has/O always/O promoted/O the/O creation/O of/O an/O autonomous/O state/O ,/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION ,/O and/O expressed/O full/O support/O for/O separatist/O groups/O at/O the/O time/O of/O the/O dissolution/O of/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION in/O 1990/O ,/O with/O an/O enthusiastic/O welcome/O for/O the/O creation/O of/O independent/O Muslim/O states/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Beijing/LOCATION government/O ,/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O has/O suppressed/O demonstrations/O and/O imprisoned/O activists/O ,/O encouraging/O the/O settlement/O of/O the/O Chinese/O Han/O majority/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
Since/O the/O 11/O September/O 2001/O attacks/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O represented/O the/O Uighur/O separatist/O groups/O as/O affiliates/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>al-Qaeda/O</ORGANIZATION> terrorists/O ,/O claiming/O they/O are/O being/O trained/O in/O military/O camps/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O then/O returning/O home/O to/O threaten/O the/O Chinese/O territory/O ./O 
More/O recently/O China/LOCATION fears/O that/O the/O Uighurs/O may/O adopt/O the/O ideology/O and/O tactics/O of/O the/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O IS/O -RRB-/O extremists/O ./O 
The/O discriminatory/O policies/O implemented/O against/O this/O minority/O has/O caused/O a/O mass/O migration/O to/O the/O territories/O of/O <LOCATION>Central/O</LOCATION> and/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O especially/O through/O Thailand/LOCATION and/O Malaysia/LOCATION ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O according/O to/O experts/O ,/O the/O trade/O agreements/O that/O China/LOCATION has/O signed/O with/O the/O countries/O of/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION would/O strengthen/O integration/O and/O cooperation/O in/O the/O economy/O and/O help/O to/O contain/O a/O hypothetical/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O
