Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
Not/O a/O leader/O but/O ``/O a/O soldier/O fighting/O for/O her/O people/O ./O ''/O
This/O is/O how/O Rebiya/U_PERSON Kadeer/U_PERSON ,/O the/O 58-year-old/O Uighur/O political/O dissent/O ,/O defined/O herself/O in/O an/O interview/O on/O April/O 12/O ./O
Broadcast/O of/O the/O interview/O was/O banned/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
In/O it/O ,/O Kadeer/U_PERSON spoke/O out/O against/O injustices/O faced/O by/O the/O Uighur/O ethnic/O minority/O and/O testified/O to/O the/O atrocities/O that/O occur/O in/O prisons/O ./O
``/O Every/O day/O ,/O I/O could/O hear/O the/O cries/O of/O Uighurs/O who/O were/O being/O tortured/O ,/O at/O times/O without/O even/O knowing/O why/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O in/O a/O television/O interview/O ,/O adding/O that/O ``/O on/O one/O occasion/O ,/O prison/O guards/O were/O dragging/O a/O young/O man/O towards/O the/O torture/O chambers/O ./O
He/O turned/O his/O head/O ,/O saw/O me/O behind/O bars/O and/O said/O ,/O `/O Mother/O ,/O what/O are/O you/O doing/O here/O ?/O
Young/O people/O like/O me/O are/O going/O to/O jail/O so/O as/O to/O save/O mothers/O like/O you/O !/O '/O ''/O
During/O the/O interview/O ,/O Mrs/O Kadeer/U_PERSON also/O clarified/O her/O role/O in/O Uighur/O leadership/O ./O
``/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O much/O about/O being/O a/O leader/O ./O
I/O think/O of/O myself/O as/O simply/O a/O soldier/O who/O is/O fighting/O for/O the/O rights/O of/O her/O people/O ./O ''/O
Rebiya/U_PERSON Kadeer/U_PERSON was/O released/O from/O prison/O on/O the/O eve/O of/O the/O official/O visit/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O Condoleezza/PERSON Rice/PERSON ,/O U.S./LOCATION Secretary/O of/O State/O ./O
Mrs/O Kadeer/U_PERSON is/O currently/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION working/O for/O an/O organization/O founded/O by/O her/O husband/O that/O strives/O for/O the/O civil/O liberties/O and/O independence/O of/O the/O 8/O million/O Muslims/O that/O live/O in/O the/O northern/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O
Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O HRW/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O confirms/O Kadeer/U_PERSON 's/O testimony/O ./O
Yesterday/O ,/O HRW/ORGANIZATION released/O a/O dossier/O on/O the/O situation/O of/O the/O Uighur/O ethnic/O group/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
The/O dossier/O includes/O official/O orders/O and/O internal/O police/O reports/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O public/O security/O forces/O ./O
These/O documents/O prove/O that/O the/O violence/O and/O discrimination/O carried/O out/O against/O the/O Uighur/O are/O known/O to/O and/O supported/O by/O the/O organs/O of/O central/O power/O ./O
One/O official/O document/O says/O that/O ``/O parents/O and/O legal/O guardians/O may/O not/O allow/O minors/O to/O participate/O in/O religious/O activities/O ./O ''/O
According/O to/O HRW/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O Uighurs/O are/O not/O allowed/O to/O practise/O their/O religion/O publicly/O ,/O to/O study/O from/O or/O carry/O books/O on/O religion/O ,/O or/O wear/O religious/O symbols/O ./O
The/O Chinese/O government/O gives/O their/O imam/O precise/O instructions/O on/O where/O the/O faithful/O can/O meet/O and/O what/O can/O and/O can/O not/O be/O discussed/O ./O
The/O expression/O of/O religious/O sentiment/O in/O public/O places/O ,/O such/O as/O offices/O and/O schools/O ,/O is/O absolutely/O unthinkable/O ./O
Instead/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION paints/O a/O rosy/O picture/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O rights/O record/O in/O a/O policy/O paper/O released/O today/O ./O
The/O 41-page/O document/O is/O the/O eighth/O on/O human/O rights/O published/O by/O the/O government/O since/O 1991/O ./O
According/O to/O the/O State/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION organ/O that/O drafted/O the/O report/O ,/O ``/O The/O year/O 2004/O saw/O a/O process/O of/O effective/O improvement/O in/O all/O fields/O of/O human/O ,/O civil/O and/O religious/O rights/O ./O ''/O
Again/O according/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O ``/O In/O the/O past/O year/O ,/O the/O government/O cracked/O down/O on/O functionaries/O who/O violated/O such/O rights/O ./O ''/O
China/LOCATION denies/O any/O repression/O against/O the/O expression/O of/O religion/O ,/O but/O states/O that/O it/O simply/O wants/O to/O defend/O the/O state/O from/O forces/O that/O fight/O ``/O to/O achieve/O secession/O and/O ``/O to/O spread/O religious/O extremism/O ./O ''/O
