Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O --/O
``/O It/O is/O time/O for/O an/O immediate/O awakening/O ''/O ,/O wrote/O Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON ,/O famous/O lawyer/O and/O human/O rights/O activist/O ,/O at/O the/O end/O of/O his/O long/O report/O on/O the/O persecution/O targeting/O unofficial/O Christians/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION where/O ``/O once/O again/O ''/O ,/O he/O saw/O the/O rise/O of/O ``/O heavy/O shadows/O of/O the/O police/O as/O a/O social/O group/O which/O uses/O unscrupulous/O brutality/O that/O undermines/O the/O public/O order/O of/O the/O society/O ''/O ./O
The/O report/O is/O the/O fruit/O of/O five/O days/O of/O meetings/O with/O unofficial/O Christians/O of/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION and/O other/O cities/O in/O the/O province/O ,/O which/O took/O place/O between/O 20/O and/O 25/O November/O 2005/O ./O
However/O ,/O the/O origin/O of/O the/O report/O lies/O in/O the/O two/O years/O spent/O by/O Gao/PERSON in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O at/O the/O start/O of/O his/O legal/O career/O ./O
During/O this/O time/O ,/O Gao/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O born/O poor/O ,/O became/O a/O lawyer/O :/O it/O was/O here/O that/O he/O offered/O legal/O aid/O for/O free/O to/O local/O people/O ,/O and/O started/O to/O take/O an/O interest/O in/O the/O plight/O of/O Christians/O ,/O persecuted/O by/O the/O authorities/O because/O they/O were/O not/O registered/O with/O the/O Religious/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION Office/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O Year/O in/O and/O year/O out/O ,/O brutal/O arrests/O ,/O suppression/O ,/O crackdowns/O and/O interrogating/O Christians/O are/O the/O only/O work/O this/O band/O of/O policemen/O have/O to/O do/O ./O
One/O can/O never/O imagine/O this/O is/O done/O by/O a/O group/O of/O civilized/O adults/O ,/O ''/O said/O the/O lawyer/O ./O
``/O The/O report/O is/O not/O to/O remind/O them/O of/O the/O cruelty/O motivating/O them/O ,/O by/O now/O deeply/O rooted/O ./O
What/O we/O want/O is/O to/O remind/O the/O world/O of/O the/O danger/O of/O continuing/O to/O tolerate/O this/O group/O of/O slaughterers/O and/O their/O masters/O ,/O who/O destroy/O our/O purest/O values/O ./O ''/O
In/O the/O document/O ,/O ``/O it/O is/O not/O the/O worst/O testimonies/O which/O are/O presented/O ,/O but/O those/O which/O convinced/O me/O of/O the/O purity/O of/O Christian/O values/O ''/O ./O
Many/O of/O those/O who/O talked/O to/O Gao/PERSON ,/O have/O ``/O disappeared/O in/O mysterious/O circumstances/O ''/O and/O now/O the/O lawyer/O ``/O does/O not/O feel/O he/O can/O talk/O about/O cases/O known/O to/O the/O authorities/O without/O their/O explicit/O authorization/O ''/O ./O
He/O added/O :/O ``/O An/O academic/O reminded/O me/O that/O the/O suffering/O of/O Christians/O has/O been/O going/O on/O for/O 56/O years/O ''/O ./O
Here/O we/O reproduce/O a/O series/O of/O testimonies/O included/O in/O the/O document/O :/O Lianru/PERSON Ma/PERSON ,/O Christian/O ,/O arrested/O in/O November/O 2003/O As/O about/O a/O dozen/O Christians/O and/O I/O were/O gathering/O at/O an/O elderly/O person/O 's/O residence/O -LRB-/O to/O celebrate/O Christmas/O -RRB-/O ,/O we/O sang/O songs/O ./O
While/O we/O were/O doing/O this/O ,/O people/O from/O the/O local/O police/O station/O ,/O Qitai/U_ORGANIZATION County/U_ORGANIZATION Public/U_ORGANIZATION Security/U_ORGANIZATION Bureau/U_ORGANIZATION and/O Bureau/U_ORGANIZATION of/U_ORGANIZATION Religion/U_ORGANIZATION came/O in/O ./O
After/O they/O arrived/O ,/O they/O ordered/O us/O to/O stop/O singing/O and/O asked/O us/O who/O is/O the/O leader/O of/O the/O gathering/O ./O
When/O I/O said/O I/O was/O ,/O they/O began/O to/O take/O photos/O of/O the/O Bible/O passages/O written/O on/O the/O blackboard/O ./O
After/O that/O ,/O they/O took/O Christians/O one/O by/O one/O to/O a/O room/O for/O written/O statements/O ./O
Then/O ,/O they/O took/O my/O brother/O and/O me/O into/O a/O police/O vehicle/O and/O took/O away/O the/O belts/O on/O our/O trousers/O ./O
When/O we/O arrived/O at/O a/O local/O police/O station/O ,/O they/O made/O us/O stay/O in/O a/O conference/O lobby/O for/O introspection/O ./O
They/O made/O me/O answer/O their/O questions/O while/O they/O recording/O everything/O with/O a/O camera/O ./O
When/O the/O camera/O was/O switched/O off/O ,/O they/O beat/O me/O with/O the/O belts/O ./O
I/O answered/O every/O of/O their/O questions/O while/O I/O bled/O ,/O and/O at/O the/O end/O they/O told/O me/O that/O what/O we/O believe/O in/O is/O a/O cult/O and/O we/O do/O n't/O have/O their/O approval/O ./O
I/O do/O n't/O understand/O how/O this/O happened/O or/O what/O I/O was/O accused/O of/O ./O
Since/O then/O ,/O I/O have/O been/O arrested/O without/O warning/O many/O times/O :/O each/O day/O ,/O I/O wake/O up/O thinking/O I/O may/O be/O taken/O back/O to/O prison/O from/O one/O minute/O to/O the/O next/O ./O ''/O
Lingzhi/PERSON Xia/PERSON ,/O Christian/PERSON ,/O 63/O years/O :/O I/O went/O to/O attend/O a/O Christian/O prayer/O meeting/O in/O Xishan/U_LOCATION Road/U_LOCATION at/O 3pm/O on/O August/O 5/O ,/O 2005/O ./O
However/O ,/O before/O I/O could/O settle/O down/O in/O the/O seat/O in/O the/O room/O ,/O a/O group/O of/O policemen/O broke/O in/O ./O
They/O ordered/O everyone/O in/O the/O room/O to/O stand/O still/O and/O no/O one/O could/O leave/O ./O
After/O the/O operation/O ,/O they/O took/O me/O to/O a/O women/O 's/O detention/O center/O in/O Liudaowan/U_LOCATION ,/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ./O
I/O was/O then/O given/O a/O statement/O of/O decision/O on/O penalty/O and/O was/O told/O I/O would/O be/O put/O in/O administrative/O detention/O for/O 15/O days/O for/O ``/O endangering/O State/O security/O ''/O ./O
They/O interrogated/O me/O 10/O times/O ./O
I/O was/O confused/O and/O afraid/O ,/O worried/O about/O my/O husband/O and/O my/O son/O ,/O at/O home/O with/O no/O news/O of/O me/O ./O
I/O had/O coronary/O heart/O disease/O and/O high/O blood/O pressure/O ./O
On/O August/O 31/O ,/O 2005/O ,/O my/O son/O went/O to/O Guobao/ORGANIZATION Brigade/ORGANIZATION and/O a/O police/O officer/O there/O told/O him/O that/O I/O am/O on/O the/O wanted/O list/O of/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Public/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION ./O
After/O he/O went/O back/O home/O ,/O he/O became/O very/O worried/O ./O
As/O my/O son/O had/O always/O had/O high/O blood/O pressure/O ,/O like/O me/O ,/O this/O news/O provoked/O a/O cerebral/O hemorrhage/O ./O
He/O was/O rushed/O to/O a/O hospital/O ,/O where/O he/O died/O ./O
I/O was/O released/O on/O 2/O September/O ./O
Qimiao/PERSON Tong/PERSON ,/O Christian/O On/O the/O morning/O of/O September/O 28/O ,/O 2005/O ,/O I/O suddenly/O received/O a/O call/O from/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION and/O was/O told/O to/O go/O to/O the/O Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION immediately/O ./O
I/O had/O no/O idea/O why/O I/O was/O asked/O to/O go/O ;/O I/O thought/O it/O was/O to/O give/O some/O public/O testimony/O ./O
I/O arrived/O at/O the/O gate/O of/O Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION at/O almost/O 11/O o'clock/O and/O Ai/PERSON ,/O the/O man/O who/O had/O telephoned/O me/O ,/O brought/O me/O to/O a/O room/O on/O the/O second/O floor/O of/O the/O guesthouse/O in/O the/O back/O ./O
As/O soon/O as/O I/O entered/O the/O room/O ,/O I/O saw/O two/O men/O lying/O on/O the/O bed/O ./O
One/O was/O a/O person/O of/O Han/O nationality/O and/O the/O other/O was/O of/O Uighur/O -LRB-/O ethnicity/O from/O the/O northern/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION -RRB-/O nationality/O and/O they/O were/O both/O around/O 30/O years/O of/O age/O ./O
They/O were/O waiting/O for/O me/O ./O
I/O shook/O their/O hand/O and/O apologised/O for/O being/O late/O and/O one/O of/O them/O told/O me/O :/O ``/O What/O do/O you/O think/O you/O are/O ?/O
We/O saved/O your/O face/O today/O by/O not/O coming/O to/O you/O in/O a/O vehicle/O and/O bringing/O you/O here/O in/O a/O pair/O of/O handcuffs/O ./O
We/O have/O been/O following/O you/O for/O over/O a/O year/O ./O '/O
I/O said/O :/O `/O If/O you/O have/O evidence/O ,/O you/O can/O handcuff/O me/O now/O ./O '/O
When/O I/O replied/O ,/O the/O man/O of/O Han/O nationality/O named/O Wang/PERSON kicked/O me/O viciously/O in/O the/O chest/O ./O
The/O pain/O was/O so/O strong/O I/O could/O not/O talk/O ./O
My/O interrogators/O took/O me/O to/O a/O detention/O centre/O where/O I/O asked/O to/O be/O seen/O by/O a/O doctor/O ,/O but/O I/O was/O refused/O ./O
The/O three/O men/O locked/O me/O up/O in/O a/O room/O where/O I/O could/O not/O even/O lie/O down/O because/O of/O the/O pain/O ./O
After/O some/O time/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O how/O long/O ,/O they/O took/O me/O back/O to/O the/O Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION where/O ,/O after/O talking/O among/O themselves/O ,/O they/O told/O me/O :/O ``/O Good/O ,/O now/O that/O the/O holiday/O is/O around/O the/O corner/O -LRB-/O National/O Day/O -RRB-/O ,/O we/O will/O let/O you/O go/O ./O
If/O we/O need/O something/O here/O ,/O we/O 'll/O ask/O you/O to/O come/O over/O ./O ''/O
I/O struggled/O to/O the/O gate/O almost/O crawling/O in/O pain/O ./O
I/O called/O my/O wife/O and/O asked/O her/O to/O pick/O me/O up/O ./O
She/O took/O me/O to/O the/O emergency/O service/O in/O hospital/O where/O they/O found/O that/O the/O kick/O had/O fractured/O my/O rib/O ./O
