Joint/O military/O exercises/O between/O the/O six-member/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Co-operation/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION will/O continue/O till/O August/O 17/O ;/O fighting/O terrorists/O and/O criminals/O is/O one/O of/O their/O objectives/O ./O
The/O games/O are/O allowing/O high-ranking/O officials/O from/O all/O member/O states/O to/O meet/O ./O
Moscow/LOCATION is/O building/O up/O its/O fleet/O and/O Beijing/LOCATION needs/O Russian/O help/O to/O contain/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
Joint/O military/O exercises/O involving/O troops/O from/O China/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ,/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION ,/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION and/O Tajikistan/LOCATION will/O continue/O till/O August/O 17/O ./O
More/O than/O 6,000/O troops/O and/O 36/O aircraft/O from/O the/O six/O nations/O are/O currently/O engaged/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O far/O northwest/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O for/O two/O days/O ;/O tomorrow/O they/O will/O move/O to/O Chelyabinsk/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION ./O
The/O exercises/O are/O intended/O to/O improve/O cooperation/O against/O terrorism/O ,/O drug/O and/O weapons/O trafficking/O and/O criminal/O gangs/O as/O required/O by/O an/O agreement/O of/O mutual/O assistance/O against/O armed/O attacks/O ./O
But/O the/O real/O objective/O is/O political/O ./O
Chinese/O Foreign/O Minister/O Li/PERSON Hui/PERSON noted/O that/O ``/O this/O is/O the/O first/O time/O that/O all/O the/O leaders/O of/O SCO/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O the/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Co-operation/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O nations/O will/O attend/O the/O war/O games/O ./O
All/O the/O member/O countries/O put/O a/O high/O value/O on/O these/O drills/O ./O ''/O
Russian/O chief/O of/O staff/O General/O Yury/PERSON Baluyevsky/PERSON added/O that/O the/O exercises/O ``/O are/O needed/O because/O they/O help/O the/O exchange/O of/O experience/O and/O the/O improvement/O of/O co-operation/O between/O our/O forces/O in/O combating/O new/O challenges/O and/O threats/O ./O ''/O
And/O future/O exercises/O ``/O on/O a/O bigger/O scale/O ''/O are/O planned/O ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION is/O deploying/O a/O 1,600-member/O contingent/O for/O the/O war/O games/O ./O
A/O total/O of/O 32/O Mi-17/O and/O Z-9/O helicopters/O will/O also/O take/O part/O ,/O along/O with/O six/O heavy/O transport/O aircraft/O ,/O eight/O attack/O aircraft/O ,/O and/O a/O company/O of/O airborne/O troops/O ./O
Analysts/O note/O that/O China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION are/O using/O closer/O high-level/O diplomatic/O and/O political/O ties/O among/O SCO/ORGANIZATION members/O to/O expand/O their/O influence/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O contain/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O
But/O human/O rights/O activists/O have/O criticised/O the/O organisation/O for/O helping/O to/O repress/O opposition/O political/O activists/O in/O the/O member/O countries/O through/O such/O practices/O as/O extrajudicial/O transfer/O of/O ``/O suspects/O ''/O between/O countries/O ./O
Ethnic/O Uighur/O Muslims/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION know/O about/O it/O all/O too/O well/O ./O
They/O are/O persecuted/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION which/O has/O cracked/O down/O accusing/O many/O of/O them/O of/O belonging/O to/O terrorist/O and/O secessionist/O organisations/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION needs/O Moscow/LOCATION to/O build/O up/O its/O fleet/O ./O
President/O Vladimir/PERSON Putin/PERSON ,/O who/O comes/O from/O a/O naval/O family/O ,/O appointed/O Admiral/O Masorin/PERSON two/O years/O ago/O with/O instructions/O to/O upgrade/O the/O Russian/O navy/O ./O
Although/O it/O still/O has/O about/O 300/O ships/O ,/O it/O was/O badly/O neglected/O after/O the/O collapse/O of/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION in/O 1991/O ./O
Moscow/LOCATION recently/O approved/O a/O rearmament/O package/O up/O to/O 2015/O ./O
Of/O the/O US$/O 192/O billion/O allocated/O to/O the/O programme/O ,/O 25/O per/O cent/O will/O go/O into/O building/O new/O ships/O ,/O including/O six/O new/O nuclear-powered/O aircraft/O carriers/O to/O be/O built/O over/O the/O next/O 20/O years/O ./O
Some/O analysts/O dismiss/O talk/O of/O rebuilding/O a/O navy/O with/O global/O reach/O as/O propaganda/O ahead/O of/O parliamentary/O elections/O later/O this/O year/O ,/O but/O others/O suggest/O that/O it/O is/O more/O than/O bluster/O because/O Russia/LOCATION is/O now/O earning/O an/O estimated/O US$/O 1/O billion/O every/O two/O days/O from/O its/O energy/O exports/O ,/O and/O so/O has/O the/O means/O to/O do/O it/O ./O
Moreover/O ,/O India/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION depend/O to/O a/O significant/O degree/O on/O Russia/LOCATION for/O their/O own/O naval/O needs/O ./O
However/O ,/O Russian/O naval/O builders/O have/O recently/O had/O problems/O and/O had/O to/O announce/O a/O three-year/O delay/O in/O the/O construction/O of/O a/O US$/O 1.5/O billion/O aircraft/O carrier/O for/O India/LOCATION ./O
For/O Beijing/LOCATION a/O carrier/O would/O be/O a/O fundamental/O addition/O to/O its/O navy/O if/O it/O wanted/O to/O stand/O up/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O secure/O its/O energy/O supplies/O -LRB-/O which/O travel/O through/O the/O Strait/LOCATION of/LOCATION Malacca/LOCATION -RRB-/O or/O even/O mount/O a/O possible/O military/O intervention/O against/O Taiwan/LOCATION ./O
If/O China/LOCATION decides/O to/O develop/O a/O carrier/O for/O training/O and/O eventual/O operation/O ,/O it/O may/O use/O the/O Varyag/O ,/O a/O Kuznetsov-class/O Soviet/O carrier/O that/O was/O only/O 70/O per/O cent/O complete/O when/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION broke/O up/O ./O
Although/O it/O was/O bought/O by/O a/O Chinese/O firm/O in/O 1998/O ,/O the/O mainland/O would/O still/O require/O help/O from/O Russia/LOCATION to/O bring/O the/O Varyag/LOCATION into/O service/O ./O
By/O contrast/O ,/O the/O US/ORGANIZATION Navy/ORGANIZATION today/O has/O 12/O nuclear-powered/O Nimitz-class/O vessels/O ,/O each/O over/O 332/O metres/O long/O with/O 85/O aircrafts/O on/O board/O ./O
Their/O replacements/O will/O be/O even/O bigger/O when/O the/O first/O enters/O service/O in/O seven/O or/O eight/O years/O ./O
Yesterday/O the/O chiefs/O of/O staff/O from/O of/O the/O six/O SCO/ORGANIZATION member-states/O met/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ./O
