Sino-Canadian/O relations/O go/O sour/O over/O treatment/O of/O a/O Uighur-Canadian/O jailed/O for/O life/O and/O intellectual/O property/O laws/O ./O
China/LOCATION wants/O to/O focus/O on/O trade/O ,/O but/O Canada/LOCATION insists/O on/O protecting/O rights/O and/O complains/O about/O Chinese/O spying/O on/O its/O territory/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
Canada/LOCATION 's/O Foreign/O Minister/O Peter/PERSON MacKay/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O on/O a/O three-day/O visit/O to/O mainland/O China/LOCATION that/O ended/O yesterday/O ,/O was/O not/O allowed/O to/O see/O Huseyin/U_PERSON Celil/U_PERSON ,/O a/O Chinese-born/O ethnic/O Uighur/O who/O is/O also/O a/O Canadian/O citizen/O ./O
For/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Mr/O Celil/U_PERSON ,/O who/O was/O sentenced/O to/O life/O in/O prison/O by/O a/O Chinese/O court/O ,/O is/O a/O Chinese/O national/O and/O as/O such/O his/O fate/O is/O an/O internal/O matter/O ./O
Meanwhile/O in/O Canada/LOCATION ,/O Canada/LOCATION 's/O spy/O agency/O reports/O that/O half/O of/O its/O counter-espionage/O efforts/O target/O spies/O from/O the/O Chinese/O mainland/O ./O
MacKay/PERSON 's/O trip/O to/O China/LOCATION had/O been/O planned/O for/O some/O time/O ,/O but/O the/O life/O sentence/O imposed/O on/O Celil/U_PERSON ,/O a/O Uighur/O dissident/O who/O fled/O China/LOCATION for/O Canada/LOCATION where/O he/O was/O given/O refuge/O and/O citizenship/O ,/O changed/O its/O nature/O ./O
Extradited/O to/O China/LOCATION from/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION ,/O he/O was/O jailed/O for/O life/O on/O charges/O of/O `/O terrorism/O '/O and/O `/O separatism/O against/O China/LOCATION ./O '/O
China/LOCATION has/O denied/O Canadian/O diplomats/O access/O to/O him/O as/O required/O by/O a/O consular/O treaty/O between/O the/O two/O nations/O ,/O because/O Beijing/LOCATION refuses/O to/O recognise/O Celil/U_PERSON 's/O Canadian/O citizenship/O ./O
Mr/O MacKay/PERSON ,/O meeting/O his/O newly/O appointed/O counterpart/O Yang/PERSON Jiechi/PERSON ,/O demanded/O consular/O access/O to/O the/O jailed/O Canadian/O citizen/O but/O all/O he/O could/O get/O were/O assurances/O that/O Mr/O Celil/U_PERSON had/O not/O been/O tortured/O ./O
``/O Gaining/O access/O to/O Celil/U_PERSON is/O an/O important/O issue/O of/O this/O government/O and/O we/O will/O continue/O to/O pursue/O it/O ,/O ''/O Mr/O MacKay/PERSON told/O the/O press/O ./O
``/O I/O .../O expressed/O our/O deep/O disappointment/O that/O we/O have/O thus/O far/O been/O denied/O access/O to/O this/O Canadian/O citizen/O ./O ''/O
Chinese/O sources/O have/O instead/O insisted/O that/O the/O case/O was/O an/O internal/O Chinese/O affair/O with/O no/O connection/O to/O Canada/LOCATION ./O
On/O a/O more/O positive/O note/O ,/O Mr/O MacKay/PERSON said/O that/O ,/O despite/O the/O problem/O ,/O relations/O with/O China/LOCATION were/O very/O important/O to/O his/O country/O as/O was/O greater/O co-operation/O in/O every/O field/O ./O
The/O Celil/U_PERSON affair/O is/O not/O the/O only/O event/O that/O has/O soured/O relations/O between/O Ottawa/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
Almost/O half/O Canada/LOCATION 's/O counter-espionage/O efforts/O target/O spies/O from/O the/O Chinese/O mainland/O ,/O Jim/PERSON Judd/PERSON ,/O the/O head/O of/O the/O Canadian/O Security/ORGANIZATION Intelligence/ORGANIZATION Service/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O a/O Senate/ORGANIZATION committee/O on/O Monday/O ./O
Another/O irritant/O is/O the/O Canadian/O parliament/O 's/O decision/O last/O November/O to/O give/O honorary/O citizenship/O to/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ,/O Tibet/LOCATION 's/O spiritual/O leader/O who/O has/O been/O in/O exile/O since/O China/LOCATION 's/O invasion/O ,/O which/O resulted/O in/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON cancelling/O talks/O with/O Canadian/O Prime/O Minister/O Stephen/PERSON Harper/PERSON at/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION Economic/O Co-operation/O summit/O in/O Hanoi/LOCATION ./O
In/O response/O to/O the/O snub/O ,/O Mr/O Harper/PERSON said/O that/O whilst/O Canada/LOCATION wants/O to/O promote/O trade/O relations/O ,/O ``/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O Canadians/O want/O us/O to/O sell/O our/O important/O Canadian/O values/O ./O ''/O
Last/O week/O ,/O Ottawa/LOCATION also/O asked/O to/O take/O part/O in/O World/ORGANIZATION Trade/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION consultations/O on/O the/O application/O of/O intellectual/O property/O rights/O in/O China/LOCATION after/O the/O US/LOCATION lodged/O complaints/O ./O
For/O its/O part/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O complained/O that/O Canada/LOCATION has/O failed/O so/O far/O to/O extradite/O Lai/PERSON Changxing/PERSON ,/O a/O Chinese/O businessman/O it/O described/O as/O its/O most/O wanted/O fugitive/O who/O fled/O to/O Canada/LOCATION with/O his/O wife/O in/O 1999/O after/O he/O was/O accused/O of/O corruption/O and/O smuggling/O goods/O worth/O billions/O of/O dollars/O ./O
