Without/O giving/O any/O evidence/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O described/O the/O camp/O attacked/O on/O 8/O January/O as/O a/O den/O of/O terrorists/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION said/O the/O killing/O of/O 18/O people/O was/O within/O the/O limits/O of/O international/O and/O domestic/O law/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
Chinese/O police/O yesterday/O defended/O an/O attack/O against/O what/O they/O have/O described/O as/O a/O training/O camp/O run/O by/O the/O East/U_ORGANIZATION Turkestan/U_ORGANIZATION Islamic/U_ORGANIZATION Movement/U_ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O ETIM/U_ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O
The/O authorities/O said/O the/O police/O raid/O was/O within/O the/O limits/O of/O international/O and/O domestic/O law/O ./O
Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Liu/PERSON Jianchao/PERSON told/O a/O press/O conference/O that/O ``/O the/O camp/O was/O linked/O to/O international/O terrorism/O ''/O but/O he/O gave/O no/O proof/O to/O substantiate/O his/O allegation/O ./O
Eighteen/O alleged/O terrorists/O were/O killed/O and/O 17/O arrested/O in/O the/O attack/O on/O 8/O January/O in/O the/O northern/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION province/O ./O
A/O police/O official/O was/O killed/O in/O the/O clash/O and/O another/O was/O wounded/O ./O
The/O training/O camp/O is/O located/O in/O the/O Pamir/U_LOCATION Plateau/U_LOCATION in/O one/O of/O the/O highest/O altitudes/O of/O the/O region/O that/O borders/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ./O
Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Public/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Wu/PERSON Heping/PERSON said/O :/O ``/O The/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION had/O identified/O the/O ETIM/U_ORGANIZATION as/O a/O terrorist/O group/O on/O September/O 11/O ,/O 2002/O ./O
These/O activists/O have/O been/O on/O a/O list/O of/O Chinese/O most-wanted/O people/O since/O December/O 15/O ,/O 2003/O ./O ''/O
On/O this/O basis/O ,/O ``/O Chinese/O police/O will/O continue/O to/O closely/O monitor/O the/O situation/O ,/O use/O force/O ,/O strengthen/O international/O co-operation/O and/O crack/O down/O on/O the/O crimes/O of/O any/O terrorists/O and/O their/O groups/O ./O
It/O must/O do/O so/O to/O maintain/O the/O stability/O of/O border/O areas/O and/O to/O protect/O the/O lives/O of/O those/O living/O there/O ./O ''/O
However/O ,/O groups/O lobbying/O for/O human/O rights/O groups/O in/O China/LOCATION have/O accused/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O using/O the/O war/O on/O terror/O as/O a/O cover/O for/O its/O violent/O crackdown/O on/O separatist/O movements/O ./O
Wu/PERSON did/O not/O give/O details/O of/O the/O destroyed/O training/O camp/O ,/O saying/O only/O that/O ``/O police/O were/O still/O investigating/O the/O matter/O ''/O ./O
