It/O stands/O accused/O of/O forcing/O workers/O ,/O many/O of/O them/O children/O and/O mentally/O disabled/O ,/O to/O over/O 20/O hours/O of/O labour/O a/O day/O ./O
Overtime/O was/O not/O paid/O and/O wages/O were/O months/O behind/O ./O
The/O factory/O has/O been/O closed/O down/O and/O investigations/O are/O underway/O ./O
A/O lawyer/O :/O the/O problem/O is/O the/O ``/O laxity/O ''/O of/O those/O who/O should/O be/O protecting/O workers/O rights/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
The/O Xiangtai/U_LOCATION brick/O factory/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION has/O been/O closed/O down/O ./O
It/O is/O accused/O of/O forcing/O its/O workers/O ,/O children/O and/O the/O mentally/O disabled/O of/O working/O up/O to/O 20/O hours/O a/O day/O without/O pay/O ./O
Lin/PERSON Zhonggeng/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION County/U_LOCATION 's/O Labour/ORGANIZATION Supervision/ORGANIZATION Team/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O the/O Xiangtai/U_LOCATION brick/O factory/O operated/O illegally/O and/O had/O no/O records/O of/O employees/O ,/O labour/O contracts/O ,/O social/O security/O payments/O or/O paying/O overtime/O wages/O ./O
A/O former/O worker/O has/O told/O a/O local/O paper/O that/O ``/O They/O hired/O more/O than/O 40/O peasants/O ,/O including/O a/O child/O about/O 13/O year/O 's/O old/O and/O handicapped/O people/O ,/O to/O work/O in/O the/O factory/O ''/O ./O
``/O We/O were/O forced/O to/O work/O from/O 5am/O to/O 2am/O the/O next/O day/O ./O
We/O were/O often/O beaten/O for/O not/O doing/O things/O as/O well/O as/O the/O overseers/O wanted/O ''/O ./O
``/O More/O than/O half/O of/O us/O could/O not/O tolerate/O it/O any/O more/O and/O ran/O away/O without/O getting/O months/O of/O unpaid/O wages/O ''/O ./O
Another/O worker/O confirms/O that/O in/O the/O factory/O ``/O They/O employed/O mentally/O handicapped/O workers/O ./O
Most/O of/O the/O mentally/O disabled/O could/O not/O get/O paid/O even/O though/O they/O were/O forced/O to/O work/O like/O machines/O all/O day/O ''/O ./O
But/O Lin/PERSON insists/O ``/O No/O mentally/O disabled/O worker/O was/O found/O at/O the/O scene/O while/O authorities/O were/O there/O ''/O ./O
The/O factory/O has/O now/O been/O ordered/O to/O shut/O down/O and/O pay/O the/O backlog/O of/O wages/O ./O
But/O Gan/PERSON Weidong/PERSON from/O the/O Xinjiang/U_ORGANIZATION Xinnan/U_ORGANIZATION Law/U_ORGANIZATION Firm/U_ORGANIZATION told/O the/O South/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Morning/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION that/O ``/O Supervision/O and/O enforcement/O of/O relevant/O laws/O is/O too/O lax/O to/O protect/O workers/O ''/O ./O
He/O observes/O that/O although/O Premier/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON has/O spared/O no/O effort/O to/O protect/O workers/O '/O basic/O rights/O since/O taking/O office/O five/O years/O ago/O ,/O ``/O regional/O law/O enforcement/O is/O not/O strict/O enough/O in/O enforcing/O relevant/O laws/O ''/O ./O
``/O That/O 's/O the/O root/O of/O the/O problem/O ''/O ./O
Last/O June/O in/O Shanxi/LOCATION and/O in/O Henan/LOCATION the/O exploitation/O of/O hundreds/O ,/O some/O say/O thousands/O ,/O of/O ``/O slaves/O ''/O was/O denounced/O ./O
Forced/O to/O work/O in/O the/O brick/O factories/O all/O day/O barely/O being/O fed/O ,/O they/O were/O controlled/O by/O guards/O and/O dogs/O to/O prevent/O them/O fleeing/O ./O
Their/O numbers/O included/O kidnapped/O children/O and/O the/O mentally/O disabled/O ./O
But/O after/O a/O few/O weeks/O of/O clamour/O nothing/O more/O was/O heard/O of/O the/O problem/O ./O
