At/O least/O two/O dead/O and/O dozens/O arrested/O in/O a/O recent/O police/O raid/O in/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ./O
But/O human/O rights/O groups/O denounce/O that/O it/O is/O a/O pretext/O to/O undermine/O aspirations/O for/O independence/O ./O
The/O survival/O of/O an/O entire/O ethnic/O group/O at/O risk/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O defended/O its/O right/O to/O ``/O battle/O terrorism/O ''/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O saying/O its/O stance/O was/O ``/O no/O different/O from/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O world/O ''/O ./O
But/O human/O rights/O organisations/O denounce/O that/O the/O annihilation/O of/O an/O entire/O population/O is/O underway/O in/O the/O region/O ./O
State/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION reported/O that/O on/O January/O 27th/O in/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION capital/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ,/O the/O largest/O anti/O terrorism/O operation/O in/O over/O a/O year/O was/O carried/O out/O resulting/O in/O the/O death/O of/O 2/O terrorists/O and/O 15/O arrests/O ,/O accused/O of/O collaborating/O with/O the/O Islamic/O movement/O of/O eastern/O Turkestan/U_LOCATION ,/O an/O organisation/O which/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION has/O branded/O as/O terrorist/O ./O
Instead/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O Sing/ORGANIZATION Tao/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION reports/O that/O at/O least/O 18/O people/O were/O killed/O ./O
No/O further/O news/O is/O to/O be/O had/O regarding/O the/O episode/O because/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O imposed/O rigid/O control/O on/O all/O information/O from/O the/O region/O ,/O considered/O essential/O given/O its/O vast/O energy/O resources/O and/O strategic/O position/O in/O central/O Asia/LOCATION ./O
However/O some/O critics/O --/O among/O them/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION --/O accuse/O China/LOCATION of/O using/O terrorism/O a/O san/O excuse/O to/O quash/O peaceful/O aspirations/O for/O independence/O and/O to/O pursue/O a/O systematic/O elimination/O of/O the/O local/O people/O ,/O the/O Uyghur/O ,/O followers/O of/O Islam/O with/O their/O own/O language/O and/O traditions/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION gas/O favoured/O the/O immigration/O of/O millions/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O ,/O conceding/O them/O trade/O incentives/O and/O access/O to/O positions/O of/O power/O ./O
These/O have/O hit/O out/O at/O the/O local/O language/O and/O traditions/O and/O place/O obstacles/O in/O the/O way/O of/O the/O practise/O of/O the/O Islamic/O faith/O :/O women/O and/O minors/O are/O not/O allowed/O to/O enter/O mosques/O and/O Islamic/O schools/O are/O forbidden/O ./O
Moreover/O they/O have/O vastly/O reduced/O the/O number/O of/O pilgrims/O allowed/O to/O journey/O to/O Mecca/LOCATION ./O
The/O episodes/O of/O terrorism/O ,/O which/O have/O been/O isolated/O ,/O are/O being/O used/O as/O a/O pretext/O to/O deny/O vast/O swathes/O of/O the/O population/O their/O basic/O human/O rights/O ./O
In/O 2005/O 18,227/O Uyghur/O were/O arrested/O because/O they/O ``/O they/O were/O a/O threat/O to/O national/O security/O ''/O ./O
