Hu/PERSON maintains/O China/LOCATION has/O quashed/O separatism/O ,/O extremism/O and/O terrorism/O ./O
But/O he/O asks/O the/O party/O ,/O military/O and/O local/O authorities/O to/O work/O to/O improve/O the/O economic/O development/O of/O the/O population/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION denies/O the/O upcoming/O trial/O of/O 200/O Uyghur/O as/O well/O as/O torture/O and/O the/O death/O of/O hundreds/O of/O prisoners/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O
For/O the/O first/O time/O since/O violent/O clashes/O at/O the/O beginning/O of/O July/O ,/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON has/O visited/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O proclaiming/O victory/O over/O the/O three/O forces/O that/O endanger/O China/LOCATION :/O separatism/O ,/O extremism/O and/O terrorism/O ./O
In/O his/O tour/O of/O inspection/O ,/O August/O 22/O to/O 25/O ,/O Hu/PERSON visited/O villages/O ,/O farms/O ,/O industries/O ,/O communities/O and/O barracks/O ,/O having/O meetings/O with/O army/O personnel/O ,/O local/O government/O and/O religious/O representatives/O ./O
On/O 5/O July/O ,/O a/O peaceful/O demonstration/O by/O Uyghurs/O ,/O blocked/O by/O police/O ,/O turned/O into/O open/O clashes/O between/O Muslim/O ethnic/O Uyghurs/O ,/O the/O local/O population/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O who/O are/O currently/O colonizing/O the/O economics/O and/O politics/O of/O the/O region/O ./O
At/O least/O 200/O people/O died/O and/O over/O 2/O thousand/O were/O injured/O ./O
The/O Uighur/O groups/O abroad/O ,/O claim/O more/O than/O 10/O thousand/O Uyghurs/O disappeared/O ,/O probably/O killed/O or/O arrested/O ./O
Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ,/O to/O address/O the/O crisis/O ,/O was/O forced/O to/O abandon/O G8/O meetings/O in/O Italy/LOCATION and/O rush/O home/O ./O
During/O his/O tour/O ,/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON visited/O the/O widow/O ,/O Zhao/PERSON Li/PERSON ,/O wife/O of/O a/O policeman/O killed/O in/O the/O clashes/O ./O
At/O the/O same/O time/O he/O promised/O local/O farmers/O more/O efficient/O economic/O measures/O to/O support/O ethnic/O minorities/O ./O
In/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O their/O homeland/O ,/O the/O Uyghurs/O are/O marginalized/O from/O economic/O and/O political/O life/O ,/O suffering/O violations/O of/O their/O religious/O freedom/O ./O
In/O a/O meeting/O with/O party/O leaders/O ,/O army/O and/O police/O ,/O Hu/PERSON stressed/O that/O the/O key/O to/O stability/O in/O the/O region/O and/O ``/O the/O most/O urgent/O task/O ''/O is/O to/O increase/O economic/O development/O and/O living/O standards/O of/O the/O population/O ./O
Only/O then/O -/O he/O said/O -/O can/O we/O build/O a/O ``/O prosperous/O ,/O harmonious/O socialist/O ''/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
This/O emphasis/O on/O local/O problems/O contrasts/O with/O the/O interpretation/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O expounded/O since/O the/O riots/O ,/O blamed/O on/O foreign/O groups/O and/O powers/O ,/O on/O Muslim/O separatists/O and/O terrorists/O ./O
In/O recent/O days/O it/O was/O reported/O that/O ,/O at/O the/O very/O end/O of/O Hu/PERSON 's/O visit/O ,/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION the/O trial/O of/O 200/O Uyghur/O charged/O with/O violence/O during/O the/O July/O riots/O ,/O took/O place/O ./O
But/O local/O authorities/O have/O denied/O this/O ./O
Another/O news/O report/O spoke/O of/O about/O 200/O Uyghur/O ``/O tortured/O and/O killed/O ''/O in/O Chinese/O prisons/O in/O recent/O weeks/O ./O
The/O spokesman/O of/O the/O government/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O Hou/PERSON Hanmin/PERSON ,/O again/O denied/O this/O ,/O noting/O that/O the/O official/O number/O of/O those/O arrested/O is/O 83/O ./O
The/O situation/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION remains/O tense/O :/O phones/O and/O internet/O services/O are/O blocked/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O various/O local/O sites/O and/O global/O networks/O such/O as/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION and/O Twitter/ORGANIZATION ./O
According/O to/O official/O figures/O ,/O at/O least/O 200/O thousand/O tourists/O have/O cancelled/O their/O holidays/O to/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION after/O the/O riots/O ./O
