US/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION calls/O on/O China/LOCATION to/O respect/O its/O citizens/O '/O human/O and/O legal/O rights/O after/O nine/O members/O of/O the/O Uighur/O minority/O are/O executed/O ./O
The/O US/LOCATION might/O be/O shifting/O its/O stance/O ahead/O of/O the/O Hu-Obama/O meeting/O ./O
Washington/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
The/O US/LOCATION government/O has/O urged/O China/LOCATION on/O Monday/O to/O ensure/O fair/O trials/O after/O nine/O people/O were/O executed/O over/O ethnic/O unrest/O ./O
This/O has/O thrown/O the/O spotlight/O on/O human/O rights/O ahead/O of/O President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON 's/O 18/O November/O visit/O to/O mainland/O China/LOCATION ./O
Twenty/O more/O people/O have/O been/O sentenced/O to/O death/O for/O the/O same/O reasons/O ./O
Chinese/O authorities/O announced/O yesterday/O that/O nine/O members/O of/O the/O Uighur/O minority/O were/O executed/O for/O their/O action/O during/O violent/O disorders/O that/O broke/O out/O last/O July/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION Province/U_LOCATION ./O
More/O than/O 200/O people/O died/O during/O the/O incident/O ,/O which/O was/O followed/O by/O a/O large/O number/O of/O police/O arrests/O ./O
The/O death/O penalties/O were/O carried/O out/O ``/O with/O the/O approval/O of/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O China/LOCATION 's/O official/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION reported/O ./O
It/O was/O not/O clear/O when/O the/O executions/O took/O place/O ./O
All/O nine/O had/O been/O convicted/O on/O murder/O charges/O and/O other/O crimes/O ,/O Xingua/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O
Another/O 20/O were/O formally/O charged/O with/O causing/O the/O death/O of/O 18/O people/O during/O the/O unrest/O ./O
``/O The/O US/LOCATION government/O continues/O to/O urge/O China/LOCATION to/O handle/O all/O detentions/O and/O judicial/O processes/O relating/O to/O the/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION -LSB-/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION 's/O capital/O -RSB-/O violence/O in/O a/O transparent/O manner/O ,/O ''/O State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Ian/PERSON Kelly/PERSON told/O reporters/O ./O
``/O We/O also/O urge/O China/LOCATION to/O ensure/O that/O the/O legal/O rights/O of/O all/O Chinese/O citizens/O are/O respected/O in/O accordance/O with/O international/O standards/O of/O due/O process/O ./O ''/O
This/O stance/O represents/O a/O shift/O in/O policy/O towards/O China/LOCATION by/O the/O Obama/PERSON administration/O ./O
The/O new/O president/O had/O avoided/O meeting/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON during/O his/O trip/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O
Now/O with/O this/O warning/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION is/O indicating/O that/O human/O rights/O and/O other/O ethical/O issues/O will/O be/O on/O the/O table/O when/O Obama/PERSON meets/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ./O
Obama/PERSON will/O talk/O about/O religious/O freedom/O ,/O the/O plight/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O and/O other/O human/O rights/O issues/O with/O Hu/PERSON ,/O according/O to/O Jeffrey/PERSON Bader/PERSON ,/O the/O US/LOCATION president/O 's/O senior/O director/O for/O Asian/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION on/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION National/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O The/O president/O will/O raise/O human/O rights/O concerns/O directly/O with/O President/O Hu/PERSON in/O his/O meetings/O ,/O ''/O Bader/PERSON said/O ./O
``/O The/O kind/O of/O issues/O that/O are/O on/O our/O minds/O are/O issues/O of/O freedom/O of/O expression/O ,/O access/O to/O information/O ,/O freedom/O of/O religion/O ,/O rule/O of/O law/O ./O ''/O
