China/LOCATION formal/O protests/O with/O Tokyo/LOCATION over/O the/O presence/O of/O Uyghur/O leader/O Kadeer/U_PERSON ,/O even/O demanding/O cautionary/O anti-/O terrorism/O measures/O ./O
Instead/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION complains/O of/O incorrect/O versions/O of/O the/O protests/O of/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ./O
Experts/O :/O To/O avoid/O misunderstandings/O ,/O why/O not/O accept/O a/O inquiry/O commission/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O
China/LOCATION has/O called/O the/O Japanese/O ambassador/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O protest/O the/O visit/O to/O Japan/LOCATION of/O Rebiya/U_PERSON Kadeer/U_PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O Uyghur/U_ORGANIZATION World/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION ./O
The/O Chinese/O Vice/O Minister/O for/O Foreign/O Affairs/O Wu/PERSON Dawei/PERSON said/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION ``/O asked/O the/O Japanese/O government/O to/O take/O immediate/O effective/O measures/O to/O prevent/O -LSB-/O the/O Kadeer/U_PERSON -RSB-/O from/O carrying/O out/O anti-China/O separatist/O activities/O in/O Japan/LOCATION ./O ''/O
Sources/O of/O the/O Japanese/O Government/O responded/O that/O the/O woman/O has/O not/O been/O invited/O by/O the/O government/O ,/O nor/O had/O dealings/O with/O it/O ./O
In/O Tokyo/LOCATION ,/O Kadeer/U_PERSON spoke/O of/O the/O Uyghurs/O cause/O ,/O accusing/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O violence/O and/O persecution/O and/O met/O parliamentarians/O from/O the/O Liberal/ORGANIZATION Democratic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION which/O is/O part/O of/O the/O ruling/O coalition/O ./O
China/LOCATION says/O that/O the/O woman/O is/O a/O dangerous/O terrorist/O and/O separatist/O and/O organized/O violent/O protests/O that/O broke/O out/O on/O July/O 5/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
Yesterday/O ,/O the/O Kadeer/U_PERSON also/O accused/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O of/O being/O behind/O the/O overnight/O disappearance/O ``/O of/O about/O 10/O thousand/O people/O ''/O from/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ,/O capital/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
Today/O Hou/PERSON Hanmin/PERSON ,/O spokesman/O of/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION government/O ,/O denied/O the/O allegations/O ,/O insisting/O on/O the/O official/O figures/O of/O about/O 1,700/O arrests/O for/O violent/O protests/O ./O
Furthermore/O ,/O the/O province/O has/O issued/O a/O list/O of/O 15/O fugitive/O Uyghurs/O ,/O wanted/O on/O charges/O of/O having/O had/O a/O ``/O significant/O role/O ''/O in/O the/O protests/O ./O
The/O Kadeer/U_PERSON has/O also/O asked/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O ``/O to/O dialogue/O ''/O and/O called/O on/O the/O international/O community/O to/O press/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O look/O for/O a/O peaceful/O solution/O to/O the/O problem/O of/O the/O Uyghurs/O ,/O a/O minority/O in/O their/O own/O country/O and/O subject/O to/O systematic/O cultural/O and/O physical/O persecution/O ./O
Chinese/O diplomacy/O is/O working/O to/O mitigate/O the/O negative/O effect/O of/O the/O protests/O and/O the/O crackdown/O in/O place/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
Ambassador/O Song/PERSON Zhe/PERSON ,/O Head/O of/O the/O Chinese/O Mission/O to/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ,/O has/O written/O article/O in/O European/ORGANIZATION Voice/ORGANIZATION entitled/O ``/O What/O Europe/LOCATION should/O understand/O about/O the/O violence/O in/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ''/O ,/O in/O which/O he/O insists/O that/O the/O Uyghurs/O started/O the/O violent/O protests/O and/O that/O the/O police/O had/O to/O protect/O the/O safety/O of/O innocent/O citizens/O ./O
Many/O comments/O on/O blog/O posts/O from/O China/LOCATION are/O cited/O as/O evidence/O in/O support/O of/O this/O version/O ./O
But/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O internet/O was/O shut/O down/O across/O the/O region/O in/O the/O immediate/O aftermath/O of/O the/O protests/O is/O not/O explained/O ./O
Song/PERSON celebrates/O Beijing/LOCATION as/O an/O example/O of/O economic/O growth/O and/O tolerance/O and/O recalls/O the/O 23/O thousand/O mosques/O that/O exist/O across/O the/O country/O ./O
But/O the/O frequent/O prohibitions/O affecting/O Muslims/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O with/O regard/O to/O their/O religion/O ,/O language/O ,/O culture/O are/O not/O mentioned/O ./O
