As/O Beijing/LOCATION launches/O a/O `/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION 's/O charm/O '/O campaign/O to/O draw/O tourists/O back/O to/O the/O region/O and/O its/O old/O `/O Silk/U_LOCATION Road/U_LOCATION '/O ,/O the/O father/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O pro-democracy/O movement/O ,/O currently/O living/O in/O exile/O ,/O says/O the/O killing/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION earlier/O this/O month/O was/O planned/O to/O turn/O public/O opinion/O away/O from/O infighting/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O China/LOCATION 's/O campaign/O to/O extend/O its/O control/O over/O petroleum-producing/O nations/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O
Washington/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O WJSF/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O --/O
They/O all/O say/O it/O is/O a/O season/O of/O great/O events/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
Indeed/O ,/O it/O is/O ./O
What/O has/O happened/O in/O Shaoguan/LOCATION -LRB-/O Guangdong/LOCATION -RRB-/O and/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION -RRB-/O has/O already/O resulted/O in/O continued/O condemnation/O from/O the/O international/O community/O ./O
Meanwhile/O ,/O there/O is/O news/O that/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CCP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O has/O quarrelled/O with/O the/O Australian/O government/O and/O arrested/O the/O China/LOCATION chief/O of/O a/O big/O Australian/O company/O ./O
The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O neither/O put/O him/O on/O trial/O or/O sentenced/O him/O ,/O nor/O provided/O detailed/O information/O to/O the/O Australian/O government/O even/O when/O the/O Australian/O Prime/O Minister/O and/O Foreign/O Affairs/O Minister/O made/O inquiries/O ./O
This/O kind/O of/O conduct/O that/O violates/O international/O conventions/O will/O surely/O generate/O anger/O in/O Australia/LOCATION ,/O and/O will/O surely/O make/O foreign/O business/O people/O in/O China/LOCATION more/O nervous/O ./O
Who/O knows/O whether/O China/LOCATION 's/O secrecy/O laws/O will/O apply/O to/O them/O as/O well/O ?/O
Since/O the/O Yan`an/LOCATION period/O in/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON 's/O rule/O ,/O these/O secrecy/O laws/O have/O been/O 100/O per/O cent/O effective/O ./O
However/O ,/O since/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION issue/O is/O more/O important/O for/O the/O average/O Chinese/O ,/O and/O has/O had/O new/O developments/O ,/O let/O us/O put/O aside/O the/O matter/O of/O Australian/O business/O involvement/O with/O the/O corrupt/O CCP/ORGANIZATION ./O
There/O are/O two/O issues/O that/O did/O not/O receive/O enough/O attention/O lately/O ./O
According/O to/O a/O report/O by/O BoXun/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O most/O reputable/O overseas/O Chinese/O website/O ,/O an/O old/O party/O official/O who/O retired/O from/O the/O party/O during/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION 's/O 17th/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION revealed/O that/O the/O reason/O for/O the/O explosive/O situation/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION was/O a/O struggle/O within/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION ./O
From/O the/O jailing/O of/O Shanghai/LOCATION Mayor/O Chen/PERSON LiangYu/PERSON to/O last/O month/O 's/O detention/O of/O Shenzhen/LOCATION Mayor/O Xu/PERSON Zongheng/PERSON ,/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON joined/O forces/O with/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON to/O beat/O the/O leading/O members/O of/O the/O Jiang/PERSON Zemin/PERSON faction/O ./O
Thus/O the/O Jiang/PERSON faction/O had/O to/O find/O an/O opportunity/O to/O fight/O back/O ./O
They/O did/O so/O by/O fuelling/O tensions/O which/O led/O to/O the/O Shaoguan/LOCATION incident/O ,/O and/O by/O demobilising/O police/O during/O the/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION riots/O ,/O thus/O enabling/O Uyghur/O terrorists/O to/O use/O a/O peaceful/O demonstration/O to/O murder/O Han/O Chinese/O to/O the/O extent/O that/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON lost/O face/O at/O the/O G8/ORGANIZATION meeting/O in/O Italy/LOCATION ./O
Hu/PERSON had/O to/O return/O to/O China/LOCATION to/O secure/O his/O own/O backyard/O and/O prevent/O the/O situation/O from/O getting/O out/O of/O control/O at/O his/O expense/O ./O
A/O lot/O of/O information/O has/O been/O recently/O leaked/O that/O proves/O that/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION government/O is/O guilty/O of/O doing/O nothing/O ,/O thus/O allowing/O thugs/O to/O cause/O large/O scale/O murder/O ./O
This/O tragedy/O had/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O the/O World/U_ORGANIZATION Uyghur/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION which/O supported/O the/O peaceful/O demonstration/O ./O
The/O CCP/ORGANIZATION Xinjiang/U_LOCATION government/O had/O reliable/O intelligence/O and/O enough/O power/O to/O start/O police/O action/O ./O
But/O since/O the/O Jiang/PERSON faction/O controls/O China/LOCATION 's/O legal/O system/O and/O courts/O ,/O they/O chose/O the/O strategy/O of/O doing/O nothing/O before/O and/O during/O the/O tragedy/O ./O
They/O enabled/O Uyghur/O terrorists/O to/O do/O whatever/O they/O wanted/O and/O allowed/O the/O situation/O to/O get/O out/O of/O control/O ./O
Indeed/O ,/O through/O skilful/O cooperation/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION 's/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION government/O and/O Uyghur/O terrorist/O group/O are/O responsible/O for/O such/O a/O horrifying/O tragedy/O ./O
Some/O friends/O are/O still/O not/O willing/O to/O believe/O that/O it/O was/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION that/O took/O the/O initiative/O in/O this/O tragedy/O ./O
They/O do/O not/O believe/O that/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION was/O trying/O to/O cause/O hateful/O ethnic/O killing/O in/O an/O effort/O to/O shift/O political/O attention/O ./O
If/O anyone/O thinks/O this/O way/O ,/O they/O might/O want/O to/O consider/O the/O second/O piece/O of/O news/O ./O
During/O a/O review/O of/O the/O Sino-Russian/O joint/O military/O exercise/O ,/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION military/O Chief/O of/O General/O Staff/O ,/O Admiral/O Chen/PERSON Bingde/PERSON ,/O talked/O a/O lot/O about/O ``/O anti-terrorism/O ''/O ,/O pointing/O the/O finger/O at/O Uyghurs/O ./O
He/O claimed/O that/O China/LOCATION would/O cooperate/O with/O the/O four/O Central/O Asian/O members/O of/O the/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION and/O send/O troops/O outside/O of/O China/LOCATION to/O attack/O Uyghur/O terrorist/O organisations/O ./O
He/O skilfully/O played/O on/O ordinary/O people/O 's/O desire/O for/O security/O whilst/O increasing/O their/O sense/O of/O hostility/O ./O
At/O the/O same/O time/O he/O was/O able/O to/O extend/O China/LOCATION 's/O military/O forces/O to/O the/O edges/O of/O the/O Mideast/LOCATION petroleum-producing/O region/O in/O order/O to/O thwart/O Western/O goal/O of/O controlling/O it/O ./O
Trying/O to/O kill/O two/O birds/O with/O two/O stones/O is/O no/O coincidence/O but/O a/O long/O term/O strategy/O ./O
Some/O people/O wonder/O whether/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION tragedy/O was/O meant/O to/O make/O trouble/O for/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ./O
Why/O does/O he/O have/O to/O swallow/O this/O bitter/O fruit/O ?/O
Why/O did/O he/O not/O try/O to/O stop/O it/O or/O even/O counterattack/O ?/O
They/O are/O too/O anxious/O ./O
Counterattacking/O does/O not/O have/O to/O happen/O today/O ./O
``/O For/O a/O gentleman/O to/O take/O his/O revenge/O ,/O ten/O years/O is/O not/O too/O late/O ''/O says/O an/O old/O Chinese/O saying/O ./O
Not/O counterattacking/O today/O does/O not/O mean/O never/O counterattacking/O ./O
What/O is/O more/O ,/O the/O plan/O to/O cause/O the/O tragedy/O was/O perfectly/O executed/O ./O
The/O underlying/O reasons/O were/O sufficient/O ;/O the/O choice/O of/O timing/O was/O just/O right/O ./O
So/O Zhou/PERSON Yongkang/PERSON ,/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION 's/O official/O in/O charge/O of/O security/O ,/O could/O say/O that/O without/O the/O order/O from/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ,/O he/O could/O not/O order/O his/O troops/O to/O open/O fire/O to/O stop/O the/O escalation/O ,/O which/O gave/O the/O thugs/O several/O hours/O to/O murder/O ./O
As/O for/O why/O not/O letting/O the/O military/O police/O move/O into/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ,/O there/O is/O the/O simplest/O excuse/O of/O underestimating/O the/O problem/O which/O is/O not/O enough/O to/O condemn/O anyone/O to/O death/O ./O
The/O most/O important/O thing/O is/O that/O there/O is/O sufficient/O reason/O to/O do/O something/O after/O the/O tragedy/O ./O
These/O conspirators/O did/O not/O just/O shift/O people/O 's/O attention/O away/O from/O opposition/O -LSB-/O to/O the/O regime/O -RSB-/O ,/O they/O also/O might/O have/O obtained/O a/O frontier/O base/O to/O move/O west/O into/O the/O petroleum/O producing/O areas/O ./O
What/O reason/O could/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON use/O to/O go/O against/O this/O ?/O
This/O is/O exactly/O what/O he/O wanted/O to/O do/O ,/O but/O did/O not/O dare/O to/O do/O ./O
He/O had/O no/O reason/O to/O oppose/O this/O even/O if/O he/O has/O to/O carry/O a/O knife/O in/O his/O back/O ./O
This/O situation/O is/O similar/O to/O when/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON murdered/O the/O 10th/O Panchen/PERSON Lama/PERSON ,/O something/O which/O scared/O Deng/PERSON Xiao/PERSON Ping/PERSON -LSB-/O 2/O -RSB-/O even/O though/O it/O was/O one/O of/O his/O goals/O ./O
In/O fact/O Deng/PERSON wanted/O to/O do/O this/O but/O did/O not/O dare/O to/O do/O it/O ./O
In/O addition/O ,/O they/O dealt/O with/O the/O aftermath/O skilfully/O by/O not/O allowing/O Western/O media/O to/O find/O something/O to/O protest/O against/O ./O
So/O Deng/PERSON happily/O welcomed/O this/O unexpected/O surprise/O and/O saw/O Hu/PERSON in/O a/O new/O light/O ./O
This/O time/O ,/O dealing/O of/O the/O aftermath/O was/O more/O difficult/O but/O the/O outcome/O was/O good/O as/O well/O ./O
Even/O some/O anti-CCP/O patriotic/O youths/O turned/O around/O to/O help/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION attack/O Uyghur/O opposition/O forces/O ./O
Some/O Western/O media/O ,/O who/O ca/O n't/O see/O the/O forest/O for/O the/O trees/O ,/O unwittingly/O became/O accomplices/O in/O this/O evil/O ./O
This/O goes/O to/O show/O that/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION conspiracy/O was/O successful/O ,/O something/O that/O is/O bound/O to/O increase/O ./O
By/O contrast/O ,/O we/O must/O try/O instead/O to/O clearly/O distinguish/O between/O good/O from/O evil/O so/O as/O not/O to/O fall/O for/O the/O conspiracy/O of/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O
-LSB-/O 1/O -RSB-/O The/O author/O here/O refers/O to/O the/O arrest/O of/O four/O employees/O of/O the/O British-Australian/O company/O Rio/ORGANIZATION Tinto/ORGANIZATION on/O charges/O of/O corrupting/O Chinese/O officials/O in/O charge/O of/O a/O steel/O mill/O before/O a/O contract/O involving/O an/O iron/O mine/O was/O signed/O ./O
One/O of/O the/O four/O employees/O holds/O Australian/O passport/O ./O
All/O four/O are/O accused/O of/O stealing/O a/O ``/O state/O secret/O ''/O ./O
-LSB-/O 2/O -RSB-/O The/O 10th/O Panchen/PERSON Lama/PERSON died/O unexpectedly/O in/O 1989/O after/O criticising/O China/LOCATION 's/O Tibet/LOCATION policy/O in/O a/O speech/O ./O
For/O years/O Beijing/LOCATION had/O tried/O to/O subjugate/O him/O by/O different/O means/O ,/O including/O prison/O ,/O house/O arrests/O and/O forcing/O him/O to/O marry/O a/O Han/O Chinese/O woman/O ./O
