Shackled/O and/O hooded/O ,/O the/O five/O -/O who/O had/O fled/O from/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION -/O have/O been/O put/O on/O a/O plane/O to/O return/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O
There/O ,/O Uyghur/O dissidents/O denounce/O ,/O ``/O torture/O and/O jail/O await/O them/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION continues/O its/O ferocious/O repression/O against/O us/O ./O ''/O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O
With/O the/O complicity/O of/O the/O Pakistani/O government/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O regime/O has/O deported/O five/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O who/O had/O fled/O from/O China/LOCATION and/O had/O crossed/O the/O border/O into/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
Among/O the/O five/O treated/O as/O terrorists/O ,/O we/O are/O a/O woman/O and/O two/O children/O ,/O the/O extradition/O was/O imposed/O after/O the/O riots/O in/O recent/O weeks/O that/O have/O taken/O place/O in/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
The/O Pakistani/O authorities/O handcuffed/O the/O five/O on/O the/O morning/O of/O August/O 9/O and/O ,/O after/O being/O hooded/O ,/O took/O them/O in/O the/O airport/O Benazir/LOCATION Bhutto/LOCATION international/O :/O here/O they/O were/O boarded/O on/O a/O China/ORGANIZATION Southern/ORGANIZATION Airline/ORGANIZATION flight/O ./O
Among/O the/O five/O a/O women/O ,/O Manzokra/U_PERSON Mamad/U_PERSON ,/O who/O was/O carrying/O the/O minor/O daughter/O and/O teenage/O son/O ,/O was/O identified/O by/O some/O dissidents/O ,/O ./O
According/O to/O the/O World/U_ORGANIZATION Uyghur/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O non-governmental/O organization/O based/O in/O Germany/LOCATION that/O monitors/O the/O situation/O of/O compatriots/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O ``/O extradition/O is/O illegal/O ,/O cruel/O and/O shows/O hate/O towards/O minorities/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O then/O ,/O is/O even/O more/O so/O :/O they/O know/O what/O happens/O to/O the/O Uyghurs/O who/O are/O forcibly/O repatriated/O ./O
They/O are/O tortured/O and/O thrown/O into/O jail/O for/O no/O reason/O ./O ''/O
On/O August/O 1/O ,/O Chinese/O police/O shot/O in/O cold/O blood/O two/O Uyghurs/O suspected/O of/O being/O involved/O in/O the/O July/O 31/O attack/O that/O caused/O the/O death/O of/O six/O people/O in/O a/O bar/O in/O Kashgar/U_LOCATION ./O
The/O two/O -/O Memtieli/U_PERSON Tiliwaldi/U_PERSON -LRB-/O 29/O -RRB-/O and/O Turson/U_PERSON Hasan/U_PERSON -LRB-/O 34/O -RRB-/O -/O were/O killed/O in/O a/O cornfield/O and/O left/O there/O ./O
Kashgar/U_LOCATION 's/O government/O had/O put/O a/O bounty/O of/O 100/O thousand/O yuan/O -LRB-/O about/O 10/O thousand/O euros/O -RRB-/O for/O their/O capture/O ./O
Before/O this/O last/O episode/O bloody/O episodes/O erupted/O in/O the/O city/O of/O Hotan/U_LOCATION and/O in/O the/O provincial/O capital/O ,/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ./O
The/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O --/O Turkish/O speaking/O peoples/O of/O Islamic/O religion/O --/O have/O languished/O under/O the/O heel/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O since/O 1949/O which/O has/O imposed/O a/O series/O of/O extreme/O religious/O and/O cultural/O restrictions/O on/O the/O minority/O ./O
Several/O groups/O claim/O independence/O and/O demand/O the/O restoration/O of/O East/U_LOCATION Turkestan/U_LOCATION ,/O but/O the/O majority/O of/O Uyghurs/O only/O want/O greater/O autonomy/O ./O
