Beijing/LOCATION is/O providing/O ``/O sincere/O and/O selfless/O help/O ''/O to/O Karzai/PERSON in/O the/O form/O of/O US$/O 24/O million/O to/O fund/O infrastructure/O and/O scholarships/O ./O
China/LOCATION is/O concerned/O with/O fundamentalist/O influence/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
It/O will/O provide/O a/O US$/O 10/O billion/O loan/O for/O railways/O ,/O telecommunications/O and/O energy/O pipelines/O to/O SCO/ORGANIZATION member/O states/O ./O
The/O group/O reiterates/O its/O opposition/O to/O the/O use/O of/O force/O against/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O but/O calls/O on/O Iran/LOCATION to/O be/O ``/O pragmatic/O and/O flexible/O ''/O in/O nuclear/O talks/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O
The/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SCO/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O a/O group/O that/O includes/O China/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION and/O four/O Central/O Asian/O nations/O ,/O has/O granted/O Afghanistan/LOCATION observer/O status/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION has/O also/O pledged/O immediate/O aid/O to/O Kabul/LOCATION and/O much/O more/O once/O NATO/ORGANIZATION troops/O leave/O the/O country/O in/O 2014/O ./O
The/O group/O has/O also/O expressed/O its/O opposition/O to/O any/O use/O of/O force/O against/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O which/O already/O has/O observer/O status/O in/O the/O organisation/O ./O
The/O two-day/O meeting/O in/O the/O Chinese/O capital/O ,/O which/O ended/O yesterday/O ,/O saw/O the/O participation/O of/O Turkey/LOCATION as/O a/O ``/O partner/O in/O dialogue/O ''/O ./O
With/O the/O Eurasian/O country/O ,/O SCO/ORGANIZATION now/O embrace/O countries/O from/O the/O Mediterranean/LOCATION to/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION Ocean/LOCATION ./O
In/O addition/O to/O Russia/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION ,/O SCO/ORGANIZATION includes/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION ,/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ,/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION and/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ./O
Iran/LOCATION ,/O India/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Mongolia/LOCATION are/O observers/O ./O
Founded/O as/O a/O security/O community/O to/O fight/O terrorism/O ,/O the/O organisation/O is/O now/O evolving/O into/O an/O area/O of/O economic/O cooperation/O ./O
Yesterday/O ,/O China/LOCATION offered/O a/O US$/O 10/O billion/O loan/O for/O economic/O development/O to/O help/O member/O states/O establish/O railway/O ,/O telecommunications/O and/O energy/O pipeline/O links/O ./O
Member/O countries/O have/O also/O agreed/O to/O boost/O mutual/O economic/O relations/O ./O
For/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O acceptance/O by/O SCO/ORGANIZATION is/O an/O economic/O and/O political/O windfall/O ./O
President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON told/O Afghan/O President/O Karzai/PERSON that/O China/LOCATION would/O provide/O ``/O sincere/O and/O selfless/O help/O ''/O to/O the/O beleaguered/O country/O ,/O including/O 150/O million/O yuan/O -LRB-/O US$/O 24/O million/O -RRB-/O in/O aid/O this/O year/O for/O infrastructure/O and/O scholarships/O ./O
The/O two/O signed/O a/O strategic/O partnership/O agreement/O ,/O under/O which/O China/LOCATION said/O it/O would/O encourage/O Chinese/O investment/O ./O
With/O NATO/ORGANIZATION planning/O to/O pull/O out/O from/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O 2014/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O getting/O edgy/O over/O possible/O chaos/O in/O its/O western/O neighbour/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O an/O increase/O in/O the/O opium/O trade/O and/O fundamentalism/O infiltration/O ,/O especially/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
Hu/PERSON said/O that/O SCO/ORGANIZATION must/O play/O a/O greater/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O but/O Russia/LOCATION excluded/O any/O military/O presence/O in/O the/O country/O ./O
During/O the/O summit/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O leader/O met/O his/O Iranian/O counterpart/O ,/O President/O Mahmud/PERSON Ahmadinejad/PERSON ./O
During/O their/O talks/O ,/O Hu/PERSON asked/O him/O to/O be/O ``/O pragmatic/O and/O flexible/O ''/O in/O ongoing/O nuclear/O talks/O ./O
On/O 18-19/O June/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION will/O host/O a/O new/O round/O of/O talks/O between/O Iran/LOCATION and/O the/O 5/O +1/O group/O -LRB-/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Russia/LOCATION ,/O Great/LOCATION Britain/LOCATION ,/O France/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION and/O Germany/LOCATION -RRB-/O to/O stop/O Tehran/LOCATION from/O developing/O a/O programme/O they/O suspect/O might/O include/O a/O nuclear/O military/O capability/O ./O
Without/O an/O agreement/O ,/O new/O and/O tougher/O financial/O and/O trade/O sanctions/O will/O come/O into/O effect/O on/O 1/O July/O ./O
Iran/LOCATION has/O always/O said/O that/O its/O nuclear/O programme/O does/O not/O have/O a/O military/O component/O ./O
Iranian/O Ambassador/O to/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Atomic/ORGANIZATION Energy/ORGANIZATION Agency/ORGANIZATION Ali/PERSON Asghar/PERSON Soltanieh/PERSON recently/O announced/O that/O his/O government/O is/O ready/O to/O counter/O any/O fear/O ./O
``/O We/O are/O ready/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ,/O ``/O to/O remove/O all/O the/O ambiguities/O and/O prove/O to/O the/O whole/O world/O that/O our/O nuclear/O activities/O are/O exclusive/O -LSB-/O ly/O -RSB-/O for/O peaceful/O purposes/O ''/O ./O
In/O a/O final/O statement/O ,/O SCO/ORGANIZATION said/O that/O the/O use/O of/O force/O against/O Iran/LOCATION because/O of/O concerns/O about/O its/O nuclear/O programme/O would/O be/O unacceptable/O and/O would/O lead/O to/O unpredictable/O circumstances/O in/O the/O region/O and/O the/O world/O ./O
