Last/O week/O 's/O violence/O caused/O dozens/O of/O casualties/O and/O arrests/O :/O the/O central/O government/O now/O claims/O to/O be/O ``/O ready/O for/O anything/O ''/O to/O stop/O ``/O terrorist/O groups/O in/O the/O area/O ./O ''/O
Beijing/LOCATION fears/O the/O approach/O of/O July/O 5/O ,/O the/O fourth/O anniversary/O of/O the/O 2009/O riots/O that/O claimed/O the/O lives/O of/O more/O than/O 200/O people/O ./O
Urumqi/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O
After/O the/O violence/O of/O the/O past/O week/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O central/O government/O has/O sent/O paramilitary/O troops/O to/O the/O western/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O the/O scene/O of/O clashes/O between/O the/O local/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O and/O Han/O ,/O the/O majority/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O who/O emigrated/O en/O masse/O to/O the/O region/O ./O
During/O the/O latest/O episode/O of/O unrest/O ,/O the/O worst/O in/O four/O years/O ,/O 35/O people/O have/O died/O :/O it/O is/O not/O yet/O clear/O who/O started/O the/O violence/O and/O for/O what/O reasons/O ./O
On/O 26/O June/O ,/O a/O crowd/O attacked/O a/O government/O building/O and/O a/O police/O station/O in/O Lukquan/U_LOCATION ,/O the/O police/O opened/O fire/O killing/O dozens/O of/O protesters/O ./O
Two/O days/O later/O ,/O an/O armed/O group/O tried/O to/O replicate/O the/O clashes/O in/O Hotan/U_LOCATION ,/O but/O was/O stopped/O -/O apparently/O without/O victims/O -/O by/O anti-terrorism/O agents/O ./O
At/O least/O 19/O people/O were/O detained/O for/O ``/O spreading/O alarming/O news/O ''/O with/O their/O mobile/O phones/O ./O
The/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Public/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION has/O confirmed/O on/O its/O website/O the/O deployment/O of/O the/O military/O :/O Beijing/LOCATION fears/O the/O approach/O of/O July/O 5/O ,/O the/O fourth/O anniversary/O of/O the/O violent/O upheavals/O of/O 2009/O that/O claimed/O the/O lives/O of/O more/O than/O 200/O people/O ./O
Yu/PERSON Zhengsheng/PERSON ,/O member/O of/O the/O Standing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Politburo/ORGANIZATION in/O charge/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION and/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O said/O :/O ``/O We/O will/O take/O any/O decision/O needed/O to/O stop/O terrorist/O groups/O and/O extremist/O organizations/O in/O the/O area/O ./O ''/O
The/O province/O has/O long/O been/O the/O epicenter/O of/O violence/O and/O tensions/O between/O the/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O -/O once/O the/O majority/O in/O the/O area/O -/O and/O Han/O ./O
The/O central/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O encouraged/O the/O emigration/O of/O Han/O to/O the/O province/O in/O an/O attempt/O to/O ``/O even/O out/O ''/O the/O social/O reality/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O but/O the/O ongoing/O fighting/O is/O proof/O that/O the/O experiment/O has/O failed/O ./O
The/O Uyghur/O are/O Turkic-speaking/O Muslims/O and/O :/O for/O several/O decades/O have/O an/O adversarial/O relationship/O with/O the/O Chinese/O central/O government/O ./O
After/O a/O few/O -LRB-/O unsuccessful/O -RRB-/O attempts/O to/O gain/O independence/O as/O ``/O East/U_LOCATION Turkestan/U_LOCATION ''/O ,/O the/O ethnic/O leaders/O have/O asked/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O the/O possibility/O to/O safeguard/O their/O language/O ,/O culture/O and/O local/O religion/O ./O
The/O Chinese/O government/O -/O while/O granting/O tax/O and/O social/O welfare/O breaks/O -/O decided/O instead/O to/O use/O a/O heavy/O hand/O and/O launched/O a/O campaign/O of/O repression/O and/O control/O in/O the/O whole/O area/O ./O
The/O heavy/O hand/O of/O the/O regime/O is/O felt/O even/O on/O the/O Islamic/O religious/O community/O ,/O suspected/O of/O forming/O young/O people/O to/O a/O terrorist/O and/O fundamentalist/O version/O of/O Islam/ORGANIZATION ./O
There/O is/O control/O and/O censorship/O of/O Islamic/O publications/O control/O over/O the/O sermons/O of/O imams/O ,/O young/O people/O under/O 18/O are/O banned/O from/O attending/O the/O mosque/O ./O
