A/O court/O in/O western/O China/LOCATION sentences/O three/O people/O to/O death/O over/O a/O deadly/O car/O crash/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION last/O October/O ./O
Four/O others/O received/O sentences/O ranging/O from/O five/O to/O 20/O years/O in/O jail/O ./O
Urumqi/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O
Three/O people/O were/O sentenced/O to/O death/O for/O their/O roles/O in/O carrying/O outa/O deadly/O attack/O on/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION last/O October/O ./O
The/O Xinjiang/U_ORGANIZATION Intermediate/U_ORGANIZATION People/U_ORGANIZATION 's/U_ORGANIZATION Court/U_ORGANIZATION also/O handed/O a/O life/O sentence/O to/O one/O suspect/O ,/O among/O eight/O put/O on/O trial/O for/O allegedly/O planning/O the/O attack/O ./O
Four/O of/O those/O received/O sentences/O ranging/O from/O five/O to/O 20/O years/O in/O jail/O ,/O state/O television/O said/O on/O its/O official/O microblog/O ./O
The/O trial/O started/O on/O June/O 13/O ,/O and/O the/O sentence/O came/O out/O today/O ,/O said/O CCTV/ORGANIZATION ./O
It/O identified/O two/O of/O the/O accused/O with/O names/O that/O sounded/O Uygur/O ,/O the/O largest/O ethnic/O group/O in/O the/O violence-racked/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
Two/O people/O were/O killed/O and/O 40/O injured/O when/O a/O car/O ploughed/O into/O a/O crowd/O at/O the/O northern/O edge/O of/O Tiananmen/LOCATION ,/O while/O the/O three/O people/O in/O the/O car/O also/O died/O ./O
The/O government/O had/O blamed/O Islamic/O militants/O for/O the/O attack/O on/O October/O 28/O ./O
Among/O those/O killed/O were/O a/O Chinese/O visitor/O and/O a/O tourist/O from/O the/O Philippines/LOCATION were/O killed/O ,/O along/O with/O the/O vehicle/O 's/O driver/O ,/O his/O wife/O and/O mother-in-law/O ,/O according/O to/O Chinese/O authorities/O ./O
The/O attack/O was/O the/O first/O to/O strike/O Beijing/LOCATION in/O recent/O memory/O ./O
It/O pointed/O to/O a/O new/O level/O of/O violence/O and/O lethal/O intent/O in/O the/O long/O simmering/O insurgency/O against/O Chinese/O rule/O in/O the/O far/O northwestern/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
It/O is/O home/O to/O the/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O ,/O Turkic/O speaking/O peoples/O of/O Islamic/O religion/O ,/O who/O have/O always/O sought/O to/O gain/O independence/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
The/O central/O government/O ,/O for/O its/O part/O ,/O planted/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O the/O region/O to/O try/O to/O make/O them/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O
It/O also/O imposes/O serious/O restrictions/O on/O freedom/O of/O religion/O ,/O the/O practice/O of/O Islam/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O language/O and/O the/O local/O culture/O ./O
