The/O intellectual/O ,/O an/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O ,/O has/O long/O called/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O open/O a/O channel/O of/O dialogue/O for/O peace/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
The/ORGANIZATION Intermediate/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION of/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION convicted/O him/O for/O ``/O separatism/O ./O ''/O
One/O of/O his/O lawyers/O announces/O that/O he/O would/O appeal/O ./O
The/O sentence/O causes/O outrage/O among/O activists/O for/O human/O rights/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
Urumqi/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O
The/ORGANIZATION Intermediate/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION of/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION found/O Uyghur/O intellectual/O Ilham/U_PERSON Tohti/U_PERSON guilty/O of/O ``/O separatism/O ''/O and/O sentenced/O him/O to/O life/O in/O prison/O ./O
An/O economics/O professor/O at/O Beijing-based/O Minzu/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O Tohti/U_PERSON has/O strongly/O denied/O charges/O of/O separatism/O saying/O in/O a/O closing/O statement/O that/O ``/O he/O loved/O his/O country/O .../O and/O that/O it/O was/O always/O his/O opinion/O that/O it/O was/O in/O the/O best/O interests/O of/O Uighurs/O to/O remain/O in/O China/LOCATION ''/O ./O
Liu/PERSON Xiaoyuan/PERSON ,/O one/O of/O his/O defence/O lawyers/O ,/O announced/O that/O his/O client/O would/O appeal/O against/O the/O ruling/O ./O
Tohti/U_PERSON was/O arrested/O last/O January/O after/O he/O criticised/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policy/O following/O an/O attack/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION in/O October/O 2013/O ,/O blamed/O on/O some/O Uyghurs/O ./O
The/O government/O 's/O response/O to/O the/O attack/O was/O to/O boost/O repression/O in/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O ./O
For/O years/O ,/O Tohti/U_PERSON has/O called/O on/O the/O government/O to/O engage/O in/O a/O real/O dialogue/O with/O the/O Uyghurs/O and/O understand/O their/O difficulties/O ./O
For/O this/O reason/O ,/O in/O 2005/O he/O launched/O Uyghur/O Online/O ,/O a/O website/O to/O improve/O understanding/O between/O Uyghurs/O and/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O
However/O ,/O according/O to/O his/O accusers/O ,/O the/O website/O itself/O was/O evidence/O of/O the/O academic/O 's/O ``/O separatism/O ''/O ./O
Among/O activists/O for/O human/O rights/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O his/O trial/O has/O sparked/O outrage/O ./O
``/O Tohti/U_PERSON has/O consistently/O ,/O courageously/O and/O unambiguously/O advocated/O peacefully/O for/O greater/O understanding/O and/O dialogue/O between/O various/O communities/O ,/O and/O with/O the/O state/O ,/O ''/O said/O Sophie/PERSON Richardson/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION director/O at/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O If/O this/O is/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O definition/O of/O `/O separatist/O '/O activities/O ,/O it/O 's/O hard/O to/O see/O tensions/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION and/O between/O the/O communities/O decreasing/O ./O ''/O
Tohti/U_PERSON 's/O views/O are/O summarised/O in/O an/O article/O by/O his/O friend/O Tibetan/O writer/O Tsering/PERSON Woeser/PERSON ,/O published/O in/O February/O shortly/O after/O his/O arrest/O ./O
``/O Ilham/U_PERSON was/O only/O exercising/O his/O right/O to/O free/O expression/O ,/O for/O which/O he/O should/O not/O be/O imprisoned/O ,/O ''/O said/O Renee/PERSON Xia/PERSON ,/O international/O director/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Defender/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O The/O government/O is/O trying/O to/O lay/O blame/O on/O him/O for/O recent/O violent/O incidents/O and/O divert/O attention/O from/O its/O own/O policy/O failures/O that/O have/O contributed/O to/O rising/O ethnic/O tensions/O ./O ''/O
