The/O bombs/O were/O launched/O from/O two/O cars/O ,/O exploding/O among/O stalls/O and/O outdoor/O restaurants/O ./O
The/O Islamic/O separatists/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION responsible/O for/O several/O attacks/O in/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ,/O Guangzou/LOCATION ,/O Kunming/LOCATION ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O
At/O least/O 31/O people/O have/O been/O killed/O in/O bomb/O explosions/O in/O an/O outdoor/O market/O in/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ,/O capital/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION province/O ./O
About/O 90/O people/O were/O injured/O ./O
According/O to/O witnesses/O ,/O two/O cars/O arrived/O in/O the/O middle/O of/O the/O market/O towards/O 7.50/O this/O morning/O ,/O launching/O five/O bombs/O among/O the/O people/O that/O stood/O near/O the/O stalls/O and/O groups/O of/O elderly/O people/O having/O breakfast/O in/O street/O restaurants/O ./O
A/O series/O of/O photos/O posted/O on/O Weibo/ORGANIZATION show/O bodies/O and/O people/O bleeding/O ,/O boxes/O of/O fruit/O ,/O tables/O and/O clothes/O on/O strewn/O on/O the/O ground/O ./O
The/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Public/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION has/O called/O the/O incident/O ``/O a/O serious/O and/O violent/O terrorist/O attack/O ''/O ./O
For/O years/O ,/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O a/O region/O inhabited/O by/O the/O Uyghur/O people/O of/O Muslim/O faith/O and/O Turkish/O origin/O ,/O has/O been/O rocked/O by/O riots/O and/O tensions/O ./O
The/O Uyghurs/O accuse/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O wanting/O to/O colonize/O them/O and/O demand/O greater/O autonomy/O ./O
The/O government/O -/O which/O has/O transferred/O millions/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O settlers/O to/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION -/O and/O the/O Army/ORGANIZATION blame/O Uyghur/O of/O separatism/O and/O Islamic/O terrorism/O ./O
To/O quell/O the/O violence/O ,/O the/O government/O makes/O liberal/O use/O of/O the/O death/O penalty/O and/O suppresses/O the/O religious/O freedom/O of/O Muslim/O communities/O ./O
This/O is/O the/O latest/O in/O a/O series/O of/O attacks/O in/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ./O
At/O the/O end/O of/O April/O there/O was/O an/O attack/O on/O the/O main/O railway/O station/O ,/O in/O which/O some/O terrorists/O threw/O grenades/O and/O wielded/O knives/O ,/O injuring/O 79/O people/O ./O
Three/O people/O died/O ,/O including/O two/O of/O the/O attackers/O ./O
The/O violence/O took/O place/O just/O a/O few/O hours/O after/O the/O end/O of/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON 's/O visit/O to/O the/O region/O ./O
In/O recent/O months/O there/O have/O been/O attacks/O with/O bombs/O and/O knives/O in/O Guangzhou/LOCATION and/O Kunming/LOCATION ,/O which/O the/O government/O blames/O on/O Islamic/O separatists/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
