The/O lawyer/O and/O human/O rights/O activist/O was/O found/O guilty/O of/O ``/O inciting/O ethnic/O hatred/O ''/O and/O ``/O disrupting/O the/O public/O peace/O ''/O for/O online/O comments/O criticizing/O excessive/O force/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O the/O honesty/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O nationalist/O rhetoric/O over/O the/O islands/O disputed/O with/O Japan/LOCATION ./O
He/O has/O already/O spent/O 19/O months/O in/O jail/O ,/O in/O ``/O preventive/O detention/O ''/O ./O
A/O leader/O of/O the/O Tiananmen/LOCATION movement/O ,/O has/O spent/O the/O last/O 25/O years/O in/O court/O defending/O activists/O and/O dissidents/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O
The/O No./O 2/O Beijing/ORGANIZATION Intermediate/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION has/O sentenced/O the/O dissident/O lawyer/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON to/O three/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O
The/O sentence/O was/O suspended/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O unclear/O whether/O the/O lawyer/O has/O already/O been/O released/O ./O
He/O has/O already/O spent/O 19/O months/O in/O jail/O in/O ``/O preventive/O detention/O ''/O ./O
The/O judges/O found/O him/O guilty/O of/O ``/O inciting/O ethnic/O hatred/O ''/O and/O ``/O disrupting/O the/O public/O peace/O ''/O because/O of/O his/O comments/O posted/O online/O criticizing/O the/O use/O of/O excessive/O force/O by/O the/O authorities/O in/O the/O western/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
This/O morning/O ,/O before/O the/O reading/O of/O the/O verdict/O ,/O a/O group/O of/O journalists/O and/O supporters/O gathered/O outside/O the/O court/O ./O
According/O to/O some/O sources/O ,/O there/O was/O also/O a/O clash/O with/O the/O police/O ,/O and/O 12/O activists/O were/O taken/O away/O by/O officers/O ./O
Pu/PERSON is/O the/O latest/O dissident/O personality/O -LRB-/O in/O time/O -RRB-/O to/O be/O convicted/O and/O imprisoned/O for/O his/O commitment/O to/O human/O rights/O ./O
According/O to/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Defender/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CHRD/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O the/O verdict/O of/O the/O judges/O ``/O demonstrates/O the/O concept/O of/O `/O rule/O of/O law/O '/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O
Pu/PERSON 's/O friends/O and/O comrades/O believe/O that/O the/O online/O posts/O are/O only/O ``/O one/O of/O the/O causes/O ''/O that/O led/O to/O the/O persecution/O of/O the/O lawyer/O ./O
In/O his/O writings/O ,/O he/O described/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ``/O an/O entity/O which/O can/O not/O be/O trusted/O ''/O and/O made/O fun/O of/O the/O excessive/O nationalist/O rhetoric/O of/O the/O authorities/O regarding/O the/O Senkaku/LOCATION //ORGANIZATION/O Diaoyu/LOCATION ,/O disputes/O with/O Japan/LOCATION ./O
But/O the/O real/O goal/O is/O his/O career/O ,/O which/O began/O immediately/O after/O the/O riots/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION :/O Pu/PERSON has/O indeed/O defended/O several/O dissidents/O and/O human/O rights/O activists/O in/O court/O ./O
Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON ,/O writes/O the/O CHRD/ORGANIZATION commenting/O on/O the/O judgment/O ,/O ``/O should/O be/O able/O to/O go/O home/O today/O ,/O but/O he/O is/O not/O free/O ./O
He/O pays/O for/O exercising/O his/O right/O to/O speak/O ./O
During/O pre-trial/O detention/O his/O health/O deteriorated/O ,/O and/O obviously/O his/O career/O as/O a/O lawyer/O is/O now/O over/O ''/O ./O
In/O 1989/O he/O took/O part/O in/O the/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION movement/O ,/O and/O was/O one/O of/O 13/O students/O to/O start/O a/O hunger/O strike/O to/O protest/O the/O corruption/O of/O the/O government/O ./O
Over/O the/O past/O 25/O years/O he/O has/O always/O remembered/O the/O June/O 4/O massacre/O ,/O and/O every/O anniversary/O goes/O to/O the/O central/O square/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O commemorate/O the/O dead/O ./O
In/O 2008/O he/O was/O among/O the/O first/O to/O sign/O Charter/O 08/O ,/O the/O document/O drawn/O up/O by/O pro-democracy/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON ,/O which/O led/O to/O Li/PERSON 's/O being/O awarded/O the/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O and/O sentence/O of/O 14/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O
