Urumqi/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O --/O
On/O January/O 15/O ,/O rights/O activist/O Zhang/PERSON Haitao/PERSON -LRB-/O 张海涛/PERSON -RRB-/O was/O sentenced/O to/O 19/O years/O in/O prison/O by/O the/O Urumqi/U_ORGANIZATION Intermediate/U_ORGANIZATION Court/U_ORGANIZATION in/O the/O northwest/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION Autonomous/U_LOCATION Region/U_LOCATION ./O
The/O 44-year-old/O Zhang/PERSON was/O convicted/O of/O ``/O inciting/O subversion/O of/O state/O power/O ''/O and/O ``/O probing/O and/O illegally/O supplying/O intelligence/O abroad/O ''/O ./O
The/O court/O also/O ordered/O the/O confiscation/O of/O his/O personal/O assets/O of/O 120,000/O yuan/O -LRB-/O ,000/O -RRB-/O ./O
The/O accusations/O leveled/O against/O Zhang/PERSON include/O publishing/O online/O articles/O attacking/O socialism/O ,/O assisting/O the/O work/O of/O foreign/O media/O ,/O and/O ``/O rumormongering/O ./O ''/O
The/O harsh/O sentence/O handed/O down/O to/O Zhang/PERSON ,/O a/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O came/O as/O a/O surprise/O to/O both/O Zhang/PERSON 's/O lawyer/O and/O family/O ./O
Lawyer/O Li/PERSON Dunyong/PERSON -LRB-/O 李敦勇/PERSON -RRB-/O ,/O who/O represents/O Zhang/PERSON ,/O told/O China/ORGANIZATION Change/ORGANIZATION that/O he/O believed/O the/O heavy/O sentence/O has/O a/O lot/O to/O do/O with/O the/O fact/O that/O Zhang/PERSON lives/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION and/O has/O criticized/O the/O Chinese/O government/O 's/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION policies/O ./O
Dissent/O in/O this/O restive/O region/O with/O a/O large/O ethnic/O Uighur/O population/O often/O meets/O with/O particularly/O harsh/O retribution/O ./O
``/O Being/O a/O Han/O Chinese/O gives/O you/O no/O protection/O ,/O ''/O said/O lawyer/O Li/PERSON ./O
In/O 2014/O ,/O Xinjiang-based/O democracy/O activist/O Zhao/PERSON Haitong/PERSON -LRB-/O 赵海通/PERSON -RRB-/O ,/O also/O a/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O was/O sentenced/O to/O 14/O years/O for/O ``/O inciting/O subversion/O of/O state/O power/O ./O ''/O
``/O The/O 19-year/O sentence/O is/O utterly/O ludicrous/O ./O
I/O know/O my/O husband/O is/O a/O very/O honest/O man/O ./O
The/O only/O thing/O he/O did/O was/O say/O some/O honest/O things/O online/O ,/O ''/O Zhang/PERSON 's/O wife/O ,/O Li/PERSON Aijie/PERSON -LRB-/O 李爱杰/PERSON -RRB-/O ,/O told/O China/ORGANIZATION Change/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O Accusing/O him/O of/O supplying/O intelligence/O abroad/O is/O beyond/O laughable/O ./O
He/O did/O give/O information/O about/O human/O rights/O issues/O to/O overseas/O media/O outlets/O like/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Free/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION and/O Sound/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Hope/ORGANIZATION ,/O but/O there/O was/O nothing/O secretive/O about/O the/O information/O ./O
It/O was/O all/O public/O ./O ''/O
Zhang/PERSON was/O first/O criminally/O detained/O by/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION police/O last/O June/O for/O ``/O inciting/O ethnic/O hatred/O ''/O and/O ``/O ethnic/O discrimination/O ,/O ''/O and/O later/O formally/O arrested/O on/O charges/O of/O ``/O picking/O quarrels/O and/O provoking/O trouble/O ./O ''/O
After/O nearly/O five/O months/O in/O detention/O ,/O the/O charges/O were/O changed/O to/O ``/O inciting/O subversion/O of/O state/O power/O ./O ''/O
Originally/O from/O Henan/LOCATION Province/LOCATION ,/O Zhang/PERSON first/O came/O to/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION to/O partake/O in/O the/O electronics/O retail/O business/O after/O being/O laid/O off/O from/O a/O state-owned/O company/O in/O the/O 1990s/O ./O
One/O day/O in/O April/O 2009/O ,/O while/O on/O vacation/O at/O his/O home/O in/O Nanyang/LOCATION -LRB-/O 南阳/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O Henan/LOCATION ,/O a/O group/O of/O policemen/O from/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION broke/O into/O Zhang/PERSON 's/O house/O and/O took/O him/O to/O a/O train/O station/O ,/O putting/O him/O on/O a/O train/O to/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ./O
During/O the/O train/O ride/O ,/O the/O police/O handcuffed/O and/O shackled/O him/O ,/O and/O stopped/O him/O from/O using/O the/O restroom/O ./O
After/O 30/O days/O of/O interrogation/O in/O a/O detention/O center/O for/O alleged/O fraud/O in/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ,/O Zhang/PERSON was/O freed/O ./O
Upon/O release/O ,/O to/O seek/O justice/O for/O the/O unlawful/O and/O unexplained/O detention/O ,/O Zhang/PERSON took/O legal/O action/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O petitioned/O to/O different/O government/O offices/O ,/O but/O to/O no/O avail/O ./O
Through/O his/O numerous/O failed/O attempts/O to/O gain/O redress/O for/O the/O case/O ,/O Zhang/PERSON gradually/O learned/O the/O serious/O ills/O of/O the/O Chinese/O political/O system/O and/O began/O to/O publish/O articles/O online/O critical/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O
Meanwhile/O ,/O he/O also/O started/O to/O help/O other/O petitioners/O have/O their/O own/O stories/O of/O suffering/O heard/O online/O ./O
Zhang/PERSON became/O a/O volunteer/O for/O the/O human/O rights/O website/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Campaign/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O ``/O 权利运动/ORGANIZATION ''/O -RRB-/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O in/O 2010/O signed/O a/O petition/O urging/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O abolish/O the/O extra-legal/O Reeducation/O Through/O Labor/O detention/O system/O ./O
In/O the/O past/O five/O years/O ,/O Zhang/PERSON had/O been/O under/O constant/O police/O surveillance/O ./O
When/O the/O anniversary/O of/O the/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION Massacre/O or/O the/O Two/O Meetings/O approaches/O ,/O the/O police/O often/O briefly/O detain/O him/O to/O prevent/O him/O from/O commemorating/O those/O who/O died/O in/O the/O Massacre/O or/O creating/O any/O ``/O instabilities/O ./O ''/O
Li/PERSON Aijie/PERSON ,/O his/O wife/O ,/O told/O China/ORGANIZATION Change/ORGANIZATION that/O she/O suspected/O that/O the/O government/O is/O going/O to/O confiscate/O the/O apartment/O she/O and/O her/O husband/O own/O ./O
``/O We/O have/O no/O money/O ./O
The/O only/O way/O they/O can/O collect/O the/O 120,000/O yuan/O is/O to/O take/O our/O apartment/O away/O ./O
The/O community/O management/O people/O have/O come/O several/O times/O asking/O to/O see/O the/O ownership/O certificate/O of/O our/O apartment/O ,/O ''/O Li/PERSON said/O ./O
``/O The/O government/O is/O determined/O to/O force/O us/O out/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O but/O where/O can/O my/O son/O and/O I/O go/O ?/O ''/O
Zhang/PERSON and/O Li/PERSON have/O a/O one-month-old/O infant/O ./O
When/O asked/O whether/O she/O is/O worried/O that/O giving/O interviews/O to/O foreign/O entities/O would/O invoke/O further/O government/O wrath/O ,/O Li/PERSON Aijie/PERSON replied/O :/O ``/O There/O is/O nothing/O to/O be/O afraid/O of/O anymore/O ./O
Look/O at/O the/O situation/O we/O 're/O already/O in/O ./O
How/O worse/O can/O it/O get/O ?/O ''/O
