The/O charge/O was/O made/O today/O by/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION ./O 
During/O the/O protests/O that/O broke/O out/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O ``/O the/O police/O used/O torture/O and/O intimidation/O ./O ''/O 
The/O dissident/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> adds/O :/O ``/O Of/O the/O twelve/O condemned/O to/O death/O ,/O nine/O have/O already/O been/O killed/O ./O ''/O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
Of/O the/O twelve/O Uyghurs/O condemned/O to/O death/O in/O recent/O days/O ``/O nine/O have/O already/O been/O killed/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O information/O in/O our/O possession/O more/O than/O ten/O thousand/O people/O of/O Uyghur/O nationality/O were/O arrested/O and/O locked/O up/O in/O jail/O between/O July/O 5/O and/O the/O first/O of/O October/O ./O 
Many/O are/O gone/O ,/O and/O we/O think/O that/O they/O have/O been/O killed/O ''/O ./O 
The/O is/O the/O charge/O made/O this/O morning/O by/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O the/O leader/O of/O the/O ethic/O group/O from/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O during/O a/O visit/O to/O Japan/LOCATION ./O 
According/O to/O the/O dissident/O ,/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Uyghurs/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -/O the/O organization/O she/O heads/O -/O ``/O wants/O to/O talk/O to/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION must/O agree/O to/O our/O autonomy/O ,/O because/O their/O mode/O of/O action/O is/O destroying/O our/O nation/O ,/O our/O education/O ,/O our/O religion/O and/O our/O freedom/O of/O expression/O ''/O ./O 
This/O refers/O to/O the/O massive/O immigration/O of/O Chinese/O Han/O -LRB-/O the/O majority/O in/O China/LOCATION -RRB-/O to/O the/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
According/O to/O the/O locals/O --/O Muslims/O of/O Turkish/O extraction/O -/O the/O arrival/O of/O these/O ``/O guests/O ''/O aims/O to/O destroy/O the/O local/O identity/O ./O 
Protected/O by/O the/O central/O government/O ,/O the/O Han/O are/O in/O fact/O in/O a/O dominant/O position/O in/O almost/O all/O fields/O :/O economic/O ,/O academic/O and/O managerial/O ./O 
Uyghurs/O -/O who/O identify/O their/O country/O with/O <U_LOCATION>East/O Turkistan/O</U_LOCATION> -/O have/O repeatedly/O called/O for/O a/O kind/O of/O autonomy/O -LRB-/O at/O least/O cultural/O -RRB-/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
It/O was/O precisely/O this/O request/O that/O formed/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O bloody/O protests/O that/O began/O on/O 5/O July/O ,/O which/O according/O to/O official/O sources/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O claimed/O the/O lives/O of/O 192/O people/O ,/O mostly/O Han/O ./O 
But/O according/O to/O a/O report/O released/O today/O by/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>HRW/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ,/O and/O confirmed/O by/O the/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O statements/O ,/O ``/O thousands/O of/O protesters/O disappeared/O without/O trace/O soon/O after/O the/O protests/O ''/O ./O 
The/O non-governmental/O organization/O based/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O says/O it/O has/O ``/O first/O hand/O evidence/O of/O that/O concern/O more/O than/O 40/O individual/O cases/O of/O killings/O disguised/O as/O disappearances/O ./O 
But/O these/O are/O only/O the/O tip/O of/O the/O iceberg/O ''/O ./O 
The/O data/O is/O conflicting/O ,/O but/O credible/O sources/O speak/O of/O at/O least/O a/O thousand/O cases/O of/O killings/O ./O 
The/O <ORGANIZATION>HRW/O</ORGANIZATION> report/O also/O speaks/O of/O ``/O how/O the/O Chinese/O police/O tried/O to/O stop/O the/O protests/O last/O July/O ./O
The/O roads/O were/O armoured/O by/O officers/O in/O riot/O gear/O ,/O who/O took/O part/O in/O the/O violence/O ,/O even/O detaining/O suspects/O for/O interrogation/O using/O torture/O ./O 
In/O some/O cases/O ,/O the/O police/O set/O fire/O to/O homes/O and/O offices/O ,/O taking/O away/O people/O without/O charges/O or/O explanation/O ./O ''/O
