For/O a/O court/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O <U_PERSON>Hailaite/PERSON Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> endangered/O state/O security/O when/O in/O an/O interview/O he/O blamed/O police/O for/O interethnic/O clashes/O in/O July/O 2009/O ./O 
His/O one-day/O trial/O occurred/O without/O the/O presence/O of/O a/O defence/O lawyer/O ./O 
``/O This/O is/O an/O extremely/O harsh/O and/O unjust/O action/O on/O the/O part/O of/O the/O Chinese/O court/O ,/O and/O a/O clear/O violation/O of/O rights/O guaranteed/O by/O the/O Chinese/O constitution/O ,/O ''/O said/O the/O international/O director/O of/O a/O human/O rights/O group/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O 
Yesterday/O ,/O a/O court/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O sentenced/O <U_PERSON>Hailaite/PERSON Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O an/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O journalist/O ,/O to/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O endangering/O state/O security/O ,/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Defenders/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>CHRD/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ,/O a/O Hong/O Kong-based/O human/O rights/O association/O ,/O reported/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> has/O been/O held/O since/O 1/O October/O 2009/O after/O he/O gave/O an/O interview/O to/O a/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION weekly/O in/O which/O he/O blamed/O Chinese/O police/O and/O military/O for/O clashes/O between/O ethnic/O Uyghurs/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O July/O 2009/O ./O 
His/O trial/O lasted/O a/O day/O ,/O reportedly/O without/O a/O defence/O lawyer/O present/O ./O 
``/O The/O idea/O that/O <U_PERSON>Niyazi/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O interview/O somehow/O `/O endangered/O '/O state/O security/O and/O warranted/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O is/O incomprehensible/O ,/O ''/O said/O Renee/PERSON Xia/PERSON ,/O CHRD/ORGANIZATION 's/O International/O Director/O ./O 
``/O This/O is/O an/O extremely/O harsh/O and/O unjust/O action/O on/O the/O part/O of/O the/O Chinese/O court/O ,/O and/O a/O clear/O violation/O of/O rights/O guaranteed/O by/O the/O Chinese/O constitution/O ./O ''/O 
The/O predominantly/O Muslim/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O one/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O most/O troublesome/O areas/O ./O 
<OTHER>Indigenous/PERSON Muslim/PERSON Uyghurs/PERSON</OTHER> complain/O that/O the/O central/O government/O is/O engaged/O in/O a/O virtual/O policy/O of/O colonisation/O at/O their/O expense/O ,/O openly/O discriminating/O against/O them/O in/O favour/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O who/O benefit/O from/O government/O economic/O and/O social/O policies/O ./O 
The/O situation/O boiled/O over/O in/O July/O 2009/O when/O violent/O clashes/O broke/O out/O between/O the/O two/O groups/O in/O the/O regional/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O with/O more/O than/O 200/O dead/O and/O 1,700/O injured/O ./O 
Even/O now/O ,/O the/O total/O number/O of/O people/O arrested/O or/O detained/O remains/O unknown/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Uyghur/O resistance/O ,/O the/O number/O runs/O in/O the/O tens/O of/O thousands/O ./O 
When/O the/O first/O anniversary/O came/O on/O 5/O July/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O placed/O the/O capital/O under/O a/O tight/O security/O blanket/O ./O 
This/O included/O putting/O in/O place/O more/O than/O 40,000/O cameras/O in/O public/O buses/O ,/O stations/O ,/O 4,000/O roads/O ,/O 270/O schools/O and/O 100/O supermarkets/O ./O
