According/O to/O authorities/O ,/O a/O ``/O terrorist/O group/O ''/O set/O fire/O to/O police/O station/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Hotan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O was/O arrested/O ./O 
Different/O version/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O they/O ``/O protesting/O against/O the/O forced/O requisitioning/O of/O land/O and/O indiscriminate/O arrests/O and/O were/O massacred/O ./O ''/O 
<U_LOCATION>Hotan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/</ORGANIZATION>O -RRB-/O -/O 
Chinese/O police/O opened/O fire/O on/O a/O group/O of/O Uyghur/O demonstrators/O in/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> who/O were/O protesting/O against/O the/O forced/O confiscation/O of/O their/O lands/O and/O indiscriminate/O arrests/O against/O members/O of/O the/O ethnic/O minority/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O most/O feared/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
According/O to/O official/O sources/O ,/O the/O protesters/O set/O fire/O to/O a/O police/O station/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Hotan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> :/O 2/O demonstrators/O ,/O 2/O ``/O hostages/O ''/O and/O a/O policeman/O died/O in/O the/O clashes/O ,/O and/O now/O the/O situation/O is/O ``/O under/O control/O ''/O ./O 
For/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O a/O nongovernmental/O organization/O based/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O the/O dead/O were/O at/O least/O 20/O ./O 
Hou/PERSON Hanmin/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O regional/O information/O ,/O spoke/O of/O an/O ``/O organized/O terrorist/O action/O ./O 
The/O rioters/O had/O explosive/O devices/O and/O grenades/O ./O 
First/O they/O raided/O the/O headquarters/O of/O the/O local/O office/O for/O industry/O ,/O commerce/O and/O taxation/O ,/O which/O is/O located/O next/O to/O the/O police/O station/O ,/O and/O wounded/O two/O people/O ./O 
When/O they/O realized/O that/O they/O were/O not/O the/O right/O targets/O ,/O they/O attacked/O the/O police/O post/O from/O the/O ground/O floor/O to/O the/O second/O floor/O where/O they/O hung/O a/O banner/O with/O separatist/O messages/O ./O ''/O 
According/O to/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O however/O ,/O the/O police/O opened/O fire/O on/O people/O attending/O a/O peaceful/O protest/O ,/O triggering/O clashes/O ./O 
In/O addition/O to/O the/O victims/O ,/O the/O group/O has/O reported/O about/O 70/O arrests/O ./O 
``/O To/O prevent/O further/O destabilization/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O should/O immediately/O end/O the/O systematic/O repression/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O people/O ./O ''/O 
<U_LOCATION>Hotan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O a/O city/O of/O about/O 300/O thousand/O inhabitants/O ,/O 88/O %/O belonging/O to/O ethnic/O minorities/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> has/O long/O been/O the/O scene/O of/O tension/O and/O violence/O that/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION government/O attributes/O to/O ``/O separatist/O groups/O linked/O to/O Al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION ''/O that/O aim/O to/O create/O an/O independent/O state/O of/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
The/O Uyghurs/O ,/O the/O region/O 's/O indigenous/O Turkish-speaking/O Muslim/O people/O constitute/O less/O than/O half/O the/O population/O ,/O after/O decades/O of/O immigration/O from/O other/O areas/O of/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O last/O few/O years/O protests/O against/O restrictions/O imposed/O by/O the/O central/O authorities/O on/O the/O minority/O have/O become/O increasingly/O frequent/O ./O 
In/O July/O 2009/O ,/O the/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O was/O rocked/O by/O a/O wave/O of/O violence/O that/O caused/O nearly/O 200/O deaths/O ./O 
Since/O then/O ,/O nine/O people/O were/O put/O to/O death/O for/O instigating/O the/O riots/O ,/O hundreds/O were/O arrested/O and/O prosecuted/O ./O
