After/O 20/O months/O of/O total/O silence/O ,/O the/O regime/O sends/O a/O letter/O to/O the/O lawyer/O 's/O brother/O to/O communicate/O his/O detention/O in/O a/O prison/O in/O the/O remote/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
For/O 2012/O ,/O activists/O fear/O a/O worsening/O human/O rights/O situation/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O 
The/O Communist/O regime/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O confirmed/O for/O the/O first/O time/O in/O 20/O months/O that/O the/O lawyer/O Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON is/O in/O a/O prison/O in/O the/O western/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Gao/PERSON is/O a/O Christian/O who/O has/O long/O defended/O freedom/O for/O all/O social/O and/O religious/O minorities/O in/O China/LOCATION :/O arrested/O in/O February/O of/O 2009/O ,/O he/O had/O vanished/O into/O thin/O air/O ./O 
The/O confirmation/O of/O his/O detention/O was/O communicated/O to/O his/O brother/O Gao/PERSON Zhiyi/PERSON :/O ``/O I/O received/O a/O letter/O this/O morning/O informing/O me/O that/O my/O brother/O is/O in/O prison/O <U_LOCATION>Shaya/PERSON</U_LOCATION> ''/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O prison/O is/O unreachable/O by/O telephone/O ,/O and/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Office/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Shaya/ORGANIZATION County/ORGANIZATION Public/ORGANIZATION Safety/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> says/O he/O knows/O nothing/O about/O this/O case/O ./O 
Last/O month/O ,/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION regime/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O ,/O had/O confirmed/O a/O new/O arrest/O for/O Gao/PERSON guilty/O of/O ``/O violating/O the/O terms/O of/O his/O probation/O ./O ''/O 
But/O did/O not/O provide/O any/O other/O details/O ./O 
The/O choice/O of/O the/O prison/O was/O possibly/O made/O with/O a/O view/O to/O prevent/O visits/O to/O the/O detainee/O :/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O a/O very/O remote/O and/O difficult/O to/O reach/O province/O ./O 
Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O respected/O figures/O in/O the/O world/O of/O Chinese/O dissidents/O ./O 
After/O a/O brilliant/O legal/O career/O -/O he/O was/O named/O one/O of/O ``/O Ten/O Best/O Lawyers/O in/O China/LOCATION ''/O -/O he/O converted/O to/O Christianity/O and/O decided/O to/O work/O on/O his/O own/O to/O defend/O in/O court/O all/O those/O who/O were/O accused/O on/O trumped/O up/O charges/O because/O of/O their/O demands/O for/O democracy/O and/O justice/O ./O 
The/O confirmation/O of/O his/O arrest/O ,/O however/O ,/O is/O far/O from/O comforting/O for/O the/O present/O situation/O ./O 
According/O to/O many/O activists/O still/O living/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O as/O well/O as/O those/O living/O abroad/O ,/O 2012/O could/O be/O even/O worse/O than/O the/O previous/O year/O in/O terms/O of/O respect/O for/O human/O rights/O ./O 
According/O to/O Hu/PERSON Ping/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Beijing/LOCATION Spring/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> ,/O ``/O it/O gets/O worse/O from/O year/O to/O year/O ./O ''/O 
Gao/PERSON 's/O case/O ``/O along/O with/O Nobel/O Laureate/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON and/O the/O blind/O activist/O Chen/PERSON Guangcheng/PERSON have/O characterized/O 2011/O ./O 
But/O nothing/O suggests/O an/O improvement/O in/O the/O future/O ./O 
The/O regime/O continues/O to/O deny/O the/O rights/O of/O anyone/O looking/O for/O justice/O or/O democracy/O ./O ''/O
