A/O hundred/O people/O gathered/O spontaneously/O in/O the/O station/O where/O the/O massacre/O took/O place/O ./O 
The/O gang/O raided/O the/O station/O armed/O with/O curved/O swords/O and/O meat/O cleavers/O and/O stabbed/O people/O randomly/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION says/O the/O leaders/O are/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O ``/O separatists/O ''/O ,/O but/O there/O is/O no/O evidence/O to/O support/O this/O thesis/O ./O 
Kunming/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
Last/O night/O a/O hundred/O people/O held/O a/O candlelight/O vigil/O at/O the/O train/O station/O in/O Kunming/LOCATION -LRB-/O Yunnan/LOCATION Province/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O where/O March/O 1/O last/O a/O bloody/O attack/O targeted/O commuters/O and/O passengers/O ./O 
Men/O and/O women/O dressed/O in/O black/O and/O wearing/O masks/O assaulted/O bystanders/O with/O curved/O swords/O and/O meat/O cleavers/O ,/O instantly/O killing/O 29/O people/O and/O wounding/O more/O than/O 130/O ./O 
The/O critically/O injured/O includes/O a/O woman/O six/O months/O pregnant/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O ``/O separatists/O ''/O are/O responsible/O for/O the/O attack/O ./O 
However/O ,/O there/O is/O still/O no/O evidence/O against/O them/O ./O 
The/O massacre/O took/O place/O at/O 21:30/O on/O Saturday/O evening/O ./O 
The/O Kunming/LOCATION station/O ,/O in/O the/O capital/O of/O Yunnan/LOCATION ,/O is/O one/O of/O the/O largest/O and/O busiest/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O police/O have/O described/O the/O massacre/O as/O ``/O a/O well-organized/O terrorist/O attack/O ''/O :/O The/O attackers/O randomly/O stabbed/O those/O present/O ,/O in/O the/O chest/O ,/O neck/O and/O head/O ./O 
Four/O of/O them/O -/O three/O men/O and/O one/O woman/O -/O were/O killed/O on/O the/O spot/O by/O police/O ./O 
Another/O woman/O suspect/O is/O under/O arrest/O and/O is/O in/O hospital/O ./O 
More/O than/O 100/O people/O participated/O in/O a/O spontaneous/O vigil/O last/O night/O ./O 
A/O 53/O year/O old/O man/O said/O he/O was/O find/O ``/O very/O saddened/O ''/O by/O what/O happened/O ,/O but/O urged/O the/O government/O to/O provide/O answers/O to/O the/O problems/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
``/O No/O one/O ever/O told/O us/O why/O there/O is/O so/O much/O tension/O there/O -/O said/O the/O man/O -/O what/O did/O our/O government/O do/O to/O attract/O so/O much/O anger/O ?/O ''/O ./O 
The/O Uyghur/O ethnic/O group/O lives/O in/O the/O northern/O autonomous/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O is/O of/O the/O Turkish/O language/O and/O the/O Muslim/O faith/O ,/O and/O denounces/O a/O strong/O linguistic/O ,/O cultural/O and/O religious/O repression/O by/O the/O Chinese/O central/O government/O ./O 
Over/O the/O years/O there/O have/O been/O numerous/O violent/O clashes/O between/O the/O two/O sides/O :/O Beijing/LOCATION argues/O the/O region/O is/O home/O to/O Islamic/O extremists/O and/O separatists/O ,/O while/O local/O activists/O pointing/O the/O finger/O at/O ethnic/O tensions/O caused/O by/O the/O Chinese/O control/O and/O ``/O racist/O ''/O policies/O in/O implemented/O by/O the/O central/O government/O ./O 
Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON said/O that/O the/O government/O ``/O will/O do/O everything/O ''/O to/O clarify/O what/O happened/O and/O bring/O the/O perpetrators/O to/O justice/O ./O 
The/O governments/O of/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O France/LOCATION ,/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O Japan/LOCATION have/O unanimously/O condemned/O the/O attack/O and/O expressed/O their/O condolences/O to/O the/O victims/O ./O 
Ban/PERSON Ki/PERSON -/PERSON moon/PERSON ,/O Secretary/O General/O of/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O that/O ''/O there/O is/O no/O justification/O for/O the/O murder/O of/O innocent/O civilians/O ./O ''/O 
The/O attack/O took/O place/O a/O few/O days/O before/O two/O important/O appointments/O for/O Chinese/O politics/O :/O the/O opening/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Chinese/O People/O 's/O Political/O Consultative/O Conference/O</ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O CPPCC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O scheduled/O for/O today/O ,/O and/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O NPC/ORGANIZATION ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O parliament/O -RRB-/O ,/O on/O March/O 5/O ./O
