The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O formalized/O the/O charges/O against/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O an/O economics/O professor/O and/O well-known/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O activist/O for/O the/O rights/O of/O minorities/O living/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O who/O was/O arrested/O in/O January/O ./O 
Place/O of/O detention/O unknown/O ./O 
Human/O rights/O groups/O urge/O international/O community/O to/O intervene/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
More/O than/O a/O month/O after/O his/O arrest/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O formalized/O the/O charges/O against/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O an/O economics/O professor/O and/O well-known/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O activist/O for/O the/O rights/O of/O minorities/O living/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
His/O wife/O <U_PERSON>Guzaili/PERSON Nu'er/PERSON</U_PERSON> confirms/O that/O the/O academic/O has/O been/O accused/O of/O ``/O inciting/O separatism/O ''/O and/O points/O out/O that/O at/O the/O moment/O ``/O it/O is/O not/O possible/O to/O know/O ''/O where/O her/O husband/O is/O being/O held/O prisoner/O ./O 
Overseas/O Uyghur/O groups/O have/O condemned/O the/O decision/O and/O called/O on/O the/O international/O community/O to/O intervene/O for/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O release/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O 45/O ,/O was/O arrested/O on/O 15/O January/O ./O 
The/O academic/O is/O famous/O for/O his/O public/O speeches/O in/O favor/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O cause/O ./O 
This/O ethnic/O group/O lives/O in/O the/O northern/O autonomous/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O is/O of/O the/O Turkish/O language/O and/O the/O Muslim/O faith/O ,/O and/O denounces/O a/O strong/O linguistic/O ,/O cultural/O and/O religious/O repression/O by/O the/O Chinese/O central/O government/O ./O 
Over/O the/O years/O there/O have/O been/O numerous/O violent/O clashes/O between/O the/O two/O sides/O :/O Beijing/LOCATION argues/O the/O region/O is/O home/O to/O Islamic/O extremists/O and/O separatists/O ,/O while/O local/O activists/O pointing/O the/O finger/O at/O ethnic/O tensions/O caused/O by/O the/O Chinese/O control/O and/O ``/O racist/O ''/O policies/O in/O implemented/O by/O the/O central/O government/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Dilshat/PERSON Rexit/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O spokesman/O for/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> led/O by/O well-known/O activist/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O said/O :/O ``/O China/LOCATION 's/O accusations/O of/O separatism/O are/O merely/O an/O excuse/O for/O suppression/O of/O those/O with/O different/O political/O opinions/O ./O 
We/O call/O on/O the/O international/O community/O to/O monitor/O China/LOCATION and/O free/O this/O Uyghur/O scholar/O ''/O ./O 
Both/O the/O U.S./LOCATION and/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION condemned/O the/O Chinese/O government/O following/O his/O arrest/O ./O 
Several/O human/O rights/O activists/O argue/O that/O an/O article/O written/O by/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> to/O contest/O the/O charges/O against/O the/O <OTHER>Uyghur/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O after/O the/O attack/O on/O <LOCATION>Tiananmen/O Square/O</LOCATION> in/O October/O 2013/O is/O behind/O the/O arrest/O :/O ``/O Even/O on/O other/O occasions/O we/O have/O been/O referred/O to/O as/O perpetrators/O of/O serious/O acts/O ,/O only/O to/O discover/O that/O we/O had/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O them/O ''/O ./O 
The/O day/O before/O his/O arrest/O ,/O he/O posted/O on/O his/O mobile/O social/O media/O account/O :/O ``/O The/O Uygur/O people/O have/O become/O outsiders/O in/O the/O development/O of/O their/O own/O homeland/O and/O survival/O ,/O ''/O It/O is/O here/O that/O the/O people/O 's/O anger/O begins/O to/O grow/O ./O 
Uygur/O people/O need/O an/O avenue/O to/O express/O their/O aspirations/O and/O protect/O their/O rights/O ''/O ./O
