A/O video/O shows/O the/O preparation/O of/O one/O of/O the/O bombs/O used/O in/O the/O attack/O ,/O which/O resulted/O in/O three/O deaths/O and/O 79/O wounded/O ./O 
The/O authors/O are/O members/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Turkistan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O which/O seeks/O the/O independence/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O government/O :/O ``/O They/O want/O to/O destroy/O us/O but/O we/O will/O respond/O ''/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O 
The/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Islamic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>IPT/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O this/O morning/O claimed/O responsibility/O for/O the/O May/O 1/O terrorist/O attack/O on/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> train/O station/O ,/O the/O capital/O of/O the/O western/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
3/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O the/O attack/O -/O two/O attackers/O and/O a/O civilian/O -/O and/O 79/O people/O injured/O ./O 
The/O claim/O was/O announced/O by/O SITE/O -/O a/O website/O that/O tracks/O and/O controls/O the/O movements/O of/O Islamic/O extremists/O in/O the/O world/O -/O according/O to/O which/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>IPT/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> published/O a/O 10/O minute/O video/O showing/O how/O it/O made/O one/O of/O the/O bombs/O used/O in/O the/O attack/O ./O 
Along/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O <U_ORGANIZATION>IPT/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> declares/O its/O organization/O ``/O unites/O ''/O all/O those/O who/O want/O to/O gain/O independence/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O full/O religious/O freedom/O ``/O at/O all/O costs/O ''/O ./O 
Until/O now/O ,/O both/O extremist/O movements/O have/O kept/O a/O very/O low/O profile/O ,/O avoiding/O claims/O or/O public/O statements/O in/O favor/O of/O armed/O confrontation/O ./O 
The/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Its/O Uyghur/O Muslim/O minority/O ,/O who/O number/O about/O nine/O million/O ,/O have/O long/O sought/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O central/O government/O ,/O for/O its/O part/O ,/O has/O brought/O in/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O settlers/O to/O make/O Han/O Chinese/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O it/O has/O severely/O curtailed/O Muslim/O religious/O worship/O as/O well/O as/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O local/O language/O and/O culture/O ./O 
Since/O 2009/O Chinese/O police/O and/O the/O military/O have/O held/O the/O region/O under/O a/O special/O regime/O ,/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION imposed/O following/O clashes/O that/O left/O nearly/O 200/O people/O dead/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O various/O episodes/O of/O violence/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O long/O prison/O sentences/O were/O imposed/O and/O dozens/O of/O death/O penalties/O were/O carried/O out/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O blame/O Muslim/O extremists/O for/O the/O wave/O of/O violence/O ./O 
Uyghur/O exiles/O claim/O instead/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O ``/O exaggerating/O ''/O the/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O to/O justify/O repression/O against/O indigenous/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
For/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Uyghurs/O are/O responsible/O for/O the/O recent/O spate/O of/O violent/O attacks/O ,/O including/O the/O 1/O March/O 2014/O attack/O at/O the/O Kunming/LOCATION railway/O station/O by/O knives-wielding/O men/O that/O left/O 29/O people/O dead/O and/O more/O than/O 150/O wounded/O ,/O and/O the/O 28/O October/O 2013/O incident/O when/O a/O SUV/O plunged/O into/O a/O crowd/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O then/O burst/O into/O flames/O ,/O killing/O three/O people/O ./O 
Finally/O ,/O May/O 1/O ,/O 2014/O an/O attack/O on/O the/O train/O station/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -/O the/O Capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -/O shortly/O after/O the/O departure/O from/O the/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON caused/O 3/O dead/O and/O 79/O wounded/O ./O 
Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Hua/PERSON Chunying/PERSON ,/O this/O morning/O said/O that/O China/LOCATION ``/O should/O bolster/O ''/O its/O position/O on/O separatist/O groups/O :/O ''/O Some/O violent/O extremist/O terrorist/O groups/O have/O now/O emerged/O ./O 
They/O are/O colluding/O with/O foreign/O groups/O and/O are/O attempting/O violent/O activities/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O other/O areas/O in/O China/LOCATION intended/O to/O destroy/O China/LOCATION 's/O national/O policy/O and/O social/O stability/O ./O 
We/O hope/O that/O everyone/O can/O recognize/O the/O goal/O of/O these/O violent/O groups/O and/O support/O the/O Chinese/O government/O 's/O will/O to/O crack/O down/O on/O all/O violent/O terrorist/O activities/O ./O ''/O
