Chinese/O military/O raid/O cave/O where/O wanted/O suspects/O were/O hiding/O ./O 
The/O latter/O had/O been/O on/O the/O run/O for/O almost/O two/O months/O on/O suspicion/O of/O masterminding/O a/O terror/O attack/O in/O a/O coalmine/O that/O killed/O 50/O people/O ./O 
In/O what/O appears/O to/O be/O more/O Chinese/O heavy-handedness/O against/O ethnic/O Muslims/O ,/O the/O dead/O include/O the/O terrorists/O '/O relatives/O :/O four/O women/O and/O three/O children/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O 
Authorities/O in/O northwest/O China/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Uyghur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> have/O killed/O 17/O terror/O suspects/O from/O three/O families/O ,/O including/O women/O and/O children/O ,/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Free/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>RFA/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O reported/O ./O 
``/O Yes/O ,/O I/O received/O a/O notice/O from/O my/O superiors/O informing/O us/O that/O all/O of/O the/O terrorists/O have/O been/O killed/O and/O warning/O us/O to/O remain/O vigilant/O against/O a/O possible/O revenge/O attack/O ,/O ''/O said/O <U_PERSON>Exmet/PERSON Abliz/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O police/O chief/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Bay/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> <OTHER>'s/LOCATION</OTHER> <U_LOCATION>Qeyir/LOCATION Township/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O told <ORGANIZATION>RFA/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Police/O sources/O said/O that/O the/O 17/O fugitives/O were/O killed/O when/O the/O military/O blew/O up/O the/O cave/O in/O which/O they/O were/O hiding/O ./O 
The/O fugitives/O were/O wanted/O in/O connection/O with/O the <U_LOCATION>Sogan/O Colliery/O</U_LOCATION> attack/O that/O killed/O 50/O people/O ./O 
On/O that/O occasion/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O pinned/O the/O attack/O on/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O ,/O Turkic-speaking/O Muslims/O concentrated/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> who/O seek/O cultural/O and/O religious/O autonomy/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
For/O nearly/O two/O months/O ,/O police/O and/O the/O military/O sought/O the/O 17/O suspects/O :/O the/O three/O men/O believed/O to/O have/O carried/O out/O the/O attack/O --/O <U_PERSON>Tursun/PERSON Jume/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O 46/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Musa/PERSON Toxtiniyaz/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O 47/O ,/O and/O <U_PERSON>Memet/PERSON Eysa/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O 60/O ,/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Chokatal/PERSON Meadow/PERSON</U_LOCATION> ,/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Bay/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> <OTHER>'s/LOCATION</OTHER> <U_LOCATION>Kanchi/LOCATION Township/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> --/O and/O their/O family/O members/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Ekber/O</U_PERSON> ,/O the/O director/O of/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Terek/LOCATION Township/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> middle/O school/O ,/O which/O has/O been/O used/O as/O a/O base/O of/O operations/O for/O the/O manhunt/O ,/O said/O teachers/O and/O staff/O finally/O returned/O to/O classes/O on/O Tuesday/O after/O nearly/O two/O months/O ./O 
``/O I/O received/O a/O call/O from/O the/O chief/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Bay/ORGANIZATION County/ORGANIZATION Education/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O who/O told/O me/O that/O the/O war/O had/O ended/O with/O a/O great/O victory/O --/O that/O all/O the/O terrorists/O had/O been/O killed/O and/O that/O we/O could/O return/O to/O the/O middle/O school/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O Based/O on/O the/O warrant/O list/O ,/O ''/O said/O <U_PERSON>Ekber/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O ``/O we/O found/O out/O that/O the/O 17/O suspects/O included/O four/O women/O and/O three/O children/O ,/O one/O of/O which/O --/O nine-year-old/O <U_PERSON>Munire/O</U_PERSON> -LSB-/O <U_PERSON>Memet/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O the/O adopted/O granddaughter/O of/O <U_PERSON>Memet/PERSON Eysa/PERSON</U_PERSON> -RSB-/O --/O was/O one/O of/O our/O second/O grade/O students/O ./O ''/O 
A/O local/O official/O who/O provided/O the/O names/O of/O the/O suspects/O to/O RFA/ORGANIZATION in/O October/O said/O at/O the/O time/O that/O neither/O the/O women/O nor/O the/O children/O had/O been/O involved/O ./O 
The/O police/O raid/O comes/O a/O few/O days/O after/O China/LOCATION ,/O following/O the/O Paris/LOCATION attacks/O ,/O stated/O that/O it/O was/O going/O to/O intensify/O its/O fight/O against/O Uighur/O terrorism/O ,/O which/O it/O blames/O on/O the/O al/O Qaeda-linked/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>ETIM/O</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O vowed/O to/O crack/O down/O on/O the/O ``/O three/O evils/O ''/O of/O terrorism/O ,/O separatism/O ,/O and/O religious/O extremism/O ./O 
However/O ,/O experts/O have/O questioned/O China/LOCATION 's/O action/O for/O its/O heavy-handed/O rule/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O blaming/O the/O escalation/O of/O violence/O on/O the/O central/O government/O unjust/O policies/O ./O
