Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O is/O confiscating/O all/O passports/O of/O the/O population/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> motivating/O the/O gesture/O as/O a/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O is/O confiscating/O all/O passports/O of/O the/O population/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> motivating/O the/O gesture/O as/O a/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O ./O 
Citizens/O have/O been/O ordered/O to/O hand/O in/O their/O passports/O to/O the/O authorities/O has/O been/O published/O already/O for/O several/O weeks/O under/O the/O threat/O of/O being/O permanently/O banned/O from/O travel/O ./O 
Some/O <U_LOCATION>Shihezi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> police/O directives/O ,/O which/O later/O disappeared/O from/O their/O website/O ,/O stated/O that/O the/O withdrawal/O of/O travel/O documents/O was/O to/O happen/O by/O next/O February/O ./O 
The/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> has/O denounced/O the/O move/O as/O a/O further/O step/O towards/O the/O marginalization/O of/O the/O Uighur/O population/O ./O 
According/O to/O sources/O ,/O last/O June/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O forced/O the/O Uighur/O to/O give/O samples/O of/O their/O DNA/O in/O applying/O for/O new/O passports/O ./O 
The/O Uighur/O ,/O a/O Muslim/O ethnicity/O of/O Turkic/O origins/O constitute/O 45/O %/O of/O the/O population/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O northwest/O China/LOCATION ./O 
There/O have/O been/O decades/O of/O marked/O tensions/O between/O Uighur/O and/O ethnic/O Han/O -LRB-/O Chinese/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Some/O Uighur/O fringes/O dream/O of/O independence/O for/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ,/O although/O the/O majority/O of/O them/O just/O want/O more/O autonomy/O ./O 
China/LOCATION responds/O with/O a/O colonial/O military/O rule/O ,/O by/O marginalizing/O the/O Uighur/O from/O key/O posts/O in/O politics/O and/O economics/O of/O the/O region/O ./O 
China/LOCATION fears/O that/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> Muslims/O can/O strengthen/O alliances/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION or/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O which/O supports/O the/O fight/O for/O independence/O ./O 
Under/O the/O motivation/O ``/O anti-terrorism/O ''/O ,/O though/O China/LOCATION oppresses/O all/O the/O Muslim/O population/O by/O banning/O young/O people/O from/O participating/O in/O the/O prayer/O in/O the/O mosque/O ,/O forcing/O them/O to/O not/O observe/O the/O fast/O of/O Ramadan/O ,/O and/O banning/O beards/O ./O 
In/O China/LOCATION ,/O no/O resident/O has/O the/O right/O to/O have/O a/O passport/O ,/O but/O must/O apply/O to/O the/O authorities/O ./O 
This/O allows/O authorities/O to/O control/O citizens/O foreign/O travels/O ./O
