The/O World/ORGANIZATION Health/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>WHO/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O expects/O things/O to/O get/O worse/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Two/O new/O outbreaks/O reported/O in/O Hubei/LOCATION and/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> provinces/O ./O 
Indonesia/LOCATION asks/O for/O the/O world/O 's/O help/O ./O 
Tamiflu/O is/O under/O probe/O in/O Japan/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O 
After/O one/O death/O and/O two/O new/O human/O bird/O flu/O cases/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O expecting/O things/O to/O get/O worse/O ./O 
Indonesia/LOCATION openly/O acknowledges/O it/O is/O unable/O to/O cope/O with/O the/O emergency/O and/O asks/O for/O help/O ./O 
In/O Japan/LOCATION authorities/O start/O probe/O into/O possible/O Tamiflu/O side/O effects/O ./O 
China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O death/O of/O Zhou/PERSON Maoya/PERSON ,/O a/O woman/O from/O Anhui/LOCATION province/O ,/O and/O the/O confirmation/O of/O two/O other/O human/O cases/O of/O bird/O flu/O -LRB-/O a/O little/O boy/O in/O Hunan/LOCATION and/O woman/O farmer/O in/O Liaoning/LOCATION -RRB-/O have/O set/O off/O more/O alarm/O bells/O ./O 
State-owned/O media/O reported/O that/O Ms/O <PERSON>Zhou/O</PERSON> ,/O 24/O ,/O was/O a/O poultry/O worker/O from/O Yantan/LOCATION village/O ,/O Zhoutan/LOCATION County/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O Anhui/LOCATION -RRB-/O ./O 
She/O fell/O ill/O on/O November/O 1/O and/O was/O admitted/O to/O a/O hospital/O in/O Tongling/LOCATION city/O on/O November/O 6/O after/O developing/O a/O fever/O ,/O a/O cough/O and/O difficulty/O in/O breathing/O ./O 
She/O died/O on/O November/O 10/O ./O 
Zhou/PERSON 's/O family/O told/O a/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION paper/O that/O for/O a/O while/O she/O had/O been/O working/O in/O Jiangsu/LOCATION --/O a/O province/O where/O no/O outbreaks/O had/O been/O recently/O reported/O --/O and/O returned/O home/O a/O month/O ago/O to/O prepare/O for/O her/O wedding/O ./O 
Guan/PERSON Yi/PERSON ,/O a/O virologist/O from/O Hong/ORGANIZATION Kong/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O Zhou/PERSON 's/O case/O could/O be/O linked/O to/O fake/O vaccines/O ,/O which/O can/O keep/O chickens/O infected/O by/O H5N1/O alive/O and/O are/O widely/O used/O in/O mainland/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Agriculture/ORGANIZATION named/O Xiaogan/LOCATION <OTHER>city/LOCATION</OTHER> in/O Hubei/LOCATION <OTHER>province/LOCATION</OTHER> on/O November/O 5/O ,/O and/O <U_LOCATION>Hetian/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> city/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> on/O November/O 10/O as/O the/O latest/O bird-flu-infected/O areas/O ./O 
A/O total/O of/O 88,937/O birds/O within/O a/O three/O km/O radius/O of/O the/O two/O cities/O were/O culled/O ./O 
The/O two/O latest/O outbreaks/O bring/O the/O total/O number/O of/O cases/O ,/O reported/O by/O the/O government/O since/O October/O 19/O ,/O to/O 13/O ./O 
``/O We/O expect/O there/O will/O be/O more/O poultry/O outbreaks/O ,/O ''/O said/O Henk/PERSON Bekedam/PERSON ,/O the/O chief/O WHO/ORGANIZATION representative/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O adding/O that/O this/O could/O lead/O to/O a/O rise/O in/O human/O infections/O in/O winter/O ./O 
More/O optimistic/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O Prime/O Minister/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON said/O that/O ``/O we/O can/O definitely/O conquer/O bird/O flu/O ''/O ,/O Indonesia/LOCATION ./O 
Tests/O performed/O on/O a/O 20-year-old/O woman/O and/O a/O 16-year-old/O girl/O who/O died/O a/O few/O days/O ago/O came/O back/O positive/O for/O the/O H5N1/O bird/O flu/O virus/O ,/O said/O Sari/PERSON Setiogi/PERSON ,/O WHO/ORGANIZATION spokeswoman/O ./O 
``/O Our/O worst/O nightmare/O now/O would/O be/O if/O the/O avian/O flu/O virus/O finds/O a/O way/O to/O mutate/O by/O swapping/O human/O genetic/O code/O ,/O which/O would/O allow/O human-to-human/O transmission/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O The/O impact/O on/O our/O economies/O would/O be/O catastrophic/O ./O 
None/O of/O us/O can/O afford/O this/O ./O ''/O 
According/O to/O both/O experts/O and/O government/O ,/O Indonesia/LOCATION is/O unable/O to/O cope/O alone/O with/O the/O problem/O ./O 
``/O We/O have/O many/O international/O commitments/O ,/O but/O we/O need/O immediate/O action/O ,/O ''/O senior/O Indonesian/ORGANIZATION Health/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION official/O Hariadi/PERSON Wibisono/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O We/O have/O the/O health/O workers/O ,/O what/O we/O urgently/O need/O is/O equipment/O and/O capacity/O building/O ./O ''/O 
Japan/LOCATION ./O 
There/O are/O growing/O concerns/O after/O the/O deaths/O of/O 12/O children/O who/O had/O been/O using/O the/O anti-influenza/O drug/O Tamiflu/O ./O 
The/O US/ORGANIZATION Food/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Drug/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O FDA/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O wants/O to/O investigate/O the/O deaths/O to/O ascertain/O the/O drug/O 's/O potential/O risks/O ./O 
Tamiflu/O 's/O maker/O ,/O <ORGANIZATION>Roche/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> ,/O has/O been/O asked/O to/O provide/O more/O information/O about/O the/O deaths/O ./O 
The/O FDA/ORGANIZATION also/O said/O it/O was/O also/O concerned/O that/O 32/O psychiatric/O events/O ,/O such/O as/O hallucinations/O and/O abnormal/O behaviour/O ,/O have/O been/O reported/O in/O children/O who/O took/O Tamiflu/O ,/O which/O is/O in/O high/O demand/O because/O it/O is/O considered/O to/O be/O one/O of/O the/O best/O defences/O against/O bird/O flu/O in/O people/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O FDA/ORGANIZATION acknowledged/O that/O is/O was/O ``/O extremely/O difficult/O to/O interpret/O ''/O the/O causes/O of/O death/O listed/O for/O the/O 12/O children/O ,/O mostly/O cardio-respiratory/O arrest/O ,/O because/O of/O limited/O data/O ./O 
The/O FDA/ORGANIZATION 's/O investigation/O comes/O after/O reports/O on/O Saturday/O that/O two/O teenage/O boys/O in/O Japan/LOCATION exhibited/O abnormal/O behaviour/O after/O taking/O Tamiflu/O then/O committed/O suicide/O ./O 
In/O one/O case/O ,/O a/O junior/O high/O school/O student/O apparently/O fell/O from/O the/O ninth/O floor/O of/O his/O apartment/O building/O in/O February/O this/O year/O ./O 
In/O the/O second/O case/O ,/O a/O 17-year-old/O high/O school/O student/O who/O was/O at/O home/O alone/O ran/O out/O of/O the/O house/O and/O jumped/O over/O a/O railing/O into/O the/O path/O of/O a/O truck/O in/O February/O 2004/O shortly/O after/O taking/O the/O medicine/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>Roche/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> has/O denied/O that/O the/O incidence/O of/O Tamiflu-related/O deaths/O and/O neuropsychiatric/O problems/O has/O increased/O ./O 
Vietnam/LOCATION ./O 
Four/O outbreaks/O hit/O <LOCATION>Phu/PERSON Tho/PERSON</LOCATION> and/O <LOCATION>Hoa/PERSON Binh/PERSON</LOCATION> provinces/O ,/O with/O several/O thousand/O chickens/O ,/O ducks/O and/O geese/O found/O dead/O or/O slaughtered/O by/O health/O workers/O ./O 
Since/O October/O the/O virus/O has/O spread/O to/O 16/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O 64/O provinces/O ./O 
-LRB-/O PB/O -RRB-/O
