<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O an/O Uighur/O political/O dissident/O released/O on/O March/O 17/O ,/O is/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION to/O talk/O about/O human/O rights/O ,/O economics/O and/O Chinese/O prisons/O ./O 
Washington/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O 
The/O world/O should/O not/O put/O business/O before/O human/O rights/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O recently-released/O Uighur/O political/O prisoner/O said/O ./O 
Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O businesswoman/O herself/O ,/O warned/O the/O business/O community/O against/O letting/O economic/O interests/O close/O their/O hearts/O ./O 
``/O These/O businessmen/O who/O have/O a/O lot/O of/O -LSB-/O deals/O -RSB-/O in/O China/LOCATION should/O look/O deep/O into/O their/O hearts/O and/O see/O what/O 's/O truly/O important/O --/O money/O ,/O business/O or/O actually/O one/O 's/O life/O ?/O ''/O 
she/O said/O ./O 
``/O I/O would/O give/O up/O any/O business/O now/O to/O save/O one/O life/O ./O 
If/O there/O are/O no/O human/O rights/O ,/O business/O will/O go/O nowhere/O ./O ''/O 
The/O 58-year-old/O woman/O said/O she/O would/O use/O her/O new/O freedom/O to/O win/O greater/O rights/O for/O her/O fellow/O Muslims/O ,/O and/O urged/O others/O to/O ``/O pursue/O human/O rights/O from/O every/O angle/O ''/O ./O 
A/O former/O executive/O in/O a/O trading/O company/O ,/O not/O to/O mention/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Consultative/ORGANIZATION Conference/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CPPCC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O for/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ,/O she/O was/O arrested/O in/O 1999/O for/O spreading/O news/O abroad/O that/O the/O authorities/O deemed/O ``/O state/O intelligence/O ''/O ./O 
Sentenced/O to/O eight/O years/O in/O jail/O ,/O she/O was/O freed/O on/O the/O eve/O of/O a/O visit/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION by/O US/LOCATION Secretary/O of/O State/O Condoleezza/PERSON Rice/PERSON just/O as/O the/O US/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION said/O it/O would/O not/O seek/O a/O resolution/O critical/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION at/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION on/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION in/O Geneva/LOCATION ./O 
Upon/O her/O release/O ,/O Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> left/O for/O the/O US/LOCATION where/O she/O gave/O several/O interviews/O even/O though/O Chinese/O authorities/O warned/O her/O not/O to/O speak/O to/O the/O media/O ,/O reminding/O her/O that/O 6/O of/O her/O 11/O children/O remained/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
But/O she/O could/O not/O be/O silent/O over/O her/O ethnic/O group/O 's/O fate/O ./O 
As/O a/O CPPCC/ORGANIZATION member/O ,/O ``/O I/O thought/O I/O could/O speak/O to/O the/O government/O for/O my/O people/O and/O tell/O them/O that/O their/O policies/O toward/O us/O were/O wrong/O and/O point/O out/O the/O discrimination/O and/O lack/O of/O education/O spending/O on/O Uighurs/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
``/O Actually/O ,/O being/O elevated/O to/O the/O parliamentary/O position/O was/O the/O beginning/O of/O my/O troubles/O ,/O ''/O she/O added/O ./O 
She/O described/O harsh/O prison/O conditions/O and/O said/O ``/O there/O 's/O no/O forgiveness/O for/O political/O prisoners/O ./O 
We/O ca/O n't/O even/O look/O at/O each/O other/O and/O smile/O ''/O ./O 
Recalling/O this/O time/O ,/O she/O said/O that/O although/O ``/O prison/O guards/O never/O laid/O a/O finger/O on/O her/O ''/O ,/O other/O prisoners/O were/O not/O so/O lucky/O ./O 
``/O Some/O were/O beaten/O lame/O ;/O others/O were/O tortured/O within/O earshot/O to/O frighten/O her/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
One/O 96-year-old/O Uighur/O woman/O was/O in/O prison/O not/O knowing/O why/O ./O 
She/O never/O heard/O of/O the/O September/O 11/O ,/O 2001/O ,/O terror/O attacks/O ,/O or/O of/O the/O Iraq/LOCATION war/O ,/O or/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION had/O won/O the/O right/O to/O host/O the/O 2008/O Olympics/O ./O 
Many/O of/O the/O 8/O million/O Uighurs/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O which/O has/O an/O overall/O population/O of/O about/O 19/O million/O ,/O seek/O greater/O autonomy/O for/O the/O region/O ,/O although/O some/O want/O to/O restore/O the/O brief/O independence/O the/O region/O had/O as/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> from/O 1938/O to/O 1949/O --/O a/O campaign/O that/O has/O drawn/O a/O relentless/O crackdown/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> has/O never/O advocated/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O independence/O but/O demands/O that/O her/O people/O have/O ``/O basic/O freedom/O and/O human/O rights/O ./O 
I/O want/O them/O to/O have/O a/O happy/O life/O ,/O as/O the/O Chinese/O do/O ./O ''/O 
``/O There/O 's/O not/O enough/O food/O or/O housing/O for/O Uighurs/O ,/O yet/O they/O keep/O moving/O Chinese/O migrants/O from/O Chinese/O cities/O to/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O
