Washington/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O 
<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O human/O rights/O activist/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O says/O her/O nomination/O for/O the/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O has/O drawn/O world/O attention/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O oppression/O of/O her/O people/O ./O 
She/O has/O denied/O all/O links/O with/O terrorism/O ./O 
``/O I/O am/O not/O a/O terrorist/O ,/O ''/O 60-year-old/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> said/O ./O 
Shortly/O after/O she/O was/O nominated/O for/O the/O Nobel/O prize/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION accused/O her/O of/O ``/O sabotaging/O peace/O and/O stability/O of/O Chinese/O society/O ''/O ,/O of/O collaborating/O with/O terrorist/O groups/O and/O of/O organizing/O violent/O activities/O to/O attain/O the/O secession/O of/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinijiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O home/O of/O the/O Turkish-speaking/O Uighur/O minority/O -RRB-/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O millionaire/O businesswoman/O ,/O was/O arrested/O in/O 1999/O and/O imprisoned/O for/O five/O years/O for/O disseminating/O ``/O state/O secrets/O ''/O abroad/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> has/O always/O maintained/O the/O material/O consisted/O of/O newspaper/O clippings/O sent/O by/O fax/O to/O her/O husband/O abroad/O ./O 
She/O was/O released/O on/O 17/O March/O 2005/O after/O a/O widespread/O international/O campaign/O and/O obtained/O refugee/O status/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Since/O her/O release/O ,/O her/O firm/O has/O been/O submitted/O to/O continued/O checks/O and/O three/O of/O her/O sons/O have/O been/O detained/O since/O May/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O response/O was/O that/O ``/O all/O the/O Chinese/O charges/O are/O false/O ./O 
Today/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O used/O the/O charge/O of/O terrorism/O to/O persecute/O and/O eliminate/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ./O ''/O 
She/O said/O she/O hoped/O Uighurs/O held/O in/O detention/O abroad/O on/O terrorism/O charges/O would/O not/O be/O extradited/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O where/O they/O would/O be/O ``/O executed/O ''/O like/O ``/O all/O the/O Uighurs/O who/O were/O extradited/O to/O China/LOCATION in/O the/O past/O ./O ''/O 
Since/O the/O annexation/O in/O 1949/O of/O Uighur/O territory/O --/O which/O was/O the/O independent/O state/O of/O eastern/O <U_LOCATION>Turkestan/O</U_LOCATION> from/O 1938/O to/O 1949/O --/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O promoted/O a/O massive/O wave/O immigration/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O to/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O and/O has/O oppressed/O the/O people/O 's/O religion/O and/O culture/O ./O 
The/O region/O is/O rich/O in/O oil/O and/O natural/O resources/O ,/O used/O above/O all/O to/O boost/O the/O rich/O southern/O provinces/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> was/O nominated/O as/O a/O defender/O of/O Uighur/O rights/O and/O of/O women/O 's/O rights/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Among/O the/O 191/O candidates/O for/O the/O Nobel/O ,/O which/O will/O be/O awarded/O on/O 13/O October/O ,/O there/O is/O also/O the/O Indonesian/O president/O ,/O Susilo/PERSON Bambang/PERSON Yudhoyono/PERSON ,/O for/O his/O role/O in/O talks/O leading/O to/O the/O Aceh/LOCATION peace/O agreement/O in/O August/O 2005/O ./O
