The/O Uighurs/O leader/O denounces/O China/LOCATION 's/O manipulation/O of/O her/O family/O and/O describes/O as/O false/O a/O letter/O by/O some/O of/O her/O children/O ,/O accusing/O her/O of/O being/O behind/O the/O incidents/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Many/O of/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O children/O are/O in/O prison/O ./O 
Chinese/O methods/O are/O the/O same/O since/O the/O time/O of/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O and/O similar/O to/O those/O against/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ./O 
Sydney/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O the/O exiled/O Uighur/O who/O became/O an/O advocate/O of/O the/O rights/O of/O Muslim/O minority/O in/O China/LOCATION before/O the/O violence/O ,/O denounced/O as/O false/O a/O letter/O published/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION in/O which/O the/O children/O of/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> charge/O her/O with/O responsibility/O for/O all/O violence/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> at/O beginning/O of/O July/O ./O 
Arriving/O in/O Sydney/LOCATION ,/O to/O attend/O the/O International/O Film/O Festival/O ,/O she/O said/O :/O ``/O China/LOCATION has/O power/O ./O 
They/O are/O able/O to/O control/O the/O speech/O of/O my/O children/O and/O twist/O their/O language/O against/O me/O ,/O but/O they/O can/O not/O control/O the/O love/O created/O by/O God/O between/O me/O and/O my/O children/O ''/O ./O 
``/O I/O know/O my/O children/O ,/O ''/O she/O added/O ./O 
``/O Nobody/O criticizes/O his/O or/O her/O mother/O for/O something/O ,/O even/O if/O she/O did/O something/O wrong/O ./O ''/O 
According/O to/O Chinese/O media/O ,/O which/O gave/O ample/O coverage/O to/O the/O elusive/O letter/O ,/O the/O message/O comes/O from/O the/O two/O sons/O <U_PERSON>Khahar/LOCATION</U_PERSON> and/O <U_PERSON>Memet/PERSON</U_PERSON> and/O daughter/O <U_PERSON>Roxingul/PERSON</U_PERSON> ./O 
``/O Because/O of/O you/O -/O says/O the/O letter/O -/O many/O innocent/O people/O of/O all/O ethnic/O groups/O have/O lost/O their/O lives/O in/O <U_PERSON>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_PERSON> July/O 5/O last/O ,/O with/O enormous/O damage/O to/O property/O ,/O shops/O and/O vehicles/O ./O ''/O 
<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> has/O 11/O children/O ,/O who/O all/O remained/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O after/O her/O forced/O exile/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Two/O of/O them/O are/O in/O prison/O ./O 
In/O 2007/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Ablikim/PERSON Abdiriyim/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O was/O sentenced/O to/O 9/O years/O in/O prison/O by/O a/O court/O in/O <U_PERSON>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_PERSON> ./O 
According/O to/O the/O indictment/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Ablikim/PERSON</U_PERSON> spread/O secessionist/O articles/O over/O the/O internet/O ,/O instigating/O to/O act/O against/O the/O government/O and/O ``/O distorting/O ''/O the/O situation/O of/O human/O rights/O and/O ethnic/O politics/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
He/O was/O also/O deprived/O of/O political/O rights/O for/O three/O years/O ./O 
Another/O son/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON Abdiriyim/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O was/O convicted/O in/O September/O 2006/O to/O 7/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O tax/O evasion/O ./O 
A/O third/O son/O was/O arrested/O for/O tax/O evasion/O but/O was/O only/O sentenced/O to/O a/O fine/O and/O a/O daughter/O has/O for/O years/O been/O under/O house/O arrest/O ./O 
``/O I/O know/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O and/O their/O methods/O old/O and/O new/O to/O criticize/O their/O enemies/O ''/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> said/O ./O 
The/O attempt/O to/O discredit/O the/O Uighurs/O leader/O recalls/O closely/O the/O campaign/O full/O of/O lies/O and/O insults/O against/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON before/O the/O Olympics/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION in/O 2008/O ./O 
Personalities/O of/O the/O government/O accused/O him/O of/O being/O ``/O a/O devil/O disguised/O as/O an/O angel/O ,/O ''/O ``/O a/O wolf/O disguised/O as/O a/O lamb/O ./O ''/O 
The/O elusive/O letter/O also/O follows/O the/O style/O of/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O during/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O when/O Mao/PERSON called/O on/O young/O people/O to/O denounce/O their/O parents/O ./O 
Curiously/O ,/O the/O passages/O in/O the/O letter/O cited/O in/O the/O Chinese/O media/O ,/O are/O modeled/O throughout/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O reading/O of/O events/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
On/O 5/O July/O a/O demonstration/O of/O thousands/O of/O Uighurs/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> degenerated/O into/O a/O clash/O with/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
China/LOCATION accused/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> and/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uygur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> of/O designing/O the/O plan/O ``/O to/O destroy/O harmony/O and/O unity/O among/O ethnic/O groups/O ''/O and/O that/O she/O was/O directly/O responsible/O for/O the/O death/O of/O 197/O people/O ,/O majority/O Han/O ./O 
On/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O exiled/O Uighurs/O accuse/O the/O Chinese/O army/O and/O police/O of/O superficiality/O and/O of/O provoking/O the/O clash/O that/O led/O to/O the/O arrest/O of/O more/O than/O 1,400/O Uighurs/O and/O the/O disappearance/O of/O ``/O at/O least/O 10/O thousand/O ''/O ,/O according/O to/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ./O 
Careful/O observers/O believe/O that/O the/O incident/O serves/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O establish/O greater/O control/O over/O the/O country/O and/O greater/O cohesion/O a/O few/O months/O away/O from/O the/O celebrations/O of/O the/O 60th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O Peoples/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION ./O
