The/O court/O in/O Shaoguan/LOCATION also/O ruled/O life/O imprisonment/O and/O penalties/O of/O five/O to/O eight/O years/O for/O those/O responsible/O for/O the/O clashes/O in/O a/O factory/O city/O in/O southern/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O episode/O sparked/O Muslim/O Uyghurs/O protests/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O July/O that/O culminated/O in/O clashes/O between/O demonstrators/O and/O police/O ,/O 200/O dead/O ,/O 800/O injured/O and/O hundreds/O of/O arrests/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
A/O man/O of/O Han/O ethnicity/O was/O sentenced/O to/O death/O and/O another/O to/O life/O imprisonment/O for/O killing/O two/O Uyghur/O workers/O ,/O which/O occurred/O in/O June/O in/O Shaoguan/LOCATION ,/O Guangdong/LOCATION Province/LOCATION ./O 
The/O City/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION has/O sentenced/O nine/O other/O ethnic/O Han/O with/O between/O five/O and/O eight/O years/O in/O prison/O ,/O all/O involved/O in/O the/O assassination/O of/O two/O immigrants/O who/O worked/O in/O a/O factory/O in/O the/O South/LOCATION ./O 
Han/O workers/O had/O accused/O the/O two/O Uyghurs/O immigrants/O ,/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O of/O violence/O against/O two/O women/O also/O employed/O in/O the/O factory/O ./O 
The/O group/O of/O Han/O then/O beat/O the/O two/O Muslim/O workers/O with/O sticks/O and/O rods/O ,/O killing/O them/O ,/O and/O sparking/O clashes/O between/O workers/O of/O the/O two/O ethnic/O groups/O ./O 
Following/O the/O events/O of/O Shaoguan/LOCATION thousands/O of/O Uyghurs/PERSON took/O to/O the/O streets/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O to/O protest/O against/O the/O murder/O and/O the/O marginalization/O they/O endured/O ./O 
The/O Han/O population/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> has/O in/O hand/O the/O economy/O and/O the/O local/O administration/O ./O 
On/O the/O night/O of/O July/O 6th/O Army/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O Chinese/O police/O dealt/O with/O the/O demonstrators/O ,/O causing/O at/O least/O 200/O Muslims/O deaths/O ,/O 800/O wounded/O and/O arresting/O hundreds/O of/O protesters/O ./O 
The/O violent/O response/O by/O Chinese/O police/O sparked/O strong/O international/O criticism/O against/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
