The/O heavy/O presence/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O military/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION constitutes/O a/O threat/O to/O India/LOCATION 's/O sovereignty/O and/O economy/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policies/O vis-à-vis/O minorities/O are/O ``/O wrong/O and/O disastrous/O ''/O ./O 
Dharamsala/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O --/O
The/O celebration/O by/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION 's/O of/O 60/O years/O of/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION rule/O celebrates/O ``/O 60/O years/O of/O violence/O ,/O lies/O and/O oppression/O against/O the/O people/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O the/O leaders/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Tibetan/O</ORGANIZATION> Youth/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O TYC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O said/O ./O 
The/O TYC/ORGANIZATION is/O an/O exile/O group/O fighting/O for/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O Tibetan/O people/O ./O 
In/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION ,/O thousands/O of/O Indians/O and/O Tibetan/O rallied/O against/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O violent/O protest/O ./O 
Just/O like/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympics/O ,/O this/O new/O show/O put/O forth/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION is/O another/O attempt/O to/O improve/O China/LOCATION 's/O image/O in/O the/O world/O and/O win/O recognition/O for/O China/LOCATION as/O a/O world/O leader/O in/O global/O affairs/O ./O 
China/LOCATION will/O showcase/O its/O finest/O and/O most/O advanced/O military/O weapons/O in/O its/O televised/O National/O Day/O parade/O ./O 
Its/O constant/O race/O to/O acquire/O and/O build/O its/O military/O hardware/O is/O not/O only/O alarming/O ;/O it/O is/O a/O warning/O to/O the/O world/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O so-called/O ``/O peaceful/O rise/O ''/O ./O 
Today/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O celebrating/O China/LOCATION 's/O might/O ,/O economic/O miracle/O ,/O military/O prowess/O and/O space/O programmes/O ./O 
But/O in/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION ,/O thousands/O of/O Indians/O and/O Tibetans/O have/O organised/O a/O protest/O against/O the/O Chinese/O Communist/O regime/O ./O 
For/O TYC/ORGANIZATION leaders/O ,/O the/O heavy/O presence/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O military/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O represents/O ``/O a/O direct/O threat/O to/O India/LOCATION on/O security/O ,/O economy/O and/O environment/O ./O ''/O 
For/O them/O ,/O the/O ``/O continuing/O and/O ever-increasing/O Chinese/O infiltrations/O and/O incursions/O on/O Indian/O soil/O ''/O are/O motive/O for/O deep/O concern/O ./O 
For/O the/O youth/O group/O ,/O not/O only/O has/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ``/O illegally/O occupied/O and/O colonised/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O <LOCATION>Southern/O</LOCATION> -LRB-/O <LOCATION>Inner/O</LOCATION> -RRB-/O Mongolia/LOCATION ;/O it/O has/O carried/O out/O many/O wrong/O and/O disastrous/O policies/O that/O have/O resulted/O in/O the/O death/O of/O over/O 30/O million/O Chinese/O people/O ./O ''/O 
<ORGANIZATION>The/O</ORGANIZATION> Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION has/O held/O onto/O political/O power/O through/O the/O ``/O use/O of/O brute/O force/O ''/O ,/O and/O lost/O ``/O the/O respect/O of/O its/O own/O people/O ./O ''/O 
<LOCATION>The/O</LOCATION> Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION massacre/O of/O 1989/O and/O the/O ongoing/O human/O rights/O violation/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O Manchuria/LOCATION and/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION are/O cases/O in/O point/O ,/O which/O often/O come/O close/O to/O resembling/O a/O ``/O policy/O of/O genocide/O conducted/O with/O impunity/O ''/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O TYC/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O rapid/O transfer/O of/O millions/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O to/O Tibet/LOCATION marginalises/O the/O indigenous/O population/O ,/O turning/O Tibetans/O into/O a/O minority/O in/O their/O own/O country/O ./O 
More/O than/O 500,000/O troops/O and/O a/O network/O of/O railways/O ,/O roads/O ,/O bridges/O and/O tunnels/O support/O a/O vast/O military/O infrastructure/O built/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION to/O clamp/O down/O ,/O among/O other/O things/O ,/O on/O any/O form/O of/O dissent/O ./O 
The/O ``/O Chinese/O government/O lacks/O legitimacy/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O exercises/O control/O over/O Tibet/LOCATION through/O military/O force/O ,/O ''/O the/O TYC/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O 
For/O the/O group/O ,/O this/O belies/O China/LOCATION 's/O commitment/O to/O a/O harmonious/O society/O ,/O so/O dear/O to/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION voted/O to/O adopt/O the/O Universal/O Declaration/O in/O 1948/O ,/O and/O pledged/O to/O uphold/O human/O rights/O -LSB-/O .../O -RSB-/O ./O 
However/O ,/O it/O continues/O to/O ignore/O and/O violate/O all/O the/O articles/O of/O the/O Universal/O Declaration/O of/O Human/O Rights/O and/O other/O Covenants/O it/O has/O signed/O ,/O ''/O the/O TYC/ORGANIZATION noted/O ./O 
Unless/O the/O voice/O of/O ``/O Tibetans/O ,/O Uyghurs/O ,/O and/O Chinese/O -LSB-/O .../O -RSB-/O is/O respected/O and/O not/O silenced/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O celebrations/O will/O only/O be/O in/O vain/O ./O ''/O 
NC/O -RRB-/O
