For/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O they/O ``/O will/O face/O the/O same/O fate/O of/O the/O nine/O men/O executed/O in/O November/O if/O the/O world/O remains/O silent/O ''/O ./O 
In/O the/O aftermath/O of/O July/O unrest/O ,/O China/LOCATION continues/O its/O crackdown/O on/O the/O province/O 's/O indigenous/O population/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O 
A/O people/O 's/O court/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O sentenced/O five/O ethnic/O Uyghurs/O to/O death/O and/O another/O two/O to/O life/O imprisonment/O for/O their/O roles/O in/O deadly/O unrest/O in/O July/O ./O 
Six/O others/O were/O given/O varying/O jail/O terms/O ./O
<ORGANIZATION>Xinhua/O</ORGANIZATION> identified/O the/O five/O sentenced/O to/O death/O as/O <U_PERSON>Memeteli/ORGANIZATION Islam/ORGANIZATION</U_PERSON> ,/O <U_PERSON>Mamattursun/PERSON Elmu/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O <U_PERSON>Memeteli/PERSON Abburakm/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O <U_PERSON>Kushiman/PERSON Kurban/PERSON</U_PERSON> and/O <U_PERSON>Helil/PERSON Sadir/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O all/O Uyghur/O by/O the/O name/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O the/O Washington-based/O leader/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> who/O spent/O six/O years/O in/O a/O Chinese/O prison/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O slammed/O the/O decision/O ./O 
``/O The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O brazenly/O ignored/O all/O standards/O of/O due/O process/O of/O law/O in/O a/O campaign/O to/O silence/O and/O intimidate/O the/O Uyghur/O population/O through/O executions/O and/O mass/O detentions/O ,/O ''/O Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> said/O in/O a/O statement/O ./O 
``/O I/O fear/O that/O these/O five/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> will/O face/O the/O same/O fate/O of/O the/O nine/O men/O executed/O in/O November/O if/O the/O world/O remains/O silent/O ./O ''/O 
Ethnic/O tensions/O exploded/O on/O 5/O July/O when/O a/O peaceful/O Uyghur/O demonstration/O caused/O by/O the/O forced/O closure/O of/O a/O Muslim/O bazaar/O degenerated/O into/O ethnic/O clashes/O between/O indigenous/O <OTHER>Muslim/PERSON Uyghurs/PERSON</OTHER> and/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
During/O the/O unrest/O ,/O about/O 200/O people/O were/O killed/O and/O 1,600/O were/O injured/O before/O police/O and/O the/O army/O were/O able/O to/O clamp/O down/O and/O arrest/O thousands/O of/O people/O ./O 
Uyghurs/O accuse/O Han/O Chinese/O of/O colonising/O their/O country/O ,/O monopolising/O commerce/O and/O the/O public/O administration/O 
For/O decades/O ,/O indigenous/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/PERSON</OTHER> have/O suffered/O under/O heavy-handed/O Chinese/O military/O control/O ./O 
The/O energy-rich/O province/O is/O strategically/O located/O and/O China/LOCATION 's/O military/O is/O ubiquitous/O ,/O preventing/O locals/O from/O exercising/O their/O civil/O liberties/O and/O enjoying/O religious/O freedom/O ,/O often/O done/O in/O the/O name/O of/O the/O fight/O against/O Islamic/O terrorism/O ./O
