In/O order/O to/O hold/O back/O separatism/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O the/O homeland/O of/O Turkic-speaking/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uyghurs/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O forcing/O young/O Uyghurs/PERSON to/O study/O far/O from/O home/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O it/O is/O preventing/O them/O from/O praying/O or/O fasting/O for/O Ramadan/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O --/O 
School/O authorities/O have/O expelled/O two/O Muslim/O Uyghur/O students/O in/O the/O eastern/O province/O of/O Zhejiang/LOCATION because/O they/O were/O involved/O ``/O in/O illegal/O religious/O activities/O ''/O ./O 
They/O were/O attending/O a/O high/O school/O linked/O to/O the/O Hangzhou/ORGANIZATION Normal/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION and/O were/O thrown/O out/O because/O they/O were/O caught/O attending/O a/O Muslim/O prayer/O ./O 
``/O The/O school/O said/O that/O they/O had/O been/O engaged/O in/O illegal/O religious/O activities/O ,/O ''/O an/O overseas/O Uyghur/O website/O reported/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O students/O was/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Ili/LOCATION Prefecture/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O the/O other/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Shache/LOCATION County/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Their/O place/O of/O origin/O is/O important/O because/O it/O shows/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O trying/O to/O re-educate/O Uyghurs/O ,/O this/O according/O to/O <U_PERSON>Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O representative/O for/O the/O Munich-based/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Most/O Uyghurs/O ,/O who/O are/O predominantly/O Muslim/O and/O Turkic/O in/O language/O ,/O live/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ./O 
Local/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O been/O forcibly/O sending/O students/O to/O other/O parts/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O province/O itself/O has/O been/O the/O scene/O of/O anti-Han/O Chinese/O demonstrations/O and/O unrest/O ./O 
Uyghur/O students/O have/O been/O denied/O the/O right/O to/O participate/O in/O religious/O activities/O ,/O including/O celebrations/O based/O on/O their/O calendar/O ./O 
When/O they/O do/O ,/O their/O parents/O have/O been/O given/O steep/O fines/O ./O 
This/O is/O true/O for/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> as/O well/O ./O 
``/O Every/O year/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> there/O are/O high/O school/O students/O who/O are/O expelled/O from/O school/O ,/O ''/O <U_PERSON>Raxit/PERSON</U_PERSON> said/O ,/O because/O they/O fast/O ``/O during/O -LSB-/O the/O Muslim/O holy/O month/O of/O -RSB-/O Ramadan/O ''/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O Communist/O government/O is/O very/O concerned/O about/O the/O Uyghurs/O ,/O who/O are/O about/O 16/O million/O and/O connected/O by/O language/O and/O religion/O to/O other/O Central/O Asian/O peoples/O ./O 
Despite/O their/O incorporation/O into/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION ,/O they/O have/O never/O accepted/O their/O total/O subordination/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Like/O in/O other/O sensitive/O regions/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O undertaken/O a/O policy/O of/O demographic/O colonisation/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O homeland/O ./O 
Han/O Chinese/O ,/O who/O were/O just/O 6/O per/O cent/O of/O the/O population/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O 1949/O ,/O now/O constitutes/O 40/O per/O cent/O ./O 
In/O the/O regional/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O they/O are/O actually/O 80/O per/O cent/O ./O
