Despite/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O announced/O reforms/O ,/O the/O authorities/O continue/O to/O abuse/O women/O in/O the/O name/O of/O family/O planning/O ./O 
One/O woman/O managed/O to/O escape/O ,/O whilst/O the/O others/O received/O or/O will/O receive/O treatment/O ./O 
``/O My/O son/O was/O crying/O when/O he/O was/O born/O ,/O ''/O one/O man/O said/O ,/O but/O ``/O the/O abortion/O drug/O -LSB-/O .../O -RSB-/O had/O already/O been/O injected/O ''/O and/O he/O ``/O died/O an/O hour/O after/O he/O was/O born/O ./O ''/O 
Local/O authorities/O confirm/O the/O facts/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O 
The/O authorities/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O predominantly/O Muslim/O Uyghur/O northwestern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> planned/O to/O force/O six/O native/O women/O to/O undergo/O an/O abortion/O for/O ``/O violating/O ''/O the/O government/O 's/O one-child/O policy/O ./O 
Despite/O the/O new/O policy/O by/O the/O central/O government/O ,/O easing/O the/O one-child/O policy/O ,/O doctors/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Hotan/LOCATION Prefecture/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> injected/O the/O women/O with/O a/O drug/O to/O induce/O miscarriage/O ./O 
``/O We/O had/O planned/O to/O perform/O forced/O abortions/O on/O six/O women/O ./O 
Four/O of/O them/O have/O already/O undergone/O the/O abortions/O ,/O ''/O said/O <U_PERSON>Momin/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O deputy/O chief/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Hotan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O <U_LOCATION>Arish/LOCATION Township/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
``/O One/O more/O woman/O is/O waiting/O in/O hospital/O to/O undergo/O the/O abortion/O while/O another/O woman/O has/O escaped/O before/O undergoing/O the/O process/O ,/O ''/O <U_PERSON>Momin/PERSON</U_PERSON> added/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Awat/PERSON Han/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O head/O of/O the/O family/O planning/O department/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Arish/LOCATION Township/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O told/O RFA/ORGANIZATION that/O four/O forced/O abortions/O were/O carried/O out/O over/O the/O last/O week/O ,/O saying/O she/O was/O only/O following/O orders/O from/O higher/O authorities/O ./O 
In/O November/O ,/O the/O Plenum/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION announced/O reforms/O in/O family/O planning/O ./O 
Under/O the/O new/O rules/O ,/O formally/O approved/O by/O the/O Standing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION <OTHER>of/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> <OTHER>the/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION on/O 28/O December/O ,/O couples/O who/O are/O only/O children/O can/O have/O two/O children/O ./O 
When/O it/O comes/O to/O national/O minorities/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O demographic/O policies/O has/O not/O changed/O ;/O minority/O couples/O can/O have/O two/O children/O under/O certain/O circumstances/O ./O 
Although/O ``/O My/O wife/O was/O injected/O by/O a/O doctor/O ,/O ''/O said/O <U_PERSON>Memettursun/PERSON Kawul/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O the/O husband/O of/O one/O of/O the/O women/O forced/O to/O abort/O ,/O ``/O My/O son/O was/O crying/O when/O he/O was/O born/O ./O ''/O 
When/O he/O heard/O the/O cries/O of/O his/O son/O and/O wife/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Kawul/PERSON</U_PERSON> then/O stormed/O into/O the/O delivery/O room/O ,/O grabbed/O the/O baby/O and/O took/O him/O to/O a/O nearby/O hospital/O in/O a/O bid/O to/O save/O him/O ./O 
``/O The/O doctors/O in/O the/O hospital/O tried/O to/O save/O him/O but/O they/O failed/O ,/O citing/O the/O abortion/O drug/O that/O had/O already/O been/O injected/O ./O 
My/O son/O died/O an/O hour/O after/O he/O was/O born/O ./O ''/O
