Mosul/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O --/O 
More/O and/O more/O Asian/O fighters/O speaking/O Chinese/O are/O seen/O in/O the/O streets/O of/O Mosul/LOCATION ,/O jihadi/O Uighur/O mercenaries/O who/O came/O to/O Syria/LOCATION through/O Turkey/LOCATION at/O the/O start/O of/O the/O war/O ./O 
In/O the/O last/O few/O months/O ,/O they/O and/O their/O families/O have/O moved/O from/O Rakka/LOCATION in/O Syria/LOCATION --/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/LOCATION State/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> 's/O capital/O --/O to/O Iraq/LOCATION ./O 
In/O April/O 2015/O ,/O many/O of/O them/O went/O from/O Turkey/LOCATION to/O Azerbaijan/LOCATION to/O attack/O targets/O in/O Nagorno/LOCATION Karabakh/LOCATION in/O what/O came/O to/O be/O known/O as/O the/O `/O Four-day/O War/O '/O ./O 
Armenian/O intelligence/O informed/O the/O <LOCATION>West/O</LOCATION> and/O Russia/LOCATION that/O Uyghur/O ,/O Turkmen/O and/O Chechen/O fighters/O left/O Azerbaijan/LOCATION for/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
<OTHER>Dubbed/PERSON</OTHER> <ORGANIZATION>Daesh/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> 's/O police/O ,/O the/O Uyghurs/O can/O be/O seen/O everywhere/O in/O Mosul/LOCATION ./O 
Deployed/O in/O markets/O ,/O intersections/O ,/O and/O government/O buildings/O ,/O their/O task/O is/O to/O police/O the/O capital/O of/O the/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION Caliphate/ORGANIZATION ./O 
According/O to/O information/O from/O Mosul/LOCATION ,/O <OTHER>Caliph/PERSON</OTHER> al-Baghdadi/PERSON also/O gave/O Uyghurs/O the/O important/O mission/O of/O securing/O the/O plains/O lying/O to/O the/O right/O of/O Mosul/LOCATION ./O 
For/O years/O ,/O Turkey/LOCATION has/O backed/O Turkic-speaking/O Muslim/O Uyghurs/O in/O their/O struggle/O to/O secede/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
It/O is/O also/O common/O knowledge/O that/O Ankara/LOCATION brought/O in/O and/O trained/O Uyghurs/O fighters/O before/O sending/O them/O to/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
Now/O the/O Uyghurs/O have/O ``/O voluntarily/O ''/O moved/O from/O Syria/LOCATION to/O Iraq/LOCATION with/O <ORGANIZATION>Daesh/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> at/O a/O time/O when/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O as/O its/O only/O supporter/O ,/O threatens/O to/O participate/O in/O the/O ground/O assault/O to/O free/O Mosul/LOCATION from/O <ORGANIZATION>Daesh/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> ,/O ``/O which/O has/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O Islam/O ./O ''/O 
Two/O days/O ago/O ,/O Turkish/O foreign/O minister/O Mevlüt/PERSON Çavuşoğlu/PERSON ,/O who/O also/O said/O that/O <ORGANIZATION>Daesh/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> has/O ``/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O Islam/O ''/O ,/O noted/O that/O ``/O We/O are/O fighting/O armed/O men/O from/O dozens/O of/O countries/O who/O joined/O <ORGANIZATION>Daesh/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O ./O 
Scores/O of/O reports/O suggest/O however/O that/O Turkey/LOCATION has/O allowed/O jihadist/O fighters/O and/O weapons/O to/O enter/O Syria/LOCATION and/O ,/O through/O the/O latter/O ,/O Iraq/LOCATION ./O 
Iraqi/O Popular/O Forces/O Commander/O Karim/PERSON Al/PERSON Nuri/PERSON ,/O told/O a/O Pan-Arab/ORGANIZATION television/O network/O that/O ``/O we/O shall/O liberate/O Mosul/LOCATION with/O Iraqi/O groups/O ''/O and/O that/O ``/O we/O can/O not/O allow/O Mosul/LOCATION to/O become/O a/O platform/O for/O Turkish/O President/O Erdogan/PERSON 's/O ambitions/O ./O ''/O 
Nuri/PERSON was/O referring/O to/O statements/O by/O the/O Turkish/O president/O announcing/O a/O few/O days/O ago/O that/O Turkey/LOCATION would/O take/O part/O in/O the/O offensive/O against/O the/O jihadists/O of/O the/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O in/O Mosul/LOCATION ./O 
According/O to/O Erdogan/PERSON ,/O only/O ``/O Sunni/O Arabs/O and/O Kurds/O ,/O and/O Turkmen/O ''/O should/O remain/O in/O Mosul/LOCATION ./O 
Speaking/O on/O the/O matter/O ,/O Nuri/PERSON welcome/O international/O efforts/O in/O favour/O of/O Iraq/LOCATION but/O stressed/O that/O ``/O Turkey/LOCATION 's/O -LRB-/O military/O -RRB-/O intervention/O in/O Iraq/LOCATION is/O a/O violation/O of/O international/O law/O ''/O ./O 
In/O view/O of/O this/O ,/O he/O called/O on/O the/O Turkish/O president/O to/O change/O plans/O ,/O describing/O ``/O Turkish/O presence/O in/O Iraq/LOCATION is/O no/O different/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>Daesh/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> occupation/O ''/O ./O 
``/O We/O want/O to/O liberate/O Mosul/LOCATION and/O reiterate/O its/O Arab/O character/O ./O 
Those/O who/O think/O they/O can/O act/O as/O guardians/O of/O Turkmen/O ''/O are/O mistaken/O ./O 
``/O Turkmen/O are/O Iraqi/O citizens/O ,/O and/O we/O shall/O not/O allow/O them/O to/O become/O someone/O 's/O else/O pawns/O ./O ''/O 
-LRB-/O P.B./O -RRB-/O
