Official/O media/O say/O that/O mass/O social/O unrest/O has/O increased/O in/O 2009/O ,/O despite/O tighter/O security/O measures/O and/O greater/O police/O deployment/O ./O 
Ordinary/O Chinese/O increasingly/O resort/O to/O street/O protests/O to/O demand/O justice/O because/O of/O the/O absence/O of/O legal/O means/O to/O protect/O their/O rights/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O 
Mass/O incidents/O involving/O more/O than/O 500/O people/O jumped/O in/O the/O first/O half/O of/O this/O year/O for/O the/O first/O time/O since/O 2005/O ,/O a/O trend/O that/O comes/O at/O a/O time/O when/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O tightening/O security/O measures/O ahead/O of/O next/O 1/O October/O ,/O 60th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O founding/O of/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O information/O was/O reported/O in/O Outlook/O ,/O a/O reliable/O Xinhua-affiliated/O magazine/O to/O explain/O this/O year/O 's/O unprecedented/O security/O measures/O ./O 
The/O report/O did/O not/O contain/O any/O data/O about/O the/O problem/O ,/O but/O a/O commonly/O cited/O figure/O was/O 80,000/O incidents/O last/O year/O ,/O a/O 10-fold/O jump/O from/O 1993/O ./O 
Even/O though/O the/O government/O has/O not/O released/O any/O detailed/O information/O about/O the/O problem/O ,/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Outlook/O</ORGANIZATION> article/O blames/O it/O on/O unequal/O distribution/O of/O wealth/O ,/O the/O dearth/O of/O social/O services/O -LRB-/O like/O health/O care/O and/O workers/O '/O compensation/O -RRB-/O and/O widespread/O corruption/O ./O 
Analysts/O note/O that/O unrest/O is/O also/O due/O to/O the/O lack/O of/O institutional/O safety/O valves/O that/O allow/O people/O to/O voice/O their/O dissent/O ,/O report/O corruption/O or/O obtain/O justice/O ./O 
In/O a/O country/O where/O the/O authorities/O are/O unwilling/O to/O accept/O any/O criticism/O and/O the/O justice/O system/O is/O entirely/O subordinated/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O anyone/O filing/O a/O petition/O can/O be/O arrested/O or/O sent/O back/O home/O ./O 
For/O many/O communities/O the/O only/O way/O to/O vent/O their/O frustration/O is/O to/O take/O to/O the/O streets/O to/O protest/O and/O loudly/O denounce/O injustices/O in/O the/O tiny/O hope/O the/O authorities/O might/O listen/O ./O 
In/O fact/O this/O worked/O for/O residents/O living/O near/O polluting/O plants/O who/O protested/O vociferously/O in/O July/O and/O August/O in/O defence/O of/O their/O children/O 's/O health/O ./O 
However/O ,/O such/O a/O situation/O also/O explains/O why/O social/O unrest/O continues/O unabated/O despite/O the/O state/O apparatus/O tightening/O its/O screws/O ./O 
Increasingly/O the/O authorities/O seemed/O unable/O to/O enforce/O law/O and/O order/O and/O have/O to/O resort/O to/O more/O drastic/O measures/O ./O 
for/O example/O ,/O in/O some/O areas/O of/O Yunnan/LOCATION province/O ,/O tourists/O have/O been/O barred/O after/O a/O drunken/O policeman/O was/O killed/O during/O brawl/O in/O a/O karaoke/O bar/O in/O Shangri-La/LOCATION County/LOCATION ,/O a/O traditional/O tourist/O Mecca/O ./O 
Hong/O Kong-based/O Information/ORGANIZATION Centre/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Democracy/ORGANIZATION reported/O that/O thousands/O of/O police/O and/O many/O armoured/O vehicles/O were/O sent/O in/O afterwards/O but/O the/O authorities/O still/O felt/O unable/O to/O provide/O security/O and/O thus/O chose/O instead/O to/O keep/O out/O tourists/O ./O 
This/O will/O also/O be/O even/O more/O the/O case/O for/O 1/O October/O celebrations/O when/O stronger/O measures/O than/O those/O adopted/O for/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympics/O will/O be/O implemented/O ./O 
During/O last/O year/O 's/O Games/O Beijing/LOCATION was/O divided/O into/O three/O security/O rings/O ;/O this/O year/O it/O will/O have/O four/O rings/O ,/O and/O layers/O of/O security/O forces/O will/O be/O extended/O to/O six/O provinces/O and/O municipalities/O around/O the/O capital/O ./O 
In/O addition/O to/O points/O inside/O Beijing/LOCATION road/O blocks/O will/O be/O set/O up/O on/O every/O road/O leading/O into/O the/O capital/O from/O Hebei/LOCATION ,/O Shandong/LOCATION ,/O Shanxi/LOCATION ,/O Liaonig/LOCATION ,/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION and/O Tianjin/LOCATION ./O 
Anyone/O planning/O to/O visit/O the/O city/O will/O need/O special/O identity/O papers/O ./O 
Experts/O suggest/O that/O such/O controls/O appear/O more/O geared/O toward/O keeping/O potential/O protesters/O out/O of/O the/O city/O than/O preventing/O attacks/O or/O threats/O to/O public/O safety/O at/O a/O time/O when/O the/O world/O media/O will/O focus/O on/O what/O are/O expected/O to/O be/O grandiose/O celebrations/O ./O 
This/O is/O also/O the/O case/O for/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> where/O the/O authorities/O have/O imposed/O tight/O controls/O on/O the/O population/O to/O prevent/O any/O social/O disturbances/O ./O 
For/O an/O unspecified/O ``/O security/O reasons/O ''/O the/O authorities/O have/O also/O demolished/O a/O shopping/O centre/O built/O by/O exiled/O Uyghur/O dissident/O ,/O businesswoman/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O which/O can/O hold/O 500/O stores/O ./O 
Xinhua/ORGANIZATION reported/O that/O other/O buildings/O in/O the/O area/O are/O also/O slated/O for/O demolition/O ./O
