Two/O sons/O and/O a/O brother/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O leader/O have/O appeared/O on/O television/O reciting/O Chinese/O criticism/O against/O her/O :/O inciter/O of/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> revolts/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> separatist/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O criticized/O all/O the/O countries/O that/O sympathize/O with/O her/O :/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O Australia/LOCATION ,/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Beijing/LOCATION wants/O to/O impose/O its/O authoritarianism/O throughout/O the/O world/O ./O ''/O 
Melbourne/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
The/O Uyghur/O leader/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> has/O accused/O the/O Chinese/O government/O of/O ``/O psychologically/O torturing/O ''/O her/O children/O ,/O who/O have/O written/O open/O letters/O criticizing/O their/O mother/O ,/O and/O even/O appeared/O on/O national/O television/O to/O accuse/O her/O of/O having/O instigated/O Uyghur/O 's/O revolt/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> last/O July/O ./O 
Speaking/O with/O journalists/O ,/O the/O Uyghur/O leader/O said/O her/O daughter/O <U_PERSON>Roxingul/PERSON</U_PERSON> and/O her/O son/O <U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON</U_PERSON> were/O forced/O to/O accuse/O her/O ,/O and/O bend/O to/O the/O will/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION :/O ``/O The/O method/O being/O used/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O is/O perhaps/O the/O worst/O kind/O of/O violence/O against/O my/O children/O !/O 
to/O force/O them/O to/O speak/O against/O me/O .../O I/O think/O that/O this/O is/O a/O form/O of/O dictatorship/O imposed/O on/O them/O ''/O ./O 
Two/O days/O ago/O ,/O in/O the/O early/O evening/O the/O children/O and/O the/O brother/O of/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> appeared/O on/O national/O television/O news/O ./O 
``/O The/O road/O my/O mother/O has/O chosen/O leads/O to/O a/O bottomless/O hole/O ,/O ''/O said/O her/O son/O <U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O 33/O ,/O in/O prison/O for/O tax/O evasion/O ./O 
``/O With/O such/O a/O strong/O nation/O -LSB-/O China/LOCATION -RSB-/O ,/O she/O will/O fail/O in/O her/O project/O of/O separatism/O ./O ''/O 
A/O day/O before/O the/O Chinese/O media/O gave/O extensive/O space/O to/O an/O open/O letter/O by/O her/O children/O as/O they/O repeated/O the/O same/O accusations/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O laid/O against/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> :/O of/O being/O the/O cause/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O revolt/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O wanting/O to/O divide/O the/O nation/O ./O 
The/O revolts/O began/O on/O July/O 5/O ,/O then/O degenerated/O into/O ethnic/O clashes/O between/O Muslim/O Uyghurs/O and/O Chinese/O Han/O ,/O which/O led/O to/O the/O deaths/O of/O at/O least/O 197/O people/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O detained/O thousands/O of/O Uyghurs/LOCATION ,/O but/O according/O to/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ``/O in/O one/O night/O ''/O at/O least/O 10/O thousand/O people/O went/O missing/O ./O 
``/O It/O 's/O hard/O for/O me/O to/O imagine/O what/O kind/O of/O psychological/O torture/O they/O are/O going/O through/O right/O now/O ,/O ''/O said/O the/O Uyghur/O leader/O ./O 
``/O When/O I/O was/O in/O prison/O ,/O I/O was/O also/O forced/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O say/O things/O against/O my/O will/O ,/O in/O a/O video/O posted/O on/O a/O website/O ./O ''/O 
62/O year/O old/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O once/O a/O successful/O businesswoman/O and/O member/O of/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O fell/O into/O disgrace/O when/O she/O began/O to/O seek/O more/O rights/O and/O autonomy/O for/O the/O Uyghur/O criticizing/O the/O government/O 's/O policy/O of/O colonization/O ./O 
For/O this/O she/O was/O imprisoned/O for/O 5/O years/O ./O 
Released/O in/O 2005/O thanks/O to/O international/O pressure/O ,/O she/O now/O lives/O in/O exile/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O is/O a/O member/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uygur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ./O 
After/O a/O visit/O to/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O she/O has/O recently/O arrived/O in/O Melbourne/LOCATION to/O attend/O the/O International/O Film/O Festival/O ,/O where/O a/O documentary/O about/O her/O life/O will/O be/O shown/O for/O the/O first/O time/O ./O 
China/LOCATION initially/O tried/O to/O remove/O the/O film/O from/O the/O program/O ,/O then/O ,/O faced/O with/O a/O no/O from/O organizers/O ,/O withdrew/O all/O Chinese/O films/O ./O 
In/O the/O preceding/O weeks/O Beijing/LOCATION also/O criticized/O Japan/LOCATION for/O having/O given/O an/O entry/O visa/O to/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> and/O reproached/O Turkey/LOCATION for/O having/O defended/O the/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION -/O said/O the/O Uyghur/O leaders/O -/O has/O also/O put/O pressure/O on/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION to/O curb/O my/O activities/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O because/O of/O me/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O is/O trying/O in/O practice/O to/O impose/O its/O authoritarianism/O throughout/O the/O world/O ./O ''/O
