Phnom/LOCATION Penh/LOCATION considers/O them/O illegal/O immigrants/O and/O orders/O their/O return/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O group/O ,/O which/O escaped/O in/O July/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O sought/O political/O asylum/O in/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION <ORGANIZATION>'s/O Office/O</ORGANIZATION> in/O the/O capital/O ./O 
Human/O rights/O activists/O warn/O that/O if/O they/O return/O to/O China/LOCATION they/O will/O be/O tortured/O and/O killed/O ./O 
<LOCATION>Phnom/O Penh/O</LOCATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
The/O Cambodian/O government/O has/O ordered/O the/O deportation/O of/O 20/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O Chinese/O ,/O who/O fled/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O July/O during/O the/O crackdown/O against/O the/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O ./O 
They/O are/O charged/O with/O ``/O illegally/O ''/O crossing/O the/O border/O and/O will/O be/O sent/O back/O ./O 
The/O decision/O bows/O to/O pressure/O from/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O had/O branded/O the/O refugees/O ``/O criminals/O ./O ''/O 
In/O recent/O weeks/O the/O group/O had/O illegally/O entered/O Cambodia/LOCATION ,/O asking/O for/O political/O asylum/O at/O the/O office/O of/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION in/O Phnom/LOCATION Penh/LOCATION ./O 
The/O government/O ,/O under/O the/O immigration/O laws/O ,/O has/O ordered/O their/O expulsion/O ./O 
``/O They/O have/O no/O passports/O or/O permits/O -/O said/O Koy/PERSON Kuong/PERSON ,/O spokesman/O for/O the/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION -/O which/O is/O why/O we/O consider/O them/O illegal/O ./O ''/O 
He/O adds/O that/O he/O does/O not/O know/O ``/O where/O they/O will/O be/O sent/O ''/O ,/O but/O their/O ``/O final/O destination/O will/O be/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O place/O where/O they/O come/O from/O ''/O ./O 
Human/O rights/O activists/O fear/O for/O the/O lives/O of/O 20/O refugees/O ,/O if/O returned/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Amy/PERSON Reger/PERSON ,/O a/O researcher/O at/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Uyghur/ORGANIZATION American/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> in/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O explains/O that/O they/O will/O face/O ``/O a/O terrible/O fate/O ,/O possible/O execution/O and/O likely/O torture/O ''/O ./O 
The/O activist/O recalls/O the/O case/O of/O <U_PERSON>Shaheer/PERSON Ali/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O who/O fled/O to/O Nepal/LOCATION in/O 2000/O and/O was/O considered/O a/O political/O refugee/O by/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Repatriated/O to/O China/LOCATION in/O 2002/O ,/O he/O was/O executed/O a/O year/O later/O ./O 
Ethnic/O tensions/O exploded/O on/O 5/O July/O when/O a/O peaceful/O Uyghur/O demonstration/O caused/O by/O the/O forced/O closure/O of/O a/O Muslim/O bazaar/O degenerated/O into/O ethnic/O clashes/O between/O indigenous/O <OTHER>Muslim/PERSON Uyghurs/PERSON</OTHER> and/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
During/O the/O unrest/O ,/O about/O 200/O people/O were/O killed/O and/O 1,600/O were/O injured/O before/O police/O and/O the/O army/O were/O able/O to/O clamp/O down/O and/O arrest/O thousands/O of/O people/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O already/O imposed/O 12/O death/O sentences/O against/O the/O alleged/O perpetrators/O of/O the/O rebellion/O ./O 
Uyghurs/O accuse/O Han/O Chinese/O of/O colonising/O their/O country/O ,/O monopolising/O commerce/O and/O the/O public/O administration/O ./O 
They/O prevent/O locals/O from/O exercising/O their/O civil/O liberties/O and/O enjoying/O religious/O freedom/O ,/O often/O done/O in/O the/O name/O of/O the/O fight/O against/O Islamic/O terrorism/O ./O 
./O
