The/O leader/O of/O the/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O comments/O on/O the/O recent/O incidents/O of/O violence/O that/O occurred/O in/O the/O northern/O province/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/</ORGANIZATION>O ,/O ``/O China/LOCATION censors/O the/O independent/O media/O ,/O we/O do/O not/O know/O what/O 's/O going/O on/O ./O 
And/O if/O it/O is/O terrorism/O ,/O then/O it/O is/O to/O be/O condemned/O ./O 
But/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O imposed/O a/O crackdown/O on/O my/O people/O driving/O them/O to/O despair/O :/O it/O is/O its/O own/O fault/O ./O ''/O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O 
``/O I/O do/O not/O advocate/O violence/O ./O 
I/O am/O very/O saddened/O by/O the/O death/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O and/O the/O Uyghurs/O involved/O in/O recent/O clashes/O ./O 
But/O at/O the/O same/O time/O I/O can/O not/O blame/O those/O who/O carried/O out/O the/O attacks/O ,/O who/O were/O compelled/O to/O do/O so/O ,/O made/O desperate/O by/O Chinese/O policies/O ''/O ,/O says/O Uyghur/O ethnic/O leader/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> in/O an/O exclusive/O interview/O with/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> commenting/O on/O the/O recent/O riots/O and/O violence/O that/O rocked/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
The/O latest/O episode/O occurred/O last/O night/O ,/O when/O the/O Chinese/O police/O shot/O two/O Uyghurs/O in/O cold/O blood/O suspected/O of/O being/O involved/O in/O the/O July/O 31/O attack/O that/O caused/O the/O death/O of/O six/O people/O in/O a/O bar/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
The/O two/O -/O <U_PERSON>Memtieli/PERSON Tiliwaldi/PERSON</U_PERSON> -LRB-/O 29/O years/O -RRB-/O and/O <U_PERSON>Turson/PERSON Hasan/PERSON</U_PERSON> -LRB-/O 34/O -RRB-/O -/O were/O killed/O in/O a/O cornfield/O and/O left/O there/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O government/O had/O put/O a/O bounty/O of/O 100/O thousand/O yuan/O -LRB-/O about/O 10/O thousand/O euros/O -RRB-/O for/O their/O capture/O ./O 
Before/O this/O last/O episode/O violent/O attacks/O had/O increased/O in/O the/O city/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Hotan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O in/O the/O provincial/O capital/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
The/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O --/O Turkish/O speaking/O of/O Islamic/O religion/O -/O since/O 1949/O has/O been/O under/O the/O heel/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O which/O in/O turn/O has/O imposed/O a/O series/O of/O extreme/O religious/O and/O cultural/O restrictions/O ./O 
The/O province/O claims/O its/O independence/O and/O instead/O calls/O for/O the/O restoration/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Eastern/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O the/O legitimate/O government/O before/O the/O Maoist/O invasion/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O who/O heads/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O says/O :/O ``/O Without/O independent/O sources/O of/O information/O ,/O we/O do/O not/O know/O if/O these/O things/O are/O true/O ./O 
We/O do/O not/O know/O for/O certain/O who/O carried/O out/O the/O attacks/O and/O what/O kind/O they/O are/O ./O 
If/O it/O was/O terrorism/O the/O it/O should/O be/O condemned/O ,/O but/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O imposed/O a/O smoke/O screen/O on/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> that/O makes/O it/O impossible/O to/O see/O anything/O clearly/O ./O ''/O 
In/O any/O case/O ,/O she/O adds/O ,/O ``/O I/O condemn/O the/O Chinese/O government/O for/O what/O is/O happening/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O deliberately/O created/O an/O atmosphere/O of/O despair/O ,/O convincing/O the/O Uyghurs/O that/O there/O is/O no/O future/O for/O them/O in/O their/O own/O land/O ./O 
It/O is/O Beijing/LOCATION that/O it/O must/O take/O responsibility/O for/O what/O is/O happening/O ,/O because/O it/O is/O its/O mad/O discrimination/O that/O triggers/O violence/O ./O ''/O
