Pakistan/LOCATION President/O Zardari/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O present/O at/O the/O ceremony/O inaugurating/O the/O first/O expo/O set/O for/O 1-5/O September/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O said/O his/O country/O is/O ready/O to/O cooperate/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION against/O Muslim/O extremism/O ./O 
The/O latter/O ,/O however/O ,/O is/O a/O pretext/O to/O crack/O down/O on/O minority/O Muslim/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O main/O airports/O are/O put/O on/O high/O alert/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O 
China/LOCATION 's/O Vice/O Premier/O Li/PERSON Keqiang/PERSON opened/O the/O first/O China-Eurasia/O Expo/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O capital/O of/O the/O northwestern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O which/O is/O set/O to/O last/O from/O 1/O to/O 5/O September/O ./O 
Pakistani/O President/O Asif/PERSON Ali/PERSON Zardari/PERSON ,/O his/O Kyrgyz/O counterpart/O ,/O Roza/PERSON Otunbayeva/PERSON ,/O Azerbaijan/LOCATION 's/O Vice/O Premier/O Abid/PERSON Sharifov/PERSON ,/O and/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION 's/O Deputy/O Prime/O Minister/O Aset/PERSON Isekeshev/PERSON were/O also/O present/O at/O the/O opening/O ceremony/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O have/O increased/O security/O in/O the/O country/O 's/O airports/O and/O tightened/O controls/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O across/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> against/O possible/O attacks/O my/O Muslim/O Uyghur/O separatists/O ./O 
Chinese/O state/O media/O sounded/O the/O alarm/O on/O the/O eve/O of/O the/O expo/O about/O possible/O Uyghur/O attacks/O ./O 
Armed/O <ORGANIZATION>SWAT/O</ORGANIZATION> teams/O and/O baton-wielding/O riot/O police/O are/O patrolling/O the/O provincial/O capital/O ,/O especially/O the/O predominantly/O Uyghur/O old/O part/O of/O the/O city/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION boss/O Zhu/PERSON Hailun/PERSON warned/O ,/O ``/O Separatists/O ,/O religious/O extremists/O and/O terrorists/O have/O been/O plotting/O to/O sabotage/O the/O expo/O ./O ''/O 
Pakistan/LOCATION President/O Zardari/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O at/O the/O expo/O to/O boost/O economic/O ties/O and/O trade/O with/O China/LOCATION ,/O vowed/O to/O work/O with/O China/LOCATION to/O fight/O terrorism/O ./O 
In/O recent/O weeks/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O leaders/O warned/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O guilty/O in/O their/O eyes/O of/O allowing/O terrorist/O training/O in/O its/O territory/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION believes/O that/O Uyghur/O extremists/O come/O back/O home/O to/O cause/O trouble/O or/O carry/O out/O attacks/O ./O 
However/O ,/O only/O a/O small/O minority/O of/O the/O indigenous/O population/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> shares/O their/O view/O ,/O Chinese/O media/O say/O ./O 
Uyghurs/O ,/O a/O Turkic/O Muslim/O group/O ,/O are/O culturally/O closer/O to/O Central/O Asians/O and/O Turks/O than/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O ethnic/O Han/O majority/O ./O 
In/O a/O meeting/O with/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Xinjiang/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> boss/O Zhang/PERSON Chunxian/PERSON ,/O Zardari/PERSON said/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION would/O work/O with/O China/LOCATION in/O the/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O ./O 
However/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O fight/O against/O extremism/O has/O turned/O into/O an/O violent/O crackdown/O against/O an/O already/O persecuted/O minority/O ./O 
In/O mid-August/O ,/O for/O example/O ,/O China/LOCATION with/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O complicity/O repatriated/O five/O ethnic/O Uyghurs/O who/O had/O crossed/O into/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
Early/O on/O 9/O August/O ,/O the/O five/O suspects/O were/O brought/O to/O the/O Benazir/LOCATION Bhutto/LOCATION International/LOCATION Airport/LOCATION where/O they/O boarded/O a/O flight/O for/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
The/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O included/O a/O woman/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Manzokra/PERSON Mamad/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O and/O two/O children/O ,/O a/O girl/O and/O a/O boy/O ,/O dissident/O sources/O said/O ./O
