Tianjin/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O <OTHER>Agencies/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> -RRB-/O -/O 
Protestant/O Christian/O human/O rights/O activist/O ,/O Gou/PERSON Hongguo/PERSON ,/O was/O sentenced/O this/O morning/O to/O three/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O attempting/O to/O ``/O subvert/O state/O power/O ''/O ./O 
The/O sentence/O was/O suspended/O for/O three/O years/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O indictment/O ,/O Gou/PERSON -/O who/O was/O part/O of/O Hu/PERSON Shigen/PERSON 's/O community/O ,/O also/O sentenced/O days/O before/O -/O took/O part/O in/O a/O meeting/O of/O interracial/O leaders/O in/O Taiwan/LOCATION ./O 
There/O were/O supporters/O of/O independence/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION ./O 
The/O prosecutor/O acknowledged/O that/O the/O meeting/O wanted/O to/O implement/O a/O non-violent/O resistance/O and/O push/O for/O social/O and/O democratic/O change/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
But/O this/O entails/O an/O end/O to/O the/O supremacy/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O led/O to/O the/O charge/O of/O ``/O subversion/O ''/O ./O 
Gou/PERSON was/O also/O accused/O of/O having/O associated/O with/O protests/O related/O to/O workers/O '/O rights/O ,/O that/O challenge/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION rule/O ./O 
The/O arguments/O of/O the/O defense/O ,/O that/O Gou/PERSON had/O gone/O to/O Taiwan/LOCATION without/O knowing/O who/O the/O guests/O were/O and/O on/O his/O return/O did/O not/O publish/O any/O information/O about/O the/O gathering/O ,/O were/O to/O no/O avail/O ./O 
The/O defense/O lawyer/O also/O noted/O that/O the/O meeting/O only/O involved/O 15/O people/O and/O Gou/PERSON had/O a/O marginal/O role/O ./O 
Gou/PERSON 's/O ruling/O is/O the/O latest/O of/O four/O ,/O which/O took/O place/O this/O week/O against/O human/O rights/O lawyers/O and/O activists/O arrested/O in/O July/O 2015/O ./O 
Yesterday/O Zhou/PERSON Shifeng/PERSON ,/O the/O former/O director/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Fengrui/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> law/O firm/O ,/O was/O also/O sentenced/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>Fengrui/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> took/O on/O about/O 100/O lawyers/O and/O handled/O many/O sensitive/O cases/O :/O it/O represented/O the/O victims/O of/O the/O scandal/O of/O the/O melamine/O milk/O ;/O the/O artist/O <PERSON>Ai/O Weiwei/O</PERSON> ;/O the/O blind/O activist/O Chen/PERSON Guangcheng/PERSON ,/O now/O in/O exile/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ;/O the/O Christian/O lawyer/O Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON ;/O Uighur/O academic/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ./O 
The/O court/O ruled/O that/O Zhou/PERSON has/O repeatedly/O expressed/O comments/O online/O and/O in/O person/O ``/O attacking/O the/O socialist/O system/O ,/O the/O one/O country/O two/O systems/O policy/O -LSB-/O that/O exists/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION -RSB-/O ,/O and/O incited/O people/O to/O go/O against/O state/O power/O ''/O ./O 
His/O trial/O ended/O with/O an/O ironic/O scene/O :/O Zhou/PERSON spoke/O for/O 10/O minutes/O ,/O then/O stopped/O by/O the/O judges/O ./O 
He/O ``/O apologized/O to/O all/O 90/O million/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ''/O and/O the/O government/O ,/O adding/O that/O ``/O the/O legal/O system/O and/O democracy/O in/O China/LOCATION is/O greater/O than/O that/O of/O the/O state/O of/O Western/O law/O and/O above/O all/O far/O beyond/O that/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ''/O ./O
