German/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON kicked/O off/O a/O state/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION with/O a/O stop/O at/O a/O Daimler/ORGANIZATION joint-venture/O there/O ./O 
Economic/O ties/O ,/O but/O also/O human/O rights/O and/O global/O warming/O ,/O were/O on/O the/O meeting/O agenda/O ,/O advisers/O said/O ./O 
At/O the/O start/O of/O her/O trip/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Merkel/PERSON spoke/O of/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O interest/O in/O creating/O ``/O solid/O German-Chinese/O economic/O ties/O ,/O ''/O and/O held/O up/O the/O Daimler-Chinese/O cooperation/O as/O an/O example/O ./O 
Merkel/PERSON was/O at/O Daimler/ORGANIZATION for/O the/O celebration/O of/O the/O 25,000/O th/O Daimler/ORGANIZATION car/O to/O roll/O off/O the/O production/O line/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ;/O she/O was/O set/O to/O meet/O Chinese/O Premier/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON in/O the/O afternoon/O of/O Thursday/O ,/O Oct./O 23/O ,/O for/O talks/O that/O are/O expected/O to/O focus/O on/O the/O global/O financial/O crisis/O ./O 
The/O two/O leaders/O will/O then/O join/O some/O 40/O other/O heads/O of/O state/O at/O the/O biannual/O Asia-Europe/O Meeting/O -LRB-/O ASEM/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O on/O Friday/O and/O Saturday/O ./O 
Merkel/PERSON visit/O stresses/O importance/O of/O ties/O Merkel/PERSON feted/O the/O successful/O automobile/O cooperation/O German/O officials/O said/O the/O fact/O that/O Merkel/PERSON was/O one/O of/O the/O few/O foreign/O leaders/O making/O a/O formal/O state/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION for/O the/O ASEM/ORGANIZATION summit/O showed/O the/O importance/O of/O ties/O between/O the/O two/O nations/O ./O 
The/O world/O financial/O crisis/O ,/O and/O global/O warming/O ,/O are/O expected/O to/O be/O the/O main/O focal/O points/O of/O the/O ASEM/ORGANIZATION summit/O ,/O which/O groups/O 27/O European/O and/O 16/O Asian/O nations/O ./O 
Merkel/PERSON is/O scheduled/O to/O meet/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON on/O Friday/O ./O 
Her/O talks/O with/O Chinese/O leaders/O will/O deal/O with/O bilateral/O political/O and/O economic/O ties/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION 's/O heavily/O disputed/O atomic/O program/O ,/O and/O relations/O with/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O German/O politicians/O told/O reporters/O ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O Merkel/PERSON will/O meet/O with/O non-politicians/O such/O as/O journalists/O and/O writers/O ./O 
The/O trip/O to/O China/LOCATION is/O Merkel/PERSON 's/O fist/O since/O she/O met/O with/O Tibetan/O spiritual/O leader/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O last/O year/O ,/O which/O led/O to/O strained/O ties/O between/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O Berlin/LOCATION ./O 
Calls/O for/O discussion/O on/O human/O rights/O Green/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION politician/O Volker/PERSON Beck/PERSON told/O AFP/ORGANIZATION news/O service/O that/O he/O hoped/O Merkel/PERSON would/O bring/O up/O the/O ``/O continuing/O poor/O state/O of/O human/O rights/O ''/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O urged/O her/O not/O to/O let/O the/O subject/O be/O overshadowed/O by/O talks/O of/O the/O financial/O crisis/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O two/O other/O human-rights/O groups/O appealed/O to/O Merkel/PERSON to/O use/O the/O meetings/O to/O address/O human-rights/O issues/O ,/O specifically/O the/O situation/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Tibetan/O and/O Uighur/O minorities/O ./O 
Merkel/PERSON should/O press/O China/LOCATION for/O ``/O tangible/O results/O from/O the/O dialogue/O between/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O 's/O representatives/O and/O Chinese/O officials/O ,/O ''/O Kate/PERSON Saunders/PERSON ,/O communications/O director/O of/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Campaign/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Tibet/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O dpa/O press/O agency/O ./O 
Merkel/PERSON 's/O 2007/O meeting/O with/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON shook/O China/LOCATION relations/O And/O a/O European-based/O group/O representing/O China/LOCATION 's/O mainly/O Muslim/O Uighur/O urged/O the/O German/O leader/O to/O press/O China/LOCATION to/O allow/O international/O investigation/O of/O claims/O that/O Uighurs/O were/O involved/O in/O several/O plots/O to/O attack/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympic/O Games/O in/O August/O ./O 
Relations/O back/O to/O normal/O after/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON visit/O Thomas/PERSON Steg/PERSON ,/O a/O deputy/O spokesman/O for/O Merkel/PERSON ,/O told/O dpa/O that/O the/O chancellor/O would/O indeed/O raise/O human/O rights/O issues/O during/O her/O China/LOCATION visit/O ./O 
``/O She/O 'll/O bring/O it/O up/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
Ruprecht/PERSON Polenz/PERSON ,/O a/O foreign/O affairs/O spokesman/O for/O Merkel/PERSON 's/O party/O ,/O the/O Christian/ORGANIZATION Democratic/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ,/O insisted/O that/O China-Germany/O relations/O were/O back/O to/O normal/O after/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O displeasure/O at/O Merkel/PERSON meeting/O in/O her/O office/O last/O year/O with/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ./O 
But/O Polenz/PERSON ,/O who/O chairs/O the/O parliamentary/O committee/O on/O foreign/O policy/O ,/O acknowledged/O that/O ``/O human/O rights/O remain/O a/O problem/O issue/O ./O ''/O 
He/O called/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O grant/O greater/O autonomy/O to/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
