A/O deadly/O mortar/O attack/O in/O northwestern/O China/LOCATION has/O stirred/O up/O fear/O of/O attacks/O during/O the/O Olympic/O Games/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O whether/O the/O Games/O are/O really/O in/O danger/O is/O a/O highly/O disputed/O matter/O ./O 
According/O to/O Chinese/O authorities/O ,/O the/O attack/O in/O the/O Muslim/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O which/O killed/O 16/O police/O officers/O on/O Monday/O ,/O Aug./O 4/O ,/O was/O carried/O out/O by/O terrorists/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O second/O attack/O of/O this/O kind/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION in/O the/O past/O two/O weeks/O ./O 
Now/O the/O question/O is/O :/O How/O concerned/O should/O the/O world/O be/O of/O an/O attack/O during/O the/O Olympics/O ./O 
Terrorism/O is/O the/O biggest/O threat/O during/O the/O Games/O ,/O Rohan/PERSON Gunaratna/PERSON ,/O one/O of/O Singapore/LOCATION 's/O most/O prominent/O terrorism/O experts/O ,/O told/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION dailyStraits/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Head/O of/O the/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Violence/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Terrorism/ORGANIZATION Research/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O Nanyang/ORGANIZATION Technological/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O Gunaratna/PERSON said/O the/O Olympic/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION categorizes/O al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O ETIM/O -RRB-/O ,/O Tibetan/O separatists/O and/O the/O Falun/ORGANIZATION Gong/ORGANIZATION sects/O as/O threats/O ./O 
Gunaratna/PERSON said/O he/O believes/O the/O ETIM/ORGANIZATION poses/O the/O biggest/O threat/O ./O 
That/O group/O was/O blamed/O for/O Monday/O 's/O attack/O by/O theChina/O Daily/O newspaper/O ./O 
The/O Beijing/LOCATION fortress/O The/O attack/O took/O place/O in/O the/O most/O western/O reaches/O of/O the/O country/O Other/O political/O observers/O warned/O against/O lapsing/O into/O panic/O or/O dramatizing/O the/O danger/O to/O the/O Games/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Chinese/O capital/O can/O be/O compared/O to/O a/O fortress/O ,/O and/O that/O the/O danger/O of/O an/O attack/O is/O therefore/O remote/O ,/O according/O to/O East/O Asian/O expert/O Xuewu/PERSON Gu/PERSON ./O 
Xuewu/PERSON added/O that/O the/O most/O dangerous/O groups/O are/O not/O in/O a/O position/O to/O stage/O an/O attack/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION because/O they/O are/O being/O forced/O to/O deal/O with/O the/O police/O outside/O the/O capital/O ./O 
State/O in/O a/O state/O Martin/PERSON Wagener/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O on/O violence/O in/O East/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION at/O Trier/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O called/O Beijing/LOCATION a/O ``/O true/O security/O state/O ./O ''/O 
Around/O 110,000/O police/O officers/O and/O 34,000/O soldiers/O have/O been/O enlisted/O to/O work/O security/O The/O government/O has/O put/O 34,000/O soldiers/O of/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION along/O with/O 110,000/O police/O officers/O in/O place/O for/O security/O ,/O Wagener/PERSON said/O his/O research/O has/O shown/O ./O 
They/O will/O be/O backed/O up/O by/O fighter/O jets/O ,/O helicopters/O and/O ships/O ./O 
There/O have/O also/O been/O some/O 300,000/O security/O cameras/O installed/O ,/O and/O up/O to/O 1.4/O million/O people/O have/O reportedly/O volunteered/O to/O make/O sure/O nothing/O goes/O wrong/O ./O 
``/O It/O will/O be/O very/O difficult/O to/O smuggle/O any/O sort/O of/O explosives/O into/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O Wagener/PERSON ./O 
The/O attack/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION is/O not/O an/O uncommon/O occurrence/O ./O 
For/O years/O there/O have/O been/O both/O small/O and/O large/O attacks/O against/O the/O police/O and/O government/O buildings/O ./O 
Until/O now/O ,/O however/O ,/O they/O have/O not/O been/O reported/O on/O outside/O the/O country/O ./O 
Xuewu/PERSON said/O he/O expects/O the/O attacks/O to/O continue/O after/O the/O Olympics/O ,/O because/O the/O groups/O '/O causes/O will/O not/O fade/O away/O as/O international/O media/O leave/O China/LOCATION after/O the/O Games/O ./O 
``/O Just/O the/O opposite/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O There/O will/O still/O be/O problems/O because/O the/O injustice/O in/O China/LOCATION will/O just/O get/O bigger/O ,/O and/O the/O relationship/O between/O the/O central/O government/O and/O the/O minorities/O will/O get/O worse/O ./O ''/O 
Selective/O disinformation/O Wagener/PERSON said/O he/O believes/O it/O is/O possible/O that/O the/O central/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O instrumented/O accidents/O ,/O like/O the/O one/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION ,/O in/O order/O to/O justify/O their/O giant/O security/O apparatus/O ./O 
When/O the/O Games/O are/O over/O they/O are/O likely/O to/O use/O it/O for/O other/O purposes/O ,/O such/O as/O controlling/O separatist/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Tibet/LOCATION protesters/O ,/O and/O the/O religious/O Falun/ORGANIZATION Gong/ORGANIZATION sects/O ,/O Wagener/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O This/O seems/O to/O be/O the/O central/O concern/O for/O the/O authorities/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
Local/O police/O tried/O to/O keep/O the/O story/O from/O getting/O out/O The/O Chinese/O government/O seems/O to/O be/O carrying/O out/O a/O campaign/O of/O selective/O disinformation/O of/O the/O public/O ./O 
At/O least/O that/O 's/O what/O actions/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION are/O pointing/O to/O ./O 
According/O to/O one/O reporter/O from/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O independent/O reports/O of/O the/O attack/O were/O difficult/O to/O come/O by/O ./O 
The/O local/O authorities/O blocked/O Internet/O access/O on/O the/O day/O of/O the/O attack/O ./O 
The/O police/O tried/O to/O prohibit/O any/O news/O of/O the/O attack/O getting/O out/O ,/O and/O even/O broke/O into/O the/O hotel/O room/O of/O an/O AFP/ORGANIZATION photographer/O and/O forced/O him/O to/O delete/O photos/O of/O the/O attack/O site/O ./O 
Two/O Japanese/O journalists/O ,/O who/O wanted/O to/O report/O on/O the/O attack/O ,/O were/O momentarily/O detained/O according/O to/O the/O Associated/ORGANIZATION Press/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Reporter/O Shinji/PERSON Katsuta/PERSON said/O that/O he/O was/O hit/O multiple/O times/O in/O the/O face/O ./O 
Authorities/O apologized/O later/O for/O the/O incident/O ./O 
