The/O human/O rights/O envoy/O for/O the/O German/O government/O has/O urged/O Berlin/LOCATION to/O help/O US/LOCATION President-Elect/O Obama/PERSON meet/O his/O promise/O to/O close/O the/O controversial/O prison/O camp/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION by/O taking/O in/O innocent/O inmates/O ./O 
In/O an/O interview/O with/O newspaper/O Frankfurter/ORGANIZATION Rundschau/ORGANIZATION published/O on/O Saturday/O ,/O Dec/O 20/O ,/O Guenter/PERSON Nooke/PERSON said/O Germany/LOCATION along/O with/O other/O European/O nations/O had/O to/O ensure/O that/O Guantanamo/LOCATION 's/O planned/O closure/O went/O ahead/O as/O planned/O ./O 
Nooke/PERSON wants/O Germany/LOCATION to/O help/O close/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ``/LOCATION Guantanamo/LOCATION is/O an/O American/O problem/O ./O 
But/O you/O ca/O n't/O allow/O its/O closure/O to/O fail/O because/O no-one/O knows/O where/O to/O put/O the/O prisoners/O ,/O ''/O Nooke/PERSON told/O the/O paper/O ./O 
In/O particular/O ,/O Germany/LOCATION should/O be/O prepared/O to/O take/O in/O some/O of/O the/O 17/O Uighurs/O held/O at/O the/O prison/O camp/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION ,/O Nooke/PERSON said/O ./O 
Germany/LOCATION urged/O to/O take/O in/O Uighur/LOCATION prisoners/O 
A/O Muslim/O minority/O native/O to/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O the/O Uighurs/O face/O political/O persecution/O in/O their/O homeland/O China/LOCATION ,/O according/O to/O human/O rights/O groups/O ./O 
Their/O struggle/O for/O independence/O is/O strongly/O opposed/O by/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Germany/LOCATION has/O a/O small/O Uighur/O community/O ,/O many/O of/O whom/O live/O in/O Munich/LOCATION ./O 
The/O head/O of/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION 's/O Germany/LOCATION chapter/O ,/O Barbara/PERSON Lochbiler/PERSON too/O urged/O the/O German/O government/O to/O lay/O particular/O emphasis/O on/O the/O Uighurs/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION --/O there/O is/O no/O evidence/O of/O their/O involvement/O in/O terrorist/O activities/O --/O while/O considering/O taking/O in/O prisoners/O ./O 
``/O The/O Uighurs/O have/O a/O network/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
That/O 's/O why/O it/O would/O be/O easier/O for/O them/O to/O start/O a/O new/O life/O here/O ,/O ''/O Lochbiler/PERSON told/O German/O news/O agency/O dpa/O ./O 
Lochbiler/PERSON said/O the/O German/O government/O together/O with/O other/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION nations/O should/O show/O its/O readiness/O to/O take/O in/O apparently/O innocent/O Guantanamo/LOCATION inmates/O ./O 
``/O Quick/O action/O is/O more/O than/O overdue/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
<LOCATION>Guantanamo/O</LOCATION> closure/O wo/O n't/O be/O easy/O 
Earlier/O this/O week/O ,/O a/O US/LOCATION defense/O official/O said/O the/O Pentagon/ORGANIZATION is/O working/O on/O a/O plan/O to/O shut/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION that/O would/O be/O available/O to/O President-elect/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON when/O he/O takes/O office/O on/O Jan./O 20/O 
Obama/PERSON 's/O decision/O to/O close/O the/O hugely/O controversial/O prison/O camp/O located/O at/O the/O US/LOCATION naval/O station/O in/O southeastern/O Cuba/LOCATION ,/O has/O been/O welcomed/O by/O human/O rights/O groups/O and/O governments/O around/O the/O world/O ./O 
The/O prison/O has/O come/O to/O symbolize/O aggressive/O detention/O practices/O and/O has/O opened/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION to/O allegations/O of/O torture/O ./O 
But/O it/O 's/O largely/O accepted/O that/O shuttering/O the/O prison/O ,/O set/O up/O by/O President/O Bush/PERSON after/O the/O Sept/O 11/O attack/O on/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O will/O be/O a/O tricky/O legal/O task/O ./O 
Many/O experts/O doubt/O whether/O any/O of/O the/O suspected/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O <ORGANIZATION>al-Qaeda/O</ORGANIZATION> fighters/O imprisoned/O there/O will/O receive/O a/O fair/O public/O trial/O ./O 
The/O German/O government/O has/O long/O called/O for/O the/O prison/O 's/O closure/O with/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON repeatedly/O bringing/O it/O up/O in/O talks/O with/O President/O Bush/PERSON ./O 
Murat/PERSON Kurnaz/PERSON has/O published/O a/O book/O on/O his/O imprisonment/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION 
One/O of/O the/O first/O prisoners/O brought/O to/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION in/O 2002/O included/O a/O German-born/O Turkish/O national/O Murat/PERSON Kurnaz/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O held/O in/O the/O camp/O until/O 2006/O and/O claims/O to/O have/O been/O tortured/O ./O 
No/O trial/O was/O held/O ./O 
The/O head/O of/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O opposition/O Green/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O Claudia/PERSON Roth/PERSON ,/O on/O Saturday/O urged/O Merkel/PERSON ``/O to/O convey/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION government/O that/O Germany/LOCATION was/O prepared/O to/O take/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION inmates/O ./O ''/O
