Tibetans/O '/O protests/O against/O Chinese/O rule/O have/O been/O reported/O widely/O in/O the/O Indian/O media/O ./O 
Editorials/O call/O for/O restraint/O by/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O and/O criticize/O the/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION government/O for/O not/O speaking/O up/O for/O the/O Tibetans/O ./O 
They/O also/O cover/O the/O activities/O of/O the/O exile/O community/O in/O India/LOCATION in/O detail/O ./O 
It/O is/O one/O thing/O to/O construct/O great/O wonders/O like/O the/O Lhasa/LOCATION railway/O ,/O but/O quite/O another/O to/O meet/O the/O aspirations/O of/O the/O Tibetans/O ./O 
A/O great/O deal/O of/O Chinese/O policy/O is/O motivated/O by/O a/O morbid/O fear/O of/O China/LOCATION breaking/O up/O ./O 
Yet/O ,/O almost/O every/O country/O in/O the/O world/O recognizes/O that/O Tibet/LOCATION is/O a/O part/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
What/O the/O Tibetans/O ,/O or/O for/O that/O matter/O Uighurs/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> want/O is/O essentially/O to/O preserve/O their/O culture/O ./O 
A/O celebration/O of/O diversity/O will/O add/O to/O the/O glory/O of/O a/O great/O country/O like/O China/LOCATION ,/O rather/O than/O detract/O from/O it/O ./O 
It/O is/O also/O noteworthy/O that/O unlike/O agitations/O by/O disaffected/O populations/O in/O other/O lands/O ,/O where/O the/O gun/O quickly/O comes/O into/O play/O ,/O the/O Tibetans/O '/O strategy/O is/O largely/O Gandhian/O ./O 
This/O is/O true/O of/O the/O protests/O inside/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION ,/O as/O well/O as/O those/O by/O their/O compatriots/O living/O in/O exile/O in/O this/O country/O who/O began/O a/O march/O from/O Dharamsala/LOCATION ,/O seat/O of/O the/O government-in-exile/O ,/O to/O the/O Tibetan/O border/O ./O 
Some/O of/O them/O carried/O portraits/O not/O only/O of/O the/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> but/O also/O that/O of/O Mahatma/PERSON Gandhi/PERSON ,/O as/O a/O mark/O of/O tribute/O to/O the/O land/O which/O has/O given/O them/O as/O well/O as/O their/O spiritual/O head/O refuge/O for/O the/O last/O 50/O years/O ./O 
The/O Indian/O government/O is/O caught/O in/O a/O bit/O of/O a/O bind/O :/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION recognises/O that/O Tibet/LOCATION is/O a/O part/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O has/O indeed/O given/O undertakings/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION that/O political/O activity/O directed/O against/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Republic/ORGANIZATION would/O not/O be/O permitted/O from/O Indian/O soil/O ./O 
But/O at/O the/O same/O time/O this/O is/O a/O democracy/O ,/O the/O world/O 's/O biggest/O as/O we/O so/O proudly/O proclaim/O ,/O and/O the/O Indian/O people/O will/O find/O it/O hard/O to/O stomach/O any/O kind/O of/O brutal/O crackdown/O on/O peaceful/O demonstrators/O in/O Lhasa/LOCATION ./O 
The/O ministry/O of/O external/O affairs/O has/O intoned/O that/O no/O ``/O anti-China/O ''/O activity/O will/O be/O permitted/O from/O Indian/O soil/O ./O 
It/O 's/O an/O authoritarian/O trait/O to/O describe/O any/O protest/O as/O anti-national/O ./O 
India/LOCATION is/O a/O democracy/O ./O 
That/O principle/O is/O n't/O worth/O suspending/O just/O because/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O offended/O ./O 
Neither/O has/O it/O paid/O much/O dividend/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O response/O to/O India/LOCATION 's/O wholehearted/O backing/O of/O Chinese/O claims/O on/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Taiwan/LOCATION has/O so/O far/O been/O meagre/O :/O recognition/O perhaps/O of/O India/LOCATION 's/O claims/O on/O Sikkim/LOCATION ,/O but/O not/O a/O settling/O of/O the/O boundary/O question/O in/O its/O entirety/O ./O 
China/LOCATION still/O continues/O to/O claim/O Arunachal/LOCATION Pradesh/LOCATION ./O 
It/O wo/O n't/O hurt/O if/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION were/O to/O say/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION that/O while/O it/O fully/O recognises/O Chinese/O claims/O over/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O it/O wo/O n't/O jail/O people/O who/O think/O otherwise/O ./O 
At/O the/O very/O least/O ,/O India/LOCATION can/O be/O more/O supportive/O of/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON 's/O call/O for/O Tibetan/O autonomy/O within/O China/LOCATION 's/O borders/O ./O 
The/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> 's/O restrained/O criticism/O of/O the/O Chinese/O crackdown/O in/O Lhasa/LOCATION has/O annoyed/O the/O Tibetan/O youth/O in/O India/LOCATION who/O now/O say/O his/O ``/O middle/O way/O ''/O has/O become/O irrelevant/O ./O 
The/O Buddhist/O spiritual/O leader/O said/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympics/O should/O not/O be/O called/O off/O ./O 
Radical/O youth/O groups/O that/O want/O the/O Games/O scrapped/O right/O away/O reacted/O with/O disappointment/O ./O 
The/O Tibetan/ORGANIZATION Women/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION too/O said/O the/O middle/O way/O ,/O which/O it/O backed/O till/O recently/O ,/O had/O ``/O failed/O so/O far/O ''/O ./O
