The/O Olympic/O torch/O has/O begun/O its/O journey/O through/O Asia/LOCATION ./O 
The/O first/O leg/O of/O its/O tour/O was/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O where/O it/O arrived/O on/O Tuesday/O night/O ./O 
Amid/O safety/O fears/O the/O authorities/O had/O to/O cut/O short/O the/O route/O of/O the/O torch/O relay/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O a/O close/O ally/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O has/O been/O supporting/O its/O stand/O on/O the/O Tibet/LOCATION crisis/O ,/O an/O issue/O which/O has/O led/O to/O widespread/O protests/O across/O the/O world/O ./O 
The/O Olympic/O torch/O relay/O kicked/O off/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION with/O music/O and/O a/O colourful/O ceremony/O ./O 
More/O than/O 60/O other/O sporting/O icons/O and/O celebrities/O carried/O the/O flame/O along/O the/O 3.5-kilometre-long/O route/O ./O 
In/O his/O speech/O ,/O Arif/PERSON Hassan/PERSON ,/O the/O president/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Olympics/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION called/O the/O event/O a/O great/O honour/O for/O Pakistan/LOCATION :/O ``/O The/O relay/O will/O promote/O the/O Olympic/O spirit/O ,/O further/O deepen/O our/O friendship/O and/O of/O course/O deepen/O our/O resolve/O for/O the/O Olympic/O movement/O ./O ''/O 
The/O original/O plan/O was/O to/O carry/O the/O torch/O on/O the/O street/O from/O the/O parliament/O building/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION to/O the/O city/O 's/O main/O Jinnah/LOCATION stadium/O ./O 
But/O safety/O fears/O forced/O the/O authorities/O to/O make/O last/O minute/O changes/O in/O the/O plan/O ./O 
Instead/O ,/O the/O torch/O took/O the/O shortest/O route/O to/O the/O sports/O arena/O ,/O which/O was/O surrounded/O by/O around/O 3,000/O policemen/O and/O soldiers/O ./O 
Support/O for/O China/LOCATION 
But/O Pakistan/LOCATION was/O not/O expecting/O any/O anti/O China/LOCATION protests/O as/O in/O London/LOCATION ,/O Paris/LOCATION and/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O route/O of/O the/O torch/O relay/O had/O to/O be/O drastically/O curtailed/O because/O of/O demonstrations/O against/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O crackdown/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
President/O Pervez/PERSON Musharraf/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O just/O returned/O from/O a/O week-long/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O has/O condemned/O pro-Tibet/O protests/O and/O assured/O earlier/O this/O week/O his/O country/O 's/O full/O support/O for/O the/O long/O term/O ally/O Beijing/LOCATION on/O the/O Tibet/LOCATION crisis/O :/O ``/O As/O far/O as/O action/O around/O the/O world/O ,/O in/O some/O parts/O of/O the/O world/O ,/O we/O condemn/O it/O very/O strongly/O ./O 
Because/O we/O think/O that/O politics/O must/O be/O kept/O out/O of/O sports/O ./O 
Sports/O generates/O brotherhood/O ,/O sports/O generates/O closeness/O ./O 
Now/O if/O we/O bring/O politics/O into/O it/O ,/O then/O the/O whole/O idea/O of/O sports/O is/O killed/O ./O ''/O 
More/O protests/O However/O the/O authorities/O said/O the/O precautions/O were/O taken/O because/O of/O the/O presence/O of/O Muslim/O separatists/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O north-western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O troubled/O tribal/O areas/O ./O 
The/O country/O has/O also/O witnessed/O a/O surge/O in/O attacks/O by/O <ORGANIZATION>Al-Qaeda/O</ORGANIZATION> and/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION militants/O that/O has/O killed/O 1,000/O people/O in/O the/O past/O one/O year/O ./O 
After/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O the/O torch/O will/O head/O to/O India/LOCATION ,/O one/O of/O the/O most/O thorny/O legs/O of/O the/O Asia/LOCATION tour/O ./O 
An/O estimated/O 100,000/O Tibetan/O refugees/O live/O in/O India/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O also/O the/O seat/O of/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON 's/O government/O in/O exile/O ./O 
On/O Wednesday/O ,/O a/O pro-Tibetan/O group/O protested/O against/O Beijing/LOCATION in/O front/O of/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O in/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION ./O 
And/O another/O 3000/O are/O expected/O to/O be/O on/O the/O streets/O of/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION on/O Thursday/O ,/O when/O the/O flame/O arrives/O ./O 
Indian/O authorities/O have/O boosted/O security/O in/O the/O capital/O heavily/O to/O avoid/O any/O untoward/O incidents/O ./O
