The/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> has/O started/O his/O visit/O to/O the/O German/O city/O of/O Frankfurt/LOCATION ./O 
He/O has/O been/O invited/O by/O Buddhist/ORGANIZATION Organisations/ORGANIZATION based/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
During/O his/O stay/O ,/O the/O exiled/O Tibetan/O spiritual/O leader/O will/O address/O a/O crowd/O of/O nearly/O 40,000/O people/O at/O a/O stadium/O and/O will/O hold/O a/O series/O of/O lectures/O on/O <ORGANIZATION>Buddhism/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
He/O will/O also/O participate/O in/O seminars/O on/O topics/O such/O as/O peace/O ,/O the/O environment/O ,/O and/O the/O economy/O ./O 
``/O I/O have/O nothing/O to/O say/O except/O showing/O my/O face/O to/O your/O camera/O .../O ./O ''/O 
In/O a/O cheerful/O mood/O ,/O the/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> greeted/O the/O media/O in/O Frankfurt/LOCATION late/O Wednesday/O ./O 
He/O said/O he/O was/O happy/O to/O be/O in/O Germany/LOCATION again/O ./O 
At/O the/O press/O conference/O ,/O the/O exiled/O leader/O did/O not/O speak/O about/O politics/O ,/O but/O about/O politicians/O and/O about/O rules/O of/O a/O happy/O life/O ./O 
``/O I/O believe/O every/O human/O being/O ,/O including/O politicians/O ,/O have/O a/O potential/O to/O develop/O inner/O peace/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O My/O commitment/O is/O to/O make/O this/O clear/O that/O everyone/O has/O that/O potential/O to/O have/O a/O happy/O life/O ./O ''/O 
Missing/O <LOCATION>Lhasa/O</LOCATION> 
During/O the/O press/O conference/O ,/O the/O exiled/O leader/O gave/O a/O lot/O of/O attention/O to/O a/O child/O reporter/O ,/O who/O asked/O him/O one/O question/O after/O another/O ./O 
The/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> answered/O all/O the/O questions/O with/O patience/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O that/O he/O never/O liked/O to/O study/O as/O a/O child/O or/O that/O he/O meditates/O in/O his/O spare/O time/O ./O 
The/O journalist/O also/O asked/O if/O he/O ever/O missed/O his/O home/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON responded/O thoughtfully/O :/O ``/O If/O I/O were/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O in/O Potala/LOCATION ,/O today/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O I/O could/O have/O seen/O so/O many/O opportunities/O ./O 
Because/O we/O became/O refugees/O and/O came/O to/O India/LOCATION and/O we/O found/O new/O opportunities/O ./O 
Of/O course/O inside/O Tibet/LOCATION things/O are/O very/O ,/O very/O sad/O ./O 
But/O Lhasa/LOCATION 's/O climate/O is/O pleasant/O and/O I/O am/O missing/O that/O ./O ''/O 
Support/O for/O the/O plight/O of/O Tibetans/O On/O Wednesday/O ,/O he/O also/O met/O his/O longtime/O friend/O Roland/PERSON Koch/PERSON ,/O the/O Premier/O of/O the/O state/O of/O Hesse/LOCATION ./O 
Koch/PERSON told/O the/O Tibetan/O leader/O that/O Germany/LOCATION was/O concerned/O about/O human/O rights/O violations/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O western/O China/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ./O 
He/O also/O said/O that/O the/O nation/O supports/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON 's/O peaceful/O efforts/O to/O seek/O cultural/O autonomy/O and/O religious/O freedom/O ./O 
In/O 2007/O ,/O relations/O between/O Germany/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION soured/O over/O German/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Markel/PERSON 's/O meeting/O with/O the/O Tibetan/O spiritual/O leader/O in/O Berlin/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION does/O not/O recognise/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON 's/O government-in-exile/O ./O 
It/O accuses/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON of/O using/O his/O foreign/O trips/O to/O engage/O in/O separatist/O activities/O to/O seek/O full/O independence/O ./O 
The/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> denies/O this/O accusation/O and/O insists/O he/O seeks/O only/O greater/O autonomy/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Hao/PERSON <PERSON>Gui/O</PERSON> //O <PERSON>Disha/O Uppal/O</PERSON> 
Editor/O :/O Pia/PERSON Chandavarkar/PERSON
