Germany/LOCATION has/O officially/O been/O asked/O to/O be/O the/O new/O home/O for/O up/O to/O 10/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION inmates/O after/O the/O prison/O is/O closed/O next/O year/O ,/O however/O the/O government/O will/O make/O a/O case-by/O case/O decision/O ./O 
German/O government/O officials/O said/O on/O Monday/O that/O Berlin/LOCATION would/O run/O its/O own/O checks/O on/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION prisoners/O slated/O for/O release/O and/O resettlement/O to/O ensure/O that/O none/O of/O those/O freed/O pose/O any/O type/O of/O security/O threat/O ./O 
``/O Germany/LOCATION has/O to/O make/O its/O own/O assessment/O ,/O ''/O foreign/O ministry/O spokesman/O Jens/PERSON Ploetner/PERSON told/O reporters/O in/O Berlin/LOCATION ./O 
An/O interior/ORGANIZATION ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O added/O that/O ``/O every/O decision/O is/O concerned/O with/O the/O individual/O case/O ./O ''/O 
Government/O officials/O also/O said/O that/O Washington/LOCATION had/O drawn/O up/O an/O initial/O list/O of/O candidates/O slated/O for/O release/O ,/O however/O they/O declined/O to/O say/O how/O many/O names/O were/O on/O the/O list/O under/O an/O agreement/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION administration/O to/O keep/O that/O information/O confidential/O ./O 
The/O spokesman/O added/O that/O the/O ministry/O would/O make/O its/O decisions/O on/O a/O case-by-case/O basis/O in/O consultation/O with/O other/O EU/LOCATION countries/O and/O officials/O from/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O 16/O federal/O states/O ./O 
He/O said/O that/O the/O criteria/O were/O related/O to/O German/O foreign/O residency/O law/O and/O would/O consider/O whether/O a/O detainee/O posed/O a/O security/O threat/O to/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
Der/ORGANIZATION Spiegel/ORGANIZATION news/ORGANIZATION magazine/ORGANIZATION reported/O on/O Saturday/O that/O up/O to/O 10/O so-called/O non-dangerous/O captives/O were/O being/O considered/O for/O release/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ./O 
German/O daily/O newspaper/O Bild/ORGANIZATION reported/O that/O the/O request/O concerned/O 10/O Chinese/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O ,/O who/O are/O viewed/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION as/O ``/O Chinese/O terrorists/O ./O ''/O 
Munich/LOCATION ,/O in/O the/O southern/O German/O state/O Bavaria/LOCATION ,/O is/O home/O to/O around/O 500/O Uighurs/O ,/O the/O largest/O known/O community/O in/O exile/O ./O 
But/O Bavaria/LOCATION 's/O interior/O minister/O Joachim/PERSON Herrmann/PERSON told/O Bild/ORGANIZATION his/O state/O would/O not/O offer/O its/O ``/O candidacy/O to/O welcome/O these/O people/O ./O ''/O 
Most/O of/O the/O 17/O Uighurs/O held/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION have/O been/O cleared/O of/O being/O enemy/O combatants/O ./O 
Officials/O say/O it/O will/O be/O critical/O for/O the/O German/O government/O to/O be/O assured/O that/O none/O of/O the/O released/O prisoners/O have/O ties/O to/O terrorist/O networks/O ./O 
US/LOCATION officials/O will/O also/O have/O to/O explain/O why/O the/O prisoners/O can/O not/O be/O sent/O back/O to/O their/O home/O countries/O or/O settled/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O 
Around/O 50/O detainees/O are/O unable/O to/O return/O to/O their/O homelands/O because/O of/O the/O danger/O that/O they/O will/O be/O tortured/O there/O ./O 
US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON fulfilled/O one/O of/O his/O campaign/O promises/O in/O the/O first/O days/O of/O his/O presidency/O by/O ordering/O the/O closure/O of/O the/O controversial/O detention/O center/O on/O the/O Cuban/O coast/O ./O 
Now/O he/O must/O decide/O what/O to/O do/O with/O the/O 241/O remaining/O prisoners/O ./O 
US/LOCATION Attorney/O General/O Eric/PERSON Holder/PERSON said/O in/O Berlin/LOCATION last/O week/O that/O Washington/LOCATION would/O soon/O like/O to/O release/O 30/O prisoners/O ./O 
While/O other/O European/O nations/O ,/O including/O France/LOCATION and/O Portugal/LOCATION ,/O have/O indicated/O they/O are/O willing/O to/O accept/O Guantanamo/LOCATION prisoners/O ,/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O fractious/O left-right/O government/O is/O at/O odds/O over/O the/O issue/O ./O 
Foreign/O Minister/O Frank-Walter/PERSON Steinmeier/PERSON ,/O a/O Social/O Democrat/O running/O for/O chancellor/O this/O year/O ,/O said/O in/O an/O open/O letter/O to/O Obama/PERSON in/O January/O that/O Germany/LOCATION would/O be/O willing/O to/O take/O in/O detainees/O if/O it/O helped/O him/O close/O Guantanamo/LOCATION ./O 
But/O the/O conservative/O Interior/ORGANIZATION Minister/O Wolfgang/PERSON Schaeuble/PERSON said/O Obama/PERSON could/O not/O expect/O Germany/LOCATION to/O accept/O freed/O inmates/O ./O 
According/O to/O Bild/ORGANIZATION ,/O Schaeuble/PERSON wants/O first/O to/O exhaust/O all/O possibilities/O of/O their/O being/O resettled/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
