The/O violence/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O continued/O on/O Wednesday/O ./O 
There/O were/O reports/O of/O several/O incidents/O of/O mobs/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O armed/O with/O wooden/O bats/O ,/O shovels/O and/O other/O makeshift/O weapons/O attacking/O Uighurs/O on/O the/O streets/O ./O 
Chinese/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON rushed/O back/O to/O his/O country/O after/O cutting/O short/O a/O visit/O to/O L'Aquila/LOCATION ,/O Italy/LOCATION ,/O where/O he/O was/O due/O to/O attend/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>G8/O</ORGANIZATION> summit/O ./O
