The/O recent/O festivities/O may/O have/O been/O a/O reflection/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O 's/O need/O to/O project/O a/O strong/O and/O organized/O image/O ,/O argues/O Dr./O Doris/PERSON Fischer/PERSON ./O 
What/O do/O ``/O normal/O ''/O German/O citizens/O do/O on/O the/O German/O national/O holiday/O ?/O 
They/O enjoy/O a/O day/O off/O ,/O get/O together/O with/O family/O or/O friends/O and/O ,/O if/O weather/O permits/O ,/O they/O may/O venture/O out/O on/O walks/O or/O bicycle/O trips/O ./O 
They/O also/O like/O to/O eat/O something/O good/O ,/O whether/O at/O home/O or/O out/O ./O 
As/O such/O ,/O the/O national/O holiday/O is/O unlikely/O to/O be/O of/O much/O ,/O if/O any/O ,/O interest/O to/O them/O ./O 
What/O do/O ``/O normal/O ''/O Chinese/O citizens/O do/O on/O the/O Chinese/O national/O holiday/O ?/O 
They/O may/O either/O work/O ,/O since/O many/O businesses/O ,/O including/O restaurants/O ,/O are/O open/O for/O the/O day/O ,/O or/O they/O may/O enjoy/O some/O time/O off/O ,/O get/O together/O with/O family/O or/O friends/O ,/O and/O go/O out/O for/O walks/O ./O 
And/O they/O are/O more/O than/O likely/O to/O indulge/O in/O some/O good/O food/O ./O 
As/O such/O ,/O the/O national/O holiday/O is/O unlikely/O to/O be/O of/O much/O ,/O if/O any/O ,/O interest/O to/O them/O ./O 
Making/O an/O impression/O 
China/LOCATION 's/O leaders/O wanted/O to/O inspire/O patriotism/O among/O their/O own/O people/O 
The/O year/O ,/O however/O ,/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION is/O celebrating/O its/O sixtieth/O birthday/O ./O 
This/O is/O a/O very/O important/O anniversary/O in/O Chinese/O tradition/O -/O even/O more/O important/O than/O the/O fiftieth/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O saw/O it/O fit/O to/O celebrate/O the/O occasion/O by/O staging/O a/O huge/O military/O and/O civilian/O parade/O in/O the/O centre/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O finishing/O off/O with/O a/O gigantic/O show/O party/O on/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ./O 
While/O the/O logistical/O effort/O that/O went/O into/O all/O this/O is/O certainly/O admirable/O ,/O the/O patriotic/O vocabulary/O used/O in/O the/O speeches/O ,/O propaganda/O and/O songs/O presented/O there/O was/O disturbing/O ./O 
The/O demonstration/O of/O power/O embodied/O in/O the/O mobilization/O and/O coordination/O of/O thousands/O of/O persons/O marching/O in/O step/O and/O in/O huge/O pictures/O created/O by/O groups/O of/O dancing/O actors/O was/O enough/O to/O give/O the/O observer/O goose-bumps/O ./O 
Keeping/O up/O appearances/O ?/O 
Despite/O fast/O economic/O growth/O ,/O poverty/O is/O still/O a/O major/O problem/O in/O China/LOCATION 
Any/O doubts/O as/O to/O whether/O China/LOCATION is/O capable/O of/O organizing/O events/O of/O this/O magnitude/O were/O already/O dispelled/O during/O the/O opening/O ceremonies/O for/O the/O 2008/O Summer/O Olympics/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
But/O why/O China/LOCATION needs/O all/O this/O is/O a/O question/O not/O so/O easily/O answered/O ./O 
Is/O what/O we/O see/O here/O merely/O a/O strong/O ,/O self-confident/O state/O celebrating/O its/O own/O existence/O ?/O 
A/O rising/O world/O power/O that/O feels/O a/O need/O to/O demonstrate/O its/O military/O and/O logistical/O prowess/O to/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O world/O and/O perhaps/O even/O use/O it/O as/O a/O threat/O ?/O 
Or/O is/O it/O just/O an/O insecure/O regime/O using/O gargantuan/O festivities/O to/O disguise/O existing/O problems/O ?/O 
Perhaps/O the/O truth/O lies/O somewhere/O in/O between/O ./O 
When/O in/O 1949/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON proclaimed/O the/O People/O 's/O Republic/O ,/O China/LOCATION was/O a/O very/O poor/O country/O shaken/O by/O war/O and/O civil/O conflict/O ./O 
The/O first/O successes/O of/O the/O new/O regime/O were/O shattered/O when/O Mao/PERSON opted/O for/O the/O Great/O Leap/O Forward/O to/O expedite/O national/O development/O ./O 
This/O huge/O social/O experiment/O ended/O in/O miserable/O failure/O ,/O and/O its/O consequence/O was/O a/O famine/O that/O has/O left/O indelible/O marks/O on/O the/O country/O 's/O birth/O and/O death/O statistics/O ./O 
In/O the/O aftermath/O ,/O Mao/PERSON 's/O opponents/O first/O sought/O to/O curb/O his/O influence/O ,/O but/O in/O response/O Mao/PERSON launched/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O in/O 1966/O ,/O which/O thrust/O the/O country/O into/O a/O state/O of/O turmoil/O close/O to/O civil/O war/O ./O 
While/O the/O tide/O of/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O had/O already/O begun/O to/O subside/O in/O 1969/O ,/O it/O was/O not/O until/O 1978/O that/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ,/O under/O Deng/PERSON Xiaoping/PERSON ,/O was/O able/O to/O launch/O a/O set/O of/O deep-reaching/O economic/O reforms/O ./O 
These/O in/O turn/O constituted/O the/O foundation/O for/O China/LOCATION 's/O headlong/O course/O of/O economic/O development/O ./O 
Building/O on/O them/O ,/O China/LOCATION committed/O itself/O to/O developing/O a/O socialist/O market/O economy/O in/O 1992/O -/O a/O move/O on/O which/O it/O followed/O up/O in/O 2001/O by/O joining/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Trade/ORGANIZATION Organization/ORGANIZATION ./O 
A/O modern/O power/O 
Shanghai/LOCATION 's/O visible/O modernity/O and/O wealth/O are/O a/O source/O of/O pride/O for/O the/O Chinese/O 
While/O today/O 's/O China/LOCATION is/O still/O a/O developing/O nation/O ,/O it/O is/O no/O longer/O poor/O in/O all/O parts/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Shanghai/LOCATION ,/O and/O some/O other/O Chinese/O cities/O and/O regions/O have/O become/O thriving/O economic/O centers/O ,/O attracting/O trade/O ,/O investment/O and/O ,/O increasingly/O ,/O labor/O from/O all/O over/O the/O world/O ./O 
These/O are/O successes/O that/O the/O Chinese/O government/O sees/O as/O worthy/O of/O celebration/O and/O that/O ,/O we/O might/O perhaps/O add/O ,/O rightly/O deserve/O to/O be/O celebrated/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O rise/O has/O made/O the/O country/O more/O powerful/O ./O 
A/O number/O of/O important/O global/O challenges/O are/O virtually/O bound/O to/O not/O get/O solved/O without/O China/LOCATION 's/O cooperation/O ./O 
But/O ,/O thanks/O to/O its/O political/O system/O as/O well/O as/O its/O new/O economic/O power/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O not/O necessarily/O on/O friendly/O terms/O with/O everyone/O ./O 
And/O for/O that/O reason/O the/O Chinese/O government/O may/O think/O :/O It/O could/O n't/O hurt/O to/O exhibit/O the/O country/O 's/O weapons/O arsenal/O and/O to/O show/O off/O its/O national/O capacities/O to/O develop/O and/O build/O weapons/O systems/O and/O fighter/O aircraft/O of/O its/O own/O -/O despite/O all/O of/O its/O solemn/O assurances/O that/O it/O seeks/O only/O friendly/O relations/O with/O all/O other/O countries/O ./O 
Tensions/O under/O the/O surface/O 
The/O conflict/O with/O Tibet/LOCATION is/O one/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O many/O social/O problems/O 
The/O demonstration/O of/O strength/O was/O certainly/O also/O addressed/O to/O a/O domestic/O audience/O ./O 
Tensions/O in/O the/O country/O have/O ,/O in/O recent/O years/O ,/O tended/O to/O increase/O rather/O than/O fade/O ./O 
Major/O income/O disparities/O ,/O widespread/O corruption/O ,/O suppression/O of/O freedom/O of/O the/O press/O ,/O disgruntlement/O over/O cases/O of/O expropriation/O and/O environmental/O scandals/O ,/O and/O ,/O not/O least/O ,/O violent/O expressions/O of/O dissatisfaction/O on/O the/O part/O of/O the/O indigenous/O populations/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -/O all/O this/O has/O repeatedly/O demonstrated/O to/O the/O Chinese/O government/O that/O social/O peace/O in/O China/LOCATION continues/O to/O be/O elusive/O and/O fragile/O ./O 
The/O events/O of/O 1989/O have/O not/O been/O forgotten/O ,/O either/O -/O one/O more/O reason/O why/O on/O the/O national/O holiday/O there/O was/O just/O as/O much/O talk/O of/O harmony/O ,/O peace/O ,/O and/O stability/O as/O there/O was/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O pride/O and/O self-confidence/O ./O 
The/O idea/O seems/O to/O be/O that/O these/O elements/O will/O serve/O as/O ``/O cement/O ''/O that/O continues/O to/O hold/O the/O country/O together/O ,/O in/O the/O future/O as/O well/O ./O 
Whether/O or/O not/O the/O constant/O ,/O mantra-style/O repetition/O of/O slogans/O of/O this/O kind/O will/O really/O turn/O out/O to/O be/O a/O self-fulfilling/O prophecy/O is/O an/O entirely/O different/O matter/O ./O 
Doris/PERSON Fischer/PERSON is/O a/O researcher/O at/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION 
It/O is/O perhaps/O reassuring/O to/O know/O that/O ``/O normal/O ''/O Chinese/O citizens/O -/O in/O other/O words/O ,/O those/O who/O were/O not/O obliged/O to/O march/O in/O step/O or/O dance/O on/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION -/O this/O year/O once/O again/O made/O use/O of/O their/O day/O off/O to/O take/O long/O walks/O with/O their/O families/O and/O to/O enjoy/O good/O meals/O ./O 
It/O was/O this/O behavior/O that/O gave/O the/O day/O its/O relaxed/O character/O ,/O and/O provided/O some/O relief/O from/O the/O awe-inspiring/O scenes/O to/O be/O observed/O in/O the/O centre/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
It/O may/O well/O be/O that/O it/O is/O mostly/O the/O Chinese/O government/O that/O needs/O gargantuan/O celebrations/O ,/O while/O the/O general/O population/O has/O other/O interests/O ./O 
Perhaps/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O will/O one/O day/O come/O to/O realize/O that/O that/O the/O benefits/O of/O any/O such/O demonstration/O of/O power/O are/O bound/O to/O be/O smaller/O than/O the/O costs/O ,/O which/O are/O sure/O to/O be/O enormous/O ./O 
Dr./O Doris/PERSON Fischer/PERSON is/O a/O researcher/O in/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Competitiveness/O and/O</ORGANIZATION> Social/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION department/O at/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>DIE/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ./O 
Based/O in/O Bonn/LOCATION ,/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION draws/O together/O the/O knowledge/O of/O development/O research/O available/O worldwide/O ,/O dedicating/O its/O work/O to/O key/O issues/O facing/O the/O future/O of/O development/O policy/O ./O 
It/O consults/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O independent/O research/O findings/O in/O Germany/LOCATION and/O worldwide/O and/O deals/O with/O current/O issues/O in/O cooperation/O between/O industrial/O and/O developing/O countries/O ./O
