The/O transfer/O of/O two/O Chinese/O Uighur/O brothers/O from/O the/O detention/O camp/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION to/O Switzerland/LOCATION has/O prompted/O mixed/O reactions/O from/O Swiss/O politicians/O ,/O with/O some/O saying/O the/O US/LOCATION should/O sort/O out/O its/O own/O problems/O ./O 
After/O long/O negotiations/O with/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O the/O Swiss/O government/O has/O finally/O agreed/O to/O take/O two/O Chinese/O nationals/O from/O the/O US/LOCATION Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION prison/LOCATION ./O 
President/O Obama/PERSON promised/O to/O close/O the/O detention/O center/O ,/O but/O finding/O new/O homes/O for/O all/O the/O detainees/O has/O turned/O into/O a/O complex/O diplomatic/O undertaking/O ./O 
Obama/PERSON has/O vowed/O to/O shut/O down/O the/O controversial/O detention/O facility/O The/O two/O Chinese/O brothers/O -/O both/O Muslims/O from/O the/O Uighur/O ethnic/O group/O -/O were/O apparently/O detained/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O 2001/O and/O held/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION for/O more/O than/O eight/O years/O before/O being/O freed/O ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION believes/O they/O could/O be/O at/O risk/O if/O they/O are/O returned/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O but/O many/O American/O politicians/O have/O strongly/O opposed/O allowing/O them/O to/O stay/O in/O US/LOCATION territory/O ./O 
Conflicting/O views/O China/LOCATION has/O bitterly/O criticized/O Switzerland/LOCATION for/O accepting/O the/O two/O ,/O saying/O they/O are/O a/O security/O risk/O ./O 
But/O Swiss/O Social/O Democrat/O member/O of/O parliament/O Mario/PERSON Fehr/PERSON said/O he/O has/O no/O problem/O accepting/O the/O two/O men/O ./O 
``/O There/O have/O been/O security/O investigations/O by/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O by/O our/O government/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O We/O are/O told/O they/O are/O ready/O to/O integrate/O .../O These/O two/O are/O innocent/O and/O they/O need/O somewhere/O to/O go/O ./O ''/O 
The/O Uighurs/O are/O a/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O in/O China/LOCATION Fehr/PERSON said/O it/O would/O be/O ``/O unthinkable/O ''/O for/O Switzerland/LOCATION to/O bow/O to/O Chinese/O pressure/O and/O not/O accept/O the/O men/O ./O 
But/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O suggested/O the/O traditionally/O good/O ties/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O could/O be/O damaged/O by/O Switzerland/LOCATION 's/O decision/O ./O 
Not/O everyone/O in/O Switzerland/LOCATION is/O ready/O to/O welcome/O the/O Uighur/O men/O ./O 
Hans/PERSON Fehr/PERSON ,/O a/O parliamentarian/O of/O the/O right-wing/O Swiss/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O is/O furious/O that/O Switzerland/LOCATION is/O offering/O to/O sort/O out/O a/O mess/O that/O he/O firmly/O believes/O should/O be/O left/O entirely/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
``/O President/O Obama/PERSON got/O the/O Nobel/O peace/O prize/O ,/O he/O 's/O opened/O up/O the/O camp/O ,/O he/O 's/O letting/O the/O detainees/O out/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O America/LOCATION has/O to/O solve/O this/O problem/O itself/O ,/O it/O should/O n't/O be/O our/O job/O ./O ''/O 
Fehr/PERSON also/O questioned/O whether/O the/O two/O Uighurs/O were/O as/O safe/O as/O authorities/O say/O they/O are/O ,/O saying/O they/O were/O found/O in/O a/O weapons/O camp/O and/O ``/O are/O certainly/O not/O Sunday/O school/O boys/O ./O ''/O 
A/O moral/O obligation/O The/O complicated/O situation/O the/O Uighurs/O are/O in/O is/O difficult/O for/O many/O Swiss/O to/O understand/O :/O the/O US/LOCATION says/O the/O two/O former/O detainees/O pose/O no/O security/O threat/O ,/O but/O it/O has/O also/O barred/O them/O from/O settling/O in/O America/LOCATION ./O 
Instead/O ,/O the/O two/O are/O beginning/O a/O new/O life/O in/O a/O quiet/O village/O in/O northwest/O Switzerland/LOCATION ./O 
Lukas/PERSON Labhardt/PERSON of/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION insists/O the/O two/O would/O be/O in/O danger/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O so/O Switzerland/LOCATION has/O a/O moral/O obligation/O ./O 
``/O For/O us/O it/O 's/O about/O human/O rights/O for/O these/O detainees/O ,/O ''/O Labhardt/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O They/O 've/O been/O locked/O up/O for/O 8/O years/O ,/O they/O had/O no/O hope/O ,/O no/O idea/O what/O would/O happen/O to/O them/O now/O that/O Guantanamo/LOCATION is/O being/O shut/O ./O 
600/O detainees/O have/O gone/O home/O ,/O but/O some/O difficult/O cases/O remain/O ./O 
In/O some/O cases/O ,/O like/O these/O Uighurs/O ,/O it/O 's/O considered/O dangerous/O to/O send/O them/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O but/O they/O ca/O n't/O go/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION either/O ./O 
So/O it/O 's/O quite/O right/O that/O we/O help/O ;/O it/O 's/O Switzerland/LOCATION 's/O duty/O ./O ''/O 
Author/O :/O Imogen/PERSON Foulkes/PERSON -LRB-/O acb/hf/O -RRB-/O Editor/O :/O Ben/PERSON Knight/PERSON 
