In/O the/O face/O of/O Chinese/O objections/O ,/O the/O Swiss/O government/O decided/O Wednesday/O to/O allow/O two/O Chinese/O detainees/O from/O the/O US/LOCATION military/O prison/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION to/O relocate/O to/O Switzerland/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Swiss/O government/O said/O Wednesday/O it/O would/O allow/O two/O Chinese/O <LOCATION>Guantanamo/O</LOCATION> detainees/O to/O resettle/O in/O northwestern/O Switzerland/LOCATION ,/O despite/O objections/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION warned/O the/O Swiss/O government/O in/O early/O January/O that/O accepting/O the/O inmates/O ,/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O and/O alleged/O terrorists/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O could/O sour/O relations/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O ./O 
The/O Swiss/ORGANIZATION Justice/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION said/O it/O was/O aware/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O concerns/O but/O had/O decided/O to/O grant/O asylum/O to/O the/O men/O based/O on/O humanitarian/O grounds/O ,/O adding/O that/O the/O men/O did/O n't/O represent/O a/O security/O risk/O ./O 
``/O Today/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION decided/O to/O admit/O for/O humanitarian/O reasons/O two/O Uighurs/O with/O Chinese/O citizenship/O ,/O who/O have/O been/O imprisoned/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION for/O years/O by/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION without/O being/O charged/O with/O a/O crime/O nor/O condemned/O ,/O ''/O it/O said/O ./O 
Justice/O Minister/O Eveline/PERSON Widmer-Schlumpf/PERSON said/O Switzerland/LOCATION has/O a/O ``/O stable/O ,/O good/O relationship/O with/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O we/O want/O to/O keep/O it/O that/O way/O ./O ''/O 
In/O January/O ,/O a/O Swiss/O parliamentary/O committee/O recommended/O not/O to/O accept/O the/O detainees/O ,/O citing/O security/O fears/O after/O the/O attempted/O bombing/O of/O an/O American/O airliner/O on/O December/O 25/O ./O 
The/O detainees/O ,/O who/O are/O brothers/O ,/O will/O be/O resettled/O in/O the/O canton/O of/O Jura/LOCATION ./O 
In/O January/O ,/O an/O Uzbek/O became/O the/O first/O former/O Guantanamo/LOCATION inmate/O to/O be/O resettled/O in/O Switzerland/LOCATION ./O 
Widmer-Schlumpf/PERSON said/O the/O country/O is/O not/O planning/O to/O take/O in/O any/O further/O detainees/O ./O 
cmk/AFP/AP/O //O Reuters/ORGANIZATION 
Editor/O :/O Nancy/PERSON Isenson/PERSON
