Five/O Uighurs/O of/O a/O total/O of/O 22/O who/O were/O wrongfully/O arrested/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O 2001/O remain/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ./O 
This/O week/O ,/O the/O President/O of/O Palau/LOCATION told/O journalists/O his/O country/O was/O willing/O to/O accept/O them/O ./O 
Six/O other/O Uighurs/O have/O already/O been/O living/O on/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION island/O since/O last/O year/O ./O 
However/O ,/O they/O have/O their/O hopes/O set/O on/O Australia/LOCATION ./O 
From/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION to/O Palau/LOCATION ./O 
After/O eight/O years/O in/O detention/O in/O the/O infamous/O US/LOCATION prison/O ,/O six/O Uighurs/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O found/O asylum/O in/O the/O South/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION Islands/LOCATION ./O 
Having/O lived/O in/O tiny/O ,/O isolated/O cells/O ,/O they/O now/O have/O a/O spacious/O six-room/O house/O with/O a/O view/O of/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION ./O 
Ahmad/PERSON Tourson/PERSON rarely/O goes/O out/O and/O does/O not/O like/O to/O talk/O about/O his/O time/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION ./O 
``/O We/O sat/O in/O little/O cages/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION and/O could/O barely/O move/O ,/O ''/O he/O says/O ./O 
``/O We/O had/O no/O idea/O what/O was/O happening/O to/O other/O prisoners/O just/O five/O or/O six/O meters/O away/O ./O 
The/O time/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION was/O the/O darkest/O chapter/O of/O our/O lives/O ./O ''/O 
The/O six/O were/O arrested/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O handed/O over/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION army/O by/O armed/O bounty/O hunters/O for/O 5,000/O US/O dollars/O a/O piece/O ./O 
They/O were/O making/O their/O way/O towards/O Turkey/LOCATION to/O escape/O persecution/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
They/O were/O later/O sent/O to/O Guantanamo/LOCATION as/O suspected/O terrorists/O ./O 
It/O took/O their/O lawyer/O ,/O George/PERSON Clark/PERSON ,/O six/O years/O to/O get/O them/O out/O ,/O despite/O the/O fact/O that/O ``/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION military/O cleared/O these/O men/O in/O 2003/O ./O 
The/O Department/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Justice/ORGANIZATION cleared/O them/O after/O that/O ./O 
The/O courts/O have/O looked/O at/O their/O cases/O ./O 
Everybody/O agrees/O that/O they/O 're/O not/O only/O not/O a/O danger/O but/O as/O far/O as/O the/O terrorism/O aspect/O ./O 
``/O These/O men/O have/O never/O committed/O any/O terrorist/O acts/O ,/O they/O have/O never/O engaged/O in/O any/O sort/O of/O terrorist/O training/O ,/O these/O men/O are/O not/O suicide/O bombers/O ./O 
You/O have/O to/O be/O careful/O about/O what/O 's/O reported/O --/O what/O 's/O reported/O is/O that/O they/O had/O military/O training/O but/O boy/O scouts/O shooting/O cans/O in/O the/O county/O dump/O have/O had/O more/O military/O training/O than/O these/O guys/O have/O ./O ''/O 
For/O Palau/LOCATION 's/O head/O of/O state/O Johnson/PERSON Toribiong/PERSON ,/O it/O was/O a/O humanitarian/O gesture/O to/O take/O in/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON thanked/O him/O personally/O and/O at/O the/O same/O time/O increased/O annual/O development/O aid/O to/O the/O island/O by/O over/O 50/O million/O to/O 200/O million/O US/O dollars/O ./O 
However/O ,/O China/LOCATION was/O angry/O ./O 
After/O the/O Uighurs/O arrived/O ,/O two/O projects/O financed/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION were/O put/O on/O hold/O --/O one/O to/O build/O a/O hotel/O and/O the/O other/O to/O expand/O a/O ring/O road/O on/O the/O island/O ./O 
In/O Palau/LOCATION ,/O the/O six/O Uighurs/O have/O access/O to/O a/O translator/O ,/O a/O social/O worker/O and/O a/O lawyer/O but/O only/O have/O temporary/O residence/O ./O 
Adel/PERSON Noori/PERSON eventually/O wants/O to/O get/O to/O a/O bigger/O island/O ./O 
``/O We/O were/O scared/O about/O coming/O to/O Palau/LOCATION because/O China/LOCATION 's/O influence/O is/O very/O big/O in/O this/O region/O but/O we/O had/O no/O choice/O ,/O ''/O he/O says/O ./O 
``/O We/O would/O feel/O safer/O in/O Australia/LOCATION ./O 
We/O just/O want/O to/O live/O in/O peace/O ./O 
Far/O from/O the/O threats/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O 
We/O hope/O that/O we/O will/O find/O such/O a/O country/O ./O ''/O 
So/O far/O ,/O the/O Australian/O government/O refuses/O to/O take/O them/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O most/O important/O export/O market/O and/O trade/O partner/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O application/O for/O asylum/O is/O apparently/O under/O consideration/O ./O 
Until/O a/O final/O decision/O is/O made/O ,/O the/O Uighurs/O will/O be/O stranded/O in/O the/O middle/O of/O the/O South/LOCATION Seas/LOCATION ./O 
Author/O :/O Andreas/PERSON Stummer/actEditor/O :/O Thomas/PERSON Bärthlein/PERSON 
