European/O countries/O on/O the/O whole/O are/O still/O reluctant/O to/O take/O in/O detainees/O from/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION despite/O the/O best/O persuasive/O efforts/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
While/O some/O have/O grudgingly/O agreed/O to/O help/O ,/O others/O still/O resist/O ./O 
Despite/O missing/O his/O self-imposed/O original/O deadline/O ,/O US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON still/O aims/O to/O shut/O down/O the/O US/LOCATION prison/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION during/O his/O first/O term/O ,/O according/O to/O sources/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ./O 
But/O one/O of/O the/O major/O obstacles/O in/O finally/O closing/O the/O book/O on/O the/O military/O prison/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION is/O the/O White/ORGANIZATION House/ORGANIZATION 's/O struggle/O to/O convince/O foreign/O governments/O to/O accept/O detainees/O ./O 
Obama/PERSON had/O promised/O to/O close/O the/O facility/O during/O his/O first/O year/O in/O office/O but/O that/O deadline/O passed/O in/O January/O ./O 
At/O the/O time/O of/O the/O deadline/O passing/O ,/O 192/O detainees/O remained/O at/O the/O much-criticized/O camp/O ,/O with/O fewer/O than/O 50/O inmates/O having/O left/O Cuba/LOCATION since/O Obama/PERSON took/O office/O ./O 
While/O canvassing/O for/O host/O nations/O has/O been/O worldwide/O ,/O the/O Obama/PERSON administration/O has/O specifically/O concentrated/O its/O powers/O of/O persuasion/O on/O its/O allies/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O Obama/PERSON has/O yet/O to/O charm/O many/O in/O Europe/LOCATION into/O accepting/O detainees/O ./O 
Obama/PERSON 's/O charisma/O has/O failed/O to/O inspire/O some/O EU/ORGANIZATION leaders/O to/O help/O 
``/O The/O US/LOCATION is/O taking/O a/O salesmanship/O approach/O to/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Anthony/PERSON Dworkin/PERSON ,/O a/O US/LOCATION foreign/O policy/O expert/O at/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Relations/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O It/O 's/O a/O mixture/O of/O appreciation/O and/O pressure/O ./O 
On/O the/O one/O hand/O ,/O the/O US/LOCATION says/O it/O would/O be/O really/O grateful/O if/O the/O Europeans/O help/O ,/O and/O on/O the/O other/O it/O says/O ,/O `/O well/O ,/O you/O told/O us/O to/O sort/O out/O this/O mess/O ,/O now/O help/O us/O to/O sort/O it/O out/O '/O ./O 
Mostly/O the/O Americans/O are/O making/O it/O very/O clear/O that/O any/O help/O will/O be/O much/O appreciated/O ./O ''/O 
Despite/O being/O given/O the/O chance/O to/O curry/O favor/O with/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O European/O governments/O on/O the/O whole/O are/O reluctant/O to/O help/O ,/O although/O some/O have/O grudgingly/O pledged/O to/O assist/O ./O 
Some/O of/O those/O who/O have/O agreed/O to/O take/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION detainees/O have/O preferred/O not/O to/O advertise/O the/O fact/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O the/O official/O numbers/O relating/O to/O European/O nations/O who/O have/O heeded/O Obama/PERSON 's/O call/O are/O sketchy/O ./O 
It/O is/O thought/O that/O about/O 10/O EU/ORGANIZATION member/O states/O have/O already/O accepted/O detainees/O ,/O including/O Britain/LOCATION ,/O France/LOCATION ,/O Ireland/LOCATION ,/O Italy/LOCATION and/O Portugal/LOCATION ./O 
Spain/LOCATION agrees/O to/O host/O detainees/O and/O rebuild/O US/LOCATION ties/O Spain/LOCATION confirmed/O its/O status/O as/O a/O public/O supporter/O of/O the/O policy/O this/O week/O when/O it/O announced/O that/O the/O process/O of/O accepting/O five/O inmates/O was/O nearing/O completion/O ;/O a/O move/O which/O earned/O praise/O from/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O 
Zapatero/PERSON 's/O Spain/LOCATION hopes/O to/O mend/O relations/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION 
Dworkin/PERSON believes/O that/O Spain/LOCATION is/O acting/O out/O of/O good/O faith/O towards/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O a/O reason/O that/O has/O inspired/O other/O countries/O to/O take/O in/O inmates/O ,/O but/O he/O also/O believes/O the/O Spanish/O government/O is/O looking/O to/O mend/O some/O fences/O ./O 
``/O This/O agreement/O to/O take/O in/O five/O inmates/O is/O an/O attempt/O to/O improve/O relations/O between/O Spain/LOCATION and/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O Relations/O took/O a/O downturn/O when/O Spain/LOCATION withdrew/O its/O troops/O out/O of/O Iraq/LOCATION ./O 
This/O offer/O is/O demonstrating/O a/O new/O Spanish/O approach/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Spain/LOCATION had/O announced/O in/O January/O that/O it/O was/O finalizing/O procedures/O for/O taking/O in/O two/O Guantanamo/LOCATION detainees/O ,/O a/O Palestinian/O and/O a/O Yemeni/O national/O ,/O but/O had/O not/O revealed/O the/O nationalities/O of/O the/O other/O three/O ./O 
Spain/LOCATION calls/O on/O EU/ORGANIZATION members/O to/O make/O good/O on/O pledge/O 
Moratinos/PERSON called/O on/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION to/O honor/O its/O pledge/O to/O help/O the/O US/LOCATION 
On/O Monday/O ,/O Spain/LOCATION 's/O Foreign/O Minister/O Miguel/PERSON Angel/PERSON Moratinos/PERSON called/O on/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION members/O to/O follow/O his/O country/O in/O taking/O in/O detainees/O ./O 
``/O We/O are/O encouraging/O other/O European/O countries/O to/O do/O their/O utmost/O ''/O on/O taking/O in/O former/O Guantanamo/LOCATION detainees/O ,/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O If/O we/O all/O agree/O -LRB-/O in/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O that/O Guantanamo/LOCATION was/O a/O horror/O ,/O an/O unacceptable/O and/O morally/O reprehensible/O anachronism/O ,/O then/O let/O us/O make/O the/O effort/O to/O close/O it/O down/O ./O ''/O 
Moratinos/PERSON also/O recalled/O that/O all/O 27/O EU/ORGANIZATION member/O states/O had/O previously/O said/O they/O would/O help/O President/O Obama/PERSON ,/O a/O commitment/O ``/O which/O explicitly/O included/O the/O possibility/O of/O accepting/O Guantanamo/LOCATION detainees/O on/O European/O soil/O ./O ''/O 
European/O powers/O dragging/O their/O heels/O Some/O European/O governments/O have/O been/O wary/O of/O agreeing/O to/O transfers/O because/O of/O security/O concerns/O and/O other/O domestic/O factors/O ,/O with/O a/O number/O of/O powerful/O EU/ORGANIZATION states/O the/O most/O conspicuous/O in/O their/O reluctance/O to/O help/O out/O ./O 
EU/ORGANIZATION nations/O harbor/O a/O number/O of/O concerns/O over/O detainees/O 
``/O Those/O countries/O which/O have/O not/O accepted/O inmates/O are/O refusing/O to/O do/O so/O for/O a/O variety/O of/O domestic/O reasons/O ,/O ''/O Dworkin/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O They/O wonder/O why/O they/O should/O take/O the/O security/O risk/O when/O the/O US/LOCATION is/O not/O prepared/O to/O do/O so/O ;/O there/O are/O also/O questions/O of/O internal/O politics/O which/O are/O preventing/O them/O for/O making/O decisions/O ,/O questions/O on/O legal/O issues/O and/O how/O accepting/O detainees/O would/O fit/O in/O with/O their/O asylum/O policies/O ./O 
The/O slow/O progress/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION in/O wrapping/O this/O all/O up/O is/O also/O a/O determining/O factor/O in/O some/O countries/O '/O reluctance/O ./O ''/O 
Germany/LOCATION is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O high/O profile/O countries/O to/O be/O dragging/O its/O heels/O ./O 
``/O Germany/LOCATION was/O asked/O by/O the/O US/LOCATION administration/O last/O year/O to/O take/O in/O between/O nine/O and/O 12/O -LRB-/O ethnic/O Chinese/O -RRB-/O Uyghur/O inmates/O ,/O mainly/O because/O there/O is/O an/O Uyghur/O exile/O community/O in/O Hamburg/LOCATION ,/O but/O the/O Germans/O refused/O ,/O ''/O Henning/PERSON Riecke/PERSON ,/O the/O head/O of/O the/O Transatlantic/ORGANIZATION Relations/ORGANIZATION Program/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>German/O Council/O on/O Foreign/O Relations/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O The/O German/O government/O did/O not/O accept/O because/O this/O would/O overshadow/O German-Chinese/O relations/O as/O Beijing/LOCATION considers/O the/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/LOCATION</OTHER> to/O be/O terrorists/O because/O they/O fight/O for/O independence/O ./O 
This/O was/O a/O weak/O response/O ,/O in/O my/O opinion/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>The/O</ORGANIZATION> Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Interior/ORGANIZATION also/O cited/O a/O fear/O of/O Islamist/O infiltration/O in/O its/O decision/O ./O ''/O 
The/O Interior/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION said/O at/O the/O time/O that/O the/O information/O it/O had/O received/O on/O the/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/LOCATION</OTHER> Germany/LOCATION was/O being/O asked/O to/O accept/O included/O details/O that/O they/O had/O been/O in/O terrorist/O training/O camps/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION before/O being/O sent/O to/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ./O 
It/O also/O expressed/O concern/O that/O any/O detainees/O accepted/O by/O an/O EU/ORGANIZATION country/O belonging/O to/O the/O Schengen/LOCATION area/O -/O in/O which/O there/O are/O no/O border/O controls/O -/O would/O be/O allowed/O to/O move/O freely/O among/O these/O countries/O ./O 
Almost/O a/O year/O on/O ,/O Germany/LOCATION -/O and/O many/O other/O EU/LOCATION countries/O -/O have/O still/O yet/O to/O make/O a/O commitment/O to/O hosting/O detainees/O and/O assisting/O President/O Obama/PERSON to/O achieve/O his/O goal/O of/O closing/O down/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ./O 
Author/O :/O Nick/PERSON Amies/PERSON 
Editor/O :/O Michael/PERSON Knigge/PERSON
