China/LOCATION will/O deploy/O more/O `/O anti-terrorism/O forces/O '/O to/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> following/O a/O series/O of/O deadly/O attacks/O there/O ./O 
The/O Public/O security/O minister/O emphasized/O that/O stability/O was/O important/O for/O China/LOCATION 's/O `/O overall/O security/O and/O unification/O ./O '/O 
4,000/O kilometers/O west/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O close/O to/O the/O Chinese/O border/O with/O Kirgizia/LOCATION and/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ,/O the/O clocks/O tick/O differently/O ./O 
People/O in/O the/O western/O Chinese/O city/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> live/O hours/O behind/O local/O Beijing/LOCATION --/O when/O people/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION are/O getting/O ready/O for/O bed/O ,/O people/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> are/O just/O sitting/O down/O for/O dinner/O ./O 
Yet/O there/O is/O only/O one/O time/O zone/O for/O the/O whole/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Last/O Saturday/O when/O people/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION were/O getting/O ready/O for/O bed/O and/O people/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> were/O getting/O ready/O for/O dinner/O ,/O news/O reports/O were/O broadcast/O :/O ``/O On/O Saturday/O at/O 11/O pm/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> two/O criminals/O stabbed/O a/O truck/O driver/O before/O hijacking/O his/O truck/O and/O driving/O it/O into/O a/O crowd/O ./O 
They/O then/O exited/O the/O vehicle/O ,/O stabbed/O six/O people/O with/O knives/O and/O injured/O 28/O others/O ./O 
The/O crowd/O was/O able/O to/O subdue/O the/O two/O attackers/O and/O one/O of/O them/O was/O killed/O ./O ''/O 
The/O Uighurs/O belong/O to/O a/O Turkic/O ethnic/O group/O and/O are/O related/O to/O the/O peoples/O of/O <LOCATION>Asia/O Minor/O</LOCATION> and/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION 
Just/O a/O day/O later/O ,/O men/O with/O knives/O attacked/O pedestrians/O on/O the/O street/O ./O 
Police/O shot/O two/O of/O the/O attackers/O ./O 
Around/O 15/O people/O died/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> on/O that/O weekend/O ./O 
The/O province/O 's/O party/O leader/O ,/O Zhang/PERSON Chun/PERSON Xian/PERSON ,/O spoke/O of/O acts/O of/O terrorism/O ,/O saying/O ,/O ``/O this/O dirty/O terrorism/O is/O a/O danger/O to/O the/O stability/O of/O society/O ,/O to/O the/O people/O and/O to/O the/O people/O 's/O property/O ./O ''/O 
Tension/O 
What/O Zhang/PERSON ,/O a/O Han/O Chinese/O like/O all/O provincial/O party/O leaders/O ,/O did/O not/O say/O is/O that/O all/O attackers/O were/O Uighurs/O who/O had/O apparently/O targeted/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
Ethnic/O tension/O heats/O up/O and/O results/O in/O violence/O time/O and/O time/O again/O between/O ethnic/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O the/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Two/O years/O ago/O ,/O Uighurs/O went/O on/O a/O murder/O spree/O in/O the/O streets/O of/O the/O province/O 's/O capital/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Han/O Chinese/O responded/O by/O hounding/O Muslims/O ./O 
At/O least/O 200/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O the/O unrest/O ./O 
Asgar/O <U_PERSON>Can/O</U_PERSON> of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> in/O Munich/LOCATION believes/O it/O was/O probably/O more/O than/O 200/O people/O ./O 
He/O believes/O ``/O the/O situation/O has/O gotten/O worse/O ./O 
It/O is/O much/O worse/O now/O than/O two/O years/O ago/O ./O ''/O 
Police/O officers/O patrol/O streets/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> a/O year/O after/O China/LOCATION 's/O worst/O ethnic/O violence/O in/O decades/O Leading/O up/O to/O the/O recent/O attacks/O ,/O the/O Uighurs/O have/O started/O feeling/O more/O and/O more/O like/O a/O minority/O in/O their/O own/O land/O ./O 
Shortly/O after/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION was/O founded/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION stationed/O large/O military/O units/O it/O its/O wild/O west/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O large-scale/O economic/O reforms/O in/O the/O 1980s/O opened/O up/O the/O doors/O to/O waves/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O immigrating/O to/O the/O region/O ./O 
Now/O the/O capital/O city/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O dominated/O by/O Han/O Chinese/O who/O have/O decided/O to/O reconstruct/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
`/O Loss/O of/O culture/O '/O Excavation/O work/O has/O been/O going/O on/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O historical/O town/O for/O two/O years/O now/O ./O 
Once/O a/O major/O commercial/O city/O along/O the/O historical/O <U_LOCATION>Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O city/O officials/O have/O decided/O that/O the/O old/O clay/O houses/O are/O no/O longer/O earthquake-proof/O ./O 
But/O the/O Uighurs/O secretly/O believe/O that/O the/O old/O town/O is/O being/O rebuilt/O because/O the/O soldiers/O are/O afraid/O of/O what/O could/O be/O hiding/O in/O the/O labyrinth-style/O grid/O of/O the/O old/O ,/O small/O and/O winding/O passageways/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> teaches/O at/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Language/LOCATION <ORGANIZATION>and/O</ORGANIZATION> Culture/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION and/O is/O watching/O what/O is/O happening/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> with/O great/O concern/O ./O 
``/O Our/O culture/O is/O slowly/O being/O destroyed/O ./O 
Many/O of/O us/O know/O that/O but/O we/O are/O afraid/O to/O talk/O about/O it/O ./O 
We/O know/O that/O it/O will/O lead/O to/O ethnic/O conflict/O sooner/O or/O later/O ,/O ''/O he/O adds/O ./O 
Uighurs/O use/O the/O Arabic/O script/O and/O speak/O their/O own/O Turkic/O language/O which/O is/O similar/O to/O Uzbek/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O pumping/O billions/O of/O yuan/O into/O its/O resource-rich/O northwestern/O province/O in/O the/O hope/O that/O economic/O growth/O will/O appease/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
But/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> says/O the/O money/O does/O not/O end/O up/O with/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
``/O All/O the/O lucrative/O jobs/O are/O done/O by/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O ''/O he/O says/O ./O 
People/O working/O at/O reception/O desks/O in/O large/O hotels/O or/O as/O ticket/O collectors/O in/O trains/O travelling/O to/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> are/O usually/O also/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
That/O means/O that/O people/O tend/O to/O speak/O Chinese/O instead/O of/O the/O Uighur/O language/O in/O public/O places/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> points/O out/O that/O when/O Uighurs/O speak/O Chinese/O and/O pronounce/O something/O wrong/O ,/O people/O make/O fun/O of/O them/O because/O the/O Han/O do/O not/O respect/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
``/O But/O who/O 's/O fault/O is/O the/O poor/O schooling/O ?/O 
It/O is/O the/O government/O 's/O ./O ''/O 
In/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> most/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O and/O Chinese/O live/O in/O separate/O worlds/O ./O 
Friendships/O between/O members/O of/O the/O two/O ethnic/O groups/O are/O rare/O ./O 
They/O live/O in/O separate/O parts/O of/O town/O ,/O shop/O in/O different/O stores/O ,/O and/O eat/O at/O different/O restaurants/O ./O 
A/O Chinese/O taxi/O driver/O says/O that/O 's/O just/O how/O it/O goes/O ./O 
``/O We/O stick/O to/O our/O own/O kind/O ./O 
There/O is/O a/O wall/O deep/O in/O our/O hearts/O ,/O ''/O he/O explains/O ./O 
`/O Ting/PERSON bu/O dong/O '/O 
Religion/O is/O not/O the/O only/O aspect/O that/O divides/O the/O two/O ethnicities/O ./O 
The/O Uighurs/O belong/O to/O a/O Turkic/O ethnic/O group/O and/O are/O related/O to/O the/O peoples/O of/O <LOCATION>Asia/O Minor/O</LOCATION> and/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
They/O use/O the/O Arabic/O script/O and/O speak/O their/O own/O Turkic/O language/O which/O is/O similar/O to/O Uzbek/O ./O 
One/O Uighur/O says/O ,/O ``/O I/O do/O n't/O like/O speaking/O Chinese/O because/O the/O Chinese/O always/O say/O `/O ting/O bu/O dong/O '/O when/O I/O tell/O them/O something/O ./O 
They/O tell/O me/O they/O do/O n't/O understand/O me/O and/O that/O I/O can/O not/O speak/O Chinese/O properly/O ./O 
My/O brother/O is/O afraid/O to/O speak/O Chinese/O --/O he/O does/O not/O have/O enough/O self-confidence/O ./O ''/O 
Once/O a/O major/O commercial/O city/O along/O the/O historical/O <U_LOCATION>Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O being/O rebuilt/O by/O Han/O Chinese/O Such/O things/O upset/O the/O Uighurs/O but/O most/O would/O not/O go/O so/O far/O as/O to/O use/O violence/O ./O 
Another/O Uighur/O says/O ,/O ``/O it/O was/O wrong/O ,/O what/O the/O terrorists/O did/O ./O 
I/O can/O understand/O that/O the/O government/O is/O worried/O ./O 
This/O used/O to/O be/O a/O very/O peaceful/O place/O to/O live/O ./O 
We/O are/O simple/O people/O who/O want/O to/O live/O in/O peace/O ./O 
We/O do/O n't/O like/O violence/O ./O ''/O 
After/O the/O latest/O attacks/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O many/O of/O the/O city/O 's/O shops/O and/O restaurants/O are/O closed/O as/O military/O personnel/O patrol/O the/O streets/O ./O 
Chinese/O propaganda/O has/O spread/O the/O news/O that/O last/O weekend/O 's/O attacks/O were/O carried/O out/O by/O terrorists/O who/O had/O been/O trained/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION in/O the/O use/O of/O guns/O and/O explosives/O ./O 
It/O does/O not/O add/O up/O ,/O then/O ,/O that/O they/O used/O knives/O in/O the/O attacks/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> does/O not/O believe/O that/O radical/O terrorist/O organizations/O like/O al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION have/O penetrated/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
``/O A/O radical/O form/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>Islam/O</ORGANIZATION> will/O never/O be/O the/O solution/O for/O us/O ./O 
If/O we/O ,/O who/O are/O such/O a/O small/O minority/O as/O it/O is/O ,/O allow/O ourselves/O to/O be/O misused/O by/O such/O groups/O ,/O it/O would/O only/O give/O the/O government/O more/O reason/O to/O suppress/O us/O ./O 
Ultimately/O ,/O we/O would/O suffer/O the/O consequences/O ,/O ''/O he/O says/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Frank/PERSON Hohmann/PERSON //O sb/O 
Editor/O :/O Arun/PERSON Chowdhury/PERSON
