Kashgar/LOCATION ,/O an/O oasis/O city/O of/O the/O Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION ,/O has/O been/O on/O the/O brink/O of/O extinction/O since/O the/O Chinese/O government/O introduced/O a/O plan/O to/O demolish/O much/O of/O the/O old/O town/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION two/O years/O ago/O ./O 
Kashgar/LOCATION ,/O an/O oasis/O city/O of/O the/O Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION ,/O is/O on/O the/O brink/O of/O extinction/O ./O 
Since/O the/O Chinese/O government/O introduced/O a/O plan/O to/O demolish/O much/O of/O the/O old/O town/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION two/O years/O ago/O ,/O 60-70/O per/O cent/O of/O the/O planned/O area/O has/O already/O been/O torn/O down/O ./O 
The/O president/O of/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON ,/O came/O to/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION Parliament/ORGANIZATION last/O week/O to/O ask/O for/O help/O ./O 
The/O city/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION is/O located/O in/O the/O western/O extreme/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
It/O has/O been/O the/O capital/O of/O many/O Uighur/O kingdoms/O in/O history/O ./O 
``/O Kashgar/LOCATION is/O Uighur/O ,/O and/O Uighur/O is/O Kashgar/LOCATION ''/O ,/O says/O Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O called/O by/O her/O people/O ``/O Mother/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O ''/O 
She/O says/O that/O Kashgar/LOCATION is/O a/O symbol/O for/O the/O cultural/O identity/O of/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ./O 
However/O ,/O this/O identity/O is/O being/O destroyed/O ./O 
The/O razing/O of/O the/O old/O town/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION is/O one/O example/O ./O 
The/O local/O government/O announced/O plans/O to/O demolish/O 85/O per/O cent/O of/O the/O historical/O old/O town/O and/O so/O far/O 60-70/O per/O cent/O of/O it/O has/O already/O disappeared/O ./O 
The/O process/O is/O accelerating/O ./O 
Traditional/O mud-and-straw/O buildings/O along/O narrow/O lanes/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION are/O thought/O by/O the/O government/O to/O be/O too/O fragile/O for/O earthquakes/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O only/O around/O 10/O per/O cent/O of/O the/O old/O town/O will/O eventually/O be/O preserved/O for/O touristic/O purposes/O ./O 
Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON asked/O for/O help/O from/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Parliament/ORGANIZATION ./O 
A/O conference/O was/O held/O on/O Thursday/O in/O Brussels/LOCATION by/O Frieda/PERSON Brepoels/PERSON ,/O Member/O of/O the/O Greens/ORGANIZATION and/O European/ORGANIZATION Free/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION parliamentary/O group/O ./O 
``/O It/O is/O the/O aim/O of/O this/O conference/O to/O identify/O Kashgar/LOCATION 's/O relevance/O to/O the/O Uighur/O identity/O of/O the/O region/O ,/O to/O draw/O attention/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O cultural/O diversity/O including/O the/O traditions/O of/O the/O ethnic/O Uighur/O community/O and/O to/O consider/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O reconstruction/O plans/O and/O its/O effect/O for/O the/O local/O people/O ,/O ''/O says/O Brepoels/PERSON ./O 
Six/O parliamentarians/O from/O different/O party/O groups/O attended/O the/O meeting/O ./O 
Frieda/PERSON Brepoels/PERSON said/O that/O was/O a/O ``/O very/O good/O result/O ./O ''/O 
In/O 2009/O the/O EP/O passed/O a/O resolution/O to/O call/O for/O protection/O of/O the/O cultural/O rights/O of/O Tibetans/O and/O Uighurs/O ./O 
``/O We/O have/O to/O go/O further/O than/O that/O and/O especially/O focus/O on/O the/O Kashgar/LOCATION situation/O ./O 
We/O 'll/O definitely/O have/O discussions/O with/O members/O who/O are/O interested/O in/O this/O in/O the/O following/O days/O and/O weeks/O ,/O ''/O promises/O Brepoels/O ./O 
Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON also/O called/O on/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O apply/O to/O UNESCO/ORGANIZATION to/O recognize/O Kashgar/LOCATION as/O a/O World/O Heritage/O site/O ./O 
Two/O years/O ago/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION took/O the/O Chinese/O section/O of/O the/O Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION onto/O a/O tentative/O list/O ,/O but/O Kashgar/LOCATION was/O not/O mentioned/O in/O it/O ./O 
Representatives/O from/O rights/O groups/O pointed/O out/O at/O the/O conference/O that/O what/O is/O going/O on/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION is/O not/O only/O a/O cultural/O issue/O ,/O but/O also/O a/O human/O rights/O issue/O ./O 
Contrary/O to/O what/O the/O government/O claims/O ,/O local/O people/O are/O not/O consulted/O before/O demolitions/O ./O 
Many/O Uighur/O families/O are/O losing/O their/O only/O source/O of/O living/O with/O their/O small/O shops/O and/O homes/O being/O torn/O down/O ./O 
The/O degree/O of/O dissatisfaction/O among/O Uighurs/O is/O high/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Miao/PERSON TianEditor/PERSON :/O Sarah/PERSON Berning/PERSON 
