China/LOCATION has/O sentenced/O four/O people/O to/O death/O over/O unrest/O in/O the/O ethnically-torn/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O after/O vowing/O to/O crack/O down/O on/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O in/O the/O troubled/O far-western/O area/O ./O 
Two/O courts/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION have/O sentenced/O four/O people/O to/O death/O after/O they/O were/O found/O guilty/O of/O masterminding/O and/O engaging/O in/O terrorist/O organizations/O ,/O illegally/O making/O explosives/O ,/O murder/O and/O arson/O ./O 
The/O official/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/ORGANIZATION agency/ORGANIZATION has/O reported/O that/O two/O others/O have/O received/O 19/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O their/O participation/O in/O violent/O outbreaks/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Protests/O had/O broken/O out/O in/O July/O among/O the/O mainly/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION minority/O against/O Chinese/O rule/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O government/O has/O ordered/O a/O crackdown/O on/O terrorism/O The/O rulings/O related/O to/O a/O July/O 18/O assault/O on/O a/O police/O station/O in/O Hotan/LOCATION which/O killed/O four/O people/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O two/O further/O attacks/O which/O happened/O on/O July/O 30/O and/O 31/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION and/O left/O 13/O dead/O ,/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O 
The/O wave/O of/O unrest/O killed/O at/O least/O 21/O people/O ,/O including/O eight/O suspects/O allegedly/O involved/O in/O the/O attacks/O ,/O prompting/O the/O top/O official/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION to/O vow/O a/O tough/O crackdown/O ./O 
An/O elite/O police/O counter-terror/O squad/O ,/O the/O Snow/ORGANIZATION Leopard/ORGANIZATION Commando/ORGANIZATION unit/O ,/O was/O sent/O to/O the/O area/O in/O August/O ./O 
Zhang/PERSON Chunxian/PERSON ,/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION chief/O for/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O had/O vowed/O a/O ``/O strike-hard/O policy/O in/O the/O crackdown/O against/O terrorists/O ./O ''/O 
Beijing/LOCATION blames/O Pakistan-trained/O extremists/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O blamed/O much/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION 's/O unrest/O on/O the/O ``/O three/O forces/O ''/O of/O extremism/O ,/O separatism/O and/O terrorism/O and/O said/O Pakistan-trained/O Muslim/O separatists/O were/O behind/O the/O latest/O attacks/O ./O 
Tensions/O between/O Uighurs/O and/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O have/O been/O common/O in/O the/O past/O years/O But/O many/O experts/O doubt/O that/O terror/O cells/O operate/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O where/O Uighurs/O are/O Sunni/O and/O practice/O a/O moderate/O form/O of/O Islam/O ./O 
They/O say/O the/O government/O has/O produced/O little/O evidence/O of/O an/O organized/O terrorist/O threat/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O and/O argue/O its/O sporadic/O bouts/O of/O unrest/O stem/O more/O from/O long-standing/O local/O resentment/O ./O 
Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O a/O resource-rich/O and/O strategically/O vital/O region/O that/O borders/O eight/O countries/O ,/O is/O home/O to/O roughly/O nine/O million/O Turkic-speaking/O Uighurs/O who/O have/O long/O bridled/O under/O what/O many/O see/O as/O government/O oppression/O ./O 
An/O influx/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O has/O fuelled/O anger/O ,/O with/O some/O Uighurs/O complaining/O that/O their/O culture/O is/O being/O deliberately/O diluted/O ./O 
They/O also/O claim/O that/O Han/O Chinese/O citizens/O get/O better/O jobs/O and/O pay/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Manasi/PERSON Gopalakrishnan/PERSON -LRB-/O AFP/O ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O Editor/O :/O Sarah/PERSON Berning/PERSON 
