The/O filthy/O back/O alleys/O and/O packed/O mosques/O of/O the/O remote/O western/O Chinese/O city/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> are/O one/O of/O the/O more/O obscure/O front/O lines/O in/O the/O U.S.-backed/O war/O on/O terror/O ,/O launched/O after/O the/O September/O 11/O ,/O 2001/O attacks/O ./O 
Streets/O crawl/O with/O baton-wielding/O riot/O police/O and/O heavily/O armed/O <ORGANIZATION>SWAT/O</ORGANIZATION> teams/O brought/O in/O for/O a/O trade/O fair/O ./O 
They/O are/O a/O tense/O reminder/O that/O China/LOCATION considers/O the/O region/O fertile/O ground/O for/O terrorism/O and/O Islamic/O radicalism/O ,/O a/O claim/O many/O scoff/O at/O ./O 
Ten/O years/O ago/O ,/O China/LOCATION used/O the/O 9/11/O attacks/O to/O justify/O cracking/O down/O on/O what/O it/O said/O were/O al/O Qaeda-backed/O extremists/O who/O wanted/O to/O bring/O similar/O carnage/O to/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O a/O heavily/O Muslim/O region/O with/O close/O cultural/O links/O to/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
More/O restrictions/O on/O Uighurs/O ,/O the/O Turkic-speaking/O people/O who/O call/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> home/O ,/O followed/O ./O 
Enjoying/O the/O economic/O boom/O :/O local/O Chinese/O Uighur/O citizens/O walk/O past/O apparel/O shops/O on/O a/O street/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 
Pumping/LOCATION in/O yuan/O China/LOCATION has/O used/O a/O carrot/O and/O stick/O approach/O ,/O going/O after/O Uighurs/O it/O suspects/O of/O harboring/O separatist/O views/O ,/O but/O also/O pumping/O in/O billions/O of/O yuan/O to/O boost/O development/O and/O lessen/O the/O appeal/O of/O the/O militants/O ./O 
Annual/O incomes/O in/O rural/O areas/O ,/O where/O most/O Uighurs/O live/O ,/O averaged/O just/O 4,600/O yuan/O -LRB-/O $/O 720/O -RRB-/O last/O year/O ,/O more/O than/O 1,000/O yuan/O below/O the/O national/O average/O and/O more/O than/O 5,000/O yuan/O below/O the/O top/O province/O ,/O Zhejiang/LOCATION ,/O in/O eastern/O China/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O main/O state-owned/O companies/O will/O double/O their/O investments/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> over/O the/O next/O five/O years/O to/O an/O eye-popping/O 991.6/O billion/O yuan/O -LRB-/O $/O 155/O billion/O -RRB-/O ,/O state/O media/O said/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION sees/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> as/O a/O bulwark/O facing/O the/O Muslim/O nations/O of/O central/O Asia/LOCATION ,/O and/O ,/O with/O a/O sixth/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O land/O mass/O ,/O as/O an/O important/O and/O largely/O empty/O space/O to/O offer/O some/O relief/O to/O the/O teeming/O provinces/O to/O the/O east/O ./O 
The/O land/O is/O also/O rich/O in/O natural/O resources/O ,/O including/O oil/O ,/O coal/O and/O gas/O ./O 
Any/O loss/O of/O control/O could/O wreak/O havoc/O in/O the/O world/O 's/O second/O largest/O economy/O ,/O whose/O growth/O Beijing/LOCATION sees/O as/O key/O to/O maintaining/O social/O stability/O and/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION 's/O grip/O on/O power/O ./O 
Police/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> prepare/O for/O deployment/O in/O the/O event/O of/O a/O riot/O 
Ethnic/O differences/O 
Riots/O between/O Uighurs/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> two/O years/O ago/O killed/O almost/O 200/O people/O ,/O deepening/O mutual/O suspicion/O ./O 
``/O We/O used/O to/O mix/O with/O the/O Chinese/O but/O no/O longer/O ./O 
That/O restaurant/O there/O once/O had/O many/O Chinese/O customers/O ./O 
No/O one/O dares/O to/O come/O here/O now/O ,/O ''/O said/O trader/O <U_PERSON>Anwar/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O pointing/O across/O the/O street/O to/O a/O kebab/O shop/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O heavily/O Uighur/O old/O quarter/O ./O 
The/O Han/O who/O dominate/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O rarely/O venture/O far/O into/O the/O old/O quarter/O and/O say/O they/O have/O little/O time/O for/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
If/O anything/O ,/O the/O Uighurs/O are/O treated/O too/O well/O ,/O Han/O Chinese/O say/O ,/O spoiled/O by/O preferential/O places/O at/O university/O and/O no/O restrictions/O on/O the/O number/O of/O children/O they/O can/O have/O ./O 
A/O `/O label/O '/O for/O the/O Uighurs/O 
The/O rather/O benign/O Han/O view/O of/O Uighurs/O which/O existed/O pre-September/O 11/O ,/O 2001/O as/O wild/O ,/O slightly/O lawless/O but/O generally/O affable/O and/O colourful/O people/O who/O love/O dancing/O and/O singing/O has/O been/O replaced/O with/O something/O much/O more/O sinister/O ./O 
``/O The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O always/O applied/O labels/O to/O Uighurs/O who/O chafe/O at/O its/O rule/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
They/O were/O feudal/O landlords/O first/O ,/O then/O they/O were/O Soviet/O stooges/O ,/O then/O they/O were/O counter-revolutionaries/O ,/O then/O they/O were/O separatists/O and/O after/O 9/11/O they/O became/O terrorists/O ,/O ''/O says/O Nicholas/PERSON Bequelin/PERSON ,/O a/O researcher/O on/O China/LOCATION for/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION ./O 
An/O ethnic/O Uighur/O woman/O with/O a/O headscarf/O 
A/O small/O number/O of/O Uighurs/O were/O indeed/O swept/O up/O by/O the/O U.S./LOCATION government/O during/O the/O Afghanistan/LOCATION war/O launched/O after/O the/O 9/11/O attacks/O ,/O though/O rights/O groups/O said/O they/O were/O simply/O in/O the/O wrong/O place/O at/O the/O wrong/O time/O ,/O having/O fled/O persecution/O at/O home/O ./O 
Despite/O Chinese/O protests/O ,/O the/O U.S./LOCATION ended/O up/O ruling/O they/O were/O not/O ``/O enemy/O combatants/O ''/O ,/O and/O sent/O them/O to/O a/O range/O of/O countries/O ,/O including/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION island/O state/O of/O Palau/LOCATION ./O 
The/O irony/O of/O all/O the/O security/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O elsewhere/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O that/O many/O experts/O do/O not/O consider/O <ORGANIZATION>al/O Qaeda/O</ORGANIZATION> or/O its/O supposed/O ally/O ,/O the/O ``/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ''/O ,/O to/O have/O anywhere/O near/O the/O influence/O China/LOCATION claims/O ./O 
China/LOCATION invariably/O blames/O attacks/O on/O the/O group/O ,/O which/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION regard/O as/O a/O terrorist/O organization/O ./O 
Still/O there/O are/O doubts/O about/O its/O strength/O ,/O or/O even/O existence/O ./O 
Reuters/ORGANIZATION 
Editor/O :/O Grahame/PERSON Lucas/PERSON
