Three/O men/O accused/O of/O plotting/O to/O bomb/O the/O Danish/O newspaper/O ,/O Jyllands-Posten/LOCATION ,/O for/O printing/O cartoons/O of/O the/O prophet/O Mohammed/PERSON pleaded/O not/O guilty/O in/O a/O Norwegian/O court/O on/O Tuesday/O ./O 
The/O trio/O of/O Norwegian/O citizens/O ,/O believed/O to/O have/O ties/O to/O al-Qaeda/O ,/O is/O suspected/O of/O planning/O an/O attack/O and/O acquiring/O ingredients/O to/O make/O explosives/O to/O bomb/O the/O Danish/O Jyllands-Posten/LOCATION newspaper/O for/O printing/O cartoons/O of/O the/O prophet/O Mohammed/PERSON ,/O which/O is/O considered/O blasphemous/O in/O Islam/LOCATION ./O 
They/O have/O been/O charged/O with/O ``/O conspiracy/O to/O commit/O a/O terrorist/O attack/O ./O ''/O 
If/O convicted/O ,/O the/O men/O face/O up/O to/O 20/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O 
The/O men/O ,/O who/O were/O arrested/O in/O July/O 2010/O ,/O had/O bought/O bomb-making/O materials/O ,/O including/O hydrogen/O peroxide/O and/O acetone/O ,/O which/O police/O discovered/O in/O a/O cellar/O belonging/O to/O one/O of/O them/O ./O 
The/O men/O have/O been/O identified/O as/O Mikael/PERSON Davud/PERSON ,/O a/O Norwegian/O of/O Uighur/O origin/O ,/O Shawan/PERSON Sadek/PERSON Saeed/PERSON Bujak/PERSON ,/O an/O Iraqi/O Kurd/O residing/O in/O Norway/LOCATION and/O David/PERSON Jakobsen/PERSON ,/O an/O ethnic/O Uzbek/O also/O living/O in/O Norway/LOCATION ./O 
Police/O found/O weapons/O manuals/O ,/O bomb-making/O instructions/O and/O pro/O al-Qaeda/O propaganda/O on/O Davud/PERSON 's/O computer/O in/O Norway/LOCATION ./O 
During/O earlier/O interviews/O ,/O Davud/PERSON and/O Bujak/PERSON had/O both/O admitted/O that/O they/O were/O planning/O an/O attack/O ,/O although/O their/O versions/O have/O differed/O on/O the/O target/O ./O 
Davud/PERSON had/O claimed/O the/O target/O was/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O in/O Oslo/LOCATION ,/O while/O Bujak/PERSON had/O said/O it/O was/O the/O Jyllands-Posten/LOCATION newspaper/O ./O 
Jyllands-Posten/LOCATION was/O the/O first/O of/O several/O European/O publications/O in/O 2005/O to/O print/O cartoons/O lampooning/O Mohammed/PERSON ,/O sparking/O violent/O protests/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION and/O Africa/LOCATION ,/O and/O generating/O a/O widespread/O debate/O about/O freedom/O of/O the/O press/O ./O 
The/O most/O controversial/O cartoons/O were/O illustrated/O by/O Kurt/PERSON Westergaard/PERSON ,/O which/O featured/O Mohammed/PERSON with/O a/O bomb/O under/O his/O turban/O ./O 
Since/O the/O cartoons/O were/O published/O ,/O Westergaard/PERSON and/O the/O Danish/O newspaper/O have/O been/O the/O targets/O of/O numerous/O threats/O from/O Islamist/O circles/O ./O 
Westergaard/PERSON was/O the/O victim/O of/O a/O murder/O attempt/O in/O January/O 2010/O ,/O when/O an/O ax-wielding/O man/O burst/O into/O his/O home/O ./O 
He/O now/O lives/O under/O round-the-clock/O protection/O ./O 
The/O trial/O in/O Oslo/LOCATION comes/O less/O than/O two/O weeks/O after/O the/O offices/O of/O the/O French/O satirical/O weekly/O Charlie/PERSON Hebdo/PERSON were/O firebombed/O in/O Paris/LOCATION as/O it/O published/O an/O edition/O featuring/O Mohammed/PERSON as/O ``/O guest/O editor/O ''/O on/O the/O cover/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Gregg/PERSON Benzow/PERSON -LRB-/O dpa/O ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O Editor/O :/O Andreas/PERSON Illmer/PERSON 
