What/O kind/O of/O rock/O music/O is/O China/LOCATION making/O ,/O and/O what/O do/O hip-hop/O and/O old/O English/O dance/O styles/O have/O in/O common/O ?/O 
The/O 22nd/O edition/O of/O the/O TFF/O <LOCATION>Rudolstadt/O</LOCATION> festival/O had/O some/O answers/O -/O and/O much/O more/O ./O 
Joy/O and/O sadness/O came/O all/O at/O once/O at/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O largest/O world/O music/O festival/O ./O 
Some/O of/O the/O finest/O concertina/O players/O in/O the/O world/O had/O arranged/O for/O a/O joint/O concert/O ,/O rehearsing/O together/O for/O a/O week/O ahead/O of/O time/O ./O 
One/O of/O them/O was/O 84/O -/O year-old/O Horst/PERSON Foit/PERSON ./O 
Before/O his/O appearance/O ,/O he/O had/O said/O that/O he/O simply/O could/O not/O believe/O that/O so/O many/O people/O wanted/O to/O hear/O his/O music/O ./O 
But/O he/O suffered/O a/O heart/O attack/O while/O standing/O overjoyed/O on/O stage/O ./O 
The/O concert/O had/O to/O be/O cancelled/O ,/O and/O Foit/PERSON went/O to/O the/O emergency/O room/O ./O 
The/O other/O musicians/O decided/O to/O make/O up/O the/O concertina/O program/O the/O next/O night/O ,/O devoting/O it/O to/O their/O colleague/O ./O 
<LOCATION>Rudolstadt/O</LOCATION> prize-winners/O :/O the/O Al/O Andaluz/O Project/O 
The/O concertina/O ,/O a/O baby/O cousin/O of/O the/O accordion/O ,/O was/O one/O focal/O point/O of/O the/O 22nd/O Dance/O and/O Folk/O Festival/O in/O <LOCATION>Rudolstadt/O</LOCATION> -LRB-/O TFF/O <LOCATION>Rudolstadt/O</LOCATION> -RRB-/O ,/O which/O ended/O this/O week/O after/O hosting/O 85,000/O visitors/O at/O 20/O festival/O stages/O ./O 
With/O 163/O acts/O ,/O bands/O ,/O ensembles/O and/O artists/O from/O 40/O countries/O ,/O the/O festival/O again/O offered/O its/O special/O blend/O of/O traditional/O and/O contemporary/O global/O and/O local/O music/O ,/O from/O folk/O and/O reggae/O to/O hip-hop/O ,/O country/O and/O Chinese/O opera/O ./O 
Diverse/O genres/O from/O China/LOCATION 
There/O are/O probably/O two/O things/O that/O spring/O to/O mind/O when/O people/O in/O the/O West/LOCATION think/O of/O music/O from/O China/LOCATION :/O cheesy/O pop/O songs/O at/O a/O local/O Chinese/O joint/O and/O the/O often/O inaccessible/O Chinese/O opera/O with/O its/O dramatic/O effects/O and/O shrill/O vocals/O ./O 
But/O that/O 's/O far/O from/O all/O China/LOCATION has/O to/O offer/O musically/O ,/O as/O festival-goers/O this/O year/O could/O discover/O ./O 
There/O was/O opera/O ,/O but/O there/O was/O also/O music/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O ,/O a/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ethnic/O minority/O ./O 
The/O band/O <ORGANIZATION>Er/O Shou/PERSON Mei/PERSON Gui/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> offered/O contemporary/O rock/O music/O ,/O and/O singer/O Gong/PERSON Linna/PERSON appeared/O with/O the/O first/O Chinese/O folk/O music/O choir/O ,/O <ORGANIZATION>DaBaiSong/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Gong/PERSON Linna/PERSON also/O took/O part/O in/O an/O orchestral/O project/O featuring/O the/O Thuringian/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Symphony/ORGANIZATION Orchestra/ORGANIZATION ,/O whose/O members/O have/O appeared/O at/O the/O TFF/O <LOCATION>Rudolstadt/O</LOCATION> for/O several/O years/O ./O 
Street/O musicians/O of/O every/O stripe/O take/O to/O the/O festival/O 
Dancing/O in/O the/O streets/O 
Even/O for/O seasoned/O TFF/O fans/O ,/O it/O 's/O a/O welcome/O surprise/O each/O year/O to/O see/O how/O engaged/O the/O audience/O is/O at/O the/O events/O ./O 
There/O are/O countless/O street/O music/O ensembles/O that/O play/O everywhere/O in/O the/O city/O ,/O and/O numerous/O visitors/O also/O bring/O along/O their/O instruments/O ./O 
They/O like/O to/O jam/O out/O wherever/O they/O please/O ,/O or/O they/O can/O head/O to/O the/O various/O concerts/O and/O workshops/O where/O there/O are/O chances/O to/O dance/O and/O play/O along/O ./O 
Street/O dance/O styles/O ranging/O from/O folk/O to/O hip-hop/O are/O still/O an/O important/O ingredient/O in/O the/O <LOCATION>Rudolstadt/O</LOCATION> music/O mix/O ./O 
The/O amateurs/O in/O <LOCATION>Rudolstadt/O</LOCATION> perform/O at/O a/O high/O level/O ./O 
Providing/O the/O backdrop/O around/O nearly/O every/O corner/O are/O the/O sounds/O of/O solo/O guitarists/O ,/O percussion/O ensembles/O ,/O cajon/O players/O and/O even/O entire/O Balkan/O combos/O ./O 
When/O the/O weather/O permits/O ,/O the/O street/O music/O is/O often/O as/O big/O of/O a/O draw/O as/O the/O stage/O programming/O ./O 
Prize-winning/O unknowns/O Hannes/PERSON Wader/PERSON won/O the/O festival/O 's/O lifetime/O achievement/O award/O 
Ruth/PERSON is/O the/O name/O of/O the/O world/O music/O award/O presented/O annually/O to/O three/O musicians/O at/O <OTHER>TFF/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> <LOCATION>Rudolstadt/ORGANIZATION</LOCATION> ./O 
This/O time/O ,/O protest/O singer/O Hannes/PERSON Wader/O from/O Germany/LOCATION received/O the/O award/O for/O lifetime/O achievement/O ./O 
Wader/O confessed/O that/O he/O had/O not/O yet/O received/O a/O single/O prize/O in/O his/O 50-year/O career/O as/O an/O artist/O and/O that/O at/O his/O age/O he/O prefers/O to/O write/O songs/O about/O death/O or/O women/O than/O about/O current/O political/O affairs/O ./O 
The/O Al/ORGANIZATION 
Andaluz/ORGANIZATION Project/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O consortium/O of/O German/O ,/O Spanish/O and/O Moroccan/O musicians/O ,/O was/O also/O awarded/O a/O prize/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Strottern/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> ,/O who/O now/O play/O their/O modernist/O ,/O blues-filled/O Viennese/O songs/O with/O backing/O from/O wind/O players/O ./O 
There/O are/O very/O few/O big/O names/O in/O <LOCATION>Rudolstadt/O</LOCATION> ,/O even/O among/O the/O prize-winners/O ,/O but/O the/O festival/O does/O n't/O live/O from/O star/O power/O ./O 
There/O are/O ,/O however/O ,/O a/O few/O exceptions/O in/O each/O year/O 's/O program/O ,/O like/O German/O reggae/O superstar/O Gentleman/O or/O American/O singer-songwriter/O Alison/PERSON Krauss/PERSON in/O 2012/O ./O 
The/O draw/O of/O <LOCATION>Rudolstadt/O</LOCATION> lies/O much/O more/O in/O the/O discovery/O of/O the/O new/O ,/O and/O in/O being/O part/O of/O a/O spring-up/O community/O that/O is/O singular/O in/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O festival/O season/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Matthias/PERSON Klaus/PERSON //O gsw/O Editor/O :/O Kate/PERSON Bowen/PERSON
