Chinese/O Vice/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON is/O expected/O to/O visit/O Ireland/LOCATION on/O Saturday/O after/O he/O finishes/O his/O high-profile/O US/LOCATION tour/O ./O 
In/O an/O interview/O with/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ,/O David/PERSON O'Brien/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O on/O China/LOCATION ,/O talks/O about/O the/O importance/O of/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O Ireland/LOCATION visit/O ./O 
David/PERSON O'Brien/PERSON is/O a/O China/LOCATION researcher/O at/O the/O School/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Asian/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION <OTHER>of/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> <OTHER>the/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> University/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION Cork/ORGANIZATION ,/O Ireland/LOCATION ./O 
Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION :/O Vice/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON is/O going/O to/O Ireland/LOCATION this/O week/O ./O 
What/O is/O the/O reason/O for/O his/O visit/O ?/O 
David/PERSON O`Brien/PERSON :/O Well/O I/O think/O some/O eyebrows/O were/O raised/O in/O Ireland/LOCATION when/O it/O was/O announced/O that/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON would/O visit/O Ireland/LOCATION as/O part/O of/O his/O trip/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O Turkey/LOCATION as/O very/O high/O level/O trip/O particularly/O -LRB-/O because/O -RRB-/O it/O was/O his/O first/O visit/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON will/O spend/O three/O days/O in/O total/O in/O Ireland/LOCATION which/O for/O such/O a/O small/O country/O is/O a/O relatively/O long/O visit/O ./O 
I/O think/O the/O key/O thing/O here/O is/O that/O China/LOCATION sees/O Ireland/LOCATION as/O a/O potential/O gateway/O to/O Europe/LOCATION ./O 
We/O have/O relatively/O a/O large/O trade/O volume/O of/O 8.3/O billion/O euros/O between/O the/O countries/O ./O 
What/O makes/O it/O interesting/O is/O that/O Ireland/LOCATION is/O one/O of/O the/O few/O countries/O to/O run/O a/O trade/O surplus/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O 
And/O I/O think/O trade/O is/O the/O key/O issue/O during/O his/O visit/O ./O 
There/O is/O also/O I/O think/O an/O emotional/O aspect/O to/O his/O visit/O ./O 
In/O that/O his/O father/O Xi/PERSON Zhongxun/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O involved/O in/O the/O setting/O up/O of/O the/O Shenzhen/LOCATION special/O economic/O zone/O and/O he/O modelled/O that/O economic/O zone/O very/O much/O on/O the/O Shannon/LOCATION free/O trade/O zone/O ,/O which/O I/O think/O marks/O another/O indication/O of/O trade/O being/O the/O key/O to/O the/O visit/O ./O 
Would/O you/O also/O say/O that/O Xi/PERSON is/O expected/O to/O help/O Ireland/LOCATION financially/O ?/O 
Well/O ,/O I/O think/O the/O indications/O are/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O going/O to/O become/O more/O involved/O in/O helping/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION financially/O ./O 
I/O would/O n't/O expect/O any/O bilateral/O agreements/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O Ireland/LOCATION to/O come/O out/O of/O this/O visit/O ./O 
But/O the/O fact/O that/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> is/O visiting/O at/O a/O time/O when/O Ireland/LOCATION 's/O economy/O -/O although/O showing/O some/O signs/O of/O recovery/O -/O is/O still/O in/O a/O very/O precarious/O situation/O is/O of/O course/O significant/O ./O 
And/O the/O Irish/O government/O is/O extremely/O well/O aware/O of/O the/O importance/O of/O this/O visit/O and/O the/O need/O to/O continue/O to/O grow/O in/O the/O Chinese/O market/O ./O 
I/O think/O from/O the/O Irish/O government/O 's/O point/O of/O view/O is/O that/O they/O see/O this/O as/O a/O real/O opportunity/O to/O develop/O further/O trade/O links/O with/O China/LOCATION ,/O as/O well/O as/O develop/O a/O personal/O relationship/O with/O the/O man/O who/O will/O in/O October/O become/O one/O of/O the/O most/O powerful/O people/O in/O the/O world/O ./O 
Besides/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O Ireland/LOCATION is/O the/O only/O country/O in/O Europe/LOCATION <PERSON>Xi/LOCATION</PERSON> is/O visiting/O ./O 
Do/O you/O think/O there/O is/O any/O special/O reason/O for/O Ireland/LOCATION ?/O 
Well/O ,/O I/O mean/O the/O cynic/O in/O me/O kind/O of/O looks/O at/O it/O as/O a/O stopover/O -/O a/O refueling/O stop/O ./O 
But/O there/O is/O a/O personal/O connection/O ,/O he/O is/O going/O to/O Ireland/LOCATION because/O of/O his/O father/O 's/O involvement/O with/O the/O setting/O up/O of/O the/O Shenzhen/LOCATION SEZ/LOCATION ,/O I/O think/O he/O also/O has/O an/O interest/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
He/O met/O our/O former/O president/O Mary/PERSON McAleese/PERSON at/O the/O Shanghai/LOCATION Expo/LOCATION in/O 2010/O and/O the/O meeting/O was/O scheduled/O to/O last/O about/O 45/O minutes/O and/O in/O the/O end/O it/O went/O to/O almost/O two/O hours/O and/O I/O think/O people/O were/O surprised/O by/O that/O and/O his/O level/O of/O engagement/O with/O Ireland/LOCATION ./O 
Can/O you/O say/O something/O about/O the/O expectations/O surrounding/O his/O visit/O in/O the/O Irish/O media/O ?/O 
Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON is/O still/O not/O particularly/O well/O known/O in/O Ireland/LOCATION and/O though/O anyone/O that/O follows/O China/LOCATION or/O has/O an/O interest/O in/O China/LOCATION will/O have/O heard/O of/O him/O ,/O there/O has/O n't/O been/O a/O huge/O amount/O of/O coverage/O ./O 
You/O can/O in/O no/O way/O compare/O the/O visit/O of/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON with/O last/O year/O 's/O visit/O of/O the/O Queen/O of/O England/LOCATION or/O President/O Obama/PERSON ./O 
But/O I/O think/O there/O is/O a/O growing/O awareness/O in/O Ireland/LOCATION of/O our/O bilateral/O relations/O with/O China/LOCATION and/O of/O the/O potential/O for/O further/O trade/O between/O the/O two/O nations/O ./O 
One/O aspect/O that/O of/O course/O is/O commented/O on/O is/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O Irish/O government/O will/O bring/O up/O any/O of/O the/O more/O controversial/O issues/O such/O as/O human/O rights/O ,/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O various/O other/O controversial/O matters/O ./O 
The/O clear/O indication/O in/O the/O media/O is/O that/O it/O is/O completely/O off/O the/O agenda/O and/O that/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION is/O the/O forum/O for/O this/O topic/O ./O 
Was/O there/O any/O reaction/O in/O the/O media/O about/O his/O USA/LOCATION trip/O ,/O how/O was/O it/O perceived/O ?/O 
Well/O there/O is/O coverage/O in/O the/O papers/O today/O about/O it/O and/O it/O certainly/O is/O perceived/O as/O a/O meeting/O that/O in/O many/O ways/O will/O potentially/O go/O well/O for/O both/O individuals/O ,/O the/O leaders/O of/O the/O two/O world/O superpowers/O for/O the/O coming/O years/O ./O 
I/O think/O the/O coverage/O in/O the/O Irish/O media/O is/O maybe/O focused/O on/O the/O fact/O that/O US-Chinese/O relations/O are/O going/O through/O a/O period/O of/O transition/O and/O as/O the/O US/LOCATION becomes/O more/O involved/O in/O Asia/LOCATION ,/O with/O the/O opening/O of/O a/O base/O in/O Australia/LOCATION and/O continuing/O from/O a/O Chinese/O perspective/O to/O become/O involved/O in/O its/O sphere/O of/O influence/O ./O 
Interview/O :/O Phyllis/PERSON Kuhn/PERSON 
Editor/O :/O Grahame/PERSON Lucas/PERSON
