Prominent/O Chinese/O rights/O activist/O Hu/PERSON Jia/PERSON spoke/O to/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION about/O his/O detention/O and/O interrogation/O by/O Chinese/O police/O ./O 
Hu/PERSON 's/O home/O was/O recently/O raided/O and/O he/O was/O threatened/O with/O detention/O for/O expressing/O his/O views/O ./O 
Hu/PERSON Jia/PERSON ,/O 38/O ,/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O prominent/O Chinese/O dissidents/O active/O in/O the/O country/O 's/O repressed/O democracy/O movement/O ./O 
He/O is/O also/O a/O campaigner/O for/O environmental/O protection/O and/O an/O advocate/O for/O rural/O victims/O of/O AIDS/O ./O 
He/O was/O imprisoned/O in/O 2008/O as/O part/O of/O a/O crackdown/O on/O dissents/O ahead/O of/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympics/O and/O served/O a/O three/O and/O a/O half/O year/O sentence/O for/O ``/O inciting/O subversion/O of/O state/O power/O ,/O ''/O charges/O to/O which/O he/O did/O not/O plead/O guilty/O ./O 
Upon/O Hu/PERSON 's/O release/O from/O prison/O on/O June/O 26/O last/O year/O ,/O he/O was/O told/O not/O to/O accept/O interviews/O from/O foreign/O reporters/O ./O 
He/O was/O also/O banned/O from/O protesting/O ,/O publishing/O his/O comments/O online/O and/O speaking/O out/O in/O any/O way/O ./O 
Sharon/PERSON Hom/PERSON ,/O executive/O director/O at/O international/O NGO/O Human/O Rights/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION that/O following/O his/O release/O ,/O Hu/PERSON was/O subjected/O to/O a/O year-long/O deprivation/O of/O political/O rights/O -LRB-/O DPR/O -RRB-/O ,/O a/O measure/O sanctioned/O under/O Chinese/O law/O ./O 
While/O the/O actions/O of/O police/O may/O have/O been/O authorized/O under/O Chinese/O DPR/O legislation/O ,/O they/O nonetheless/O ``/O undermine/O rights/O protected/O by/O China/LOCATION 's/O international/O human/O rights/O obligations/O to/O respect/O fundamental/O rights/O and/O freedoms/O ,/O ''/O said/O Hom/PERSON ./O 
Hu/PERSON spoke/O to/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION on/O Thursday/O ,/O following/O an/O eight-hour/O ordeal/O in/O which/O police/O interrogated/O him/O at/O a/O district/O police/O headquarters/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
He/O said/O authorities/O grilled/O him/O over/O three/O separate/O issues/O they/O took/O issue/O with/O ./O 
``/O First/O of/O all/O ,/O US/LOCATION Congressman/O Chris/PERSON Smith/PERSON planned/O to/O visit/O the/O blind/O Chinese/O rights/O lawyer/O Chen/PERSON Guangcheng/PERSON but/O the/O government/O refused/O his/O entry/O to/O the/O country/O ./O 
I/O commended/O his/O move/O and/O his/O care/O for/O Chen/PERSON on/O -LSB-/O social/O media/O tool/O -RSB-/O Twitter/O ,/O ''/O said/O Hu/PERSON ./O 
He/O appealed/O to/O the/O public/O to/O travel/O to/O Dongshigu/LOCATION village/O in/O Shangdong/LOCATION province/LOCATION ,/O where/O Chen/PERSON was/O under/O house/O arrest/O ./O 
Hu/PERSON said/O this/O could/O leverage/O pressure/O on/O the/O local/O government/O to/O free/O Chen/PERSON ./O 
The/O second/O matter/O police/O wanted/O to/O speak/O with/O Hu/PERSON about/O was/O a/O call/O he/O made/O to/O Twitter/O users/O to/O send/O postcards/O to/O a/O remote/O prison/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O outspoken/O rights/O lawyer/O Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON was/O jailed/O ./O 
He/O said/O there/O was/O a/O chance/O that/O conditions/O for/O Gao/PERSON could/O improve/O if/O authorities/O knew/O that/O the/O public/O were/O keeping/O track/O of/O him/O ./O 
The/O third/O issue/O related/O to/O Hu/PERSON 's/O confirmation/O to/O the/O international/O community/O that/O Nobel/O Peace/O laureate/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON 's/O wife/O Liu/PERSON Xia/PERSON was/O currently/O under/O illegal/O detention/O by/O the/O government/O ./O 
``/O Actually/O I/O 've/O published/O quite/O a/O lot/O of/O comments/O recently/O but/O the/O policemen/O only/O pinpointed/O these/O three/O issues/O ./O 
So/O we/O can/O see/O these/O dissidents/O '/O names/O are/O the/O most/O sensitive/O and/O threatening/O to/O the/O government/O at/O the/O moment/O ,/O ''/O said/O Hu/PERSON ,/O adding/O that/O he/O has/O been/O warned/O by/O police/O that/O he/O faces/O further/O detention/O if/O he/O continues/O to/O be/O so/O outspoken/O ./O 
Hu/PERSON said/O he/O was/O surprised/O by/O the/O police/O raid/O late/O Wednesday/O :/O ``/O In/O the/O past/O ,/O policemen/O have/O entered/O my/O house/O ,/O but/O on/O those/O occasions/O they/O were/O n't/O wearing/O uniforms/O ./O 
They/O came/O in/O stealthily/O ./O 
But/O last/O night/O ,/O eight/O uniformed/O policemen/O descended/O upon/O my/O house/O at/O around/O 8/O o'clock/O with/O a/O police/O car/O and/O stayed/O for/O around/O one/O and/O a/O half/O hours/O ./O 
That/O means/O this/O time/O they/O based/O their/O raid/O on/O a/O legitimate/O procedure/O with/O a/O search/O warrant/O ,/O ''/O said/O Hu/PERSON ./O 
The/O policemen/O claimed/O they/O had/O found/O data/O on/O his/O laptop/O which/O showed/O his/O violation/O of/O DPR/O laws/O ,/O prompting/O them/O to/O confiscate/O his/O and/O his/O wife/O 's/O computers/O for/O further/O investigation/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O are/O expected/O to/O keep/O a/O tighter/O lid/O on/O dissidents/O and/O rights/O defenders/O before/O the/O upcoming/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION National/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION and/O power/O transitions/O expected/O to/O take/O place/O in/O China/LOCATION later/O this/O year/O ./O 
However/O ,/O ``/O recent/O mass/O protests/O ,/O such/O as/O a/O villagers/O '/O protest/O in/O Wukan/LOCATION and/O the/O influential/O rise/O of/O microblogs/O and/O -LSB-/O Chinese/O Twitter/O equivalent/O -RSB-/O Weibo/PERSON are/O pressuring/O the/O authorities/O to/O respond/O to/O demands/O and/O problems/O ,/O ''/O said/O Hom/PERSON ./O 
``/O They/O can/O not/O continue/O to/O silence/O or/O intimidate/O these/O voices/O successfully/O ./O ''/O 
Author/O :/O Miriam/PERSON Wong/PERSON Editor/O :/O Darren/PERSON Mara/PERSON 
