A/O new/O report/O on/O minorities/O and/O indigenous/O people/O warns/O that/O the/O global/O `/O intensification/O '/O in/O the/O exploitation/O of/O natural/O resources/O is/O leading/O to/O mounting/O conflicts/O for/O the/O world/O 's/O 370/O million/O indigenous/O people/O ./O 
The/O report/O for/O 2012/O by/O the/O London-based/O human/O rights/O group/O ,/O Minority/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O MRG/O -RRB-/O ,/O says/O indigenous/O peoples/O ``/O in/O every/O region/O of/O the/O world/O ''/O face/O the/O risk/O of/O being/O ``/O driven/O from/O their/O land/O and/O natural/O resources/O ./O ''/O 
The/O land/O and/O resources/O are/O all/O ``/O vital/O for/O their/O livelihoods/O ,/O their/O culture/O and/O often/O their/O identity/O as/O a/O people/O ,/O ''/O Vital/PERSON Bambanze/PERSON ,/O chair/O of/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Expert/O Mechanism/O on/O the/O Rights/O of/O Indigenous/O Peoples/O ,/O said/O in/O the/O report/O ./O 
Coal/O mining/O projects/O have/O disturbed/O the/O lives/O of/O ethnic/O Mongolians/O From/O the/O Batwa/LOCATION of/LOCATION the/LOCATION Great/LOCATION Lakes/LOCATION region/O in/O Central/LOCATION Africa/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O Endorois/O and/O Ogiek/LOCATION in/O Kenya/LOCATION ,/O to/O hill/O tribes/O in/O northern/O Thailand/LOCATION ,/O Bedouin/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION and/O Uighurs/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O -/O all/O ``/O struggle/O to/O maintain/O their/O cultural/O integrity/O against/O their/O respective/O governments/O '/O desire/O to/O put/O national/O development/O first/O ,/O ''/O Bambanze/PERSON said/O ./O 
Unprecedented/O demand/O for/O resources/O in/O Asia/LOCATION The/O report/O says/O the/O unprecedented/O demand/O for/O natural/O resources/O across/O Asia/LOCATION is/O ``/O feeding/O ethnic/O conflict/O and/O displacement/O and/O is/O a/O severe/O threat/O to/O the/O lands/O ,/O livelihoods/O and/O the/O way/O of/O life/O of/O minorities/O and/O indigenous/O people/O ./O ''/O 
Carl/PERSON Soderbergh/PERSON ,/O an/O MRG/O spokesperson/O ,/O warns/O the/O situation/O faced/O by/O indigenous/O groups/O is/O deteriorating/O world-wide/O ./O 
``/O In/O terms/O of/O the/O trends/O globally/O what/O has/O been/O happening/O over/O the/O last/O decade/O is/O that/O there/O 's/O been/O an/O intensification/O of/O the/O exploitation/O of/O natural/O resources/O pushing/O into/O areas/O populated/O by/O minorities/O and/O indigenous/O peoples/O ,/O ''/O Soderbergh/PERSON told/O DW/O ./O 
Many/O indigenous/O communities/O have/O their/O land/O confiscated/O In/O regions/O such/O as/O Latin/LOCATION America/LOCATION ,/O the/O issues/O faced/O by/O communities/O centered/O on/O mining/O and/O logging/O ,/O in/O North/LOCATION America/LOCATION on/O tar-sands/O mining/O ,/O there/O were/O conflicts/O over/O wind/O farms/O and/O iron/O ore/O mining/O in/O the/O Arctic/LOCATION ,/O while/O in/O Africa/LOCATION ,/O indigenous/O communities/O faced/O the/O leasing/O of/O thousands/O of/O hectares/O of/O land/O for/O corporations/O or/O foreign/O governments/O ./O 
``/O All/O governments/O are/O chasing/O a/O dominant/O development/O paradigm/O n/O which/O today/O minorities/O and/O indigenous/O peoples/O do/O n't/O really/O have/O a/O place/O and/O that/O is/O a/O problem/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
In/O China/LOCATION ,/O investment/O in/O mining/O has/O forced/O herders/O off/O traditional/O grazing/O lands/O and/O ancestral/O villages/O in/O regions/O such/O as/O Xinjiang/LOCATION Uighur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION ,/O as/O well/O as/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
In/O Vietnam/LOCATION ,/O over/O 90,000/O people/O ,/O mostly/O ethnic/O Thai/O ,/O were/O relocated/O to/O make/O way/O for/O the/O Son/O La/O hydropower/O plant/O with/O Vietnamese/O scientists/O saying/O many/O were/O left/O without/O access/O to/O agricultural/O land/O ./O 
Indiginous/O peoples/O around/O the/O world/O face/O displacement/O Meanwhile/O ,/O in/O Cambodia/LOCATION 's/O Prey/LOCATION Lang/LOCATION Forest/LOCATION region/O ,/O home/O to/O the/O Kuy/O indigenous/O people/O ,/O official/O land/O grants/O of/O tens/O of/O thousands/O of/O hectares/O of/O forest/O for/O mineral/O extraction/O ,/O timber/O and/O rubber/O plantations/O have/O forced/O many/O people/O to/O give/O up/O their/O traditional/O livelihoods/O ./O 
Conflict/O has/O also/O been/O evident/O in/O Indonesia/LOCATION in/O areas/O of/O increased/O palm/O oil/O plantation/O development/O and/O the/O mining/O industry/O in/O Papua/LOCATION ./O 
Investment/O from/O China/LOCATION seen/O as/O a/O driver/O for/O economic/O growth/O Nicole/PERSON Girard/PERSON ,/O the/O rights/O group/O 's/O Asia/LOCATION Program/O Director/O ,/O says/O levels/O of/O conflict/O over/O land/O is/O increasing/O in/O South/LOCATION East/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O driven/O by/O foreign/O investment/O ,/O including/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
``/O It/O 's/O definitely/O increasing/O ,/O the/O resource/O exploitation/O in/O indigenous/O people/O 's/O territories/O ;/O in/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O the/O economies/O of/O Laos/LOCATION and/O Vietnam/LOCATION are/O opening/O to/O more/O foreign/O investment/O ,/O including/O lots/O of/O Chinese/O investment/O and/O including/O Burma/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Girard/PERSON said/O ./O 
Girard/PERSON says/O the/O increased/O fighting/O in/O Myanmar/LOCATION 's/O ethnic/O controlled/O Kachin/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION over/O the/O past/O year/O is/O directly/O linked/O to/O conflict/O over/O resource/O investment/O largely/O by/O Chinese/O businesses/O ./O 
Indigenous/O communities/O are/O also/O threatened/O by/O climate/O change/O Myanmar/LOCATION ,/O led/O by/O the/O military-backed/O civilian/O government/O of/O President/O Thein/PERSON Sein/PERSON ,/O has/O been/O undergoing/O reforms/O over/O the/O past/O year/O to/O improve/O its/O human/O rights/O situation/O ./O 
But/O Naw/PERSON San/PERSON ,/O General/O Secretary/O of/O the/O Students/O and/O Youth/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION Burma/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O Myanmar/LOCATION -RRB-/O says/O despite/O steps/O to/O peace/O talks/O with/O ethnic/O groups/O in/O Myanmar/LOCATION ,/O the/O development/O process/O is/O still/O not/O inclusive/O ./O 
``/O We/O are/O still/O worried/O that/O ,/O like/O in/O the/O past/O ,/O investment/O and/O development/O projects/O will/O be/O dealt/O with/O by/O the/O central/O government/O and/O that/O there/O will/O be/O -LRB-/O no/O real/O -RRB-/O engagement/O or/O consultations/O with/O the/O process/O on/O the/O ground/O ,/O ''/O Naw/O San/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O What/O the/O ethnic/O -LRB-/O communities/O -RRB-/O need/O now/O is/O national/O equality/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
Two/O thirds/O of/O Indigenous/O People/O live/O in/O Asia/LOCATION The/O Asia/LOCATION Indigenous/LOCATION People/LOCATION 's/O Pact/O -LRB-/O AIPP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION ,/O in/O a/O separate/O report/O ,/O noted/O that/O two/O thirds/O of/O the/O world/O 's/O 370/O million/O self-identified/O indigenous/O peoples/O live/O in/O Asia/LOCATION ./O 
And/O those/O people/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O AIPP/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION ,/O ``/O are/O currently/O marginalized/O and/O subordinated/O economically/O ,/O politically/O and/O culturally/O ./O ''/O 
They/O are/O ``/O overrepresented/O among/O the/O poor/O ,/O illiterate/O ,/O malnourished/O and/O stunted/O ,/O ''/O it/O said/O ./O 
AIPP/ORGANIZATION 's/O report/O says/O for/O many/O in/O the/O region/O ``/O militarization/O ,/O -LRB-/O the/O -RRB-/O plundering/O of/O resources/O ,/O forced/O relocation/O ,/O cultural/O genocide/O and/O discrimination/O in/O everyday/O life/O are/O common/O experiences/O ./O ''/O 
The/O report/O pointed/O to/O the/O construction/O of/O dams/O in/O Asia/LOCATION ,/O which/O since/O the/O 1960s/O ,/O has/O led/O to/O ``/O massive/O displacements/O ,/O loss/O of/O livelihoods/O ,/O and/O food/O insecurity/O of/O indigenous/O peoples/O in/O India/LOCATION ,/O the/O Philippines/LOCATION ,/O Laos/LOCATION and/O Malaysia/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Bernice/PERSON See/PERSON ,/O an/O AIPP/O coordinator/O ,/O said/O governments/O give/O priority/O to/O economic/O ventures/O and/O investments/O over/O people/O 's/O rights/O ./O 
See/O called/O on/O Asia/LOCATION 's/O governments/O to/O respect/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION 's/O Declaration/O of/O the/O Rights/O of/O Indigenous/O peoples/O and/O the/O provisions/O calling/O for/O the/O ``/O free/O prior/O of/O informed/O consent/O from/O any/O development/O that/O comes/O into/O their/O territory/O ./O ''/O 
``/O These/O governments/O should/O have/O the/O moral/O obligation/O to/O respect/O these/O agreements/O ./O 
The/O declaration/O should/O be/O used/O as/O a/O framework/O for/O dealing/O with/O indigenous/O people/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Ron/PERSON Corben/PERSON Editor/O :/O Sarah/PERSON Berning/PERSON 
