Neither/O repression/O nor/O investments/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION can/O turn/O Tibetans/O into/O patriotic/O Chinese/O citizens/O ./O 
And/O the/O unrest/O which/O continues/O to/O flare/O up/O has/O an/O effect/O on/O party/O politics/O ./O 
The/O unrest/O flaring/O up/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION since/O last/O year/O has/O presented/O a/O tough/O challenge/O to/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CCP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O leadership/O ,/O which/O is/O obsessed/O with/O upholding/O stability/O in/O the/O run-up/O to/O the/O all-important/O 18th/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION later/O this/O year/O ./O 
The/O situation/O is/O particularly/O serious/O in/O the/O Greater/LOCATION Tibet/LOCATION Region/LOCATION -/O the/O Tibet/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION -LRB-/O TAR/O -RRB-/O ,/O home/O to/O about/O 2.7/O million/O Tibetans/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O Tibetan/O counties/O in/O the/O four/O neighboring/O provinces/O of/O Sichuan/LOCATION ,/O Gansu/LOCATION ,/O Qinghai/LOCATION and/O Yunnan/LOCATION ,/O where/O close/O to/O 3.5/O million/O Tibetans/O live/O ./O 
According/O to/O international/O watchdogs/O ,/O since/O mid-2011/O ,/O up/O to/O 100/O instances/O of/O protests/O and/O disturbances/O have/O erupted/O in/O the/O Greater/O Tibetan/O Region/O ,/O particularly/O western/O Sichuan/LOCATION ./O 
These/O have/O included/O some/O 19/O cases/O of/O self-immolation/O involving/O 18/O monks/O and/O one/O nun/O ./O 
Several/O riots/O broke/O out/O in/O at/O least/O two/O Tibetan/O counties/O in/O western/O Sichuan/LOCATION during/O the/O long/O Chinese/O New/O Year/O vacation/O which/O started/O on/O January/O 23/O ./O 
People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Armed/ORGANIZATION Police/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O PAP/O -RRB-/O officers/O opened/O fire/O on/O the/O demonstrators/O and/O 20-odd/O Tibetans/O were/O reportedly/O shot/O dead/O or/O injured/O ./O 
Taken/O together/O ,/O these/O mishaps/O have/O amounted/O to/O the/O most/O severe/O outbreak/O of/O disorder/O since/O the/O spate/O of/O rioting/O in/O March/O and/O April/O 2008/O in/O the/O TAR/O ,/O Sichuan/LOCATION and/O Gansu/LOCATION ./O 
Given/O that/O the/O 2008/O disturbances/O were/O just/O a/O few/O months/O before/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympic/O Summer/O Games/O ,/O the/O Central/ORGANIZATION Military/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION ,/O headed/O by/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ,/O responded/O by/O sending/O heavy/O reinforcements/O of/O troops/O ,/O PAP/ORGANIZATION and/O police/O officers/O particularly/O to/O TAR/O and/O western/O Sichuan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O number/O of/O military/O and/O security/O personnel/O has/O again/O been/O increased/O since/O the/O middle/O of/O last/O year/O ./O 
In/O an/O apparent/O show/O of/O force/O ,/O the/O Tibet/LOCATION District/LOCATION of/O the/O PLA/ORGANIZATION last/O month/O launched/O its/O first-ever/O maneuvers/O of/O jetfighters/O in/O the/O Tibetan/LOCATION Highlands/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O display/O of/O hard/O power/O has/O failed/O to/O cow/O the/O spirit/O of/O dissent/O among/O both/O monks/O and/O the/O deeply/O religious/O Tibetan/O public/O ./O 
In/O late/O 2011/O ,/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION leadership/O also/O tried/O a/O softer/O approach/O by/O replacing/O the/O long-time/O hawkish/O party/O secretary/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O Zhang/PERSON Qingli/PERSON ,/O with/O a/O more/O moderate/O cadre/O ,/O Hebei/O Governor/O Chen/PERSON Quanguo/PERSON ./O 
Deemed/O an/O ally/O of/O Executive/O Vice-premier/O Li/PERSON Keqiang/PERSON ,/O Chen/PERSON has/O since/O his/O arrival/O in/O Lhasa/LOCATION concentrated/O on/O economic/O matters/O ,/O including/O promoting/O social/O welfare/O benefits/O among/O Tibetans/O both/O in/O and/O out/O of/O the/O TAR/O ./O 
Chen/PERSON has/O also/O persuaded/O more/O small/O to/O medium-sized/O enterprises/O in/O Sichuan/LOCATION and/O other/O neighboring/O provinces/O to/O move/O to/O TAR/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O ``/O economic/O card/O ''/O does/O not/O seem/O to/O have/O produced/O results/O in/O terms/O of/O winning/O the/O hearts/O and/O minds/O of/O Tibetans/O ./O 
The/O crux/O of/O the/O Tibet/LOCATION conundrum/O is/O that/O despite/O guarantees/O of/O religious/O freedom/O -/O and/O the/O rights/O of/O ethnic/O minorities/O -/O in/O the/O Chinese/O Constitution/O ,/O the/O monks/O and/O nuns/O in/O the/O Greater/LOCATION Tibet/LOCATION Region/LOCATION have/O been/O subjected/O to/O tight/O control/O by/O PAP/ORGANIZATION and/O state-security/O agents/O ./O 
The/O situation/O has/O markedly/O deteriorated/O since/O March/O 2008/O ./O 
PAP/ORGANIZATION officers/O and/O plainclothes/O police/O are/O permanently/O stationed/O in/O monasteries/O ./O 
Monks/O are/O forced/O to/O undergo/O ``/O patriotic/O education/O ''/O and/O their/O normal/O interactions/O with/O ordinary/O Tibetans/O are/O often/O monitored/O by/O police/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O official/O line/O is/O that/O the/O security/O forces/O are/O hitting/O hard/O at/O ``/O secessionists/O ''/O who/O are/O acting/O in/O collusion/O with/O ``/O anti-Chinese/O forces/O in/O the/O West/O ./O ''/O 
However/O ,/O international/O human/O rights/O organizations/O have/O provided/O convincing/O evidence/O that/O ordinary/O Tibetans/O '/O basic/O religious/O freedom/O has/O been/O seriously/O undermined/O ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O both/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O persevering/O with/O its/O Sinicization/O policy/O -/O encouraging/O Han/O Chinese/O businessmen/O and/O workers/O to/O migrate/O to/O the/O western/O areas/O ./O 
Sinicization/O has/O been/O largely/O successful/O in/O eastern/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O where/O Han/O Chinese/O already/O outnumber/O native/O Uighurs/O by/O a/O large/O margin/O ./O 
The/O Sinicization/O strategy/O ,/O however/O ,/O is/O less/O successful/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION because/O most/O Han/O Chinese/O can/O not/O adapt/O to/O the/O low-oxygen/O life/O in/O the/O Tibetan/O highland/O ./O 
The/O Tibet/LOCATION disaster/O has/O stark/O ramifications/O for/O both/O President/O Hu/PERSON and/O his/O key/O protégé/O ,/O Hu/PERSON Chunhua/PERSON ,/O 48/O ,/O Party/ORGANIZATION Secretary/O of/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION ./O 
In/O theory/O ,/O Jia/PERSON Qinglin/PERSON ,/O Chairman/O of/O the/O Chinese/O People/O 's/O Political/O Consultative/O Conference/O ,/O is/O the/O most/O senior/O decision-maker/O on/O Tibet/LOCATION by/O virtue/O of/O his/O being/O Head/O of/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION Leading/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION on/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O President/O Hu/PERSON has/O been/O the/O highest-level/O arbiter/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Tibet/LOCATION policy/O thanks/O to/O his/O being/O party/O boss/O of/O TAR/O from/O 1988/O to/O 1992/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O Hu/PERSON 's/O role/O in/O suppressing/O the/O Lhasa/LOCATION riots/O of/O March/O 1989/O was/O seen/O as/O a/O precursor/O to/O the/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION massacre/O three/O months/O later/O ./O 
Hu/PERSON 's/O ``/O bold/O and/O resolute/O action/O ''/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION won/O unreserved/O praise/O from/O Deng/PERSON Xiaoping/PERSON ,/O who/O in/O 1992/O designated/O Hu/O ,/O then/O 49/O ,/O as/O successor/O to/O ex-president/O Jiang/PERSON Zemin/PERSON ./O 
This/O was/O the/O beginning/O of/O the/O tradition/O of/O the/O so-called/O cross-generation/O designation/O of/O leaders/O in/O recent/O Chinese/O history/O ./O 
The/O Tibet/LOCATION contretemps/O -/O if/O they/O are/O not/O rectified/O soon/O enough/O -/O would/O also/O affect/O the/O promotion/O prospects/O of/O Hu/PERSON Chunhua/PERSON ,/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON 's/O favorite/O among/O Sixth-Generation/O -LRB-/O 6G/O -RRB-/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Youth/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION cadres/O ./O 
A/O former/O Party/ORGANIZATION Secretary/O of/O the/O CYL/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O younger/O Hu/PERSON -LRB-/O who/O is/O not/O related/O to/O his/O patron/O -RRB-/O served/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION for/O 19/O years/O immediately/O after/O his/O graduation/O from/O Peking/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION in/O 1983/O ./O 
He/O rose/O to/O become/O First/ORGANIZATION Deputy/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Secretary/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION in/O 2005/O ,/O when/O he/O was/O merely/O 42/O years/O old/O ./O 
Given/O that/O Hu/PERSON Chunhua/PERSON is/O identified/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O draconian/O Tibetan/O policy/O ,/O he/O will/O suffer/O at/O least/O political/O damage/O simply/O because/O this/O tough/O line/O has/O failed/O to/O uphold/O political/O stability/O ./O 
Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON is/O most/O impressed/O with/O Hu/PERSON Chunha/PERSON 's/O ability/O and/O political/O rectitude/O ./O 
Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON is/O trying/O his/O best/O to/O maneuver/O him/O into/O the/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION Standing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O PBSC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O at/O the/O 18th/O CCP/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Owing/O to/O the/O recent/O troubles/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O however/O ,/O it/O is/O more/O likely/O that/O Hu/PERSON Chunhua/PERSON can/O only/O become/O an/O ordinary/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION member/O ,/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O PBSC/ORGANIZATION ./O 
At/O the/O end/O of/O the/O day/O ,/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION leadership/O has/O to/O face/O the/O fact/O that/O exacerbated/O contradictions/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION have/O become/O a/O time/O bomb/O that/O could/O tear/O asunder/O the/O country/O 's/O already/O much/O strained/O ethnic/O fabric/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Willy/O Lam/O Editor/O :/O Sarah/PERSON Berning/PERSON 
