The/O German/O auto/O giant/O is/O due/O to/O sign/O an/O agreement/O with/O China/LOCATION for/O a/O new/O car/O plant/O to/O be/O built/O in/O the/O western/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
The/O region/O is/O home/O to/O the/O Uighurs/O --/O a/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O opposed/O to/O Chinese/O central/O power/O ./O 
The/O new/O Volkswagen/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O VW/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O car/O factory/O is/O to/O be/O set/O up/O in/O the/O provincial/O capital/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> with/O a/O production/O capacity/O of/O up/O to/O 50,000/O vehicles/O per/O year/O ,/O German/O news/O agency/O DPA/ORGANIZATION said/O Wednesday/O ./O 
Funding/O for/O the/O project/O worth/O 2/O billion/O yuan/O -LRB-/O 240/O million/O euros/O -RRB-/O would/O be/O provided/O by/O a/O joint/O venture/O between/O VW/ORGANIZATION and/O Chinese/O automaker/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Automotive/ORGANIZATION Industry/ORGANIZATION Corporation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SAIC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O the/O agency/O said/O ./O 
In/O addition/O ,/O news/O agency/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION quoted/O a/O German/O government/O source/O as/O saying/O that/O the/O agreement/O for/O the/O plant/O would/O be/O signed/O in/O Germany/LOCATION on/O Monday/O in/O the/O presence/O of/O German/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON and/O Chinese/O Premier/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON ./O 
The/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> plant/O ,/O which/O is/O scheduled/O to/O start/O production/O in/O 2013/O ,/O will/O be/O Volkswagen/ORGANIZATION 's/O fifth/O car/O factory/O in/O China/LOCATION with/O an/O additional/O four/O plants/O on/O the/O drawing/O board/O ./O 
The/O German/O auto/O giant/O already/O has/O six/O component/O factories/O in/O the/O Asian/O country/O ./O 
In/O China/LOCATION ,/O Volkswagen/ORGANIZATION reached/O a/O new/O sales/O record/O of/O 633,000/O vehicles/O in/O the/O first/O quarter/O of/O 2012/O ,/O and/O has/O announced/O investments/O in/O China/LOCATION to/O the/O tune/O of/O 14/O billion/O euros/O until/O 2016/O ./O 
Uighur/O trouble/O spot/O 
According/O to/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Tianshan/LOCATION Net/LOCATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -/O a/O local/O website/O based/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O -/O Volkswagen/ORGANIZATION Chairman/O Martin/PERSON Winterkorn/PERSON visited/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> last/O week/O for/O talks/O with/O regional/O leaders/O ./O 
Winterkorn/PERSON said/O the/O new/O plant/O was/O part/O of/O VW/ORGANIZATION 's/O strategy/O to/O expand/O into/O China/LOCATION 's/O less/O developed/O inland/O areas/O ./O 
``/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Volkswagen/ORGANIZATION plans/O to/O manufacture/O car/O models/O with/O the/O most/O advanced/O technology/O and/O based/O on/O the/O latest/O platforms/O in/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> project/O ,/O ''/O <U_LOCATION>Tianshan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> quoted/O him/O as/O saying/O last/O week/O ./O 
Volkswagen/ORGANIZATION is/O the/O first/O international/O auto/O maker/O to/O venture/O out/O into/O China/LOCATION 's/O far/O west/O -/O a/O region/O troubled/O with/O ethnic/O tension/O between/O minority/O Uighurs/O and/O the/O Chinese/O majority/O population/O ./O 
In/O 2009/O ,/O some/O 200/O people/O died/O in/O clashes/O unleashed/O by/O the/O Muslim/O separatist/O Uighurs/O in/O protest/O at/O what/O they/O called/O political/O and/O cultural/O oppression/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O Communist/O government/O ./O 
uhe/nk/O -LRB-/O dpa/O ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
