Dozens/O of/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O have/O protested/O the/O presence/O of/O Chinese/O Vice/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON in/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O as/O the/O man/O expected/O to/O become/O China/LOCATION 's/O next/O leader/O arrived/O for/O talks/O with/O Turkish/O leaders/O ./O 
The/O man/O slated/O to/O become/O China/LOCATION 's/O next/O leader/O ,/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O was/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION on/O Tuesday/O for/O talks/O with/O President/O Abdullah/PERSON Gul/PERSON ./O 
The/O visit/O marks/O the/O rise/O of/O Turkish/O clout/O on/O the/O international/O stage/O and/O recognition/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O role/O in/O maintaining/O stability/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
``/O In/O today/O 's/O complex/O and/O changing/O international/O situation/O ,/O the/O enrichment/O of/O the/O strategic/O cooperation/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O Turkey/LOCATION is/O to/O the/O benefit/O of/O both/O countries/O ,/O now/O and/O in/O the/O long/O term/O ,/O ''/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> told/O the/O Turkey/LOCATION Sabah/LOCATION newspaper/O in/O an/O interview/O ./O 
``/O A/O member/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>G20/O</ORGANIZATION> with/O a/O growing/O economy/O and/O an/O important/O country/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O Turkey/LOCATION has/O for/O a/O long/O time/O tried/O to/O bring/O stability/O and/O development/O to/O the/O region/O and/O played/O an/O active/O role/O in/O trying/O to/O solve/O `/O hot/O '/O issues/O ,/O ''/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> said/O ,/O citing/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O the/O Iranian/O nuclear/O dispute/O among/O others/O ./O 
DW/O recommends/O 
Turkey/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION eye/O closer/O cooperation/O 
Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O the/O expected/O next/O leader/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O is/O making/O a/O key/O visit/O to/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
While/O the/O emerging/O global/O powers/O aim/O at/O developing/O strategic/O ties/O ,/O the/O crisis/O in/O Syria/LOCATION has/O offered/O a/O test/O case/O for/O their/O cooperation/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 19.02.2012/O -RRB-/O 
But/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O arrival/O has/O already/O been/O marked/O by/O protests/O by/O dozens/O of/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O ,/O who/O desecrated/O a/O poster/O of/O the/O senior/O official/O and/O set/O fire/O to/O two/O Chinese/O flags/O ./O 
The/O demonstrators/O were/O venting/O anger/O over/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O treatment/O of/O Uighur/O populations/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Turkey/LOCATION is/O also/O home/O to/O a/O large/O Uighur/O community/O ./O 
On/O Wednesday/O ,/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> is/O to/O attend/O a/O business/O forum/O in/O Istanbul/LOCATION ,/O where/O he/O is/O likely/O to/O be/O assailed/O by/O exporters/O eager/O to/O bridge/O a/O wide/O trade/O gap/O between/O the/O countries/O ./O 
China/LOCATION sells/O some/O $/O 21.6/O billion/O worth/O of/O goods/O to/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O whilst/O Turkey/LOCATION sends/O only/O $/O 2.5/O billion/O worth/O to/O its/O Asian/O partner/O ./O 
<PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> is/O wrapping/O up/O a/O world/O tour/O that/O saw/O him/O meet/O with/O US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON in/O Washington/LOCATION and/O most/O recently/O travel/O to/O Ireland/LOCATION ./O 
dfm/jw/O -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
