Eight/O people/O who/O were/O attacking/O a/O police/O station/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O have/O been/O killed/O by/O police/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O say/O ./O 
The/O largely/O Muslim/O region/O has/O seen/O a/O recent/O string/O of/O deadly/O incidents/O ./O 
Authorities/O in/O western/O China/LOCATION said/O on/O Monday/O that/O police/O had/O shot/O dead/O eight/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O who/O launched/O an/O attack/O on/O a/O police/O station/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Shache/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> <OTHER>county/LOCATION</OTHER> ./O 
One/O of/O the/O attackers/O has/O been/O detained/O following/O the/O attack/O ,/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> government/O news/O portal/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Tianshan/ORGANIZATION Net/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> said/O ./O 
The/O website/O said/O the/O attackers/O were/O armed/O with/O knives/O and/O explosives/O ./O 
The/O region/O ,/O where/O mainly/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uighurs/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> are/O the/O largest/O ethnic/O group/O ,/O has/O seen/O a/O number/O of/O violent/O incidents/O this/O year/O ,/O with/O authorities/O blaming/O them/O on/O what/O they/O call/O ``/O terrorists/O ./O ''/O 
Some/O observers/O say/O ,/O however/O ,/O that/O cultural/O oppression/O ,/O severe/O security/O measures/O and/O the/O continuing/O influx/O and/O economic/O dominance/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Han/O majority/O have/O caused/O the/O unrest/O ./O 
The/O region/O is/O rich/O in/O oil/O and/O natural/O gas/O ./O 
The/O latest/O violence/O comes/O after/O a/O clash/O near/O the/O city/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> last/O month/O in/O which/O around/O a/O dozen/O people/O ,/O including/O two/O police/O officers/O ,/O were/O killed/O ./O 
In/O late/O October/O ,/O police/O blamed/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> Uighurs/O for/O an/O attack/O opposite/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION in/O which/O five/O people/O ,/O including/O the/O three/O attackers/O ,/O were/O killed/O and/O more/O than/O 40/O injured/O when/O a/O car/O drove/O into/O crowds/O of/O tourists/O ./O 
State/O media/O reported/O last/O month/O that/O more/O than/O 190/O ``/O terrorist/O ''/O attacks/O had/O taken/O place/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> last/O year/O ,/O noting/O a/O ``/O significant/O ''/O rise/O in/O comparison/O with/O 2011/O ./O 
tj/msh/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O dpa/O -RRB-/O
