After/O a/O fatal/O car/O crash/O at/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O Uighurs/O fear/O more/O restrictions/O by/O authorities/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Exiled/O leader/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> says/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O using/O the/O incident/O as/O an/O excuse/O to/O further/O oppress/O the/O ethnic/O minority/O ./O 
On/O October/O 28/O ,/O a/O car/O ploughed/O through/O bystanders/O on/O the/O edge/O of/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION and/O burst/O into/O flames/O ,/O killing/O the/O three/O in/O the/O car/O as/O well/O as/O two/O bystanders/O ./O 
Initially/O ,/O it/O was/O unclear/O whether/O the/O crash/O had/O been/O an/O accident/O or/O a/O deliberate/O strike/O ./O 
But/O the/O Chinese/O government/O later/O made/O five/O arrests/O and/O referred/O to/O the/O incident/O as/O a/O ``/O terrorist/O attack/O ''/O carried/O out/O by/O Islamist/O militants/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O a/O region/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwest/O where/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O make/O up/O around/O 45/O percent/O of/O the/O population/O ./O 
The/O autonomous/O region/O has/O been/O the/O scene/O of/O several/O violent/O clashes/O ,/O the/O most/O recent/O of/O which/O left/O dozens/O dead/O in/O April/O ,/O June/O and/O August/O of/O this/O year/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O top/O security/O official/O ,/O Meng/PERSON Jianzhu/PERSON ,/O described/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>ETIM/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ,/O based/O in/O <LOCATION>Central/O</LOCATION> and/O West/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O as/O ``/O behind-the-scenes/O supporters/O ''/O of/O the/O fatal/O vehicle/O crash/O ./O 
Ethnic/O Uighurs/O now/O say/O they/O 're/O facing/O new/O police/O scrutiny/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION following/O the/O Tiananmen/LOCATION incident/O ./O 
In/O a/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> interview/O ,/O the/O US-based/O exiled/O leader/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O calls/O for/O an/O internationally-verified/O and/O independent/O investigation/O into/O the/O October/O 28/O incident/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> :/O How/O likely/O is/O it/O that/O Uighurs/O were/O behind/O the/O incident/O at/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ?/O 
<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> :/O I/O am/O highly/O suspicious/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O claim/O that/O last/O Monday/O 's/O incident/O was/O an/O Uighur-inspired/O terrorist/O incident/O ,/O because/O this/O alleged/O attack/O did/O not/O show/O many/O of/O the/O signs/O of/O a/O premeditated/O ,/O planned/O terrorist/O attack/O ,/O as/O China/LOCATION claims/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> says/O the/O car/O crash/O did/O not/O show/O many/O of/O the/O signs/O of/O a/O premeditated/O ,/O planned/O terrorist/O attack/O 
As/O long/O as/O the/O Chinese/O government/O is/O unwilling/O to/O cooperate/O with/O the/O international/O community/O ,/O the/O international/O media/O and/O its/O own/O public/O to/O release/O evidence/O pertaining/O to/O the/O details/O of/O the/O incident/O ,/O I/O am/O afraid/O that/O the/O world/O will/O never/O know/O what/O happened/O on/O October/O 28th/O at/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ./O 
What/O 's/O worse/O is/O that/O the/O damage/O to/O my/O people/O ,/O the/O millions/O of/O innocent/O Uighur/O people/O of/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LSB-/O an/O area/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O north-western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ,/O but/O a/O term/O associated/O with/O Uighur/O separatists/O and/O not/O recognized/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O -RSB-/O ,/O has/O already/O been/O done/O ./O 
Because/O of/O the/O unsubstantiated/O claims/O of/O a/O Uighur/O terrorist/O attack/O on/O the/O capital/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O begun/O to/O step/O up/O the/O long-standing/O ,/O repressive/O crackdown/O on/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ./O 
Assuming/O that/O Uighurs/O were/O involved/O in/O the/O incident/O ,/O what/O could/O have/O driven/O them/O to/O commit/O such/O an/O act/O ?/O 
Assuming/O intention/O was/O involved/O in/O this/O incident/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O cruel/O and/O repressive/O policies/O towards/O the/O Uighurs/O are/O to/O blame/O ./O 
Specifically/O ,/O recent/O crackdowns/O on/O religious/O beliefs/O ,/O culture/O and/O identity/O have/O proven/O to/O be/O more/O intense/O than/O ever/O ,/O demonstrating/O that/O the/O Chinese/O government/O actively/O seeks/O to/O totally/O marginalize/O and/O demonize/O the/O Uighur/O people/O -/O actions/O which/O have/O effectively/O pushed/O the/O Uighurs/O into/O a/O state/O of/O utter/O despair/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Ethnic/O tensions/O escalating/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 
The/O latest/O incidents/O of/O deadly/O violence/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> indicate/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policies/O towards/O ethnic/O minorities/O have/O reached/O a/O dead/O end/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 05.07.2013/O -RRB-/O 
`/O We/O will/O fight/O until/O they/O grant/O us/O self-determination/O '/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O the/O exiled/O leader/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O is/O in/O Japan/LOCATION to/O draw/O attention/O to/O the/O struggle/O of/O her/O people/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
In/O a/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> interview/O she/O says/O her/O people/O will/O continue/O fighting/O for/O independence/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 21.06.2013/O -RRB-/O 
China/LOCATION punishes/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> military/O boss/O after/O Beijing/LOCATION attack/O China/LOCATION 's/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION says/O it/O has/O sacked/O the/O military/O chief/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> from/O the/O region/O 's/O governing/O council/O ./O 
The/O dismissal/O follows/O an/O attack/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION officially/O blamed/O on/O Islamist/O militants/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
-LRB-/O 03.11.2013/O -RRB-/O 
Riots/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O leave/O dozens/O dead/O 
More/O than/O two/O dozen/O people/O have/O died/O in/O clashes/O with/O police/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ./O 
The/O riots/O are/O the/O deadliest/O since/O the/O 2009/O clashes/O between/O Muslims/O and/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O population/O there/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 26.06.2013/O -RRB-/O 
Furthermore/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION continues/O to/O restrict/O freedom/O of/O speech/O and/O maintain/O practices/O of/O forced/O assimilation/O ,/O which/O is/O not/O relieving/O the/O already/O tense/O situation/O in/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION ./O 
Instead/O ,/O these/O highly/O repressive/O policies/O and/O egregious/O human/O rights/O violations/O are/O only/O making/O the/O situation/O worse/O ,/O effectively/O causing/O Uighurs/O to/O feel/O even/O more/O estranged/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O more/O than/O ever/O before/O ,/O Uighurs/O are/O frustrated/O ,/O desperate/O and/O hopeless/O in/O the/O face/O of/O continued/O repression/O at/O the/O hands/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O 
The/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>WUC/O</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O rejected/O the/O way/O in/O which/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O dealt/O with/O the/O Tiananmen/LOCATION explosion/O in/O public/O ./O 
What/O exactly/O does/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>WUC/O</U_ORGANIZATION> accuse/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O ?/O 
The/O <U_ORGANIZATION>WUC/O</U_ORGANIZATION> accuses/O the/O Chinese/O government/O of/O being/O extremely/O irresponsible/O in/O the/O way/O it/O has/O treated/O the/O Tiananmen/LOCATION explosion/O ,/O and/O hopes/O that/O it/O will/O immediately/O expose/O the/O truth/O ,/O backed/O up/O by/O evidence/O gathered/O by/O an/O internationally-verified/O ,/O independent/O investigation/O ./O 
Furthermore/O ,/O the/O WUC/ORGANIZATION accuses/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O exaggerating/O a/O Uighur/O terrorist/O threat/O ,/O and/O urges/O the/O international/O community/O to/O read/O the/O Chinese/O Media/O with/O caution/O ./O 
What/O kind/O of/O measures/O has/O Beijing/LOCATION taken/O in/O the/O aftermath/O of/O the/O incident/O ?/O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O intensified/O surveillance/O ,/O harassment/O ,/O censorship/O ,/O detention/O ,/O and/O interrogation/O of/O Uighurs/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O have/O already/O begun/O to/O round/O up/O Uighurs/O living/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O other/O Chinese/O cities/O ./O 
They/O have/O intensified/O the/O repression/O in/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O begun/O to/O detain/O jobless/O Uighur/O youth/O in/O many/O cities/O ./O 
They/O have/O erected/O more/O checkpoints/O in/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O arbitrarily/O stopping/O cars/O and/O harassing/O Uighurs/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION claims/O that/O the/O so-called/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>ETIM/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O is/O active/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O and/O that/O it/O represents/O a/O ``/O clear/O threat/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
What/O is/O your/O comment/O on/O that/O claim/O ?/O 
I/O am/O confident/O that/O there/O is/O no/O organized/O terrorist/O threat/O within/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
I/O feel/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O exaggerated/O an/O <U_ORGANIZATION>ETIM/O</U_ORGANIZATION> terrorist/O threat/O ./O 
One/O thing/O is/O clear/O :/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O used/O three/O evils/O -/O terrorism/O ,/O separatism/O and/O religious/O extremism/O -/O as/O an/O excuse/O to/O further/O oppress/O the/O Uighur/O people/O and/O to/O invoke/O the/O approval/O from/O the/O <LOCATION>West/O</LOCATION> under/O the/O auspices/O of/O fighting/O global/O terror/O ./O 
<PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</PERSON> :/O `/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O begun/O to/O step/O up/O the/O long-standing/O repressive/O crackdown/O on/O the/O Uighur/O people/O '/O Is/O there/O a/O way/O for/O Uighurs/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O to/O live/O in/O harmony/O ?/O 
I/O feel/O that/O the/O only/O way/O for/O peace/O to/O be/O achieved/O is/O through/O policies/O that/O respect/O the/O rights/O ,/O freedoms/O and/O dignity/O of/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION needs/O to/O adopt/O policies/O that/O ensure/O self-determination/O ,/O free/O and/O fair/O treatment/O ,/O economic/O equality/O and/O political/O rights/O of/O my/O people/O ./O 
It/O is/O quite/O simple/O :/O all/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O to/O do/O is/O protect/O every/O citizen/O 's/O rights/O as/O promised/O in/O the/O Universal/O Declaration/O of/O Human/O Rights/O and/O China/LOCATION 's/O own/O constitution/O ,/O and/O peace/O will/O be/O realized/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> is/O the/O president/O of/O the/O Munich-based/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ./O 
The/O interview/O was/O conducted/O by/O Gabriel/PERSON Domínguez/PERSON ./O
