German/O auto/O giant/O Volkswagen/ORGANIZATION has/O opened/O a/O new/O plant/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O under/O efforts/O to/O almost/O double/O its/O sales/O there/O by/O 2018/O ./O 
The/O Ningbo/LOCATION factory/O ,/O close/O to/O Shanghai/LOCATION ,/O is/O VW/ORGANIZATION 's/O third/O new/O plant/O inaugurated/O in/O China/LOCATION this/O year/O ./O 
Volkswagen/ORGANIZATION 's/O new/O car/O factory/O in/O Ningbo/LOCATION city/O will/O have/O a/O capacity/O of/O 300,000/O units/O per/O year/O ,/O and/O will/O be/O an/O important/O strategic/O pillar/O for/O expanding/O sales/O in/O the/O world/O 's/O largest/O car/O market/O ,/O the/O German/O car/O group/O said/O Thursday/O ./O 
At/O its/O Ningbo/LOCATION plant/O ,/O which/O is/O situated/O close/O to/O the/O city/O of/O Shanghai/LOCATION ,/O Volkswagen/ORGANIZATION is/O assembling/O primarily/O the/O Skoda/O Superb/O ,/O but/O is/O also/O planning/O to/O extend/O production/O to/O its/O own/O VW/ORGANIZATION models/O later/O on/O ,/O the/O carmaker/O added/O ./O 
Inaugurating/O the/O new/O plant/O on/O Thursday/O ,/O VW/ORGANIZATION Chairman/O Martin/PERSON Winterkorn/PERSON said/O the/O state-of-the-art/O factory/O was/O proof/O of/O Volkswagen/ORGANIZATION 's/O commitment/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
``/O For/O our/O brands/O ,/O this/O Ningbo/LOCATION plant/O will/O be/O a/O driver/O for/O tapping/O the/O full/O potential/O of/O the/O growing/O markets/O south/O and/O west/O of/O Shanghai/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Winterkorn/PERSON said/O ./O 
Ningbo/LOCATION is/O the/O third/O car/O factory/O opened/O by/O VW/ORGANIZATION in/O China/LOCATION in/O 2013/O ./O 
Last/O month/O ,/O the/O carmaker/O inaugurated/O a/O 300,000-capacity/O factory/O inFoshan/O ,/O after/O it/O had/O already/O opened/O a/O plant/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O in/O August/O ./O 
In/O 2015/O ,/O a/O fourth/O VW/ORGANIZATION plant/O is/O scheduled/O to/O open/O in/O Changsha/LOCATION ,/O central/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O new/O factories/O are/O key/O to/O VW/ORGANIZATION 's/O effort/O to/O boost/O sales/O in/O the/O Asian/O country/O to/O 4/O million/O vehicles/O per/O year/O by/O 2018/O ./O 
In/O 2012/O ,/O the/O auto/O maker/O delivered/O about/O 2.8/O million/O cars/O to/O customers/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O up/O 23/O percent/O over/O the/O year/O ./O 
In/O the/O first/O nine/O month/O of/O 2013/O ,/O VW/ORGANIZATION already/O sold/O 2.36/O million/O units/O in/O China/LOCATION -/O an/O increase/O of/O another/O 18/O percent/O ./O 
In/O its/O China/LOCATION factories/O ,/O which/O are/O run/O as/O joint/O ventures/O with/O local/O partners/O ,/O the/O 12-brand/O German/O carmaker/O already/O produces/O 20/O Volkswagen/ORGANIZATION ,/O Skoda/O andAudi/O models/O ./O 
uhe/pfd/O -LRB-/O dpa/O ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 
