Chinese/O officials/O say/O several/O small/O bombs/O have/O exploded/O in/O front/O of/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION headquarters/O in/O the/O northern/O city/O of/O Taiyuan/LOCATION ,/O killing/O one/O person/O ./O 
No/O explanation/O for/O the/O attack/O has/O been/O given/O ./O 
Officials/O said/O the/O explosions/O occurred/O early/O on/O Wednesday/O morning/O local/O time/O outside/O an/O office/O building/O of/O the/O Shanxi/ORGANIZATION Provincial/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Taiyuan/LOCATION ,/O the/O capital/O of/O Shanxi/LOCATION province/LOCATION ./O 
One/O person/O was/O killed/O in/O the/O blasts/O ,/O and/O eight/O people/O injured/O ,/O one/O of/O them/O seriously/O ,/O according/O to/O official/O media/O ./O 
``/O Judging/O from/O the/O scattering/O of/O small/O metal/O balls/O ,/O it/O is/O suspected/O that/O improvised/O bombs/O exploded/O ,/O ''/O the/O state-run/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION reported/O ./O 
Xinhua/PERSON quoted/O residents/O as/O saying/O that/O there/O were/O as/O many/O as/O seven/O blasts/O ./O 
Regular/O revenge/O attacks/O There/O was/O no/O information/O about/O the/O presumed/O target/O or/O perpetrators/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O attack/O bore/O the/O hallmark/O of/O the/O kind/O of/O attack/O occasionally/O carried/O out/O in/O China/LOCATION by/O citizens/O angered/O at/O perceived/O injustices/O ./O 
Shanxi/LOCATION ,/O which/O lies/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O coal/O belt/O ,/O has/O a/O relatively/O large/O wealth/O divide/O between/O rich/O owners/O of/O mines/O and/O the/O poorer/O people/O who/O work/O them/O ./O 
Wednesday/O 's/O incident/O comes/O after/O an/O attack/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION last/O week/O in/O which/O three/O people/O drove/O through/O crowds/O to/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Gate/LOCATION before/O setting/O their/O vehicle/O alight/O ./O 
Five/O people/O ,/O including/O three/O inside/O the/O vehicle/O ,/O were/O killed/O ./O 
The/O attack/O has/O been/O blamed/O on/O extremist/O separatists/O from/O the/O restive/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ,/O home/O to/O the/O mostly/O Muslim/O Uighur/O minority/O ./O 
tj/mkg/O -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 
