Eleven/O people/O have/O been/O killed/O in/O an/O assault/O on/O a/O police/O station/O in/O northwestern/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O attack/O is/O the/O latest/O in/O a/O series/O pointing/O to/O growing/O unrest/O in/O the/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
According/O to/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> regional/O government/O ,/O two/O officers/O died/O and/O police/O killed/O nine/O of/O the/O assailants/O ,/O who/O used/O knives/O and/O axes/O in/O Saturday/O 's/O attack/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Bachu/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> <OTHER>county/LOCATION</OTHER> 's/O <U_LOCATION>Serikbuya/LOCATION township/O</U_LOCATION> ,/O near/O the/O historic/O city/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
State/O media/O reported/O that/O the/O attackers/O also/O injured/O two/O police/O officers/O ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION government-funded/O broadcaster/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Free/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION reported/O that/O a/O police/O special/O weapons/O and/O tactics/O team/O killed/O several/O of/O the/O young/O attackers/O despite/O appeals/O from/O residents/O who/O had/O gathered/O at/O the/O scene/O to/O take/O them/O alive/O ./O 
``/O There/O were/O around/O 40/O to/O 50/O people/O gathered/O around/O the/O station/O ,/O ''/O the/O broadcaster/O quoted/O an/O eyewitness/O as/O saying/O ,/O though/O it/O did/O not/O identify/O the/O person/O because/O of/O the/O sensitivity/O of/O the/O matter/O ./O 
``/O They/O shouted/O to/O the/O police/O not/O to/O shoot/O ,/O capture/O them/O alive/O and/O try/O them/O ./O ''/O 
The/O government/O statement/O on/O Saturday/O 's/O attack/O gave/O fewer/O details/O ,/O but/O the/O official/O China/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION newspaper/O reported/O that/O police/O shot/O the/O nine/O attackers/O dead/O on/O the/O spot/O ,/O and/O identified/O one/O of/O them/O by/O the/O Uighur/O name/O of/O <U_PERSON>Abula/PERSON Ahat/PERSON</U_PERSON> ./O 
The/O newspaper/O reported/O that/O the/O assailants/O had/O targeted/O a/O police/O station/O already/O attacked/O once/O this/O year/O ,/O in/O April/O ./O 
That/O attack/O resulted/O in/O a/O group/O hacking/O and/O burning/O to/O death/O 15/O members/O of/O the/O security/O services/O ,/O with/O police/O shooting/O dead/O six/O of/O the/O assailants/O ./O 
'Emergency/O measures/O '/O 
Many/O Uighurs/O have/O long/O resented/O Chinese/O rule/O ,/O and/O insurgency/O has/O occasionally/O flared/O up/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ./O 
This/O year/O ,/O for/O example/O ,/O has/O provem/O particularly/O bloody/O ,/O with/O a/O number/O of/O deadly/O clashes/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O one/O in/O the/O heart/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION in/O which/O three/O attackers/O drove/O a/O vehicle/O through/O crowds/O in/O front/O of/O historic/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Gate/LOCATION ,/O killing/O themselves/O and/O two/O tourists/O ./O 
Overall/O ,/O the/O attacks/O have/O led/O to/O the/O deaths/O of/O scores/O of/O attackers/O and/O government/O officials/O ,/O with/O an/O accurate/O total/O figure/O hard/O to/O pin/O down/O because/O many/O incidents/O go/O unreported/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Power/O games/O in/O the/O shadow/O of/O disaster/O 
The/O whole/O world/O is/O rallying/O round/O to/O help/O the/O Philippines/LOCATION after/O the/O devastation/O caused/O by/O <OTHER>Typhoon/PERSON Haiyan/PERSON</OTHER> ./O 
Only/O China/LOCATION is/O hesitant/O -/O Bejing/LOCATION 's/O reserve/O has/O a/O political/O history/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 14.11.2013/O -RRB-/O 
More/O than/O 8/O million/O Uighurs/O -/O a/O generally/O Islamic/O group/O of/O Turkic/O descent/O -/O live/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O a/O sprawling/O region/O of/O about/O 21/O million/O people/O that/O borders/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O a/O number/O of/O Central/O Asian/O states/O ./O 
Many/O Uighurs/O complain/O that/O policies/O that/O favor/O ethnic/O Chinese/O have/O marginalized/O them/O as/O the/O indigenous/O population/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O blame/O violence/O in/O the/O region/O on/O alliances/O formed/O by/O some/O Uighurs/O with/O <ORGANIZATION>al/O Qaeda/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
However/O ,/O activists/O say/O despair/O over/O economic/O and/O social/O discrimination/O and/O cultural/O and/O religious/O restrictions/O have/O fueled/O the/O anger/O among/O Uighurs/O ./O 
``/O I/O again/O call/O on/O international/O society/O to/O take/O emergency/O measures/O to/O stop/O the/O Chinese/O government/O from/O directly/O opening/O fire/O to/O suppress/O Uighur/O protesters/O and/O depriving/O them/O of/O using/O legal/O appeals/O and/O defending/O their/O rights/O ,/O ''/O said/O <U_PERSON>Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O spokesman/O for/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O an/O advocacy/O group/O based/O in/O Munich/LOCATION ./O 
mkg/hc/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O dpa/O ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
