An/O explosion/O followed/O by/O an/O attack/O by/O armed/O assailants/O has/O occurred/O at/O a/O train/O station/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ./O 
The/O incident/O coincided/O with/O a/O visit/O to/O the/O western/O province/O by/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ./O 
Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON said/O Thursday/O the/O attack/O was/O being/O investigated/O ,/O with/O authorities/O blaming/O radical/O Islamists/O and/O separatists/O ./O 
He/O promised/O ``/O decisive/O actions/O against/O violent/O terrorist/O attacks/O ''/O after/O the/O incident/O ,/O urging/O a/O ``/O profound/O awareness/O of/O separatist/O forces/O ./O ''/O 
``/O At/O the/O moment/O ,/O it/O is/O acknowledged/O to/O be/O a/O terrorist/O attack/O ./O 
What/O is/O yet/O to/O be/O found/O is/O who/O did/O this/O and/O for/O what/O purpose/O under/O whose/O instigation/O ,/O ''/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> added/O ./O 
A/O sudden/O blast/O ripped/O through/O through/O the/O South/LOCATION Station/LOCATION in/O the/O regional/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> on/O Wednesday/O ./O 
A/O large/O group/O of/O attackers/O with/O knives/O then/O went/O after/O passengers/O ./O 
At/O least/O three/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O the/O attack/O and/O an/O additional/O 79/O people/O injured/O ,/O according/O to/O Chinese/O state/O media/O ./O 
Train/O service/O was/O suspended/O for/O around/O two/O hours/O ,/O said/O the/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION state/O news/O agency/O ./O 
The/O incident/O occurred/O on/O the/O last/O day/O of/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O visit/O to/O the/O restive/O province/O ./O 
It/O was/O not/O immediately/O clear/O whether/O he/O was/O still/O in/O the/O region/O when/O the/O attack/O happened/O ./O 
A/O posting/O on/O Chinese/O social/O media/O website/O <ORGANIZATION>Weibo/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> showed/O photos/O of/O littered/O debris/O ,/O luggage/O torn/O apart/O by/O the/O blast/O and/O security/O forces/O at/O the/O site/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O photos/O had/O been/O removed/O within/O hours/O of/O being/O posted/O ./O 
Violence/O has/O plagued/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ,/O home/O to/O an/O ethnically/O diverse/O population/O comprised/O primarily/O of/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O blamed/O the/O unrest/O on/O terrorists/O backed/O by/O foreigners/O ,/O however/O rights/O groups/O cite/O cultural/O repression/O as/O the/O cause/O of/O the/O ethnic/O clashes/O in/O recent/O years/O ./O 
During/O his/O four-day/O trip/O ,/O President/O Xi/PERSON called/O for/O more/O support/O for/O local/O police/O and/O greater/O security/O for/O the/O people/O of/O the/O region/O ./O 
kms/O ,/O dr/ccp/O -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
