For/O years/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O involved/O in/O territorial/O disputes/O with/O its/O neighbors/O ./O 
But/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION now/O fears/O that/O allies/O such/O as/O Japan/LOCATION and/O the/O Philippines/LOCATION might/O be/O drawn/O into/O a/O conflict/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
At/O the/O start/O of/O his/O three-day/O trip/O to/O China/LOCATION on/O April/O 7/O ,/O US/LOCATION Secretary/O of/O <OTHER>Defense/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Chuck/PERSON Hagel/PERSON -LRB-/O pictured/O left/O -RRB-/O traveled/O to/O the/O eastern/O port/O city/O of/O Qingdao/LOCATION to/O pay/O a/O visit/O to/O the/O symbol/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O military/O rise/O ,/O the/O aircraft/O carrier/O Liaoning/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION purchased/O the/O 60,000-ton/O carrier/O in/O 1998/O from/O Ukraine/LOCATION and/O has/O been/O retrofitting/O it/O ever/O since/O ./O 
Although/O experts/O believe/O it/O may/O take/O years/O for/O the/O carrier/O to/O be/O fully/O operational/O ,/O the/O naval/O vessel/O underlines/O China/LOCATION 's/O military/O ambitions/O ./O 
The/O appearance/O of/O the/O US/LOCATION <OTHER>Defense/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Secretary/O as/O a/O guest/O on/O the/O aircraft/O carrier/O was/O an/O important/O symbol/O ,/O according/O to/O Asia/LOCATION expert/O Gerhard/PERSON Will/PERSON ./O 
``/O The/O gesture/O shows/O that/O the/O two/O sides/O want/O to/O ease/O tensions/O and/O communicate/O with/O each/O other/O at/O the/O highest/O military/O level/O ,/O ``/O he/O said/O ./O 
The/O symbol/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O military/O rise/O :/O the/O aircraft/O carrier/O Liaoning/LOCATION 
Sino-American/O ties/O have/O been/O challenged/O for/O several/O years/O ,/O especially/O due/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O rise/O and/O the/O resulting/O power/O shifts/O in/O <LOCATION>East/O</LOCATION> and/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O heightened/O geopolitical/O status/O runs/O parallel/O with/O increases/O to/O its/O military/O expenditure/O ./O 
In/O 2014/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O defense/O budget/O increased/O by/O 12/O percent/O ,/O making/O it/O the/O second/O largest/O in/O the/O world/O ,/O second/O only/O to/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION responds/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O growing/O clout/O by/O increasing/O its/O engagement/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
Security/O expert/O Michael/PERSON Paul/PERSON ,/O of/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>SWP/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ,/O says/O that/O the/O rise/O of/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O American/O ``/O pivot/O ''/O to/O Asia/LOCATION could/O eventually/O ``/O lead/O to/O a/O direct/O confrontation/O ./O ''/O 
Territorial/O disputes/O 
Conflicting/O claims/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O its/O neighbors/O over/O vast/O swathes/O of/O territory/O in/O the/O South/LOCATION and/O East/LOCATION China/LOCATION Seas/O could/O trigger/O such/O a/O confrontation/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O in/O the/O East/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ,/O Japan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION claim/O ownership/O of/O the/O <LOCATION>Senkaku/ORGANIZATION</LOCATION> <OTHER>//ORGANIZATION</OTHER> <LOCATION>Diaoyu/ORGANIZATION</LOCATION> islands/O ,/O a/O chain/O of/O uninhabited/O rocks/O believed/O to/O be/O rich/O in/O natural/O gas/O reserves/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O in/O the/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION China/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION lays/O claim/O to/O an/O area/O that/O is/O almost/O one-and-a-half/O times/O the/O size/O of/O the/O <OTHER>Mediterranean/LOCATION</OTHER> ./O 
The/O territory/O encompasses/O countless/O islands/O that/O are/O believed/O to/O be/O rich/O fishing/O grounds/O with/O abundant/O ambient/O oil/O and/O natural/O gas/O deposits/O ./O 
Vietnam/LOCATION and/O the/O Philippines/LOCATION strongly/O oppose/O many/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O assertions/O in/O the/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
US/LOCATION and/O Japan/LOCATION send/O message/O to/O China/LOCATION 
The/O US/LOCATION is/O stepping/O up/O efforts/O to/O defend/O Japan/LOCATION against/O threats/O from/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Several/O disputed/O islands/O in/O the/O South/LOCATION and/O East/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION have/O the/O potential/O to/O threaten/O the/O stability/O of/O the/O entire/O region/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 09.04.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Obama/PERSON to/O tour/O Asia/LOCATION amid/O rising/O regional/O tensions/O Six/O months/O after/O scrapping/O a/O trip/O to/O the/O region/O ,/O US/LOCATION President/O Obama/PERSON has/O announced/O a/O four-nation/O tour/O of/O Asia/LOCATION aimed/O at/O quelling/O doubts/O about/O his/O commitment/O to/O a/O part/O of/O the/O world/O increasingly/O marked/O by/O security/O tensions/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 19.02.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Analysts/O fear/O escalation/O of/O China-Japan/O dispute/O Analysts/O from/O Japan/LOCATION 's/O National/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Defense/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION call/O on/O Tokyo/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O discuss/O a/O shared/O crisis/O management/O system/O ,/O arguing/O that/O increased/O regional/O tensions/O may/O cause/O minor/O incidents/O to/O escalate/O rapidly/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 02.02.2014/O -RRB-/O 
<LOCATION>Southeast/O</LOCATION> ,/O East/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION build/O up/O naval/O capabilities/O Due/O to/O a/O lack/O of/O security/O agreements/O and/O codes/O of/O conduct/O ,/O East/O Asian/O countries/O continue/O their/O naval/O arms/O race/O ,/O increasing/O the/O risk/O of/O a/O military/O confrontation/O as/O rapidly/O expanding/O economies/O vie/O for/O scarce/O resources/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 13.01.2014/O -RRB-/O 
As/O a/O long/O standing/O ally/O of/O both/O Japan/LOCATION and/O the/O Philippines/LOCATION ,/O the/O US/LOCATION could/O be/O forced/O to/O take/O action/O in/O the/O event/O of/O a/O conflict/O ./O 
Before/O landing/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O Hagel/PERSON had/O visited/O Japan/LOCATION where/O he/O underlined/O China/LOCATION as/O a/O great/O power/O and/O said/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION had/O a/O great/O responsibility/O ./O 
Regarding/O the/O territorial/O disputes/O ,/O Hagel/PERSON said/O :/O ``/O You/O can/O not/O go/O around/O the/O world/O ,/O redefine/O boundaries/O and/O violate/O territorial/O integrity/O and/O the/O sovereignty/O of/O nations/O by/O force/O ,/O coercion/O or/O intimidation/O ,/O whether/O it/O 's/O in/O small/O islands/O in/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION ,/O or/O in/O large/O nations/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
The/O US/LOCATION <OTHER>Defense/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Secretary/O also/O called/O for/O more/O transparency/O in/O order/O to/O ``/O prevent/O misinterpretations/O and/O misunderstandings/O and/O ,/O ultimately/O ,/O to/O reduce/O the/O risk/O of/O a/O conflict/O ./O ''/O 
The/O state-affiliated/O Chinese/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION called/O on/O Hagel/PERSON to/O acknowledge/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O China-friendly/O intentions/O and/O said/O that/O the/O two/O largest/O economies/O in/O the/O world/O could/O not/O afford/O confrontation/O ./O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O Defense/O Minister/O Chang/PERSON Wanquan/PERSON stressed/O that/O although/O Beijing/LOCATION would/O not/O provoke/O a/O conflict/O ,/O all/O military/O options/O would/O remain/O on/O the/O table/O for/O the/O defense/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O territorial/O sovereignty/O ./O 
Drawing/O parallels/O 
However/O ,/O Asia/LOCATION expert/O <PERSON>Will/O</PERSON> disapproves/O of/O the/O parallel/O drawn/O by/O Hagel/PERSON and/O others/O between/O the/O crisis/O in/O Ukraine/LOCATION and/O the/O conflicts/O in/O the/O East/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ./O 
He/O argues/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O that/O China/LOCATION would/O view/O referendums/O such/O as/O the/O one/O held/O in/O Crimea/LOCATION as/O threats/O ,/O especially/O if/O conducted/O in/O regions/O like/O Tibet/LOCATION or/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> where/O ethnic/O groups/O are/O striving/O for/O independence/O ./O 
Instead/O ,/O security/O expert/O Michael/PERSON Paul/PERSON sees/O some/O similarities/O between/O the/O current/O stand-off/O and/O the/O political/O constellation/O shortly/O before/O the/O outbreak/O of/O World/O War/O I/O in/O 1914/O ./O 
In/O a/O recently/O published/O study/O ,/O Paul/PERSON points/O to/O four/O major/O developments/O in/O the/O <LOCATION>German/O Reich/O</LOCATION> which/O preceded/O the/O outbreak/O of/O the/O war/O :/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O fear/O of/O encirclement/O ,/O fantasies/O to/O become/O the/O dominant/O power/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O nationalism/O and/O the/O build-up/O of/O the/O navy/O ./O 
All/O of/O these/O factors/O can/O be/O applied/O to/O modern-day/O China/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Nowadays/O ,/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION is/O striving/O to/O play/O a/O dominant/O role/O in/O Asia/LOCATION ,/O and/O -/O similar/O to/O the/O German/O thirst/O for/O power/O back/O then/O -/O the/O Chinese/O are/O resorting/O to/O naval/O might/O to/O achieve/O this/O ,/O ''/O Paul/PERSON said/O ./O 
The/O territorial/O disputes/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O neighboring/O countries/O have/O sparked/O protests/O The/O expert/O added/O that/O for/O years/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O been/O feeling/O increasingly/O encircled/O and/O staking/O everything/O on/O the/O nationalist/O card/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O latest/O version/O ,/O China/LOCATION fears/O it/O is/O being/O encircled/O by/O ``/O the/O missile/O defense/O systems/O of/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O its/O allies/O ,/O which/O stretch/O from/O Japan/LOCATION over/O the/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION all/O the/O way/O to/O India/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Paul/PERSON said/O ./O 
Trade/O is/O no/O guarantee/O for/O peace/O The/O analyst/O stressed/O that/O the/O similarities/O between/O today/O and/O 1914/O do/O n't/O necessarily/O mean/O that/O war/O is/O inevitable/O ,/O but/O he/O also/O pointed/O out/O that/O peace/O in/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION was/O ``/O by/O no/O means/O certain/O ./O ''/O 
Asia/LOCATION expert/O Will/PERSON told/O DW/O that/O ``/O trade/O relations/O alone/O can/O not/O replace/O a/O security/O architecture/O ./O ''/O 
In/O this/O context/O he/O pointed/O to/O the/O situation/O in/O Europe/LOCATION just/O before/O World/O War/O I/O ,/O arguing/O that/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O German/O Reich/PERSON had/O close/O economic/O ties/O with/O its/O European/O neighbors/O was/O n't/O enough/O to/O prevent/O war/O ./O 
``/O This/O is/O why/O it/O is/O important/O to/O study/O the/O story/O of/O the/O events/O unfolding/O in/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O
