Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON is/O set/O to/O visit/O Germany/LOCATION on/O March/O 28-29/O as/O part/O of/O his/O 11-day/O Europe/LOCATION tour/O ./O 
But/O instead/O of/O economic/O issues/O ,/O security/O is/O expected/O to/O be/O high/O on/O the/O agenda/O given/O recent/O developments/O in/O Ukraine/LOCATION ./O 
Sino-German/O relations/O are/O mainly/O defined/O by/O economic/O ties/O ./O 
The/O annual/O bilateral/O trade/O stands/O at/O around/O 205/O billion/O USD/O ./O 
That/O 's/O equivalent/O to/O about/O a/O third/O of/O the/O total/O EU/ORGANIZATION trade/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O economic/O nature/O of/O this/O relationship/O is/O highlighted/O by/O the/O fact/O that/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON will/O be/O accompanied/O by/O a/O 200-strong/O business/O delegation/O in/O his/O first/O trip/O to/O Germany/LOCATION as/O Chinese/O president/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
China/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION and/O the/O Ukrainian/O divide/O 
Sticking/O to/O its/O traditional/O policy/O of/O non-interference/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O adopted/O a/O cautious/O stance/O on/O the/O tug/O of/O war/O over/O Ukraine/LOCATION ./O 
Faced/O with/O pressing/O separatist/O threats/O and/O energy/O needs/O ,/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION would/O be/O another/O matter/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 25.03.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Germany/LOCATION redefines/O its/O major/O export/O markets/O 
The/O German/O government/O and/O domestic/O trade/O organizations/O have/O agreed/O on/O focusing/O export/O activities/O on/O six/O markets/O deemed/O most/O promising/O for/O German/O companies/O ./O 
The/O move/O came/O on/O the/O back/O of/O a/O global/O market/O analysis/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 26.03.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Chinese/O products/O top/O list/O of/O dangerous/O goods/O found/O across/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>EU/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> 
<ORGANIZATION>The/O European/O Commission/O</ORGANIZATION> has/O warned/O of/O a/O rising/O number/O of/O notifications/O relating/O to/O the/O import/O of/O consumer/O products/O registered/O as/O dangerous/O to/O consumers/O ./O 
It/O said/O most/O of/O the/O dangerous/O goods/O are/O coming/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
-LRB-/O 25.03.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Trade/O ties/O expose/O EU/ORGANIZATION ,/O US/LOCATION rift/O over/O Russia/LOCATION sanctions/O 
As/O the/O US/LOCATION moves/O to/O impose/O sanctions/O on/O Russia/LOCATION over/O Crimea/LOCATION ,/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION calls/O for/O more/O negotiations/O ./O 
The/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION have/O threatened/O Russia/LOCATION with/O punitive/O measures/O if/O Moscow/LOCATION does/O not/O reduce/O tensions/O in/O Ukraine/LOCATION ./O 
But/O some/O European/O countries/O are/O reluctant/O to/O impose/O sanctions/O due/O to/O close/O trade/O ties/O with/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
-LRB-/O 05.03.2014/O -RRB-/O 
And/O yet/O the/O focus/O of/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O state/O visit/O will/O not/O be/O on/O business/O deals/O ,/O but/O rather/O on/O global/O and/O security/O issues/O ,/O according/O to/O Sebastian/PERSON Heilmann/PERSON ,/O a/O China/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O Berlin-based/O <ORGANIZATION>Merics/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> think/O tank/O ./O 
``/O This/O is/O new/O to/O the/O Sino-German/O relations/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
The/O recent/O events/O in/O Ukraine/LOCATION are/O the/O main/O reason/O for/O this/O change/O ./O 
China/LOCATION does/O not/O agree/O with/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O annexation/O of/O Crimea/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION argues/O that/O the/O principles/O of/O territorial/O integrity/O and/O non-interference/O in/O the/O internal/O affairs/O of/O other/O states/O are/O at/O the/O core/O of/O its/O foreign/O policy/O ./O 
Furthermore/O ,/O given/O the/O autonomy/O movements/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> or/O Taiwan/LOCATION ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O rejects/O the/O idea/O of/O holding/O referendums/O ./O 
More/O scope/O for/O cooperation/O 
Considering/O the/O otherwise/O very/O close/O Sino-Russian/O ties/O ,/O analysts/O do/O not/O expect/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O abandon/O Moscow/LOCATION and/O openly/O criticize/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O actions/O ./O 
``/O But/O we/O do/O see/O signs/O of/O cracks/O in/O their/O relationship/O ,/O ''/O political/O expert/O Heilmann/PERSON told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O adding/O that/O the/O recent/O development/O had/O widened/O the/O scope/O for/O German/O co-operation/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Berlin/LOCATION wants/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O support/O the/O West/LOCATION 's/O position/O on/O the/O Crimea/LOCATION issue/O and/O to/O have/O a/O moderating/O effect/O on/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O had/O recently/O declared/O its/O intention/O to/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION that/O it/O wanted/O to/O take/O on/O more/O responsibility/O in/O global/O affairs/O and/O continue/O to/O adhere/O to/O international/O law/O ./O 
Analyst/O Heilmann/PERSON sees/O great/O opportunities/O for/O Beijing/LOCATION in/O light/O of/O the/O current/O situation/O :/O ``/O Behind/O the/O scenes/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O the/O opportunity/O to/O say/O that/O divisions/O within/O Eastern/LOCATION Europe/LOCATION and/O a/O shift/O from/O the/O current/O territorial/O boundaries/O are/O not/O in/O the/O interest/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
It/O can/O argue/O that/O stability/O is/O much/O more/O important/O and/O that/O the/O goal/O should/O be/O a/O joint/O development/O of/O the/O contested/O areas/O supported/O by/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>International/O Monetary/O Fund/O</ORGANIZATION> and/O protected/O by/O international/O law/O ./O 
Strategic/O partnership/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> -LRB-/O l/O -RRB-/O is/O expected/O to/O hold/O talks/O with/O German/O Chancellor/O Merkel/PERSON during/O his/O visit/O 
Perhaps/O Germany/LOCATION is/O the/O right/O country/O to/O address/O these/O issues/O during/O <PERSON>Xi/O Jinping/O</PERSON> 's/O upcoming/O state/O visit/O ./O 
Sino-German/O ties/O have/O become/O so/O close/O that/O they/O have/O been/O raised/O to/O the/O level/O of/O a/O strategic/O partnership/O ./O 
Delegations/O from/O both/O sides/O take/O part/O in/O several/O dialogue/O forums/O every/O year/O ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O dozens/O of/O bilateral/O agreements/O are/O signed/O in/O intergovernmental/O consultations/O ./O 
Germany/LOCATION has/O an/O excellent/O reputation/O as/O a/O reliable/O partner/O in/O China/LOCATION where/O it/O is/O regarded/O as/O the/O ``/O gate/O to/O Europe/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
During/O his/O visit/O ,/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> will/O first/O be/O meeting/O German/O President/O Joachim/PERSON Gauck/PERSON ./O 
But/O since/O Xi/PERSON Jingpin/PERSON is/O also/O China/LOCATION 's/O top/O politician/O ,/O he/O is/O also/O set/O to/O engage/O in/O extensive/O talks/O with/O Chancellor/O Merkel/PERSON ./O 
<PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> is/O then/O expected/O to/O travel/O to/O North/LOCATION Rhine-Westphalia/LOCATION and/O meet/O with/O Vice-Chancellor/O Sigmar/PERSON Gabriel/PERSON on/O the/O second/O day/O of/O his/O trip/O ./O 
Human/O rights/O Just/O a/O few/O days/O after/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O visit/O ,/O Berlin/LOCATION will/O be/O hosting/O the/O largest-ever/O exhibition/O by/O Chinese/O artist/O and/O political/O dissident/O Ai/PERSON Weiwei/PERSON ./O 
But/O ,/O as/O Nora/PERSON Sausmikat/PERSON from/O the/O German/O foundation/O <ORGANIZATION>Asienhaus/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> indicates/O ,/O <PERSON>Ai/O</PERSON> is/O unlikely/O to/O be/O present/O at/O the/O event/O as/O his/O passport/O was/O confiscated/O in/O 2011/O following/O a/O nearly/O three-month/O detention/O ./O 
The/O foundation/O therefore/O demands/O that/O Chancellor/O Merkel/PERSON push/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O <PERSON>Ai/O</PERSON> 's/O right/O to/O travel/O freely/O ./O 
Berlin/LOCATION will/O be/O hosting/O the/O largest-ever/O exhibition/O by/O Chinese/O artist/O and/O political/O dissident/O Ai/PERSON Weiwei/PERSON 
Sausmikat/PERSON also/O points/O out/O that/O -/O ever/O since/O Xi/PERSON took/O over/O the/O reins/O as/O president/O and/O party/O chief/O -/O censorship/O in/O China/LOCATION has/O become/O stricter/O and/O authorities/O have/O been/O cracking/O down/O hard/O on/O civil/O rights/O activists/O ./O 
<PERSON>Sausmikat/O</PERSON> therefore/O urged/O the/O German/O chancellor/O to/O stand/O up/O for/O freedom/O of/O expression/O and/O opinion/O in/O the/O Asian/O country/O ./O 
China/LOCATION analyst/O Heilman/PERSON believes/O it/O 's/O possible/O that/O the/O Xi-led/O government/O will/O be/O willing/O to/O take/O a/O more/O lenient/O approach/O towards/O <PERSON>Ai/O</PERSON> ./O 
``/O This/O hard/O line/O was/O taken/O up/O by/O the/O previous/O administration/O ./O 
The/O current/O government/O has/O more/O room/O to/O maneuver/O ,/O especially/O no/O court/O has/O convicted/O <PERSON>Ai/O</PERSON> of/O anything/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O
