Since/O the/O APEC/ORGANIZATION Summit/O ,/O all/O attention/O has/O been/O directed/O at/O the/O world/O 's/O new/O superpower/O ,/O China/LOCATION ./O 
But/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O dominance/O seems/O disproportionate/O when/O compared/O to/O what/O the/O country/O has/O to/O offer/O ,/O says/O DW/O 's/O Rodion/PERSON Ebbighausen/PERSON ./O 
For/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O recent/O APEC/ORGANIZATION Summit/O was/O a/O big/O success/O ./O 
President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O the/O conference/O 's/O host/O ,/O was/O able/O to/O present/O his/O country/O to/O the/O world/O as/O a/O rising/O world/O power/O ./O 
Commentators/O and/O analysts/O now/O admire/O the/O ascent/O of/O the/O East/O Asian/O country/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O indeed/O joined/O the/O ranks/O of/O the/O great/O nations/O ,/O but/O the/O surprising/O thing/O is/O that/O nobody/O seems/O to/O be/O asking/O an/O obvious/O question/O :/O What/O does/O this/O new/O power/O have/O to/O offer/O the/O world/O ?/O 
For/O quite/O some/O time/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O exploiting/O a/O number/O of/O countries/O under/O the/O guise/O of/O development/O cooperation/O ./O 
There/O has/O been/O a/O constant/O pattern/O to/O it/O ./O 
Firstly/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION engages/O with/O the/O elites/O of/O a/O country/O ,/O irrespective/O of/O the/O legitimacy/O of/O their/O rule/O -/O their/O human/O rights/O record/O is/O of/O no/O concern/O to/O the/O Chinese/O leadership/O ./O 
In/O the/O next/O phase/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O Chinese/O migrant/O workers/O pour/O into/O the/O recipient/O nation/O to/O help/O build/O its/O infrastructure/O ,/O but/O without/O employing/O the/O local/O population/O ./O 
Then/O ,/O the/O country/O 's/O raw/O materials/O are/O transported/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O end/O ,/O cheap/O Chinese/O products/O flood/O the/O country/O 's/O market/O ,/O partially/O ruining/O the/O local/O economy/O ./O 
Let/O 's/O then/O turn/O to/O the/O Asian/O giant/O 's/O domestic/O politics/O :/O There/O are/O strong/O restrictions/O on/O the/O freedom/O of/O press/O and/O expression/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O great/O firewall/O is/O considered/O the/O most/O effective/O filter/O in/O the/O world/O ,/O obstructing/O any/O diversity/O of/O opinion/O and/O pluralism/O ./O 
Criticism/O is/O only/O allowed/O as/O long/O as/O the/O system/O is/O not/O questioned/O or/O high-ranking/O officials/O are/O unaffected/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O tell/O the/O people/O on/O the/O mainland/O that/O the/O democracy/O movement/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION democracy/O is/O a/O rebellion/O triggered/O by/O anarchists/O ./O 
For/O decades/O ,/O the/O central/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O been/O harassing/O the/O ethnic/O minorities/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
The/O authorities/O have/O dealt/O strictly/O with/O the/O social/O upheaval/O in/O the/O country/O 's/O far/O west/O ,/O partially/O triggered/O by/O the/O massive/O influx/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O to/O the/O region/O ./O 
When/O it/O comes/O to/O the/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O shown/O it/O does/O n't/O place/O much/O value/O on/O international/O law/O ./O 
It/O bullies/O its/O smaller/O neighbors/O and/O expands/O its/O sphere/O of/O influence/O by/O implementing/O salami/O tactics/O ./O 
China/LOCATION also/O refuses/O to/O take/O part/O in/O a/O case/O filed/O by/O the/O Philippines/LOCATION in/O the/O Permanent/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Arbitration/ORGANIZATION ./O 
In/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O China/LOCATION mostly/O stands/O out/O for/O a/O lack/O of/O constructive/O contributions/O as/O well/O as/O for/O almost/O always/O insisting/O on/O the/O principle/O on/O non-intervention/O ./O 
Exceptions/O such/O as/O the/O 2009/O UN/ORGANIZATION resolution/O against/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION 's/O nuclear/O program/O confirm/O the/O rule/O ./O 
In/O reality/O ,/O China/LOCATION holds/O a/O protective/O hand/O over/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION 's/O terror/O regime/O ./O 
The/O pursuit/O of/O one/O 's/O own/O advantage/O and/O the/O maximization/O of/O profits/O are/O core/O values/O of/O the/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
These/O are/O not/O generally/O reproachable/O aims/O ,/O as/O other/O countries/O also/O strive/O for/O power/O and/O profits/O ./O 
But/O the/O difference/O is/O that/O in/O countries/O such/O as/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION or/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION Member/O States/O the/O pursuit/O of/O power/O and/O profits/O is/O often/O confronted/O by/O other/O forces/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O these/O countries/O allow/O the/O work/O of/O NGOs/O such/O as/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION or/O Transparency/O International/O ./O 
They/O also/O have/O a/O civil/O society/O and/O an/O open/O debate/O about/O what/O is/O desirable/O and/O what/O is/O not/O ./O 
These/O are/O all/O elements/O which/O ultimately/O also/O have/O an/O impact/O on/O foreign/O policy/O ./O 
But/O China/LOCATION does/O n't/O have/O any/O of/O this/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O elites/O suppress/O dissent/O in/O order/O to/O maintain/O power/O ./O 
They/O fear/O transparency/O and/O are/O not/O accountable/O to/O the/O people/O ,/O but/O only/O to/O the/O party/O ./O 
This/O view/O of/O politics/O is/O also/O reflected/O in/O the/O country/O 's/O foreign/O policy/O ,/O which/O is/O either/O indifferent/O or/O primarily/O guided/O by/O economic/O interests/O ./O 
This/O is/O why/O China/LOCATION is/O a/O big/O world/O power/O that/O shies/O away/O from/O its/O responsibilities/O ./O 
It/O does/O n't/O offer/O the/O world/O much/O more/O than/O a/O giant/O marketplace/O ./O 
