Conventional/O thinking/O is/O that/O when/O countries/O experience/O greater/O economic/O growth/O ,/O they/O are/O less/O vulnerable/O to/O large-scale/O violent/O conflicts/O ./O 
However/O ,/O this/O has/O not/O been/O the/O case/O in/O Asia/LOCATION ,/O as/O analyst/O Patrick/PERSON Barron/PERSON tells/O DW/O ./O 
Asia/LOCATION 's/O economic/O rise/O has/O been/O momentous/O ./O 
Since/O the/O early/O 1960s/O ,/O Asia/LOCATION has/O grown/O richer/O faster/O than/O any/O other/O region/O in/O the/O world/O ./O 
In/O 1990/O ,/O 56/O percent/O of/O people/O in/O East/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O 54/O percent/O in/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION lived/O on/O less/O than/O 1.25/O USD/O a/O day/O ./O 
By/O 2010/O ,/O these/O rates/O had/O fallen/O to/O 12/O percent/O and/O 31/O percent/O ,/O respectively/O ./O 
Last/O year/O ,/O East/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION grew/O by/O 7.1/O percent/O and/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION by/O 5.2/O percent/O ,/O faster/O than/O any/O other/O region/O in/O the/O world/O ./O 
Even/O though/O these/O countries/O have/O become/O much/O richer/O ,/O the/O number/O of/O so-called/O subnational/O conflicts/O has/O grown/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O an/O occurrence/O that/O defies/O the/O common/O political/O belief/O that/O prosperity/O reduces/O the/O likelihood/O of/O violent/O conflicts/O ./O 
Between/O 1999/O and/O 2008/O ,/O more/O people/O died/O in/O such/O conflicts/O in/O Asia/LOCATION than/O all/O other/O types/O of/O conflict/O -LRB-/O interstate/O war/O ,/O terrorism/O -RRB-/O combined/O ./O 
Patrick/PERSON Barron/PERSON ,/O The/O Asia/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION 's/O regional/O director/O for/O conflict/O and/O development/O ,/O says/O in/O a/O DW/O interview/O that/O the/O growth-stimulating/O strategies/O chosen/O by/O Asian/O countries/O have/O led/O to/O such/O subnational/O conflicts/O ./O 
The/O ingredients/O of/O these/O strategies/O ,/O he/O adds/O ,/O include/O a/O strong/O focus/O on/O centralizing/O power/O and/O an/O emphasis/O on/O creating/O a/O dominant/O national/O culture/O and/O identity/O ./O 
But/O he/O also/O says/O that/O there/O is/O a/O chance/O for/O Asian/O nations/O to/O create/O new/O decentralized/O leadership/O models/O ./O 
DW/O :/O What/O do/O subnational/O conflicts/O involve/O and/O where/O can/O they/O be/O found/O ?/O 
Patrick/PERSON Barron/PERSON :/O Subnational/O conflicts/O involve/O violent/O armed/O struggles/O between/O states/O and/O non-state/O insurgent/O groups/O who/O are/O trying/O to/O gain/O self-rule/O -/O either/O independence/O or/O greater/O autonomy/O ./O 
They/O differ/O from/O regular/O civil/O wars/O because/O they/O do/O n't/O involve/O battles/O for/O control/O of/O the/O central/O state/O ./O 
Usually/O ,/O they/O occur/O in/O the/O remote/O peripheries/O of/O states/O ,/O where/O the/O majority/O population/O is/O a/O religious/O or/O ethnic/O minority/O within/O the/O broader/O country/O ./O 
Barron/PERSON says/O subnational/O conflicts/O usually/O involve/O violent/O armed/O struggles/O between/O states/O and/O non-state/O insurgent/O groups/O The/O economic/O explosion/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O for/O example/O ,/O has/O been/O accompanied/O by/O deepening/O unrest/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
The/O majority/O of/O the/O people/O of/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O conflict-affected/O Deep/O South/O are/O Malay-Muslim/PERSON ,/O while/O Muslims/O probably/O account/O for/O only/O six/O percent/O of/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O population/O ./O 
Over/O the/O past/O decade/O ,/O such/O conflicts/O have/O affected/O over/O half/O of/O the/O countries/O of/O South/O and/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
The/O continent/O 's/O current/O most/O deadly/O subnational/O conflicts/O are/O occurring/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ,/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
In/O Myanmar/LOCATION ,/O progress/O has/O been/O made/O towards/O finding/O peace/O agreement/O in/O many/O -/O but/O not/O all/O -/O subnational/O conflict/O regions/O ./O 
In/O Mindanao/LOCATION in/O the/O Philippines/LOCATION ,/O great/O progress/O has/O been/O made/O with/O the/O recent/O signing/O of/O a/O Comprehensive/O Agreement/O on/O the/O Bangsamoro/O ,/O but/O there/O will/O no/O doubt/O be/O challenges/O ahead/O ./O 
Why/O are/O Asian/O countries/O particularly/O susceptible/O to/O such/O conflicts/O ?/O 
In/O many/O cases/O ,/O it/O is/O the/O ingredients/O of/O the/O strategies/O that/O Asian/O countries/O chose/O to/O stimulate/O growth/O and/O development/O that/O have/O led/O to/O subnational/O conflicts/O ./O 
These/O include/O a/O strong/O focus/O on/O centralizing/O power/O at/O the/O expense/O of/O power/O in/O the/O peripheries/O ,/O an/O emphasis/O on/O creating/O a/O dominant/O national/O culture/O and/O identity/O -/O sometimes/O at/O the/O expense/O of/O minority/O cultural/O identities/O ,/O and/O an/O opening/O up/O of/O markets/O to/O outside/O investment/O -/O often/O over-riding/O traditional/O claims/O to/O land/O and/O other/O natural/O resources/O ./O 
These/O policies/O and/O practices/O have/O generally/O been/O quite/O successful/O in/O stimulating/O growth/O ./O 
But/O they/O have/O also/O led/O to/O resentment/O in/O regions/O that/O have/O not/O benefitted/O from/O this/O growth/O and/or/O who/O perceive/O their/O cultures/O and/O identities/O to/O have/O been/O marginalized/O ./O 
The/O security-focused/O responses/O of/O some/O Asian/O countries/O ,/O who/O have/O sent/O the/O military/O in/O rather/O than/O search/O for/O solutions/O to/O underlying/O problems/O ,/O has/O also/O led/O to/O resentment/O which/O has/O given/O some/O conflicts/O a/O new/O lease/O of/O life/O ./O 
What/O are/O the/O key/O factors/O that/O lead/O to/O subnational/O conflicts/O in/O Asia/LOCATION ?/O 
We/O can/O think/O of/O both/O underlying/O causes/O which/O lead/O to/O initial/O unrest/O and/O then/O factors/O that/O sustain/O Asian/O subnational/O conflicts/O ./O 
As/O noted/O before/O ,/O a/O trampling/O over/O local/O cultural/O identity/O ,/O accompanied/O by/O relative/O economic/O deprivation/O ,/O often/O creates/O initial/O sparks/O of/O violence/O ./O 
However/O ,/O over/O time/O it/O is/O often/O different/O issues/O that/O keep/O these/O conflicts/O going/O and/O that/O cause/O them/O to/O escalate/O ./O 
One/O is/O that/O repressive/O state/O security/O policies/O sometimes/O lead/O to/O rights/O abuses/O ,/O in/O turn/O reinforcing/O hatred/O towards/O the/O state/O ./O 
DW/O recommends/O Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION disputes/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O account/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION clash/O A/O day/O after/O dozens/O of/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O clashes/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ,/O the/O Uighur/ORGANIZATION World/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION '/O Alim/PERSON Seytoff/PERSON tells/O DW/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O account/O of/O events/O intends/O to/O depict/O peaceful/O protesters/O as/O ``/O terrorists/O ./O ''/O 
-LRB-/O 30.07.2014/O -RRB-/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O unrest/O puts/O dent/O in/O tourism/O Political/O instability/O has/O hardly/O affected/O the/O image/O of/O the/O holiday/O paradise/O of/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O 
But/O while/O the/O military/O protects/O the/O all-important/O industry/O ,/O the/O country/O has/O missed/O its/O ambitious/O growth/O targets/O for/O 2014/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 21.07.2014/O -RRB-/O More/O tribal/O rights/O could/O squelch/O Maoist/O revolt/O in/O India/LOCATION For/O decades/O ,/O India/LOCATION 's/O government/O has/O been/O locked/O in/O a/O struggle/O with/O rebels/O seeking/O to/O impose/O Maoism/O on/O the/O world/O 's/O largest/O democracy/O ./O 
The/O solution/O may/O not/O lie/O in/O the/O use/O of/O force/O ,/O but/O rather/O in/O protecting/O tribal/O rights/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 11.11.2013/O -RRB-/O Thai/O army/O needs/O to/O revive/O the/O economy/O Months/O of/O political/O turmoil/O have/O negatively/O affected/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O economy/O with/O output/O shrinking/O in/O the/O first/O quarter/O ./O 
Experts/O say/O investors/O are/O postponing/O decisions/O until/O there/O is/O more/O clarity/O about/O the/O situation/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 30.05.2014/O -RRB-/O A/O second/O is/O that/O over/O time/O conflict/O can/O become/O a/O profitable/O endeavor/O for/O many/O of/O the/O parties/O involved/O ./O 
Militaries/O sometimes/O benefit/O from/O subnational/O conflicts/O because/O they/O can/O strengthen/O their/O calls/O for/O greater/O funding/O ./O 
In/O many/O cases/O ,/O insurgent/O groups/O also/O do/O well/O out/O of/O conflict/O -/O both/O through/O benefitting/O from/O informal/O taxation/O of/O the/O poor/O ,/O but/O also/O from/O the/O political/O power/O and/O resultant/O economic/O opportunities/O that/O conflict/O garners/O ./O 
Dealing/O with/O the/O incentives/O that/O create/O this/O `/O political/O economy/O of/O conflict/O '/O can/O often/O be/O the/O greatest/O barrier/O towards/O peace/O ./O 
What/O impact/O are/O these/O conflicts/O having/O in/O their/O respective/O countries/O ?/O 
The/O economic/O costs/O of/O civil/O war/O in/O Indonesia/LOCATION 's/O Aceh/LOCATION province/O ,/O for/O example/O ,/O have/O been/O estimated/O at/O 10.7/O billion/O USD/O ,/O more/O than/O twice/O that/O of/O the/O Indian/LOCATION Ocean/LOCATION tsunami/O ./O 
In/O the/O past/O decade/O ,/O more/O than/O 100,000/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O subnational/O conflicts/O in/O South/O and/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
The/O number/O of/O lives/O that/O were/O scarred/O obviously/O far/O exceeds/O this/O total/O ./O 
The/O political/O costs/O are/O less/O certain/O ./O 
The/O average/O subnational/O conflict/O in/O Asia/LOCATION lasts/O for/O 33/O years/O ,/O double/O the/O global/O average/O ./O 
One/O reason/O for/O this/O is/O that/O the/O political/O cost/O of/O these/O conflicts/O to/O governments/O is/O often/O rather/O slight/O ./O 
Thailand/LOCATION 's/O Deep/O South/O houses/O only/O three/O percent/O of/O the/O national/O population/O ./O 
Less/O than/O two/O percent/O of/O Indonesians/O live/O in/O Aceh/LOCATION ./O 
Subnational/O conflict/O areas/O are/O usually/O relatively/O isolated/O peripheries/O ./O 
In/O nations/O '/O capitals/O ,/O the/O killing/O is/O often/O too/O distant/O to/O arouse/O widespread/O indignation/O ./O 
Governments/O often/O find/O it/O easier/O to/O ignore/O or/O contain/O subnational/O conflicts/O than/O deal/O with/O the/O complex/O underlying/O problems/O ./O 
Why/O have/O some/O of/O these/O conflicts/O continued/O even/O as/O democracy/O has/O consolidated/O ?/O 
It/O 's/O unsurprising/O to/O see/O more/O violent/O conflict/O at/O times/O of/O transition/O when/O the/O ``/O rules/O of/O the/O game/O ''/O are/O less/O clear/O ./O 
Democracy/O brings/O with/O it/O new/O opportunities/O for/O expression/O of/O dissent/O and/O identity/O ./O 
In/O some/O of/O these/O cases/O ,/O this/O increased/O the/O confidence/O of/O some/O groups/O to/O push/O for/O greater/O freedoms/O ./O 
And/O sometimes/O ,/O when/O states/O did/O not/O respond/O positively/O ,/O people/O took/O up/O arms/O ./O 
But/O we/O would/O expect/O democracies/O ,/O once/O they/O have/O consolidated/O ,/O to/O be/O more/O effective/O at/O managing/O conflicts/O :/O firstly/O ,/O because/O groups/O can/O compete/O politically/O rather/O than/O violently/O ;/O secondly/O ,/O because/O there/O is/O more/O room/O for/O freedom/O of/O expression/O and/O choice/O of/O representation/O ;/O and/O finally/O ,/O because/O there/O are/O more/O likely/O to/O be/O accountability/O mechanisms/O -/O such/O as/O a/O free/O press/O and/O vibrant/O civil/O society/O -/O in/O place/O ,/O hence/O limiting/O abuses/O ./O 
The/O researcher/O says/O the/O deadliest/O conflicts/O right/O now/O are/O happening/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ,/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION One/O thing/O that/O has/O sometimes/O been/O missing/O in/O Asia/LOCATION 's/O new/O democracies/O is/O substantive/O decentralization/O of/O powers/O that/O allow/O for/O local/O identities/O to/O be/O expressed/O and/O decisions/O on/O the/O use/O of/O local/O resources/O to/O be/O controlled/O locally/O ./O 
Where/O there/O has/O been/O decentralization/O ,/O there/O have/O often/O not/O been/O serious/O attempts/O to/O make/O sure/O local/O institutions/O have/O the/O capacity/O to/O oversee/O these/O processes/O and/O that/O they/O are/O transparent/O and/O held/O accountable/O ./O 
What/O must/O these/O countries/O do/O to/O try/O to/O deter/O such/O conflicts/O ?/O 
Subnational/O conflicts/O are/O ultimately/O political/O problems/O ;/O overcoming/O them/O requires/O political/O solutions/O ./O 
Changing/O the/O approaches/O of/O governments/O to/O these/O conflict/O areas/O also/O requires/O political/O will/O and/O this/O can/O not/O be/O externally/O imposed/O ./O 
There/O are/O no/O easy/O answers/O to/O ending/O conflicts/O that/O have/O ,/O in/O many/O cases/O ,/O endured/O for/O generations/O ./O 
However/O ,/O there/O are/O a/O few/O things/O governments/O might/O think/O about/O ./O 
First/O ,/O they/O should/O seek/O to/O use/O dialogue/O as/O a/O means/O for/O dealing/O with/O contention/O rather/O than/O the/O application/O of/O coercive/O force/O ./O 
Globally/O ,/O from/O Iraq/LOCATION to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O beyond/O ,/O counter-insurgency/O operations/O have/O often/O led/O to/O increased/O resentment/O against/O the/O state/O amongst/O local/O populations/O ./O 
Second/O ,/O they/O should/O explore/O means/O to/O use/O decentralization/O as/O a/O core/O component/O of/O any/O peace/O settlement/O ./O 
Many/O Asian/O countries/O ,/O which/O have/O seen/O the/O economic/O and/O security/O benefits/O of/O centralization/O ,/O are/O wary/O of/O devolving/O powers/O to/O areas/O ./O 
But/O ,/O as/O the/O case/O of/O Indonesia/LOCATION shows/O -/O where/O most/O subnational/O conflicts/O have/O ended/O -/O allowing/O for/O more/O local/O control/O of/O resources/O and/O decisions/O ,/O within/O the/O framework/O of/O a/O sovereign/O state/O ,/O can/O actually/O be/O quite/O an/O effective/O conflict/O prevention/O and/O management/O tool/O ./O 
Barron/PERSON :/O China/LOCATION is/O an/O example/O of/O how/O economic/O growth/O has/O been/O accompanied/O by/O deepening/O unrest/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION Third/LOCATION ,/O look/O for/O new/O ideas/O and/O create/O the/O organizations/O ,/O spaces/O and/O networks/O to/O develop/O them/O ./O 
Many/O of/O the/O standard/O approaches/O to/O dealing/O with/O conflict/O were/O developed/O based/O on/O experiences/O dealing/O with/O national-level/O civil/O wars/O in/O the/O fragile/O states/O of/O Sub-Saharan/LOCATION Africa/LOCATION ./O 
These/O are/O very/O different/O contexts/O to/O most/O of/O Asia/LOCATION 's/O subnational/O conflict/O areas/O ./O 
There/O is/O a/O need/O to/O develop/O new/O approaches/O and/O tools/O for/O dealing/O with/O conflicts/O in/O middle/O income/O and/O growing/O states/O ,/O and/O to/O document/O cases/O of/O success/O and/O failure/O ./O 
There/O is/O a/O real/O opportunity/O for/O Asia/LOCATION 's/O economic/O rise/O to/O be/O accompanied/O by/O leadership/O in/O finding/O new/O ways/O to/O deal/O with/O the/O region/O 's/O subnational/O conflicts/O ./O 
Patrick/PERSON Barron/PERSON ,/O The/O Asia/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION 's/O regional/O director/O for/O conflict/O and/O development/O ,/O is/O based/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O 
