Indian/O Prime/O Minister/O Narendra/PERSON Modi/PERSON has/O arrived/O in/O China/LOCATION for/O a/O three-day-visit/O in/O a/O bid/O to/O strengthen/O an/O economic/O and/O political/O bilateral/O relationship/O afflicted/O by/O an/O underlying/O climate/O of/O mistrust/O ./O 
DW/O examines/O ./O 
Modi/PERSON 's/O first/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION as/O prime/O minister/O -/O from/O May/O 14-16/O -/O will/O provide/O an/O opportunity/O to/O address/O the/O issues/O confronting/O the/O two/O nations/O and/O solidify/O the/O bilateral/O relationship/O ./O 
Just/O like/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O who/O started/O his/O India/LOCATION tour/O last/O September/O in/O Modi/PERSON 's/O home/O state/O of/O Gujarat/LOCATION ,/O Modi/PERSON first/O landed/O in/O Xi/O 's/O home/O province/O of/O Shaanxi/LOCATION before/O heading/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O Shanghai/LOCATION ./O 
During/O the/O trip/O ,/O the/O Indian/O leader/O will/O meet/O not/O only/O President/O Xi/O ,/O but/O also/O Prime/O Minister/O Li/PERSON Keqiang/PERSON and/O a/O host/O of/O other/O Chinese/O leaders/O ,/O and/O hold/O talks/O over/O a/O range/O of/O bilateral/O and/O global/O issues/O ./O 
Modi/PERSON -/O who/O recently/O joined/O the/O Chinese/O social/O networking/O site/O Weibo/PERSON -/O wrote/O that/O he/O hoped/O his/O China/LOCATION visit/O would/O ``/O strengthen/O stability/O ,/O progress/O and/O prosperity/O in/O Asia/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
``/O Modi/PERSON is/O the/O most/O pro-China/O Indian/O PM/O in/O a/O long/O time/O ,/O and/O he/O is/O eager/O to/O reset/O Indo-China/LOCATION ties/O ,/O ''/O said/O Gauri/PERSON Khandekar/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O Asia/ORGANIZATION Program/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O European/O think/O tank/O FRIDE/O ./O 
The/O visit/O will/O largely/O focus/O on/O economic/O issues/O ,/O including/O India/LOCATION 's/O huge/O trade/O deficit/O with/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O analyst/O told/O DW/O ,/O adding/O that/O both/O sides/O are/O likely/O to/O discuss/O existing/O cooperation/O in/O high-speed/O railway/O ,/O nuclear/O power/O and/O electricity/O facilities/O ./O 
China/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION are/O home/O to/O a/O third/O of/O humanity/O ./O 
Hence/O ,/O the/O relationship/O of/O these/O two/O emerging/O powers/O with/O other/O nations/O as/O well/O as/O with/O each/O other/O is/O likely/O to/O play/O a/O decisive/O role/O in/O tackling/O 21st/O century/O global/O challenges/O such/O as/O combating/O climate/O change/O ,/O ensuring/O sustainable/O economic/O development/O ,/O guaranteeing/O free/O trade/O ,/O and/O maintaining/O stability/O ./O 
Although/O China/LOCATION is/O far/O ahead/O of/O India/LOCATION in/O terms/O of/O its/O economic/O size/O and/O military/O capabilities/O ,/O both/O nations/O still/O face/O similar/O and/O vexing/O problems/O :/O endemic/O corruption/O ,/O air/O and/O water/O pollution/O ,/O rapid/O urbanization/O and/O migrant/O workers/O ,/O among/O other/O issues/O ./O 
However/O ,/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O relations/O between/O the/O two/O Asian/O giants/O ,/O there/O are/O ``/O areas/O of/O shared/O interests/O ,/O and/O areas/O of/O significant/O divergence/O ,/O ''/O as/O Gareth/PERSON Price/PERSON ,/O senior/O analyst/O at/O the/O Asia/ORGANIZATION Program/ORGANIZATION at/O Chatham/ORGANIZATION House/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
Over/O the/O years/O ,/O economic/O engagement/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O has/O been/O on/O the/O rise/O ,/O with/O bilateral/O commerce/O worth/O around/O $/O 70/O billion/O in/O 2014/O ./O 
There/O are/O concerns/O on/O the/O Indian/O side/O about/O the/O massive/O trade/O deficit/O of/O over/O $/O 37/O billion/O the/O country/O has/O with/O its/O northern/O neighbor/O ./O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O India/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION have/O fixed/O a/O trade/O target/O of/O $/O 100/O billion/O for/O 2015/O ./O 
But/O despite/O the/O common/O challenges/O and/O growing/O economic/O interdependence/O ,/O an/O underlying/O climate/O of/O mistrust/O continues/O to/O permeate/O the/O bilateral/O relationship/O ./O 
A/O key/O source/O of/O apprehension/O is/O rooted/O in/O their/O unresolved/O border/O dispute/O ./O 
The/O two/O countries/O have/O conflicting/O territorial/O claims/O along/O their/O 2,500-mile-long/O ill-defined/O border/O ,/O and/O they/O fought/O a/O brief/O but/O bloody/O war/O in/O 1962/O ./O 
While/O China/LOCATION claims/O the/O Indian/O state/O of/O Arunachal/LOCATION Pradesh/LOCATION ,/O calling/O it/O as/O South/LOCATION Tibet/LOCATION ,/O India/LOCATION claims/O the/O Aksai/LOCATION Chin/LOCATION region/O -/O a/O virtually/O uninhabited/O area/O between/O China/LOCATION 's/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O and/O Indian-administered/O Kashmir/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O two/O countries/O have/O managed/O to/O maintain/O peace/O and/O tranquility/O along/O the/O border/O for/O over/O a/O quarter/O of/O a/O century/O now/O ,/O despite/O some/O occasional/O low-level/O incidents/O involving/O territorial/O incursions/O ./O 
``/O The/O propensity/O for/O misunderstanding/O is/O also/O fuelled/O by/O limited/O people-to-people/O contacts/O ,/O cultural/O barriers/O and/O rising/O levels/O of/O nationalism/O that/O accompany/O the/O growing/O international/O clout/O of/O both/O countries/O ,/O ''/O Chietigj/PERSON Bajpaee/PERSON ,/O an/O India/LOCATION expert/O at/O King/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION in/O London/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
Prime/O Minister/O Modi/PERSON ,/O whose/O core/O electoral/O promise/O was/O to/O foster/O economic/O development/O ,/O has/O spoken/O of/O emulating/O the/O Chinese/O development/O model/O while/O attracting/O investment/O to/O upgrade/O India/LOCATION 's/O infrastructure/O and/O manufacturing/O capacity/O ./O 
But/O Chinese/O investment/O in/O India/LOCATION amounted/O to/O a/O mere/O $/O 400/O million/O between/O 2000/O and/O 2014/O ,/O a/O figure/O which/O the/O prime/O minister/O hopes/O will/O increase/O in/O the/O future/O ./O 
When/O Xi/PERSON visited/O India/LOCATION last/O year/O ,/O he/O pledged/O some/O $/O 20/O billion/O in/O investments/O as/O part/O of/O a/O five-year/O economic/O and/O trade/O development/O plan/O ./O 
Modi/PERSON will/O also/O be/O seeking/O to/O correct/O the/O underlying/O disparity/O in/O the/O economic/O relationship/O by/O pushing/O for/O greater/O market/O access/O for/O Indian/O exports/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O said/O Bajpaee/PERSON ./O 
India/LOCATION 's/O exports/O to/O China/LOCATION are/O primarily/O natural/O resources/O whereas/O China/LOCATION 's/O exports/O to/O India/LOCATION are/O largely/O manufactured/O and/O value-added/O products/O ./O 
``/O Correcting/O this/O imbalance/O will/O entail/O granting/O Indian/O companies/O ,/O particularly/O those/O in/O the/O pharmaceutical/O ,/O agricultural/O and/O IT/O sectors/O --/O where/O India/LOCATION maintains/O a/O comparative/O advantage/O --/O greater/O access/O to/O Chinese/O markets/O ,/O ''/O argued/O Bajpaee/PERSON ./O 
China/LOCATION ,/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O will/O be/O seeking/O better/O access/O to/O the/O Indian/O market/O for/O Chinese/O companies/O ,/O Liu/PERSON Zongyi/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O on/O Indo-Chinese/O ties/O at/O the/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Institutes/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SIIS/O -RRB-/O ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION would/O also/O like/O to/O cooperate/O with/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION on/O regional/O and/O global/O economic/O issues/O ,/O including/O reforming/O the/O international/O financial/O system/O ,/O Liu/PERSON underlined/O ./O 
Beyond/O economics/O ,/O both/O Xi/O and/O Modi/PERSON will/O also/O hold/O discussions/O on/O prickly/O geopolitical/O issues/O ./O 
A/O cause/O of/O mutual/O distrust/O lies/O in/O the/O growing/O geopolitical/O competition/O between/O the/O two/O powers/O ,/O which/O have/O strategic/O engagements/O with/O each/O others/O '/O adversaries/O ./O 
While/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION is/O deeply/O suspicious/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O increasingly/O closer/O ties/O with/O India/LOCATION 's/O arch-rival/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION looks/O warily/O at/O the/O South/LOCATION Asian/LOCATION nation/O 's/O broadening/O partnership/O with/O countries/O such/O as/O US/LOCATION ,/O Japan/LOCATION and/O Vietnam/LOCATION ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION does/O n't/O want/O to/O see/O India/LOCATION 's/O interference/O in/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION and/O East/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION disputes/O ,/O ''/O stressed/O analyst/O Liu/PERSON ./O 
This/O view/O is/O shared/O by/O Bajpaee/PERSON ./O 
``/O India/LOCATION has/O increasingly/O injected/O itself/O into/O the/O disputes/O through/O its/O pursuit/O of/O deepening/O relations/O with/O several/O claimant/O states/O ,/O including/O Vietnam/LOCATION and/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O pointed/O out/O ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION has/O echoed/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O position/O by/O issuing/O a/O joint/O statement/O in/O January/O and/O calling/O for/O these/O disputes/O to/O be/O settled/O peacefully/O while/O safeguarding/O maritime/O security/O and/O maintaining/O the/O freedom/O of/O navigation/O ./O 
In/O this/O context/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION will/O seek/O reassurances/O from/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION that/O ``/O it/O will/O not/O be/O adding/O fuel/O to/O the/O fire/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O maritime/O disputes/O where/O Beijing/LOCATION maintains/O a/O preference/O for/O a/O bilateral/O ,/O non-internationalized/O approach/O ,/O ''/O Bajpaee/PERSON said/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O India/LOCATION is/O likely/O to/O ask/O China/LOCATION ``/O to/O abandon/O cooperation/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O or/O persuade/O Islamabad/LOCATION to/O eliminate/O terrorism/O in/O Kashmir/LOCATION ,/O ''/O underlined/O China/LOCATION expert/O Liu/PERSON ./O 
Despite/O the/O multiple/O disagreements/O ,/O analysts/O say/O both/O countries/O will/O likely/O discuss/O developments/O in/O regions/O such/O as/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION that/O now/O accounts/O for/O half/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O oil/O and/O 70/O percent/O of/O India/LOCATION 's/O energy/O imports/O ./O 
With/O Modi/PERSON 's/O visit/O ,/O says/O analyst/O Khandekar/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION will/O hope/O not/O only/O to/O build/O better/O ties/O with/O India/LOCATION but/O also/O enlist/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION 's/O support/O for/O shared/O multilateral/O ambitions/O and/O mutual/O interests/O ./O 
