After/O the/O terrorist/O attacks/O in/O Paris/LOCATION ,/O economic/O issues/O are/O no/O longer/O in/O the/O forefront/O at/O the/O two/O Asian/O summits/O ./O 
But/O the/O dispute/O over/O the/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION is/O still/O high/O on/O the/O agenda/O ,/O says/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON ./O 
Immediately/O after/O the/O G20/O Summit/O in/O the/O Turkish/O city/O of/O Antalya/LOCATION ,/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON -LRB-/O above/O -RRB-/O and/O his/O US/LOCATION counterpart/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON flew/O to/O the/O Philippine/O capital/O of/O Manila/LOCATION for/O a/O two-day/O meeting/O of/O the/O 21/O members/O of/O the/O Asia-Pacific/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O APEC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O forum/O ./O 
Afterwards/O ,/O Obama/PERSON goes/O on/O to/O Kuala/LOCATION Lumpur/LOCATION for/O a/O US-ASEAN/O summit/O ,/O while/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> will/O be/O represented/O by/O his/O prime/O minister/O Li/PERSON Keqiang/PERSON ./O 
Russian/O President/O Vladimir/PERSON Putin/PERSON took/O his/O leave/O after/O the/O G20/O summit/O ./O 
He/O has/O enough/O to/O do/O with/O Syria/LOCATION and/O is/O also/O sending/O his/O prime/O minister/O ,/O Dmitry/PERSON Medvedev/PERSON ,/O to/O APEC/ORGANIZATION ./O 
In/O recent/O years/O ,/O such/O summits/O in/O Asia/LOCATION have/O largely/O been/O about/O economic/O issues/O like/O free/O trade/O zones/O and/O trade/O partnerships/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O conflict/O in/O the/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ./O 
This/O year/O ,/O the/O focus/O is/O on/O the/O threat/O of/O terrorism/O ./O 
Even/O at/O the/O G20/O ,/O there/O was/O no/O time/O for/O animosity/O between/O presidents/O :/O Obama/PERSON and/O Putin/PERSON were/O suddenly/O sitting/O together/O in/O club/O chairs/O ,/O holding/O their/O first/O private/O talk/O since/O Russian/O attacks/O on/O Syria/LOCATION began/O -/O as/O if/O the/O West/LOCATION 's/O sanctions/O against/O Russia/LOCATION never/O existed/O ./O 
This/O week/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION offered/O to/O help/O in/O the/O fight/O against/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
It/O 's/O also/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O interest/O that/O militant/O groups/O on/O its/O borders/O in/O the/O western/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> are/O weakened/O ./O 
Islamist/O terrorism/O in/O Asia/LOCATION 
Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION also/O faces/O Islamist/O terrorism/O -/O the/O Philippines/LOCATION ,/O Thailand/LOCATION and/O Indonesia/LOCATION have/O suffered/O attacks/O by/O <ORGANIZATION>Abu/PERSON Sayyaf/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> and/O <ORGANIZATION>Jemaah/O Islamiyah/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Attacks/O and/O kidnappings/O are/O commonplace/O in/O the/O southern/O Philippines/LOCATION ./O 
Extremists/O have/O killed/O people/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O Muslim/O south/O to/O weaken/O the/O Thai/O government/O through/O fear/O and/O terror/O ./O 
There/O have/O been/O attacks/O against/O tourists/O in/O Indonesia/LOCATION ,/O which/O boasts/O the/O largest/O Muslim/O population/O in/O the/O world/O ./O 
Earlier/O this/O week/O ,/O five/O men/O suspected/O of/O planning/O an/O attack/O on/O the/O ASEAN/ORGANIZATION summit/O at/O the/O end/O of/O the/O week/O ,/O were/O arrested/O in/O Malaysia/LOCATION ./O 
The/O terrorist/O attacks/O in/O Paris/LOCATION and/O in/O Asia/LOCATION will/O not/O prevent/O the/O US/LOCATION president/O from/O putting/O pressure/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION with/O regard/O to/O the/O dispute/O over/O the/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ./O 
On/O Tuesday/O ,/O Obama/PERSON visited/O the/O Philippine/ORGANIZATION Navy/ORGANIZATION flagship/O ,/O in/O a/O clear/O signal/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION for/O its/O part/O would/O prefer/O not/O to/O talk/O about/O the/O conflicting/O sovereignty/O claims/O in/O the/O waters/O of/O the/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ./O 
It/O tried/O to/O keep/O the/O dispute/O off/O the/O agenda/O ahead/O of/O the/O summit/O ,/O but/O to/O no/O avail/O as/O Obama/PERSON will/O not/O allow/O the/O dispute/O to/O be/O ignored/O ./O 
The/O dispute/O is/O symbolic/O of/O the/O US-China/O power/O dynamic/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
In/O recent/O weeks/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION has/O authorized/O naval/O patrols/O in/O waters/O near/O the/O Spratly/LOCATION Islands/LOCATION ,/O which/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O expanding/O artificially/O ./O 
To/O the/O major/O annoyance/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O the/O US/LOCATION military/O has/O not/O only/O entered/O the/O 12-mile/O nautical/O zone/O that/O China/LOCATION lays/O claim/O to/O ,/O but/O also/O airspace/O ./O 
Obama/PERSON has/O now/O announced/O that/O the/O US/LOCATION will/O invest/O $/O 250/O million/O to/O boost/O the/O Philippine/ORGANIZATION Navy/ORGANIZATION and/O that/O of/O other/O allies/O in/O the/O region/O to/O promote/O ``/O maritime/O security/O ''/O ./O 
Asia/LOCATION wo/O n't/O allow/O itself/O to/O be/O pocketed/O by/O China/LOCATION <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> has/O tried/O to/O exert/O influence/O on/O the/O power/O dynamic/O by/O investing/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O neighbors/O ./O 
Billions/O have/O already/O been/O spent/O on/O infrastructure/O and/O other/O projects/O ./O 
Some/O states/O have/O been/O hesitant/O to/O cooperate/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O but/O 12/O APEC/ORGANIZATION members/O have/O signed/O the/O Trans-Pacific/O Partnership/O -LRB-/O TPP/O -RRB-/O trade/O agreement/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O not/O allowed/O to/O be/O part/O of/O ./O 
It/O eliminates/O 18,000/O taxes/O that/O were/O imposed/O on/O US/LOCATION exports/O ./O 
In/O Asia/LOCATION ,/O it/O 's/O obviously/O not/O so/O easy/O for/O Obama/PERSON to/O be/O pragmatic/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Whereas/O Putin/PERSON is/O fortunate/O in/O that/O he/O is/O currently/O needed/O much/O more/O urgently/O by/O Obama/PERSON than/O by/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> ./O 
Putin/PERSON has/O entered/O the/O Syria/LOCATION game/O ,/O while/O China/LOCATION remains/O hesitant/O ./O 
Our/O correspondent/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON is/O one/O of/O the/O leading/O German/O China/LOCATION experts/O ./O 
He/O has/O lived/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O over/O 20/O years/O ./O
