Figures/O released/O by/O China/LOCATION 's/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION show/O a/O drop/O in/O the/O number/O of/O defendants/O found/O innocent/O in/O 2014/O compared/O to/O the/O year/O before/O ./O 
A/O judge/O has/O called/O for/O lessons/O to/O be/O learned/O from/O miscarriages/O of/O justice/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O courts/O had/O a/O conviction/O rate/O of/O 99.93/O percent/O in/O 2014/O ,/O with/O just/O 778/O criminal/O defendants/O being/O declared/O innocent/O from/O more/O than/O a/O million/O accused/O ,/O a/O report/O released/O by/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION showed/O on/O Thursday/O ./O 
One/O case/O saw/O a/O teenager/O from/O the/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION region/O exonerated/O 18/O years/O after/O he/O was/O executed/O for/O the/O murder/O and/O rape/O of/O a/O woman/O ./O 
``/O With/O regard/O to/O miscarriages/O of/O justice/O ,/O we/O deeply/O reprove/O ourselves/O and/O demand/O that/O courts/O at/O all/O levels/O draw/O profound/O lessons/O and/O further/O strengthen/O the/O effective/O prevention/O of/O unjust/O and/O false/O cases/O ,/O ''/O Zhou/PERSON said/O ,/O adding/O that/O courts/O must/O ``/O leave/O no/O hiding/O places/O for/O judicial/O corruption/O ./O ''/O 
Zhou/PERSON 's/O report/O for/O 2013/O showed/O 825/O acquittals/O and/O 1.158/O million/O convictions/O ./O 
`/O Forced/O confessions/O '/O 
Rights/O groups/O have/O said/O that/O regular/O miscarriages/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O justice/O system/O come/O about/O because/O force/O is/O often/O used/O to/O extract/O confessions/O and/O the/O accused/O frequently/O do/O not/O receive/O an/O adequate/O defense/O ./O 
The/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION has/O repeatedly/O promised/O legal/O reforms/O to/O prevent/O judicial/O abuses/O amid/O mounting/O public/O anger/O over/O court/O errors/O ./O 
However/O ,/O experts/O have/O argued/O that/O such/O reforms/O are/O made/O difficult/O by/O the/O fact/O that/O courts/O are/O politically/O controlled/O by/O the/O ruling/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O Party/ORGANIZATION has/O pledged/O to/O ensure/O the/O ``/O rule/O of/O law/O with/O Chinese/O characteristics/O ./O ''/O 
`/O Terrorism/O '/O crackdown/O 
Thursday/O 's/O report/O also/O noted/O a/O rise/O of/O 13.3/O percent/O over/O 2013/O in/O the/O number/O of/O people/O sentenced/O last/O year/O for/O crimes/O such/O as/O inciting/O secession/O and/O terrorist/O attacks/O ./O 
``/O -LRB-/O We/O will/O -RRB-/O actively/O participate/O in/O the/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O and/O separatism/O and/O firmly/O punish/O violent/O terrorist/O crimes/O according/O to/O the/O law/O ,/O ''/O it/O said/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O supporters/O say/O he/O has/O been/O jailed/O for/O peaceful/O dissent/O 
China/LOCATION is/O currently/O drafting/O its/O first-ever/O anti-terrorism/O law/O ,/O which/O rights/O groups/O have/O warned/O may/O give/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION even/O more/O powers/O to/O put/O peaceful/O dissent/O or/O criticism/O of/O government/O policies/O in/O the/O category/O of/O terrorist/O activities/O ./O 
Several/O high-profile/O cases/O of/O people/O jailed/O for/O ``/O separatist/O ''/O activities/O have/O drawn/O international/O attention/O in/O recent/O times/O ,/O including/O that/O of/O prominent/O Uighur/O scholar/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/O Tohti/O</U_PERSON> ,/O who/O was/O sentenced/O to/O life/O in/O prison/O in/O September/O amid/O widespread/O condemnation/O from/O rights/O groups/O around/O the/O world/O ./O 
tj/sms/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
