Chinese/O Premier/O Li/PERSON Keqiang/PERSON is/O set/O to/O begin/O a/O three-day/O visit/O to/O France/LOCATION after/O promising/O to/O invest/O more/O in/O the/O EU/LOCATION ./O 
He/O is/O also/O due/O to/O outline/O Chinese/O carbon/O emission/O cuts/O seen/O as/O crucial/O for/O Paris/LOCATION '/O UN/ORGANIZATION climate/O summit/O ./O 
Li/PERSON 's/O visit/O was/O to/O open/O Tuesday/O in/O Paris/LOCATION at/O talks/O with/O host/O French/O President/O Francois/PERSON Hollande/PERSON and/O Prime/O Minister/O Manuel/PERSON Valls/PERSON in/O the/O aftermath/O of/O Monday/O 's/O China-EU/O summit/O ./O 
In/O Brussels/LOCATION late/O Monday/O ,/O Li/PERSON told/O the/O summit/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION was/O ready/O to/O invest/O some/O of/O its/O ``/O ample/O foreign/O exchange/O reserves/O ''/O in/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION 's/O new/O 315/O billion-euro/O -LRB-/O $/O 351-billion/O -RRB-/O infrastructure/O fund/O ./O 
Greece/LOCATION ,/O he/O added/O ,/O should/O stay/O in/O the/O eurozone/O ./O 
`/O Strenuous/O '/O efforts/O on/O climate/O And/O ,/O foreshadowing/O his/O Paris/LOCATION talks/O ,/O Li/PERSON promised/O that/O China/LOCATION as/O the/O world/O 's/O biggest/O emitter/O of/O harmful/O gases/O would/O make/O ``/O strenuous/O efforts/O to/O address/O climate/O change/O ./O ''/O 
France/LOCATION ,/O as/O host/O of/O the/O climate/O summit/O in/O December/O ,/O is/O anxious/O to/O avoid/O a/O repeat/O of/O the/O failed/O 2009/O UN/ORGANIZATION Copenhagen/ORGANIZATION summit/O ,/O the/O last/O attempt/O to/O reach/O a/O global/O climate/O deal/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O so-called/O Intended/O Nationally/O Determined/O Contribution/O -LRB-/O INDC/O -RRB-/O ,/O once/O submitted/O to/O UN/ORGANIZATION climate/O officials/O ,/O is/O expected/O to/O lift/O pledges/O to/O more/O than/O half/O of/O theworld/O 's/O carbon/O emissions/O ./O 
World/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION chief/O economist/O Marianne/PERSON Fay/PERSON said/O China/LOCATION 's/O INDC/O should/O be/O seen/O as/O a/O ``/O floor/O not/O a/O ceiling/O ./O ''/O 
China/LOCATION likes/O to/O under-promise/O and/O over-deliver/O ,/O Fay/PERSON said/O ./O 
Sources/O in/O Valls/PERSON 's/O team/O quoted/O by/O the/O French/O news/O agency/O AFP/ORGANIZATION said/O a/O Chinese/O climate/O announcement/O could/O also/O push/O the/O world/O 's/O third-largest/O greenhouse/O gas/O emitter/O India/LOCATION to/O set/O a/O clear/O target/O to/O reduce/O emissions/O ./O 
French/O industry/O eyeing/O billiions/O Sources/O close/O to/O Vall/PERSON 's/O office/O quoted/O by/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION said/O France/LOCATION hoped/O to/O seal/O 53/O business/O deals/O with/O China/LOCATION during/O Li/PERSON 's/O visit/O worth/O tens/O of/O billions/O of/O euros/O ./O 
Sectors/O to/O benefit/O would/O include/O aeronautics/O ,/O France/LOCATION 's/O largely/O nuclear/O energy/O industry/O and/O container/O shipping/O ./O 
Sources/O said/O Airbus/ORGANIZATION based/O in/O Toulouse/LOCATION was/O in/O talks/O to/O sell/O at/O least/O 50/O A330/O wide-body/O jets/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O world/O 's/O fastest-growing/O aviation/O market/O ./O 
Diplomatic/O sources/O said/O Li/PERSON 's/O visit/O was/O being/O given/O ``/O very/O high/O level/O ''/O protocol/O treatment/O ./O 
It/O comes/O six/O months/O after/O Valls/PERSON travelled/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O called/O for/O more/O French/O products/O to/O be/O exported/O to/O China/LOCATION to/O ``/O rebalance/O ''/O trade/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O ./O 
France/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O struggling/O with/O weak/O growth/O and/O record/O high/O unemployment/O ./O 
It/O imports/O more/O than/O twice/O as/O much/O from/O China/LOCATION compared/O to/O what/O it/O exports/O to/O the/O Asian/O nation/O of/O 1.4/O billion/O residents/O ./O 
Interconnect/O better/O ,/O says/O Juncker/PERSON Li/PERSON 's/O host/O in/O Brussels/LOCATION on/O Monday/O ,/O Jean-Claude/PERSON Juncker/PERSON ,/O who/O heads/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION 's/O executive/O commission/O ,/O said/O two-way/O trade/O between/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION and/O China/LOCATION now/O surpassed/O one/O billion/O euros/O each/O day/O ,/O with/O China/LOCATION the/O bloc/O 's/O second/O most/O important/O trading/O partner/O after/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION and/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION should/O ,/O however/O ,/O improve/O the/O ways/O in/O which/O they/O ``/O interconnect/O ,/O ''/O Juncker/PERSON said/O ./O 
Donald/PERSON Tusk/PERSON ,/O the/O president/O of/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION 's/O Council/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Ministers/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O in/O talks/O with/O Li/PERSON that/O he/O had/O urged/O China/LOCATION to/O ``/O restart/O a/O meaningful/O dialogue/O ''/O with/O the/O exiled/O Tibetan/O spiritual/O leader/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ./O 
Tusk/PERSON said/O he/O had/O also/O expressed/O EU/ORGANIZATION concerns/O about/O curbs/O on/O freedom/O of/O expression/O and/O association/O in/O China/LOCATION in/O relation/O to/O its/O minorities/O ,/O including/O Uighur/O ./O 
Marseille/LOCATION ,/O Toulouse/LOCATION on/O itinerary/O On/O Wednesday/O ,/O Li/PERSON will/O head/O to/O the/O southern/O French/O city/O of/O Marseille/LOCATION where/O he/O will/O be/O met/O by/O Foreign/O Minister/O Laurent/PERSON Fabius/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O visited/O China/LOCATION twice/O since/O March/O last/O year/O ./O 
Li/PERSON concludes/O his/O tour/O in/O Toulouse/LOCATION ,/O where/O he/O and/O Valls/PERSON will/O attend/O a/O France-China/O gathering/O to/O be/O attended/O by/O hundreds/O of/O Chinese/O enterprises/O ./O 
ipj/kms/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 
