Thailand/LOCATION has/O forcibly/O sent/O back/O to/O China/LOCATION over/O 100/O Uighur/O Muslims/O who/O had/O been/O detained/O in/O the/O country/O since/O last/O year/O ./O 
The/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION has/O condemned/O the/O decision/O ,/O saying/O the/O Uighurs/O could/O face/O persecution/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Verachon/PERSON Sukhonthapatipak/PERSON ,/O a/O Thai/O government/O spokesman/O ,/O confirmed/O on/O Thursday/O that/O Bangkok/LOCATION had/O made/O the/O decision/O after/O receiving/O assurance/O from/O China/LOCATION about/O the/O safety/O of/O those/O repatriated/O ./O 
But/O China/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O ministry/O spokesperson/O ,/O Hua/PERSON Chunying/PERSON ,/O said/O the/O government/O would/O take/O legal/O action/O against/O Uighurs/O suspected/O of/O breaking/O the/O law/O ./O 
Uighur/O Muslims/O ,/O a/O Turkic-speaking/O minority/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ,/O have/O long/O faced/O persecution/O by/O China/LOCATION 's/O communist/O authorities/O ./O 
Last/O year/O in/O March/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O Uighurs/O fled/O to/O Thailand/LOCATION to/O seek/O refuge/O ./O 
According/O to/O Sukhonthapatipak/PERSON ,/O ``/O some/O 100/O ''/O Uighurs/O were/O deported/O to/O China/LOCATION on/O Wednesday/O after/O the/O Thai/O government/O found/O ``/O clear/O evidence/O they/O are/O Chinese/O nationals/O ./O ''/O 
A/O group/O of/O 172/O Uighurs/O was/O sent/O to/O Turkey/LOCATION in/O June/O ,/O he/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O around/O 50/O Uighurs/O still/O remain/O in/O Thai/O detention/O as/O the/O officials/O are/O determining/O their/O nationality/O ./O 
`/O Shocking/O and/O disturbing/O '/O The/O office/O of/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION <ORGANIZATION>High/O Commissioner/O</ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION>for/O Refugees/O</ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O UNHCR/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O slammed/O the/O Thai/O government/O 's/O decision/O to/O repatriate/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ./O 
It/O said/O it/O was/O ``/O shocked/O ''/O and/O considered/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O actions/O ``/O a/O flagrant/O violation/O of/O international/O law/O ./O ''/O 
``/O I/O strongly/O urge/O the/O Thai/O authorities/O to/O investigate/O this/O matter/O ,/O and/O appeal/O to/O Thailand/LOCATION to/O honor/O its/O fundamental/O international/O obligations/O ,/O ''/O Volker/PERSON Türk/PERSON ,/O UNHCR/ORGANIZATION 's/O assistant/O high/O commissioner/O for/O protection/O ,/O said/O in/O a/O statement/O on/O Thursday/O ./O 
Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>HRW/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O said/O the/O Thai/O government/O 's/O argument/O that/O the/O Uighurs/O would/O be/O safe/O in/O China/LOCATION was/O ``/O ludicrous/O ./O ''/O 
``/O It/O is/O very/O shocking/O and/O disturbing/O that/O Thailand/LOCATION caved/O in/O to/O pressure/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Sunai/PERSON Phasuk/PERSON ,/O a/O Thailand/LOCATION researcher/O at/O HRW/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O ./O 
Thailand/LOCATION defends/O move/O But/O Thai/O Prime/O Minister/O Prayuth/PERSON Chan-ocha/PERSON justified/O his/O government/O 's/O decision/O and/O said/O that/O as/O a/O third/O country/O ,/O the/O matter/O was/O not/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O problem/O ./O 
``/O I/O am/O asking/O if/O we/O do/O n't/O do/O it/O this/O way/O ,/O then/O how/O would/O we/O do/O it/O ?/O ''/O Prayuth/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O Or/O do/O you/O want/O us/O to/O keep/O them/O for/O ages/O until/O they/O have/O children/O for/O three/O generations/O ?/O ''/O 
The/O military-backed/O prime/O minister/O also/O said/O that/O his/O country/O did/O n't/O want/O to/O hurt/O <OTHER>Muslims/PERSON</OTHER> and/O that/O he/O wants/O ``/O to/O create/O peace/O as/O much/O as/O possible/O ./O ''/O 
Prayuth/PERSON 's/O government/O has/O also/O faced/O criticism/O for/O its/O treatment/O of/O Myanmar/LOCATION 's/O Rohingya/O Muslims/O who/O seek/O asylum/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O 
shs/kms/O -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O <ORGANIZATION>AFP/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O
