China/LOCATION 's/O President/O Xi/PERSON and/O his/O US/LOCATION counterpart/O Obama/PERSON are/O set/O to/O discuss/O an/O array/O of/O issues/O during/O their/O meeting/O at/O the/O White/LOCATION House/LOCATION ,/O including/O trade/O ,/O cybersecurity/O and/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION disputes/O ./O 
But/O what/O about/O human/O rights/O ?/O 
Hundreds/O of/O demonstrators/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION city/O of/O Seattle/LOCATION recently/O protested/O China/LOCATION 's/O worsening/O human/O rights/O record/O and/O growing/O crackdown/O on/O rights/O activists/O under/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ./O 
The/O Chinese/O leader/O ,/O who/O kicked/O off/O a/O high-profile/O state/O visit/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION this/O week/O ,/O is/O expected/O to/O arrive/O in/O Washington/LOCATION on/O Thursday/O to/O hold/O talks/O with/O US/LOCATION 
President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON at/O the/O White/LOCATION House/LOCATION ,/O after/O meeting/O with/O US/LOCATION business/O leaders/O in/O the/O coastal/O seaport/O city/O ./O 
And/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> is/O also/O likely/O to/O notice/O the/O protesters/O awaiting/O his/O arrival/O in/O the/O East/LOCATION Coast/LOCATION ./O 
Huge/O banners/O have/O been/O put/O up/O on/O the/O US/LOCATION capital/O 's/O popular/O museum/O ,/O Newseum/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O located/O between/O the/O White/LOCATION House/LOCATION and/O Capitol/LOCATION Hill/LOCATION ./O 
Some/O of/O the/O slogans/O read/O :/O ``/O Long/O Live/O Freedom/O ,/O Long/O Live/O Democracy/O ,/O ''/O ``/O Chinese/O Government/O Should/O Respect/O Human/O Rights/O ''/O and/O ``/O Release/O Human/O Rights/O Defenders/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Since/O early/O July/O ,/O authorities/O have/O targeted/O more/O than/O 200/O human/O rights/O lawyers/O and/O activists/O in/O China/LOCATION as/O part/O of/O a/O nationwide/O crackdown/O ,/O according/O to/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O rights/O group/O says/O that/O at/O least/O 30/O of/O them/O are/O still/O thought/O to/O be/O in/O detention/O ./O 
Furthermore/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O planning/O a/O new/O law/O that/O would/O enable/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O police/O foreign/O non-governmental/O organizations/O operating/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
Many/O say/O this/O might/O be/O China/LOCATION 's/O biggest/O crackdown/O on/O human/O rights/O activists/O in/O decades/O ./O 
Huge/O banners/O have/O been/O put/O up/O on/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O popular/O <LOCATION>Newseum/O</LOCATION> A/O miserable/O failure/O ?/O 
Despite/O the/O deteriorating/O situation/O ,/O President/O Obama/PERSON is/O unlikely/O to/O press/O his/O guest/O on/O human/O rights/O ,/O say/O critics/O ./O 
``/O This/O is/O actually/O the/O right/O time/O to/O talk/O to/O China/LOCATION not/O only/O about/O trade/O issues/O ,/O but/O also/O about/O civil/O liberties/O ,/O ''/O said/O Wei/PERSON Jingsheng/PERSON ,/O a/O Chinese/O human/O rights/O activist/O who/O has/O been/O living/O in/O exile/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION since/O 1997/O ./O 
``/O President/O Obama/PERSON is/O not/O raising/O human/O rights/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Why/O ?/O 
Because/O he/O is/O worried/O that/O such/O a/O step/O would/O offend/O the/O interests/O of/O the/O US/LOCATION business/O community/O ,/O ''/O the/O activist/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
While/O there/O is/O an/O almost/O endless/O stream/O of/O issues/O to/O discuss/O between/O the/O two/O sides/O ,/O trade/O ,/O cybersecurity/O and/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION disputes/O are/O expected/O to/O top/O the/O list/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O White/ORGANIZATION House/ORGANIZATION insists/O President/O Obama/PERSON will/O confront/O disagreements/O head/O on/O ,/O with/O National/O Security/O Advisor/O Susan/PERSON Rice/PERSON stressing/O that/O Obama/PERSON will/O not/O shy/O away/O from/O raising/O human/O rights/O concerns/O ,/O among/O other/O things/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Opinion/O :/O Powerful/O images/O ,/O little/O substance/O US/LOCATION President/O Obama/PERSON is/O set/O to/O host/O his/O Chinese/O counterpart/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON at/O the/O White/LOCATION House/LOCATION ./O 
While/O the/O meeting/O is/O unlikely/O to/O produce/O major/O breakthroughs/O ,/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> will/O get/O what/O 's/O most/O important/O to/O him/O ,/O says/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Philipp/PERSON Bilsky/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O 24.09.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Boeing/ORGANIZATION seals/O China/LOCATION plane/O deal/O as/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> tours/O factory/O 
As/O president/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON toured/O Boeing/ORGANIZATION 's/O main/O US/LOCATION factory/O ,/O the/O jet/O maker/O announced/O a/O $/O 38/O billion/O Chinese/O plane/O deal/O ./O 
The/O company/O is/O also/O set/O to/O part-build/O many/O of/O its/O 737s/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
-LRB-/O 23.09.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Popular/O US/LOCATION mistrust/O of/O China/LOCATION fueled/O by/O economic/O concerns/O Many/O Americans/O are/O suspicious/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O trade/O policies/O ./O 
Millions/O of/O manufacturing/O jobs/O have/O been/O outsourced/O ./O 
But/O could/O Chinese/O investment/O create/O new/O opportunities/O for/O US/LOCATION workers/O ?/O 
Spencer/PERSON Kimball/PERSON reports/O from/O Chicago/LOCATION ./O 
-LRB-/O 23.09.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Why/O technology/O is/O a/O double-edged/O sword/O for/O US-China/O ties/O The/O US/LOCATION has/O sent/O mixed/O messages/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
While/O the/O tech/O firms/O want/O in/O ,/O the/O government/O is/O talking/O sanctions/O ./O 
But/O with/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON visiting/O ,/O they/O may/O have/O to/O accept/O collaboration/O as/O a/O conduit/O to/O peace/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 23.09.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O for/O Chris/PERSON Smith/PERSON ,/O Chairman/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>US/LOCATION Congressional/O Executive-Commission/O</ORGANIZATION> on/O China/LOCATION ,/O these/O are/O mere/O words/O ./O 
``/O Obama/PERSON has/O failed/O miserably/O ./O 
He/O 's/O done/O nothing/O to/O advance/O the/O goals/O of/O human/O rights/O ./O 
He/O barely/O mentions/O it/O ,/O ''/O Smith/PERSON told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O adding/O that/O Obama/PERSON acted/O in/O a/O similar/O way/O when/O he/O met/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O predecessor/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ./O 
``/O Here/O 's/O the/O guy/O -LRB-/O Obama/PERSON -RRB-/O that/O got/O the/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O ./O 
He/O met/O with/O the/O man/O -LRB-/O <PERSON>Hu/O</PERSON> -RRB-/O that/O was/O holding/O a/O fellow/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize-winner/O and/O there/O was/O not/O a/O mere/O mention/O of/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON ./O ''/O 
Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON ,/O a/O literary/O critic/O and/O co-author/O of/O the/O manifesto/O ``/O Charta/O 08/O ''/O which/O called/O for/O reform/O and/O democracy/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O has/O been/O imprisoned/O since/O December/O 2009/O ./O 
In/O 2010/O ,/O Liu/PERSON received/O the/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O in/O absentia/O ./O 
US/LOCATION intelligentsia/O appeal/O for/O freedom/O Even/O before/O Xi/PERSON left/O for/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O more/O than/O 40/O US/LOCATION intellectuals/O -/O among/O them/O authors/O like/O Paul/PERSON Auster/PERSON ,/O Jeffrey/PERSON Eugenides/PERSON ,/O Jonathan/PERSON Franzen/PERSON and/O Ian/PERSON McEwan/PERSON -/O had/O written/O an/O open/O letter/O to/O the/O Chinese/O president/O demanding/O the/O release/O of/O Chinese/O writers/O who/O ``/O are/O languishing/O in/O jail/O for/O the/O crime/O of/O expressing/O their/O opinions/O ./O ''/O 
The/O authors/O highlighted/O four/O cases/O :/O that/O of/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON and/O his/O wife/O Liu/PERSON Xia/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O been/O under/O house/O arrest/O for/O nearly/O five/O years/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O that/O of/O Uighur/O blogger/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tothi/PERSON</U_PERSON> who/O was/O sentenced/O to/O life/O in/O prison/O one/O year/O ago/O ./O 
And/O they/O also/O criticized/O that/O jailed/O investigative/O journalist/O and/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> correspondent/O Gao/PERSON Yu/PERSON was/O not/O being/O offered/O proper/O medical/O care/O ./O 
``/O The/O imprisonment/O of/O writers/O and/O journalists/O damages/O China/LOCATION 's/O image/O abroad/O and/O undercuts/O its/O ambitions/O to/O be/O a/O strong/O and/O respected/O partner/O on/O the/O world/O stage/O ,/O ''/O read/O the/O letter/O ./O 
The/O authors/O urged/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> to/O release/O the/O writers/O and/O journalists/O and/O ``/O to/O take/O immediate/O steps/O to/O defend/O and/O protect/O the/O rights/O of/O all/O Chinese/O citizens/O to/O communicate/O and/O access/O information/O freely/O ./O ''/O 
Muzzling/O criticism/O Issues/O such/O as/O the/O jailing/O of/O lawyers/O and/O authors/O ,/O the/O oppression/O of/O Tibetans/O and/O Uighurs/O ,/O and/O attacks/O on/O churches/O in/O Eastern/LOCATION China/LOCATION offer/O enough/O reasons/O for/O the/O US/LOCATION to/O address/O growing/O worries/O about/O human/O rights/O with/O the/O Chinese/O leadership/O ./O 
But/O while/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION has/O expressed/O concerns/O ,/O the/O White/ORGANIZATION House/ORGANIZATION has/O ``/O failed/O to/O respond/O proportionately/O to/O the/O alarming/O deterioration/O of/O human/O rights/O ,/O ''/O Sophie/PERSON Richardson/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION director/O at/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION ,/O wrote/O in/O the/O magazine/O <ORGANIZATION>Foreign/O Policy/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
``/O It/O has/O been/O reluctant/O to/O visibly/O and/O consistently/O align/O itself/O with/O China/LOCATION 's/O besieged/O activists/O ,/O with/O the/O exceptions/O of/O eventually/O receiving/O the/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> and/O perfunctorily/O congratulating/O imprisoned/O critic/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON on/O his/O 2010/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O win/O ,/O ''/O she/O added/O ./O 
Other/O governments/O have/O similarly/O toned/O down/O their/O criticism/O ./O 
``/O This/O has/O been/O happening/O for/O more/O than/O ten/O years/O now/O ,/O ''/O Chinese/O dissident/O Wei/PERSON says/O ./O 
``/O And/O it/O 's/O getting/O worse/O and/O worse/O ./O ''/O 
Protesting/O against/O Chinese/O will/O 
A/O couple/O of/O weeks/O ago/O ,/O Chinese/O officials/O came/O to/O Washington/LOCATION to/O plan/O the/O trip/O ./O 
One/O of/O their/O demands/O was/O that/O the/O US/LOCATION ensure/O that/O protesters/O could/O neither/O be/O heard/O nor/O seen/O by/O President/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> ./O 
This/O is/O why/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O Lafayette/LOCATION Park/LOCATION is/O off-limits/O for/O the/O general/O public/O these/O days/O ./O 
However/O ,/O through/O letters/O ,/O banners/O and/O other/O forms/O of/O protest/O ,/O civil/O society/O activists/O want/O to/O make/O sure/O that/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> notices/O the/O actions/O of/O those/O decrying/O the/O deteriorating/O state/O of/O human/O rights/O in/O China/LOCATION -/O even/O if/O he/O is/O unlikely/O to/O do/O so/O in/O his/O political/O discussions/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION leadership/O ./O
