As/O China/LOCATION 's/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON wraps/O up/O a/O historic/O two-day/O visit/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION that/O saw/O the/O signing/O of/O deals/O worth/O $/O 46/O billion/O ,/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> talks/O to/O expert/O Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON about/O what/O the/O trip/O means/O for/O bilateral/O ties/O and/O the/O region/O ./O 
In/O his/O maiden/O official/O visit/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION -/O which/O ended/O on/O April/O 21/O -/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON signed/O 51/O accords/O to/O inaugurate/O the/O <U_LOCATION>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O ,/O which/O will/O create/O a/O network/O of/O roads/O ,/O railways/O and/O pipelines/O linking/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O west/O to/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION through/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O deals/O are/O also/O expected/O to/O boost/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O underperforming/O economy/O and/O generate/O employment/O opportunities/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
<PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> also/O addressed/O the/O Pakistani/O parliament/O ,/O pledging/O to/O work/O together/O with/O the/O South/O Asian/O nation/O and/O applauding/O Islamabad/LOCATION 's/O efforts/O to/O curb/O terrorism/O and/O promised/O to/O stand/O by/O its/O neighbor/O in/O overcoming/O security/O challenges/O ./O 
A/O day/O earlier/O the/O leader/O of/O Asia/LOCATION 's/O biggest/O economy/O was/O received/O with/O unprecedented/O fanfare/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O 
But/O despite/O the/O enthusiasm/O and/O the/O more-than-ever/O cordial/O Sino-Pakistani/O ties/O ,/O analysts/O say/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O main/O interest/O in/O the/O Islamic/O country/O is/O to/O expand/O its/O reach/O across/O <LOCATION>Central/O</LOCATION> and/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION in/O order/O to/O counter/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O Indian/O influence/O ./O 
In/O an/O interview/O with/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O China/LOCATION expert/O Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON ,/O a/O fellow/O with/O the/O Asia/LOCATION program/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>German/O Marshall/O Fund/O</ORGANIZATION> of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O says/O the/O Chinese/O investment/O could/O be/O a/O major/O boost/O for/O the/O ailing/O Pakistani/O economy/O but/O the/O authorities/O will/O face/O a/O number/O of/O logistical/O ,/O political/O and/O security/O challenge/O in/O the/O implementation/O of/O projects/O ./O 
<PERSON>Andrew/O Small/O</PERSON> 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> :/O How/O significant/O was/O President/O Xi/PERSON 's/O visit/O for/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O its/O struggling/O economy/O ?/O 
<PERSON>Andrew/O Small/O</PERSON> :/O It/O was/O an/O unusually/O important/O visit/O ./O 
Even/O if/O only/O some/O of/O the/O economic/O projects/O envisaged/O between/O the/O two/O sides/O succeed/O ,/O it/O would/O be/O a/O major/O investment/O boost/O for/O the/O Pakistani/O economy/O and/O provide/O serious/O support/O towards/O addressing/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O energy/O crisis/O ./O 
Ideally/O ,/O it/O would/O also/O help/O the/O country/O 's/O transition/O towards/O becoming/O an/O economic/O hub/O and/O an/O emerging/O market/O ,/O but/O that/O will/O be/O more/O challenging/O ./O 
Many/O of/O the/O plans/O for/O the/O <U_LOCATION>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/O</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O will/O take/O some/O time/O to/O come/O to/O fruition/O ,/O so/O despite/O all/O the/O fanfare/O ,/O the/O short-term/O political/O implications/O will/O be/O modest/O -/O but/O could/O be/O very/O significant/O over/O the/O long-term/O ./O 
It/O will/O also/O place/O China/LOCATION far/O closer/O to/O the/O political/O centre-stage/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
When/O the/O relationship/O was/O very/O narrowly/O focused/O on/O military/O and/O security/O matters/O ,/O it/O could/O be/O managed/O by/O a/O relatively/O small/O group/O of/O people/O on/O the/O two/O sides/O -/O now/O it/O brings/O a/O much/O wider/O group/O of/O actors/O into/O play/O and/O leaves/O China/LOCATION more/O exposed/O ./O 
Although/O the/O whole/O initiative/O is/O generally/O popular/O ,/O there/O have/O already/O been/O political/O controversies/O about/O who/O will/O benefit/O ,/O given/O the/O scale/O of/O investment/O involved/O ./O 
But/O how/O can/O the/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> help/O boost/O bilateral/O investment/O and/O trade/O ties/O ?/O 
The/O <U_LOCATION>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> is/O often/O seen/O just/O as/O a/O set/O of/O infrastructure/O linkages/O between/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ,/O in/O northwest/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O Pakistani/O port/O of/O Gwadar/LOCATION ./O 
That/O is/O part/O of/O the/O plan/O ,/O but/O many/O of/O the/O projects/O under/O the/O auspices/O of/O the/O corridor/O are/O power/O plants/O ,/O industrial/O ventures/O ,/O and/O other/O economic/O initiatives/O in/O different/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
If/O the/O principal/O infrastructure/O plans/O succeed/O ,/O they/O would/O develop/O Gwadar/LOCATION as/O a/O major/O Indian/LOCATION Ocean/LOCATION port/O for/O transshipment/O to/O China/LOCATION and/O connect/O up/O with/O pipelines/O to/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O trade/O routes/O through/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O potentially/O help/O to/O develop/O economic/O linkages/O with/O India/LOCATION in/O the/O end/O too/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
China/LOCATION expands/O influence/O in/O `/O economic/O colony/O '/O Pakistan/LOCATION
<PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> Jinping/PERSON 's/O visit/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION promises/O to/O boost/O the/O Islamic/O country/O 's/O struggling/O economy/O ,/O but/O experts/O warn/O there/O are/O many/O strings/O attached/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O aid/O ./O 
Why/O does/O Pakistan/LOCATION need/O to/O be/O careful/O in/O dealing/O with/O China/LOCATION ?/O 
-LRB-/O 20.04.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Asia-Pacific/LOCATION countries/O increasingly/O resort/O to/O death/O penalty/O to/O curb/O crime/O <LOCATION>Asia-Pacific/O</LOCATION> nations/O ,/O excluding/O China/LOCATION ,/O executed/O fewer/O people/O and/O issued/O fewer/O death/O sentences/O last/O year/O than/O in/O 2013/O ,/O a/O new/O <ORGANIZATION>AI/O</ORGANIZATION> report/O shows/O ./O 
But/O the/O study/O also/O points/O to/O some/O worrisome/O trends/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> examines/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 01.04.2015/O -RRB-/O 
The/O Sino-Pakistani/O axis/O :/O Asia/LOCATION 's/O `/O little/O understood/O '/O relationship/O China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION have/O been/O described/O as/O ``/O all/O weather/O friends/O ,/O ''/O but/O the/O nature/O of/O their/O ties/O remains/O secretive/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> talks/O to/O analyst/O Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON ,/O about/O some/O of/O the/O most/O sensitive/O aspects/O of/O this/O strategic/O relationship/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 15.01.2015/O -RRB-/O 
But/O even/O if/O some/O of/O these/O plans/O do/O not/O come/O off/O ,/O it/O will/O notably/O improve/O the/O land/O trade/O route/O between/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O infrastructure/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION itself/O ,/O and/O the/O country/O 's/O capacity/O to/O generate/O sufficient/O power/O to/O address/O its/O energy/O needs/O ./O 
What/O challenges/O does/O the/O realization/O of/O these/O projects/O face/O ?/O 
There/O are/O logistical/O ,/O political/O and/O security/O challenges/O ./O 
The/O logistical/O challenges/O are/O significant/O ./O 
The/O Karakoram/LOCATION Highway/LOCATION has/O been/O closed/O for/O five/O years/O after/O a/O landslide/O caused/O a/O lake/O to/O flood/O stretches/O of/O the/O route/O ,/O and/O the/O road/O and/O railway/O plans/O will/O be/O subject/O to/O similar/O threats/O from/O the/O natural/O environment/O in/O future/O ./O 
Travel/O up/O the/O highway/O ,/O and/O through/O the/O high/O mountain/O passes/O ,/O it/O is/O tough/O to/O imagine/O it/O as/O a/O smoothly/O functioning/O trade/O artery/O ./O 
The/O political/O challenges/O are/O familiar/O ones/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION --/O the/O capacity/O of/O the/O government/O to/O execute/O the/O plans/O ,/O suspicions/O about/O whether/O some/O of/O benefits/O will/O be/O directed/O to/O politically/O connected/O companies/O and/O regions/O rather/O than/O the/O most/O effective/O economic/O partners/O ,/O corruption/O problems/O and/O so/O on/O ./O 
The/O security/O challenges/O are/O also/O familiar/O -/O groups/O in/O conflict/O with/O the/O Pakistani/O government/O will/O target/O the/O projects/O ,/O whether/O that/O is/O <OTHER>Balochi/PERSON</OTHER> nationalists/O or/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Pakistani/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION</ORGANIZATION> ,/O and/O instability/O in/O specific/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O will/O make/O some/O the/O investments/O hard/O to/O pull/O off/O ./O 
How/O does/O China/LOCATION benefit/O from/O providing/O all/O this/O assistance/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION ?/O 
It/O 's/O not/O really/O assistance/O -/O these/O are/O investments/O ,/O and/O the/O Pakistani/O side/O has/O also/O provided/O part/O of/O the/O financing/O ./O 
But/O China/LOCATION 's/O willingness/O to/O provide/O concessional/O loans/O does/O have/O several/O broader/O benefits/O in/O mind/O ./O 
Even/O if/O only/O some/O of/O the/O economic/O projects/O envisaged/O between/O the/O two/O sides/O succeed/O ,/O it/O would/O be/O a/O major/O investment/O boost/O for/O the/O Pakistani/O economy/O The/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> forms/O part/O of/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION Economic/LOCATION Belt/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O Maritime/LOCATION Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION ,/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON 's/O signature/O foreign/O policy/O initiative/O ,/O which/O is/O intended/O to/O help/O drive/O growth/O in/O the/O Chinese/O interior/O through/O developing/O better/O infrastructure/O connections/O with/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O its/O principal/O markets/O in/O Europe/LOCATION and/O its/O natural/O resource/O suppliers/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
Chinese/O companies/O that/O can/O no/O longer/O pursue/O large/O infrastructure/O investments/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O while/O the/O country/O shifts/O to/O a/O more/O consumption-driven/O growth/O model/O ,/O are/O being/O pushed/O to/O do/O so/O abroad/O instead/O ./O 
But/O it/O is/O also/O a/O stabilization/O plan/O for/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O periphery/O --/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION withdrawal/O from/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O the/O worsening/O terrorist/O threat/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O China/LOCATION has/O grown/O far/O more/O concerned/O about/O rising/O militancy/O in/O <LOCATION>South/O</LOCATION> and/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
These/O economic/O initiatives/O are/O supposed/O to/O help/O address/O that/O ,/O including/O by/O stabilizing/O Pakistan/LOCATION itself/O ,/O which/O has/O been/O a/O particular/O source/O of/O concern/O for/O China/LOCATION ,/O given/O that/O Uighur/O militant/O groups/O have/O been/O based/O in/O the/O Pakistani/O tribal/O areas/O for/O much/O of/O the/O last/O decade/O ./O 
Many/O analysts/O argue/O however/O ,/O that/O this/O economic/O aid/O comes/O with/O many/O strings/O attached/O ./O 
What/O price/O is/O Islamabad/LOCATION set/O to/O pay/O level/O of/O financial/O support/O ?/O 
Most/O of/O the/O strings/O for/O Chinese/O financing/O involve/O the/O bidding/O terms/O for/O contracts/O and/O the/O involvement/O of/O Chinese/O companies/O ./O 
Beyond/O that/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION does/O n't/O demand/O much/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION that/O it/O would/O n't/O receive/O anyway/O ,/O given/O the/O two/O sides/O '/O longstanding/O and/O close/O security/O relationship/O ./O 
In/O this/O instance/O though/O ,/O there/O are/O expectations/O from/O China/LOCATION that/O Pakistan/LOCATION should/O ensure/O a/O stable/O environment/O for/O such/O a/O large/O set/O of/O investments/O --/O that/O does/O n't/O just/O mean/O the/O protection/O of/O projects/O ,/O it/O also/O means/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION wants/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O stabilize/O its/O relationships/O with/O its/O neighbors/O ,/O especially/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O refrain/O from/O embroiling/O itself/O in/O any/O activities/O that/O might/O create/O security/O problems/O in/O the/O wider/O region/O ./O 
To/O which/O extent/O can/O the/O rampant/O militancy/O and/O volatile/O security/O situation/O in/O the/O country/O impede/O the/O implementation/O of/O these/O projects/O ?/O 
Some/O of/O the/O projects/O could/O certainly/O be/O impaired/O -/O Chinese/O companies/O have/O withdrawn/O after/O attacks/O and/O kidnappings/O before/O ./O 
If/O the/O transportation/O links/O are/O not/O secure/O then/O they/O wo/O n't/O be/O economically/O viable/O ./O 
But/O many/O of/O the/O projects/O have/O also/O been/O planned/O for/O less/O volatile/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O ,/O or/O can/O be/O pretty/O well/O protected/O ,/O so/O barring/O a/O serious/O deterioration/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O security/O a/O number/O of/O them/O will/O move/O forward/O anyway/O ./O 
What/O implications/O does/O this/O visit/O have/O for/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O region/O ,/O especially/O India/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ?/O 
The/O <U_LOCATION>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> provides/O an/O incentive/O for/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O improve/O its/O economic/O and/O political/O relations/O with/O its/O neighbors/O ,/O and/O also/O some/O opportunities/O for/O them/O to/O use/O the/O corridor/O as/O part/O of/O their/O own/O trade/O linkages/O with/O China/LOCATION ,/O especially/O in/O the/O case/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
There/O are/O logistical/O ,/O political/O and/O security/O challenges/O to/O the/O <U_LOCATION>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O says/O <PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> 
India/LOCATION will/O be/O less/O comfortable/O with/O the/O infrastructure/O projects/O in/O Kashmir/LOCATION and/O the/O development/O of/O port/O facilities/O that/O could/O be/O used/O for/O military/O purposes/O too/O ./O 
The/O focus/O on/O economic/O relations/O during/O the/O public/O aspects/O of/O the/O visit/O has/O in/O some/O ways/O distracted/O attention/O from/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O China-Pakistan/LOCATION relationship/O is/O still/O underpinned/O by/O the/O militaries/O on/O the/O two/O sides/O ./O 
<PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O visit/O will/O almost/O certainly/O have/O involved/O new/O defense/O agreements/O and/O cooperation/O plans/O too/O ,/O much/O of/O which/O still/O has/O a/O traditional/O focus/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O balancing/O role/O vis-à-vis/O India/LOCATION ./O 
But/O the/O broad/O trajectory/O of/O the/O relationship/O ,/O which/O involves/O a/O far/O more/O serious-minded/O focus/O on/O counter-terrorism/O issues/O than/O in/O the/O past/O ,/O is/O one/O that/O should/O benefit/O even/O countries/O that/O are/O wary/O of/O the/O two/O sides/O '/O close/O security/O ties/O ./O 
Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON is/O a/O transatlantic/O fellow/O with/O the/O Asia/LOCATION program/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>German/O</ORGANIZATION> Marshall/ORGANIZATION Fund/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O author/O of/O the/O book/O ``/O The/O China-Pakistan/O Axis/O -/O Asia/LOCATION 's/O New/O Geopolitics/O ./O ''/O 
You/O can/O follow/O him/O on/O <ORGANIZATION>Twitter/O</ORGANIZATION> @ajwsmall/O ./O 
The/O interview/O was/O conducted/O by/O Gabriel/PERSON Domínguez/PERSON ./O
