Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON is/O heading/O to/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O where/O he/O will/O unveil/O investments/O worth/O $/O 46/O billion/O ./O 
The/O move/O is/O seen/O as/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O attempt/O to/O increase/O its/O influence/O in/O Asia/LOCATION ./O 
Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O president/O ,/O was/O scheduled/O to/O launch/O $/O 46/O billion/O -LRB-/O 43/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O worth/O of/O investments/O in/O energy/O and/O infrastructure/O on/O his/O visit/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION on/O Monday/O ./O 
``/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O for/O China/LOCATION ,/O is/O now/O of/O pivotal/O importance/O ./O 
This/O has/O to/O succeed/O ,/O ''/O Mushahid/PERSON Hussain/PERSON Sayed/PERSON ,/O chairman/O of/O the/O Pakistani/O parliament/O 's/O defense/O committee/O ,/O told/O the/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O about/O the/O partnership/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O ambitious/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION corridor/O Xi/O 's/O two-day/O visit/O would/O include/O a/O speech/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O parliament/O and/O announcements/O related/O to/O the/O China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O which/O would/O link/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O southern/O Gwadar/LOCATION port/O -LRB-/O pictured/O above/O -RRB-/O on/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION with/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION transferred/O control/O over/O Gwadar/LOCATION to/O a/O Chinese/O public/O company/O in/O 2013/O ./O 
The/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION also/O included/O plans/O to/O create/O road/O ,/O rail/O and/O oil/O pipeline/O links/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION would/O invest/O about/O 34/O billion/O dollars/O in/O energy/O projects/O ,/O Ahsan/PERSON Iqbal/PERSON ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O minister/O for/O planning/O and/O development/O told/O journalists/O ./O 
``/O The/O real/O opportunity/O of/O this/O China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION is/O that/O it/O changes/O the/O scope/O of/O the/O relationship/O from/O geopolitics/O to/O geoeconomics/O ,/O ''/O Iqbal/PERSON argued/O ,/O adding/O that/O the/O projects/O would/O have/O a/O ``/O significant/O transformative/O effect/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O economy/O ./O ''/O 
Islamist/O insurgency/O a/O big/O threat/O The/O two/O military/O allies/O face/O several/O challenges/O in/O the/O implementation/O of/O the/O project/O ,/O the/O biggest/O being/O that/O of/O Islamist/O militants/O active/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Baluchistan/LOCATION state/O ./O 
China/LOCATION was/O also/O worried/O about/O Muslim/O terrorists/O from/O its/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O joining/O hands/O with/O terrorists/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION need/O to/O align/O security/O concerns/O more/O closely/O to/O strengthen/O security/O cooperation/O ,/O ''/O President/O Xi/PERSON said/O in/O an/O address/O to/O journalists/O a/O day/O before/O his/O trip/O to/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Our/O cooperation/O in/O the/O security/O and/O economic/O fields/O reinforce/O each/O other/O and/O they/O must/O be/O advanced/O simultaneously/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O expanded/O investment/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O seen/O as/O an/O attempt/O to/O increase/O the/O country/O 's/O dominance/O in/O Asia/LOCATION and/O offset/O US/LOCATION and/O Indian/O influence/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O first/O visit/O by/O a/O Chinese/O head/O of/O state/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION in/O the/O last/O nine/O years/O ./O 
In/O 2013/O ,/O Pakistani/O Prime/O Minister/O Nawaz/PERSON Sharif/PERSON visited/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O seal/O important/O energy/O deals/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O investment/O has/O raised/O hope/O among/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O people/O ,/O but/O first/O problems/O like/O jihadist/O violence/O and/O improving/O infrastructure/O need/O to/O be/O tackled/O ./O 
mg/jil/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 
