While/O international/O efforts/O are/O focused/O on/O subduing/O the/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O threat/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O experts/O warn/O that/O a/O potential/O peril/O could/O emerge/O from/O Asian/O jihadist/O groups/O ,/O who/O feel/O emboldened/O by/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> '/O ``/O success/O ./O ''/O 
The/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O militant/O group/O has/O been/O trying/O to/O expand/O into/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Bangladesh/LOCATION for/O quite/O some/O time/O ./O 
While/O they/O have/O not/O been/O very/O successful/O ,/O they/O seem/O to/O have/O a/O fairly/O good/O chance/O now/O ./O 
The/O reason/O for/O this/O is/O that/O the/O Middle/O Eastern/O jihadist/O group/O can/O now/O present/O the/O terrorist/O attacks/O in/O Paris/LOCATION ,/O which/O killed/O over/O 130/O people/O and/O injured/O dozens/O on/O November/O 13/O ,/O as/O a/O ``/O success/O story/O ''/O to/O extremist/O groups/O in/O South/O and/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
Experts/O believe/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> is/O emerging/O as/O an/O inspiration/O not/O only/O to/O new/O jihadists/O ,/O but/O also/O to/O disillusioned/O members/O of/O militant/O groups/O such/O as/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O <ORGANIZATION>al/O Qaeda/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> has/O become/O an/O organization/O which/O has/O not/O only/O captured/O vast/O swathes/O of/O territory/O in/O Iraq/LOCATION and/O Syria/LOCATION ,/O but/O also/O struck/O terror/O at/O the/O heart/O of/O Europe/LOCATION -/O a/O jihadist/O cause/O shared/O by/O most/O Islamist/O organizations/O ./O 
Despite/O the/O fact/O that/O international/O efforts/O are/O currently/O focused/O on/O subduing/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O particularly/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ,/O analysts/O point/O out/O that/O a/O potent/O threat/O to/O world/O peace/O could/O come/O from/O Asia/LOCATION ./O 
Witnesses/O said/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> gunmen/O shouted/O ``/O Allahu/O Akbar/O ''/O as/O they/O stormed/O into/O the/O <LOCATION>Bataclan/O</LOCATION> concert/O hall/O in/O Paris/LOCATION ``/O The/O Paris/LOCATION attacks/O ,/O like/O all/O other/O terrorist/O activities/O of/O similar/O magnitude/O ,/O will/O hugely/O embolden/O Islamist/O groups/O not/O only/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION but/O also/O in/O other/O countries/O ,/O ''/O Arif/PERSON Jamal/PERSON ,/O a/O US-based/O scholar/O on/O Islamic/O extremism/O ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
``/O The/O attacks/O show/O that/O Western/O countries/O are/O more/O vulnerable/O to/O terrorism/O emerging/O from/O Asia/LOCATION than/O ever/O ./O 
Many/O radical/O groups/O and/O individuals/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION will/O respond/O by/O joining/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> or/O creating/O a/O wider/O support/O base/O for/O the/O militant/O group/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
This/O Paris/LOCATION attacks/O ,/O thus/O ,/O should/O be/O looked/O at/O in/O the/O broader/O perspective/O of/O an/O expanding/O global/O jihadist/O movement/O ,/O analysts/O underline/O ./O 
`/O Significant/O support/O '/O in/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION 
<PERSON>Jamal/LOCATION</PERSON> fears/O the/O Paris/LOCATION attacks/O will/O not/O only/O strengthen/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> '/O infrastructure/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION but/O also/O globally/O ./O 
``/O It/O will/O attract/O new/O allies/O from/O all/O over/O the/O world/O ./O 
Big/O and/O small/O groups/O will/O join/O its/O ranks/O ./O 
Many/O individuals/O ,/O including/O those/O who/O find/O their/O national/O Islamist/O groups/O not/O strong/O enough/O to/O impose/O shariah/O ,/O will/O move/O towards/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O ''/O Jamal/PERSON said/O ./O 
But/O more/O than/O in/O any/O other/O country/O ,/O the/O conditions/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION are/O ripe/O for/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> to/O become/O a/O major/O force/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> and/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION have/O been/O on/O hostile/O terms/O ,/O despite/O the/O fact/O that/O both/O organizations/O are/O dominated/O by/O Sunni/O extremists/O ./O 
But/O lately/O ,/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> has/O been/O building/O up/O its/O presence/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O recruiting/O disenchanted/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION members/O ./O 
A/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION splinter/O group/O ,/O headed/O by/O Mullah/PERSON Mohammad/PERSON Rasool/PERSON ,/O already/O has/O close/O ties/O with/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
It/O has/O been/O involved/O in/O a/O fierce/O battle/O against/O the/O main/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION group/O led/O by/O Mullah/PERSON Akhtar/PERSON Mansoor/PERSON ,/O inflicting/O heavy/O casualties/O on/O its/O opponents/O ./O 
``/O There/O is/O a/O significant/O support/O base/O for/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> in/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
In/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O most/O of/O the/O Salafists/O and/O <OTHER>Wahhabists/LOCATION</OTHER> have/O already/O joined/O its/O ranks/O ,/O particularly/O in/O the/O provinces/O of/O Nuristan/LOCATION ,/O Kunar/LOCATION and/O Nangarhar/LOCATION ./O 
Many/O factions/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION have/O also/O joined/O or/O allied/O themselves/O with/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Most/O importantly/O ,/O the/O Jamatud/PERSON Dawa/PERSON -LRB-/O former/O <ORGANIZATION>Lashkar-e-Taiba</ORGANIZATION>/O -RRB-/O has/O allied/O itself/O with/O the/O Middle/O Eastern/O terror/O group/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Jamal/PERSON told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O adding/O that/O the/O situation/O was/O not/O much/O different/O in/O neighboring/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Mosques/O in/O different/O Pakistani/O cities/O are/O openly/O supporting/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> and/O its/O agenda/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O most/O radicalized/O mosques/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O called/O the/O <OTHER>Red/ORGANIZATION Mosque/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ,/O has/O publicly/O declared/O backing/O the/O Sunni/O militant/O group/O ,/O ''/O Jamal/PERSON said/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Tribute/O to/O the/O French/O capital/O Many/O Parisians/O are/O determined/O to/O stand/O firm/O in/O the/O face/O of/O terror/O ./O 
Once/O the/O initial/O shock/O is/O over/O they/O will/O continue/O to/O enjoy/O life/O in/O their/O city/O ,/O not/O least/O because/O the/O French/O capital/O thrives/O on/O its/O cultural/O diversity/O ./O -LRB-/O 17.11.2015/O -RRB-/O 
`/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> to/O benefit/O '/O from/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION infighting/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 
Conflicting/O reports/O have/O emerged/O from/O Afghanistan/LOCATION about/O the/O death/O of/O Mullah/PERSON Mansoor/PERSON Dadullah/PERSON ,/O the/O leader/O of/O a/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION splinter/O group/O ./O 
Experts/O believe/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION infighting/O could/O eventually/O strengthen/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O -LRB-/O 13.11.2015/O -RRB-/O 
`/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> '/O seeking/O a/O foothold/O in/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION 
The/O terror/O group/O `/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION '/O -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O now/O controls/O large/O parts/O of/O Syria/LOCATION and/O Iraq/LOCATION ./O 
It/O is/O luring/O new/O recruits/O through/O a/O sophisticated/O media/O strategy/O ,/O which/O Southeast/O Asian/O states/O are/O finding/O difficult/O to/O counter/O ./O -LRB-/O 24.06.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Charlie/PERSON Hebdo/PERSON cartoons/O give/O impetus/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O extremists/O Protests/O against/O Charlie/PERSON Hebdo/PERSON cartoons/O have/O turned/O violent/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
Experts/O say/O the/O controversy/O surrounding/O the/O magazine/O will/O likely/O embolden/O extremists/O in/O the/O country/O and/O shrink/O the/O space/O for/O secular/O people/O ./O -LRB-/O 16.01.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Many/O Pakistanis/O and/O Afghans/O hailed/O on/O social/O media/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> and/O its/O ability/O to/O strike/O Paris/LOCATION ,/O which/O experts/O say/O is/O a/O worrying/O sign/O ,/O but/O represents/O the/O general/O anti-Western/O feeling/O ./O 
Bangladesh/LOCATION on/O the/O edge/O A/O number/O of/O attacks/O in/O Bangladesh/LOCATION have/O been/O claimed/O by/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> or/O its/O allied/O networks/O ./O 
Although/O local/O officials/O downplay/O the/O threat/O ,/O security/O experts/O have/O a/O different/O take/O on/O it/O ./O 
``/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> exists/O in/O Bangladesh/LOCATION and/O is/O expanding/O ,/O ''/O Siegfried/PERSON O./PERSON Wolf/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O research/O at/O the/O Brussels-based/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION Democratic/O Forum/O -LRB-/O <OTHER>SADF/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> -RRB-/O ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
``/O Bangladesh/LOCATION has/O turned/O into/O a/O hub/O for/O international/O terrorism/O in/O the/O past/O two/O decades/O ./O 
Today/O ,/O we/O can/O say/O that/O the/O country/O serves/O as/O a/O significant/O recruiting/O ground/O for/O the/O global/O jihadist/O movement/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O the/O arrests/O of/O Bangladeshi/O nationals/O fighting/O for/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> and/O Al-Nusra/ORGANIZATION Front/ORGANIZATION in/O Syria/LOCATION were/O proof/O of/O that/O ./O 
While/O Wolf/PERSON does/O not/O think/O the/O Paris/LOCATION attacks/O will/O drastically/O change/O the/O jihadist/O landscape/O in/O the/O Muslim-majority/O South/O Asian/O country/O ,/O he/O admits/O that/O they/O will/O likely/O function/O as/O a/O catalyst/O for/O the/O further/O polarization/O and/O entrenchment/O of/O jihadism/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O Uighurs/O and/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION 's/O militants/O
Analyst/O Wolf/PERSON says/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> '/O activities/O are/O also/O motivating/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uighur/O militants/O ./O 
``/O The/O fact/O that/O Uighur/O Muslim/O extremists/O are/O increasingly/O choosing/O territories/O outside/O China/LOCATION to/O build/O a/O support/O network/O or/O to/O carry/O out/O militant/O activities/O is/O an/O indication/O that/O they/O are/O broadening/O their/O goals/O and/O strategies/O ,/O ''/O Wolf/PERSON said/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O according/O to/O Wolf/PERSON ,/O is/O aware/O of/O the/O geo-strategic/O significance/O of/O the/O areas/O where/O Uighur/O militants/O are/O currently/O operating/O ./O 
``/O For/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O Uighurs/O are/O a/O potential/O ally/O ./O 
Uighurs/O lack/O human/O ,/O financial/O and/O logistic/O capacities/O ,/O and/O the/O wealthy/O and/O successful/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> group/O could/O boost/O their/O activities/O in/O the/O future/O ./O 
It/O is/O also/O likely/O that/O Uighurs/O could/O join/O its/O ranks/O and/O fight/O directly/O under/O its/O banner/O ,/O ''/O Wolf/PERSON warned/O ,/O adding/O that/O the/O Paris/LOCATION attacks/O could/O be/O an/O additional/O motivation/O for/O Uighur/O militants/O ./O 
`/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> '/O seeking/O a/O foothold/O in/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION The/O situation/O is/O worrisome/O in/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION as/O well/O ./O 
At/O present/O ,/O over/O 500/O Indonesians/O and/O several/O dozen/O Malaysians/O are/O believed/O to/O be/O in/O the/O ranks/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> terrorist/O group/O ./O 
These/O numbers/O were/O enough/O for/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> to/O form/O a/O combat/O unit/O called/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Malay/O Archipelago/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O ''/O 
The/O threat/O posed/O by/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> must/O be/O taken/O seriously/O ,/O Singaporean/O Prime/O Minister/O Lee/PERSON Hsien/PERSON Long/PERSON warned/O in/O June/O ./O 
``/O The/O threat/O is/O no/O longer/O over/O there/O ;/O it/O is/O over/O here/O ,/O ''/O the/O PM/O said/O at/O the/O annual/O <LOCATION>Shangri/ORGANIZATION La/ORGANIZATION</LOCATION> <OTHER>Dialogue/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> security/O conference/O ./O 
This/O perception/O is/O also/O shared/O by/O Felix/PERSON Heiduk/PERSON ,/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>SWP/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ,/O a/O Berlin-based/O think/O tank/O ./O 
``/O The/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> propaganda/O machine/O has/O been/O successful/O in/O luring/O a/O number/O of/O militant/O Islamist/O groups/O operating/O in/O Indonesia/LOCATION or/O in/O the/O south/O of/O the/O Philippines/LOCATION ,/O and/O these/O groups/O now/O openly/O pledge/O allegiance/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O ''/O 
Siegfried/PERSON Herzog/PERSON ,/O a/O regional/O director/O at/O the/O Friedrich/ORGANIZATION Naumann/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> that/O Malaysia/LOCATION recently/O sentenced/O a/O member/O of/O its/O navy/O to/O nine/O months/O in/O jail/O for/O having/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> propaganda/O on/O his/O mobile/O phone/O ./O 
``/O Some/O radicals/O have/O traveled/O to/O Syria/LOCATION to/O fight/O along/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
For/O that/O reason/O ,/O the/O security/O forces/O have/O redoubled/O their/O efforts/O to/O control/O extremists/O ./O 
But/O it/O is/O too/O early/O to/O tell/O if/O the/O Paris/LOCATION attacks/O could/O embolden/O Islamists/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O ''/O Herzog/PERSON said/O ./O
