Pakistani/O military/O 's/O alleged/O rights/O abuses/O in/O western/O Balochistan/LOCATION province/O have/O come/O under/O scrutiny/O after/O the/O killing/O of/O activist/O Sabeen/PERSON Mahmud/PERSON in/O Karachi/LOCATION ./O 
Mahmud/PERSON held/O a/O talk/O on/O the/O issue/O right/O before/O she/O was/O shot/O dead/O ./O 
The/O murder/O of/O Sabeen/LOCATION Mahmud/LOCATION on/O Friday/O has/O turned/O the/O spotlight/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O conflict-ridden/O Balochistan/LOCATION province/O and/O the/O Islamic/O country/O 's/O powerful/O army/O 's/O human/O rights/O violations/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
Balochistan/LOCATION ,/O which/O borders/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O is/O rich/O in/O oil/O ,/O gas/O ,/O and/O minerals/O ,/O yet/O it/O remains/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O poorest/O province/O ./O 
Rebel/O groups/O have/O waged/O a/O separatist/O insurgency/O in/O the/O province/O for/O decades/O ,/O complaining/O that/O the/O central/O government/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION and/O the/O richer/O Punjab/LOCATION province/O unfairly/O exploit/O their/O resources/O ./O 
In/O 2005/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION reacted/O to/O the/O insurgency/O by/O launching/O a/O military/O operation/O in/O the/O province/O ./O 
Mahmud/PERSON ,/O the/O 40-year-old/O civil/O liberties/O activist/O and/O social/O worker/O was/O director/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>The/O Second/O Floor/O</ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>T2F/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ,/O a/O community/O space/O for/O open/O dialogue/O ./O 
On/O Friday/O ,/O <ORGANIZATION>T2F/O</ORGANIZATION> organized/O a/O talk/O called/O ``/O Unsilencing/O <LOCATION>Balochistan/O</LOCATION> Take/O 2/O ,/O ''/O featuring/O two/O prominent/O <OTHER>Baloch/PERSON</OTHER> rights/O activists/O -/O <PERSON>Mama/O</PERSON> Abdul/PERSON Qadeer/PERSON and/O Farzana/PERSON Baluch/PERSON -/O who/O have/O been/O campaigning/O for/O the/O missing/O <OTHER>Baloch/PERSON</OTHER> people/O ./O 
Rights/O groups/O say/O these/O people/O have/O been/O illegally/O detained/O by/O the/O military/O 's/O intelligence/O agencies/O ./O 
Local/O rights/O groups/O have/O the/O details/O of/O 8,000/O people/O who/O they/O say/O have/O been/O disappeared/O over/O the/O past/O ten/O years/O and/O have/O not/O been/O seen/O since/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Asian/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O AHRC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O 23/O bullet-riddled/O bodies/O of/O these/O missing/O persons/O were/O discovered/O in/O different/O parts/O of/O Balochistan/LOCATION in/O January/O 2012/O ./O 
From/O August/O 2011/O to/O January/O 2012/O ,/O 56/O <OTHER>Baloch/PERSON</OTHER> people/O are/O known/O to/O have/O been/O murdered/O and/O dumped/O on/O roadsides/O ,/O according/O to/O AHRC/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Pakistani/O security/O agencies/O claim/O these/O people/O were/O arrested/O on/O terrorism/O charges/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O whereabouts/O of/O these/O people/O are/O kept/O secret/O from/O the/O public/O ;/O they/O have/O not/O been/O presented/O to/O local/O courts/O for/O a/O proper/O trial/O ./O 
Observers/O say/O that/O Balochistan/LOCATION ,/O despite/O major/O development/O projects/O initiated/O by/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O including/O the/O recently-signed/O $/O 46/O billion/O <U_LOCATION>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O project/O ,/O remains/O a/O no-go/O area/O for/O the/O media/O ./O 
The/O local/O media/O rarely/O reports/O about/O the/O rampant/O rights/O abuses/O in/O the/O province/O ,/O whereas/O <OTHER>Baloch/PERSON</OTHER> activists/O are/O constantly/O harassed/O and/O kidnapped/O by/O security/O agencies/O ,/O say/O analysts/O ./O 
Qadeer/PERSON and/O Baluch/PERSON had/O originally/O been/O scheduled/O to/O speak/O at/O a/O seminar/O titled/O `/O Unsilencing/O <LOCATION>Baluchistan/O</LOCATION> '/O at/O the/O Lahore/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Management/ORGANIZATION Sciences/ORGANIZATION some/O weeks/O ago/O ./O 
The/O event/O was/O canceled/O ,/O reportedly/O after/O pressure/O from/O Inter/ORGANIZATION Services/ORGANIZATION Intelligence/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O ISI/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O Pakistani/O army/O 's/O spy/O agency/O ./O 
That/O 's/O when/O Mahmud/PERSON decided/O to/O invite/O the/O two/O <OTHER>Baloch/PERSON</OTHER> nationalists/O to/O a/O seminar/O at/O <ORGANIZATION>T2F/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O defying/O the/O pressure/O from/O the/O authorities/O ./O 
But/O it/O seems/O that/O Mahmud/PERSON 's/O death/O has/O broken/O the/O silence/O surrounding/O Balochistan/LOCATION ,/O as/O more/O Pakistanis/O are/O talking/O about/O the/O province/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Nobel/O laureate/O for/O Peace/O ,/O Malala/PERSON Yousafzai/PERSON ,/O also/O condemned/O Sabeen/PERSON 's/O murder/O ./O 
In/O a/O statement/O released/O by/O prime/O minister/O 's/O office/O on/O Saturday/O ,/O Sharif/PERSON said/O he/O was/O ordering/O a/O high-level/O investigation/O into/O Mahmud/PERSON 's/O killing/O ./O 
The/O Islamic/O country/O 's/O ubiquitous/O army/O ,/O too/O ,/O condemned/O the/O activist/O 's/O assassination/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> to/O `/O aggravate/O rights/O abuses/O '/O 
The/O <OTHER>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> economic/O corridor/O deal/O has/O raised/O the/O stakes/O for/O the/O Pakistani/O government/O in/O Balochistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> would/O link/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O southern/O Gwadar/LOCATION port/O in/O Balochistan/LOCATION on/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION to/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ./O 
It/O also/O includes/O plans/O to/O create/O a/O road/O ,/O rail/O and/O oil/O pipeline/O links/O which/O would/O improve/O connectivity/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
In/O a/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> interview/O ,/O Brahamdagh/PERSON Bugti/PERSON ,/O leader/O of/O the/O Baloch/ORGANIZATION Republican/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION living/O in/O exile/O in/O Switzerland/LOCATION ,/O and/O grandson/O of/O slain/O nationalist/O leader/O Akbar/PERSON Bugti/PERSON ,/O says/O that/O the/O multi-billion/O dollar/O economic/O corridor/O deal/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION could/O spur/O rights/O violations/O in/O Balochistan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O I/O think/O there/O will/O be/O massive/O human/O rights/O abuses/O in/O Balochistan/LOCATION because/O of/O this/O deal/O ./O 
To/O secure/O their/O financial/O interests/O in/O the/O province/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION is/O likely/O to/O intensify/O its/O military/O operation/O there/O ./O 
They/O will/O do/O so/O in/O the/O name/O of/O providing/O security/O to/O the/O multinational/O and/O Chinese/O companies/O that/O are/O investing/O in/O the/O project/O ./O 
They/O would/O not/O even/O allow/O peaceful/O demonstrations/O and/O protests/O against/O the/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O ''/O said/O Bugti/PERSON ./O 
Development/O analyst/O Maqsood/PERSON Ahmad/PERSON Jan/PERSON told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> the/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> would/O turn/O Pakistan/LOCATION into/O ``/O China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O colony/O ./O ''/O 
With/O money/O pouring/O in/O from/O China/LOCATION for/O the/O establishment/O of/O the/O economic/O corridor/O ,/O those/O demanding/O more/O transparency/O about/O the/O Balochistan/LOCATION province/LOCATION are/O likely/O to/O face/O the/O ire/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O security/O agencies/O ./O 
``/O The/O deep/O state/O already/O controls/O media/O in/O reference/O to/O Balochistan/LOCATION coverage/O ,/O ''/O wrote/O Pakistani/O novelist/O and/O journalist/O ,/O Mohammed/PERSON Hanif/PERSON ,/O referring/O to/O Islamabad/LOCATION 's/O policy/O to/O look/O for/O strategic/O and/O geo-political/O depth/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Balochistan/LOCATION to/O thwart/O India/LOCATION 's/O potential/O influence/O ./O 
``/O Now/O <OTHER>Baloch/PERSON</OTHER> voices/O ca/O n't/O -LRB-/O even/O -RRB-/O be/O heard/O in/O private/O spaces/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ,/O alluding/O to/O Mahmud/PERSON 's/O murder/O ./O 
Islamabad-based/O journalist/O ,/O Abdul/PERSON Sattar/PERSON ,/O however/O ,/O was/O optimistic/O about/O the/O situation/O :/O ``/O Sabeen/PERSON Mahmud/PERSON was/O a/O courageous/O woman/O who/O dared/O to/O voice/O against/O all/O kinds/O of/O extremism/O ./O 
She/O dared/O to/O talk/O about/O Balochistan/LOCATION when/O most/O people/O chose/O to/O remain/O silent/O and/O save/O their/O lives/O ./O 
We/O should/O not/O let/O her/O death/O go/O in/O vain/O ./O 
Let/O 's/O talk/O about/O Balochistan/LOCATION more/O vociferously/O than/O ever/O ,/O ''/O he/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O
