Turkey/LOCATION is/O an/O important/O bridge/O to/O Europe/LOCATION for/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O countries/O cooperate/O closely/O despite/O strained/O relations/O over/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uighur/O minority/O ./O 
The/O recent/O coup/O attempt/O came/O at/O an/O inopportune/O moment/O ,/O DW/O 's/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON writes/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O government/O released/O its/O first/O statement/O the/O day/O after/O ./O 
Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Lu/PERSON Kang/PERSON said/O he/O hoped/O that/O as/O soon/O as/O possible/O ./O 
The/O statement/O was/O only/O made/O when/O it/O was/O clear/O that/O this/O would/O indeed/O happen/O ./O 
If/O the/O coup/O had/O been/O successful/O ,/O it/O might/O have/O taken/O years/O before/O bilateral/O relations/O could/O be/O restored/O to/O their/O current/O level/O ./O 
Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON -LRB-/O right/O in/O photo/O -RRB-/O and/O his/O Turkish/O counterpart/O ,/O -LRB-/O left/O -RRB-/O ,/O get/O on/O well/O ./O 
As/O a/O bridge/O between/O Europe/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION and/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O Turkey/LOCATION is/O strategically/O important/O for/O China/LOCATION 's/O new/O Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION project/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O been/O seeking/O partners/O and/O making/O investments/O along/O the/O ancient/O trade/O route/O for/O months/O ./O 
Istanbul/LOCATION plays/O an/O important/O role/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O economic/O plans/O ./O 
It/O is/O not/O surprising/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O investing/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION 's/O infrastructure/O and/O banking/O on/O stability/O so/O that/O it/O secures/O long-term/O access/O to/O the/O region/O and/O ensures/O a/O market/O for/O its/O goods/O ./O 
In/O 2014/O ,/O a/O Chinese-Turkish/O consortium/O built/O a/O $/O 4.1/O billion/O rail/O link/O between/O Ankara/LOCATION and/O Istanbul/LOCATION ./O 
The/O plan/O is/O to/O pump/O another/O $/O 45/O billion/O -LRB-/O 41/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O into/O a/O 10,000-kilometer/O -LRB-/O 6,000-mile/O -RRB-/O high-speed/O rail/O link/O largely/O built/O by/O Chinese/O companies/O by/O 2023/O ./O 
At/O the/O most/O recent/O summit/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O the/O Chinese/O and/O Turkish/O energy/O ministers/O agreed/O to/O boost/O their/O cooperation/O on/O nuclear/O technology/O ./O 
This/O will/O be/O mutually/O beneficial/O ,/O as/O China/LOCATION will/O give/O Turkey/LOCATION an/O insight/O into/O its/O research/O and/O will/O itself/O build/O the/O power/O stations/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O thus/O keeping/O out/O any/O competitors/O ./O 
-LRB-/O France/LOCATION is/O the/O only/O European/O manufacturer/O of/O nuclear/O power/O stations/O ./O -RRB-/O 
One/O strain/O on/O the/O relationship/O has/O been/O the/O situation/O with/O Uighurs/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O autonomous/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ./O 
In/O the/O past/O ,/O Erdogan/PERSON has/O felt/O compelled/O to/O stand/O by/O the/O Turkic-speaking/O mostly/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O ,/O whom/O Chinese/O officials/O accuse/O of/O separatism/O and/O terrorism/O ./O 
Uighurs/O and/O their/O allies/O have/O accused/O the/O government/O of/O cultural/O ,/O political/O and/O religious/O repression/O ./O 
Turkey/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION have/O both/O felt/O the/O menace/O of/O the/O ``/O Islamic/O State/O ./O ''/O 
On/O his/O trip/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION last/O year/O ,/O Erdogan/PERSON guaranteed/O his/O hosts/O that/O he/O and/O his/O government/O would/O act/O against/O any/O activity/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION that/O could/O harm/O China/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O question/O that/O people/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION are/O asking/O themselves/O is/O how/O much/O this/O guarantee/O is/O worth/O if/O Erdogan/PERSON 's/O own/O army/O rises/O up/O against/O him/O :/O How/O much/O stability/O can/O this/O president/O really/O guarantee/O ?/O 
China/LOCATION 's/O confidence/O in/O Erdogan/PERSON has/O been/O dented/O ./O 
The/O government/O will/O likely/O become/O more/O cautious/O ./O 
