Authorities/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION have/O arrested/O several/O people/O over/O the/O suicide/O attack/O on/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O and/O identified/O the/O bomber/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Uighur/O community/O ./O 
The/O strike/O was/O allegedly/O set/O up/O by/O Uighur/O jihadists/O ./O 
Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION officials/O detained/O five/O people/O and/O placed/O four/O more/O on/O the/O wanted/O list/O ,/O including/O an/O explosives/O expert/O trained/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ,/O authorities/O said/O on/O Tuesday/O ./O 
The/O four/O suspects/O are/O believed/O to/O be/O hiding/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
The/O security/O service/O in/O the/O ex-Soviet/O country/O says/O the/O suspects/O were/O involved/O inlast/O week/O 's/O suicide/O attack/O on/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O in/O Bishkek/LOCATION ./O 
On/O August/O 30/O ,/O an/O attacker/O rammed/O a/O van/O through/O the/O compound/O 's/O gate/O and/O detonated/O the/O charge/O ,/O injuring/O three/O embassy/O employees/O ./O 
The/O driver/O was/O killed/O in/O the/O blast/O ./O 
In/O the/O Tuesday/O statement/O ,/O authorities/O said/O the/O attacker/O was/O an/O ethnic/O Uighur/O with/O a/O Tajik/O passport/O ./O 
``/O The/O investigation/O established/O that/O the/O terrorist/O act/O was/O ordered/O by/O Uighur/O terrorist/O groups/O active/O in/O Syria/LOCATION and/O affiliated/O to/O the/O terrorist/O organization/O the/O Nusra/ORGANIZATION Front/ORGANIZATION whose/O emissaries/O .../O financed/O the/O terrorist/O action/O ,/O ''/O state/O security/O said/O ./O 
Jihadist/O tourism/O Uighurs/O are/O a/O Muslim-majority/O Turkic/O group/O spread/O across/O several/O Asian/O countries/O ./O 
Most/O of/O them/O ,/O however/O ,/O live/O in/O the/O Chinese/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ,/O across/O the/O border/O from/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O been/O accused/O of/O cracking/O down/O on/O the/O ten-million-strong/O minority/O ./O 
In/O turn/O ,/O China/LOCATION blames/O Uighur/O separatist/O groups/O of/O staging/O deadly/O attacks/O in/O region/O ./O 
Three/O Uighurs/O were/O executed/O last/O year/O overa/O stabbing/O rampage/O in/O Kunming/LOCATION that/O killed/O over/O 30/O people/O ./O 
Commenting/O on/O the/O embassy/O attack/O ,/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION officials/O said/O that/O the/O van/O driver/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>ETIM/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ,/O which/O seeks/O an/O independent/O Uighur/O state/O ./O 
The/O group/O is/O also/O active/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION claims/O scores/O of/O Uighurs/O fled/O China/LOCATION to/O join/O Islamic/O militias/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION and/O learn/O how/O to/O wage/O jihad/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Watch/O video/O 01:30/O Share/O China/LOCATION hunts/O station/O attackers/O 
Send/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION Twitter/ORGANIZATION Google/ORGANIZATION +/O <ORGANIZATION>Whatsapp/O</ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION>Tumblr/O</ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION>linkedin/O</ORGANIZATION> stumble/O <ORGANIZATION>Digg/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> reddit/O <ORGANIZATION>Newsvine/O</ORGANIZATION> Permalink/O http://dw.com/p/1BIEI/O China/LOCATION hunts/O station/O assailants/O |/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O News/O</ORGANIZATION> dj/ls/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
