A/O series/O of/O bomb/O attacks/O have/O hit/O Thailand/LOCATION in/O the/O past/O 24/O hours/O ./O 
Authorities/O said/O they/O were/O coordinated/O attacks/O meant/O to/O stir/O up/O chaos/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
Four/O people/O have/O been/O killed/O and/O dozens/O wounded/O in/O multiple/O bomb/O blasts/O across/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O 
An/O explosion/O occurred/O in/O the/O seaside/O resort/O of/O <LOCATION>Hua/PERSON Hin/PERSON</LOCATION> early/O Friday/O morning/O ,/O less/O than/O 12/O hours/O after/O separate/O twin/O bomb/O attacks/O killed/O one/O person/O and/O injured/O 20/O ,/O including/O foreigners/O ./O 
Two/O explosions/O also/O struck/O the/O southern/O province/O of/O Surat/LOCATION Thani/LOCATION ,/O another/O hit/O the/O southern/O province/O <LOCATION>Trang/PERSON</LOCATION> and/O yet/O another/O two/O bombs/O blew/O up/O in/O the/O tourist/O area/O of/O Phuket/LOCATION ./O 
``/O The/O bombings/O have/O the/O same/O attack/O profile/O ,/O ''/O Army/O General/O Danai/PERSON Kritmethavee/PERSON told/O reporters/O ./O 
``/O We/O believe/O at/O this/O time/O that/O this/O was/O a/O coordinated/O attack/O ./O ''/O 
Junta/O chief/O Prayut/PERSON Chan-O-Cha/PERSON said/O he/O would/O not/O speculate/O on/O the/O motive/O behind/O the/O attacks/O ,/O but/O suggested/O the/O bombings/O were/O an/O attempt/O to/O stir/O up/O chaos/O ./O 
``/O The/O bombs/O are/O an/O attempt/O to/O create/O chaos/O and/O confusion/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
The/O bombings/O come/O a/O week/O after/O a/O referendum/O put/O forward/O by/O the/O military/O junta/O was/O approved/O ,/O paving/O the/O way/O for/O a/O new/O constitution/O and/O elections/O next/O year/O ./O 
Opponents/O of/O the/O military-drafted/O constitution/O argue/O it/O is/O laced/O with/O undemocratic/O principles/O and/O was/O designed/O to/O keep/O the/O military/O in/O power/O for/O five/O more/O years/O ./O 
Watch/O video/O 01:56/O Share/O Constitutional/O referendum/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION Send/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION Twitter/ORGANIZATION Google/ORGANIZATION +/O <ORGANIZATION>Whatsapp/O</ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION>Tumblr/O</ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION>linkedin/O</ORGANIZATION> stumble/O Digg/ORGANIZATION reddit/O Newsvine/O Permalink/O http://dw.com/p/1JcuR/O 
Constitutional/O referendum/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION 
Thailand/LOCATION is/O faced/O with/O a/O low-level/O insurgency/O in/O three/O majority-Muslim/O southern/O provinces/O ,/O but/O attacks/O are/O usually/O localized/O to/O the/O region/O ./O 
The/O coordinated/O blasts/O on/O Thursday/O and/O Friday/O come/O several/O days/O before/O the/O one-year/O anniversary/O of/O the/O last/O major/O attack/O on/O tourists/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O 
A/O bomb/O in/O the/O Thai/O capital/O ripped/O through/O a/O Hindi/O shrine/O and/O killed/O 20/O people/O on/O August/O 17/O ,/O mostly/O foreigners/O ./O 
Thai/O authorities/O accused/O two/O Uighur/O men/O from/O western/O China/LOCATION of/O the/O bombing/O ,/O the/O deadliest/O attack/O of/O its/O kind/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION in/O recent/O years/O ./O 
The/O two/O accused/O have/O denied/O involvement/O in/O the/O attack/O and/O their/O trial/O is/O set/O to/O begin/O later/O this/O month/O ./O 
cw/kl/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O <ORGANIZATION>dpa/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O
