More/O than/O 2/O million/O people/O have/O gathered/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION for/O a/O ``/O democracy/O and/O martyrs/O ''/O rally/O to/O condemn/O the/O failed/O coup/O attempt/O on/O July/O 15/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Tom/PERSON Stevenson/PERSON reports/O from/O Istanbul/LOCATION ./O 
Sunday/O 's/O rally/O in/O Istanbul/LOCATION 's/O Yenikapi/LOCATION park/O was/O but/O the/O latest/O in/O a/O string/O of/O public/O events/O promoted/O by/O the/O Turkish/O government/O following/O a/O failed/O coup/O attempt/O on/O July/O 15/O ./O 
By/O its/O sheer/O size/O ,/O it/O was/O a/O demonstration/O unlike/O any/O other/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION 's/O recent/O history/O ./O 
People/O traveled/O by/O bus/O or/O train/O from/O across/O the/O city/O and/O beyond/O ,/O creating/O a/O sea/O of/O people/O ,/O banners/O and/O posters/O ./O 
Some/O estimates/O put/O the/O number/O of/O rallygoers/O at/O 3/O million/O or/O more/O ./O 
When/O the/O ample/O area/O of/O Yenikapi/LOCATION park/O was/O full/O ,/O and/O closed/O by/O the/O police/O for/O fear/O of/O overcrowding/O ,/O undeterred/O throngs/O massed/O at/O the/O gates/O and/O around/O the/O park/O ./O 
The/O people/O gathered/O were/O not/O only/O there/O to/O support/O the/O government/O in/O the/O wake/O of/O the/O military/O coup/O ./O 
They/O also/O protested/O the/O widely/O reviled/O Turkish/O preacher/O Fetullah/PERSON Gulen/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O lived/O in/O self-imposed/O exile/O in/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION since/O 1999/O and/O has/O been/O locked/O in/O a/O feud/O with/O President/O Recep/PERSON Tayyip/PERSON Erdogan/PERSON and/O the/O ruling/O Justice/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AKP/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O for/O the/O past/O three/O years/O ./O 
The/O president/O has/O blamed/O Gulen/PERSON 's/O followers/O for/O launching/O the/O coup/O ./O 
``/O I/O express/O my/O gratitude/O to/O our/O people/O who/O laid/O down/O their/O lives/O to/O stop/O helicopters/O and/O guns/O ,/O ''/O Erdogan/PERSON told/O the/O rally/O on/O Sunday/O ./O 
``/O They/O have/O written/O their/O names/O in/O gold/O into/O our/O history/O ./O ''/O 
The/O president/O also/O pledged/O to/O push/O for/O the/O reintroduction/O of/O the/O death/O penalty/O in/O response/O to/O what/O he/O said/O were/O popular/O calls/O for/O its/O return/O ./O 
Those/O in/O attendance/O ranged/O from/O the/O staunchly/O religious/O to/O the/O staunchly/O secular/O ,/O from/O supporters/O of/O the/O government/O to/O supporters/O of/O the/O opposition/O ./O 
*/O Erdogan/PERSON pledges/O new/O Turkey/LOCATION 
Call/O to/O the/O streets/O 
During/O last/O month/O 's/O coup/O attempt/O ,/O Turkish/O President/O <PERSON>Recep/O</PERSON> Tayyip/PERSON Erdogan/PERSON called/O on/O supporters/O to/O help/O defeat/O military/O personnel/O trying/O to/O overthrow/O his/O ruling/O Justice/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O<ORGANIZATION> AKP/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ./O 
Having/O thwarted/O the/O attempt/O and/O crediting/O much/O his/O success/O to/O loyalists/O who/O filled/O the/O street/O ,/O Erdogan/PERSON has/O since/O asked/O followers/O to/O come/O out/O for/O nightly/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Democracy/O Watch/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O rallies/O ./O 
*/O Erdogan/PERSON pledges/O new/O Turkey/LOCATION 
Once/O repressed/O ,/O now/O empowered/O 
On/O Sunday/O ,/O the/O final/O rallies/O were/O held/O ,/O with/O a/O crowd/O of/O 2/O million/O in/O Istanbul/LOCATION and/O about/O 10,000/O in/O Ankara/LOCATION ./O 
Nearly/O 80/O cities/O hosted/O demonstrations/O in/O support/O of/O Erdogan/PERSON 's/O <ORGANIZATION>AKP/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O which/O is/O Turkey/LOCATION 's/O first/O party/O with/O Islamic/O leanings/O to/O survive/O a/O military/O coup/O ./O 
Supporters/O viewed/O the/O victory/O as/O a/O triumph/O over/O the/O republic/O 's/O cyclical/O coups/O and/O secular/O constitution/O ./O 
*/O Erdogan/PERSON pledges/O new/O Turkey/LOCATION 
Optimism/O about/O a/O new/O Turkey/LOCATION 
Speaking/O from/O Istanbul/LOCATION ,/O Erdogan/PERSON promised/O to/O ``/O rebuild/O Turkey/LOCATION from/O scratch/O ''/O and/O the/O mood/O was/O optimistic/O among/O supporters/O ./O 
Lale/PERSON Alici/PERSON ,/O -LRB-/O not/O pictured/O -RRB-/O an/O Ankara-based/O real/O estate/O agent/O who/O has/O attended/O every/O rally/O since/O the/O coup/O attempt/O ,/O said/O :/O ``/O When/O the/O purges/O are/O finished/O ,/O Turkey/LOCATION will/O accelerate/O its/O development/O because/O those/O who/O infiltrated/O our/O government/O will/O no/O longer/O be/O a/O burden/O on/O our/O country/O ./O ''/O 
*/O Erdogan/PERSON pledges/O new/O Turkey/LOCATION `/O 
We/O will/O be/O a/O big/O power/O '/O 
Atalay/PERSON ,/O -LRB-/O not/O pictured/O -RRB-/O an/O interior/O designer/O who/O did/O n't/O give/O his/O full/O name/O ,/O said/O he/O supported/O Erdogan/PERSON because/O he/O 's/O bringing/O Turkey/LOCATION to/O the/O world/O stage/O ./O 
``/O Erdogan/PERSON 's/O telling/O the/O world/O we/O 're/O here/O and/O we/O 'll/O be/O a/O big/O power/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O Even/O if/O you/O do/O n't/O like/O it/O ,/O you/O 'll/O have/O to/O accept/O it/O ./O 
The/O world/O 's/O bigger/O than/O the/O -LSB-/O seven/O countries/O in/O the/O G7/O ./O -RSB-/O ''/O 
*/O Erdogan/PERSON pledges/O new/O Turkey/LOCATION 
Exclusion/O of/O HDP/ORGANIZATION 
Though/O many/O attending/O Sunday/O 's/O rallies/O said/O they/O were/O defending/O democracy/O ,/O opponents/O noted/O the/O country/O 's/O third-largest/O political/O party/O ,/O the/O pro-Kurdish/ORGANIZATION Peoples/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Democratic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>HDP/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ,/O was/O not/O allowed/O at/O the/O events/O ./O 
``/O As/O a/O Kurd/O ,/O I/O ca/O n't/O go/O to/O these/O rallies/O because/O I/O do/O n't/O feel/O safe/O ,/O ''/O said/O Havva/PERSON Ozcan/PERSON ,/O -LRB-/O not/O pictured/O -RRB-/O co-chair/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>Tuhad-Fed/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O a/O prisoners/O '/O rights/O organization/O ./O 
``/O Not/O everyone/O 's/O welcome/O ./O ''/O 
*/O Erdogan/PERSON pledges/O new/O Turkey/LOCATION 
`/O Temporary/O socialism/O '/O 
Ozcan/PERSON also/O said/O the/O rallies/O received/O full/O government/O support/O ,/O while/O other/O forms/O of/O protest/O have/O been/O largely/O banned/O ./O 
Attendees/O were/O not/O only/O given/O free/O water/O and/O food/O ,/O but/O the/O entire/O public/O transportation/O systems/O in/O Ankara/LOCATION and/O Istanbul/LOCATION have/O been/O free/O over/O the/O last/O three/O weeks/O to/O encourage/O mass/O mobilization/O ./O 
``/O We/O are/O seeing/O a/O temporary/O socialism/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Ozcan/PERSON said/O ./O 
*/O Erdogan/PERSON pledges/O new/O Turkey/LOCATION 
Social/O media/O surge/O 
Normally/O blocked/O during/O national/O emergencies/O ,/O social/O media/O has/O taken/O on/O a/O prominent/O place/O since/O the/O coup/O attempt/O ./O 
From/O Erdogan/PERSON 's/O FaceTime/ORGANIZATION speech/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>Periscope/O</ORGANIZATION> videos/O portraying/O violence/O against/O civilians/O ,/O opponents/O complained/O the/O government/O allowed/O uninterrupted/O access/O to/O social/O media/O sites/O only/O because/O they/O proved/O advantageous/O ./O 
Turkish/O service/O providers/O also/O gave/O customers/O free/O data/O packages/O ./O 
*/O Erdogan/PERSON pledges/O new/O Turkey/LOCATION 
Empty/O bars/O 
Local/O businesses/O have/O also/O been/O hit/O hard/O ,/O with/O some/O bars/O in/O the/O central/O Ankara/LOCATION seeing/O fewer/O customers/O since/O the/O rallies/O began/O ./O 
``/O Business/O has/O been/O affected/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O but/O this/O about/O much/O more/O than/O business/O ,/O ''/O said/O Can/O ,/O a/O bar/O manager/O in/O Kizilay/LOCATION who/O only/O gave/O his/O first/O name/O ./O 
``/O These/O rallies/O are/O a/O sign/O that/O worse/O things/O will/O come/O soon/O ./O ''/O 
*/O Erdogan/PERSON pledges/O new/O Turkey/LOCATION 
`/O This/O is/O training/O '/O 
Some/O have/O viewed/O the/O rallies/O as/O a/O way/O for/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>AKP/O</ORGANIZATION> to/O strengthen/O its/O support/O base/O ./O 
Speaking/O on/O condition/O of/O anonymity/O ,/O Mohammed/PERSON ,/O a/O Syrian/O refugee/O who/O witnessed/O the/O Egyptian/O coup/O and/O is/O now/O living/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O said/O the/O rallies/O were/O ``/O training/O for/O Erdogan/PERSON 's/O followers/O ''/O and/O that/O ``/O soon/O he/O may/O ask/O them/O to/O organize/O against/O another/O movement/O he/O does/O n't/O like/O ./O ''/O 
*/O Erdogan/PERSON pledges/O new/O Turkey/LOCATION 
Renaming/O public/O spaces/O 
From/O Ankara/LOCATION 's/O Kizilay/LOCATION Square/LOCATION -LRB-/O pictured/O above/O after/O the/O coup/O night/O -RRB-/O to/O Istanbul/LOCATION 's/O Bosporus/LOCATION Bridge/LOCATION ,/O prominent/O sites/O throughout/O Turkey/LOCATION have/O been/O renamed/O to/O honor/O those/O who/O lost/O their/O lives/O during/O the/O coup/O attempt/O ./O 
Now/O people/O travelling/O from/O the/O European/O side/O of/O Istanbul/LOCATION to/O the/O Asian/O side/O will/O cross/O the/O ``/O The/O Martyrs/O '/O of/O July/O 15th/O ''/O bridge/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Diego/PERSON Cupolo/PERSON ,/O Ankara/LOCATION 
``/O The/O Turkish/O people/O have/O rejected/O this/O sect/O ,/O and/O we/O are/O here/O to/O show/O that/O we/O are/O Muslims/O and/O we/O will/O not/O accept/O military/O rule/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O Mehmet/PERSON Cagi/PERSON ,/O a/O 23-year-old/O from/O a/O local/O Salafi/O religious/O group/O ./O 
In/O addition/O to/O the/O thousands/O of/O Turkish/O flags/O were/O the/O standards/O of/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Egypt/LOCATION ,/O Azerbaijan/LOCATION and/O Libya/LOCATION ,/O along/O with/O Uighur/O and/O Syrian/O opposition/O flags/O ./O 
Even/O a/O flag/O from/O Somaliland/LOCATION ,/O a/O substate/O territory/O seeking/O independence/O from/O Somalia/LOCATION ,/O was/O visible/O ./O 
``/O It/O 's/O great/O to/O be/O here/O ,/O ''/O said/O Muhumed/PERSON Mohamed/PERSON ,/O the/O bearer/O of/O the/O flag/O of/O Somaliland/LOCATION ,/O and/O one/O of/O four/O students/O from/O the/O territory/O attending/O the/O rally/O while/O studying/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
``/O We/O are/O here/O to/O support/O democracy/O ./O ''/O 
``/O You/O know/O ,/O some/O values/O in/O this/O world/O are/O universal/O ,/O and/O democracy/O has/O to/O be/O the/O first/O one/O ,/O ''/O Mohamed/PERSON said/O ./O 
The/O mood/O turned/O celebratory/O after/O a/O minute/O 's/O silence/O had/O been/O observed/O for/O the/O more/O than/O 250/O civilians/O and/O loyalist/O forces/O killed/O in/O last/O month/O 's/O coup/O attempt/O ./O 
Breaking/O with/O tradition/O ,/O the/O opposition/O leaders/O Kemal/PERSON Kilicdaroglu/PERSON ,/O of/O the/O Republican/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O Devlet/PERSON Bahceli/PERSON ,/O of/O the/O Nationalist/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O attended/O the/O rally/O and/O even/O spoke/O alongside/O Erdogan/PERSON and/O Binali/PERSON Yildirim/PERSON ,/O the/O leader/O of/O the/O ruling/O <ORGANIZATION>AKP/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Muhumed/PERSON Mohamed/PERSON -LRB-/O right/O -RRB-/O and/O students/O from/O Somaliland/LOCATION who/O attended/O the/O rally/O Army/ORGANIZATION chief/O of/O staff/O General/O Hulusi/PERSON Akar/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O kidnapped/O during/O the/O coup/O ,/O also/O addressed/O the/O rally/O in/O an/O unplanned/O speech/O ./O 
The/O crowd/O appeared/O to/O be/O constituted/O by/O a/O solid/O pro-government/O ,/O religious/O majority/O ,/O and/O the/O loudest/O chants/O entering/O the/O rally/O were/O religious/O calls/O and/O response/O and/O the/O declaration/O of/O faith/O ,/O the/O Shahada/ORGANIZATION ,/O in/O Arabic/O with/O a/O clear/O Turkish/O accent/O ./O 
But/O Turks/O from/O all/O walks/O of/O life/O attended/O ./O 
Conspicuously/O absent/O were/O representatives/O of/O the/O pro-Kurd/ORGANIZATION Peoples/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Democratic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>HDP/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ,/O which/O ,/O despite/O opposing/O the/O coup/O attempt/O ,/O has/O been/O excluded/O from/O recent/O anti-coup/O rallies/O and/O was/O refused/O an/O invitation/O by/O the/O ruling/O <ORGANIZATION>AKP/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
The/O government/O has/O been/O locked/O in/O military/O campaigns/O in/O the/O Kurdish/O southeast/O of/O Turkey/LOCATION for/O the/O past/O year/O ./O 
``/O The/O exclusion/O of/O HDP/ORGANIZATION is/O a/O very/O bad/O ,/O very/O regrettable/O decision/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O a/O waste/O ,/O ''/O said/O Hisyar/PERSON Ozsoy/PERSON ,/O the/O party/O 's/O vice/O chairman/O ./O 
``/O The/O government/O could/O have/O used/O this/O opportunity/O to/O restart/O the/O peace/O process/O with/O the/O Kurdish/O movement/O ./O ''/O 
``/O It/O 's/O clear/O that/O they/O are/O trying/O to/O build/O a/O nationalist/O alliance/O ,/O and/O in/O doing/O so/O they/O are/O following/O the/O logic/O of/O the/O coup/O plotters/O ,/O ''/O Ozsoy/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O This/O attitude/O is/O the/O root/O of/O nearly/O every/O problem/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Sentiments/O expressed/O were/O not/O purely/O position/O ./O 
One/O man/O carried/O an/O effigy/O of/O a/O lynched/O man/O with/O the/O words/O ``/O death/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>FETÖ/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O ''/O a/O Turkish/O acronym/O meaning/O ``/O Fetullah/ORGANIZATION Gulen/ORGANIZATION Terrorist/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION ./O ''/O 
Some/O in/O attendance/O freely/O expressed/O their/O frustrations/O with/O the/O perceived/O lackluster/O support/O for/O Turkey/LOCATION 's/O government/O following/O the/O coup/O from/O the/O international/O community/O and/O Europe/LOCATION in/O particular/O ./O 
``/O Outside/O ,/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O everyone/O thinks/O of/O terrorists/O when/O they/O think/O of/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O but/O this/O is/O the/O real/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O 36-year-old/O Safar/PERSON Engin/PERSON ./O 
``/O We/O 've/O been/O trying/O to/O get/O into/O Europe/LOCATION for/O 30/O years/O and/O been/O denied/O ,/O but/O then/O there/O is/O a/O coup/O and/O where/O is/O Europe/LOCATION ?/O ''/O Engin/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O Nowhere/O ./O 
No/O ,/O we/O are/O the/O ones/O standing/O for/O democracy/O ./O ''/O
