Leaders/O of/O the/O world/O 's/O eight/O top/O industrialized/O nations/O are/O meeting/O in/O L'Aquila/LOCATION ,/O Italy/LOCATION for/O the/O G-8/ORGANIZATION summit/O ,/O but/O first/O they/O visited/O towns/O in/O the/O earthquake-hit/O region/O ./O 
Before/O arriving/O at/O the/O G-8/ORGANIZATION summit/O in/O L'Aquila/LOCATION ,/O Italy/LOCATION ,/O German/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON toured/O a/O nearby/O village/O that/O was/O devastated/O by/O an/O earthquake/O in/O April/O of/O this/O year/O ./O 
She/O appeared/O visibly/O moved/O as/O she/O toured/O what/O was/O left/O of/O the/O village/O of/O Onna/LOCATION with/O Italian/O Prime/O Minister/O Berlusconi/PERSON ./O 
Merkel/PERSON ,/O along/O with/O the/O other/O G-8/ORGANIZATION leaders/O ,/O have/O a/O long/O list/O of/O issues/O to/O deal/O with/O ,/O which/O include/O the/O global/O economy/O ,/O unrest/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION and/O climate/O change/O ./O 
Early/O reports/O from/O the/O summit/O say/O that/O the/O major/O polluting/O nations/O have/O droppped/O a/O pledge/O in/O the/O draft/O declaration/O to/O halve/O global/O greenhouse/O gas/O emissions/O by/O the/O year/O 2050/O ./O 
Berlusconi/PERSON proposes/O food/O initiative/O 
Berlusconi/PERSON wants/O the/O G-8/ORGANIZATION to/O agree/O a/O food/O security/O program/O 
Berlusconi/PERSON ,/O who/O chairs/O the/O gathering/O of/O leaders/O ,/O told/O reporters/O he/O hoped/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Group/O of/O Eight/O</ORGANIZATION> summit/O attendees/O would/O approve/O $/O 10/O billion/O to/O $/O 15/O billion/O -LRB-/O 7/O billion/O to/O 11/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O for/O food/O aid/O ./O 
``/O We/O hope/O to/O approve/O an/O initiative/O for/O food/O security/O in/O the/O world/O ,/O ''/O Berlusconi/PERSON said/O ,/O adding/O that/O he/O anticipated/O US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON contributing/O up/O to/O a/O third/O of/O the/O pledge/O ./O 
The/O pledge/O would/O be/O called/O the/O L'Aquila/ORGANIZATION Food/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Initiative/ORGANIZATION ,/O after/O the/O central/O Italian/O city/O where/O the/O summit/O is/O to/O take/O place/O until/O Friday/O ./O 
Leaders/O set/O to/O discuss/O emerging/O political/O crises/O 
German/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON said/O she/O had/O planned/O to/O speak/O with/O Chinese/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON on/O the/O sidelines/O of/O the/O summit/O about/O the/O ethnic/O violence/O that/O has/O wracked/O China/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O and/O left/O at/O least/O 156/O people/O dead/O ./O 
However/O the/O Chinese/O leader/O cut/O short/O his/O visit/O to/O Italy/LOCATION to/O return/O home/O in/O the/O wake/O of/O the/O deadly/O rioting/O ./O 
Some/O leaders/O had/O hoped/O to/O put/O the/O crackdown/O on/O post-election/O protests/O in/O Iran/LOCATION at/O the/O top/O of/O the/O summit/O 's/O agenda/O ,/O but/O China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION continue/O to/O view/O the/O crisis/O as/O an/O internal/O Iranian/O issue/O ./O 
While/O Berlusconi/PERSON said/O he/O expected/O further/O dialogue/O on/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O he/O conceded/O that/O the/O G-8/ORGANIZATION leaders/O did/O not/O yet/O have/O a/O common/O position/O ./O 
``/O It/O still/O has/O to/O be/O decided/O what/O the/O statement/O on/O Iran/LOCATION will/O be/O ,/O ''/O Berlusconi/PERSON said/O at/O a/O news/O conference/O in/O Rome/LOCATION ./O 
A/O joint/O statement/O is/O expected/O Wednesday/O evening/O ./O 
av/hf/AFP/O //O AP/dpa/Reuters/O 
Editor/O :/O Michael/PERSON Lawton/PERSON
