Russia/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION have/O realigned/O their/O trade/O and/O diplomatic/O ties/O ,/O and/O Vladimir/PERSON Putin/PERSON 's/O visit/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION shows/O that/O ,/O despite/O lingering/O doubts/O and/O distrust/O ,/O the/O two/O sides/O have/O more/O to/O gain/O than/O lose/O from/O mutual/O cooperation/O ./O 
Trade/O ,/O energy/O and/O security/O deals/O worth/O an/O estimated/O 3.5/O billion/O euros/O -LRB-/O $/O 5.5/O billion/O -RRB-/O have/O been/O signed/O during/O Russian/O Prime/O Minister/O Vladimir/PERSON Putin/PERSON 's/O three-day/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
More/O than/O 20/O agreements/O have/O been/O negotiated/O ,/O including/O one/O committing/O both/O countries/O to/O notify/O the/O other/O when/O ballistic/O missiles/O are/O launched/O from/O their/O territories/O ./O 
The/O Russian/O RIA/ORGANIZATION Novosti/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O reported/O that/O the/O two/O sides/O had/O also/O signed/O an/O agreement/O to/O set/O up/O a/O presidential/O hotline/O between/O Moscow/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Agricultural/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION has/O also/O agreed/O to/O lend/O $/O 500/O million/O to/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O VTB/ORGANIZATION bank/O ./O 
A/O memorandum/O of/O understanding/O has/O also/O been/O signed/O on/O developing/O a/O high-speed/O rail/O link/O on/O Russian/O territory/O ./O 
Progress/O was/O also/O announced/O on/O a/O natural/O gas/O pipeline/O project/O as/O well/O as/O nuclear/O energy/O ,/O said/O Shi/PERSON Yajun/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O on/O Sino-Russian/O relations/O at/O East/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Normal/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Putin/PERSON 's/O visit/O coincides/O with/O the/O 60th/O anniversary/O of/O diplomatic/O relations/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
The/O expediency/O of/O closer/O ties/O But/O ,/O despite/O signs/O that/O bilateral/O ties/O are/O running/O smoothly/O ,/O some/O experts/O believe/O the/O two/O nations/O are/O banding/O together/O out/O of/O a/O common/O distrust/O of/O other/O powers/O ,/O rather/O than/O a/O real/O desire/O to/O become/O closer/O allies/O ./O 
Russia/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION have/O a/O history/O of/O rivalry/O and/O distrust/O stemming/O from/O disputes/O in/O the/O 1960s/O over/O differences/O in/O communist/O doctrine/O and/O skirmishes/O along/O their/O shared/O 4,300-kilometer/O -LRB-/O 2,672-mile/O -RRB-/O border/O ./O 
While/O most/O of/O the/O border/O issues/O have/O been/O resolved/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION is/O still/O wary/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O growing/O economic/O and/O security/O influence/O on/O its/O eastern/O flank/O ./O 
``/O Moscow/LOCATION 's/O main/O frustration/O is/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O starting/O to/O overshadow/O Russia/LOCATION as/O a/O great/O power/O ,/O ''/O Jonathan/PERSON Holslag/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O research/O at/O the/O Brussels/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION <OTHER>of/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Contemporary/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O Both/O players/O yearn/O for/O international/O esteem/O and/O status/O ,/O but/O China/LOCATION is/O way/O ahead/O ./O 
This/O has/O led/O to/O growing/O distrust/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O where/O China/LOCATION has/O gained/O influence/O at/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O expense/O ./O 
Also/O in/O <LOCATION>Northeast/O Asia/O</LOCATION> ,/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O influence/O is/O really/O squeezed/O under/O China/LOCATION 's/O demographic/O and/O commercial/O weight/O ./O ''/O 
Russia/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION still/O in/O line/O on/O Iran/LOCATION despite/O recent/O shifts/O Russia/LOCATION has/O opposed/O sanctions/O on/O Iran/LOCATION until/O recently/O However/O ,/O China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION have/O both/O seen/O the/O advantages/O of/O stronger/O ties/O ,/O even/O if/O issues/O such/O as/O China/LOCATION 's/O expanding/O influence/O remain/O thorns/O in/O their/O relations/O ./O 
With/O international/O pressure/O continuing/O to/O grow/O over/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O nuclear/O ambitions/O and/O the/O behavior/O of/O the/O regime/O in/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION ,/O Moscow/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION have/O often/O joined/O forces/O to/O deflect/O attempts/O at/O tougher/O action/O from/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O When/O it/O comes/O to/O Iran/LOCATION and/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION ,/O Moscow/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION both/O agree/O that/O those/O countries/O should/O not/O develop/O nuclear/O arms/O ,/O but/O that/O it/O is/O not/O worth/O putting/O regional/O stability/O and/O economic/O interests/O at/O risk/O ,/O ''/O said/O Holslag/PERSON ./O 
Despite/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O apparent/O U-turn/O in/O favor/O of/O sanctions/O against/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O the/O two/O nations/O are/O expected/O to/O use/O Putin/PERSON 's/O visit/O to/O coordinate/O their/O international/O diplomacy/O on/O the/O nuclear/O issues/O involving/O Iran/LOCATION and/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION ,/O suggesting/O that/O Moscow/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION are/O not/O getting/O out/O of/O step/O on/O the/O issues/O in/O which/O they/O have/O stood/O side-by-side/O in/O the/O face/O of/O Western/O pressure/O ./O 
Support/O over/O restive/O regions/O wavers/O 
Mutual/O distrust/O still/O exists/O but/O is/O put/O aside/O for/O mutual/O gain/O 
China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION have/O also/O lent/O support/O directly/O to/O each/O other/O on/O issues/O that/O have/O riled/O the/O <LOCATION>West/O</LOCATION> ,/O such/O as/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O tough/O position/O on/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O its/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O and/O Moscow/LOCATION 's/O involvement/O in/O its/O proxy/O states/O in/O the/O Caucasus/LOCATION ./O 
But/O even/O in/O these/O areas/O ,/O the/O sands/O have/O shifted/O ./O 
``/O Traditionally/O both/O countries/O emphasised/O sovereignty/O in/O their/O joint/O combat/O against/O religious/O extremism/O ,/O secessionism/O and/O American/O unilateralism/O ,/O ''/O said/O Holslag/PERSON ./O 
``/O But/O since/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O unilateral/O intervention/O in/O Georgia/LOCATION ,/O this/O normative/O common/O ground/O has/O faded/O ./O 
China/LOCATION for/O example/O refuses/O to/O recognize/O the/O independence/O of/O South/LOCATION Ossetia/LOCATION and/O Abkhazia/LOCATION as/O Russia/LOCATION would/O like/O ./O 
Behind/O closed/O doors/O the/O Chinese/O also/O criticize/O Russian/O plans/O to/O build/O new/O military/O bases/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Trade/O keeping/O potentially/O frosty/O relations/O warm/O 
The/O two/O nations/O are/O building/O the/O strongest/O ties/O in/O the/O areas/O of/O trade/O and/O energy/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O second/O largest/O trade/O partner/O after/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O despite/O bilateral/O trade/O shrinking/O by/O just/O over/O 36/O percent/O to/O $/O 24/O billion/O in/O the/O first/O eight/O months/O of/O this/O year/O as/O a/O consequence/O of/O the/O global/O financial/O crisis/O ,/O the/O two/O countries/O expect/O bilateral/O trade/O to/O increase/O to/O $/O 60-80/O billion/O by/O 2010/O ./O 
Trade/O agreements/O are/O high/O on/O Putin/PERSON and/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON 's/O agenda/O The/O driving/O force/O in/O these/O trade/O relations/O ,/O however/O ,/O is/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Chinese/O economy/O has/O left/O its/O Russian/O equivalent/O standing/O in/O recent/O years/O ,/O with/O China/LOCATION gross/O domestic/O product/O growing/O in/O contrast/O to/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O shrinkage/O during/O the/O economic/O crisis/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION represents/O less/O than/O 10/O percent/O of/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O trade/O ,/O and/O the/O Russian/O trade/O deficit/O is/O growing/O ,/O ''/O said/O Holslag/PERSON ./O 
``/O Yet/O ,/O it/O is/O clear/O that/O for/O the/O long/O turn/O ,/O Russia/LOCATION aims/O at/O developing/O stronger/O economic/O cooperation/O with/O the/O Chinese/O to/O reduce/O its/O reliance/O on/O the/O European/O consumer/O market/O ./O 
It/O has/O approved/O major/O new/O pipeline/O projects/O to/O China/LOCATION and/O is/O seeking/O to/O turn/O its/O vast/O territory/O in/O a/O land/O bridge/O between/O the/O East/O and/O the/O <LOCATION>West/O</LOCATION> ./O 
<LOCATION>The/O</LOCATION> Arctic/LOCATION Ocean/LOCATION will/O be/O another/O trump/O with/O which/O Moscow/LOCATION will/O seek/O to/O step/O up/O its/O economic/O leverage/O ./O ''/O 
Both/O sides/O looking/O to/O expand/O energy/O cooperation/O Putin/PERSON would/O like/O to/O oversee/O oil/O and/O gas/O deals/O with/O China/LOCATION 
China/LOCATION is/O also/O looking/O to/O benefit/O from/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O dissatisfaction/O with/O Europe/LOCATION as/O an/O energy/O consumer/O and/O partner/O ./O 
While/O still/O focused/O on/O the/O West/LOCATION ,/O Moscow/LOCATION is/O keen/O to/O find/O alternative/O customers/O for/O its/O oil/O and/O gas/O and/O China/LOCATION has/O made/O it/O clear/O that/O it/O is/O ready/O to/O strike/O deals/O over/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O huge/O mineral/O resources/O ./O 
``/O As/O opposed/O to/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION is/O highly/O interested/O in/O `/O security/O of/O demand/O '/O -/O especially/O in/O view/O of/O tightening/O climate/O change/O policies/O ,/O ''/O Arno/PERSON Behrens/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O energy/O research/O at/O the/O Centre/O for/O European/ORGANIZATION Policy/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION in/O Brussels/LOCATION ,/O told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O Russia/LOCATION is/O thus/O very/O keen/O to/O diversify/O its/O demand/O structure/O and/O China/LOCATION would/O be/O an/O ideal/O partner/O to/O do/O so/O -/O guaranteeing/O a/O high/O level/O of/O demand/O in/O the/O long-run/O ./O 
Similarly/O ,/O a/O better/O cooperation/O with/O Russia/LOCATION as/O a/O substitution/O for/O increasing/O trade/O relationships/O with/O rogue/O states/O may/O benefit/O China/LOCATION 's/O political/O image/O in/O the/O <LOCATION>West/O</LOCATION> ./O ''/O 
One/O deal/O which/O could/O further/O Russian-Chinese/O energy/O cooperation/O was/O struck/O in/O April/O when/O ,/O in/O return/O for/O 300/O million/O tons/O of/O Russian/O oil/O over/O 20/O years/O ,/O China/LOCATION agreed/O to/O lend/O Russian/O oil/O pipeline/O monopoly/O Transneft/ORGANIZATION $/O 10/O billion/O and/O state-run/O oil/O company/O Rosneft/ORGANIZATION $/O 15/O billion/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O investment/O in/O Transneft/ORGANIZATION 's/O East/LOCATION Siberia-Pacific/LOCATION Ocean/LOCATION pipeline/O will/O help/O to/O aid/O its/O slated/O 2010/O completion/O and/O could/O lead/O to/O 15/O million/O tons/O of/O crude/O oil/O being/O pumped/O into/O the/O insatiable/O Chinese/O industry/O sector/O ./O 
Gas/O deals/O could/O capitalize/O on/O China/LOCATION 's/O growing/O status/O
China/LOCATION could/O also/O become/O a/O major/O consumer/O of/O Russian/O gas/O if/O export/O monopoly/O Gazprom/ORGANIZATION can/O overcome/O its/O pricing/O disagreements/O with/O the/O Chinese/O and/O make/O good/O on/O a/O 2006/O agreement/O to/O build/O two/O major/O pipelines/O into/O China/LOCATION ./O 
``/O According/O to/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Energy/ORGANIZATION Agency/ORGANIZATION ,/O China/LOCATION is/O the/O world/O 's/O second/O largest/O and/O fastest/O growing/O energy/O consumer/O ,/O and/O will/O be/O the/O world/O 's/O largest/O energy/O consumer/O as/O of/O 2010/O ,/O ''/O Behrens/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O Total/O primary/O energy/O demand/O has/O almost/O tripled/O between/O 1980/O and/O 2005/O and/O is/O expected/O to/O more/O than/O double/O again/O between/O 2005/O and/O 2030/O ./O 
But/O despite/O this/O huge/O potential/O ,/O energy/O relations/O with/O Russia/LOCATION remain/O underdeveloped/O ./O ''/O 
Author/O :/O Nick/PERSON Amies/PERSON -LRB-/O gb/O -RRB-/O 
Editor/O :/O Rob/PERSON Mudge/PERSON
