<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O the/O exiled/O Uighur/O leader/O ,/O attended/O the/O Frankfurt/O Book/O Fair/O on/O Sunday/O and/O criticised/O the/O fact/O that/O China/LOCATION had/O been/O this/O year/O 's/O guest/O of/O honour/O ./O 
China/LOCATION accuses/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> of/O orchestrating/O riots/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O that/O resulted/O in/O some/O 200/O deaths/O earlier/O this/O year/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> rejects/O the/O allegations/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> has/O been/O fighting/O for/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O for/O almost/O 20/O years/O ./O 
China/LOCATION accuses/O her/O of/O conducting/O separatist/O activities/O ,/O for/O which/O she/O even/O spent/O six/O years/O in/O jail/O until/O 2005/O ./O 
She/O now/O lives/O in/O exile/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O holds/O her/O responsible/O for/O the/O deadly/O violence/O that/O erupted/O in/O the/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> this/O summer/O ./O 
The/O killing/O of/O two/O Uighurs/O at/O a/O factory/O in/O the/O southern/O province/O of/O Guangdong/LOCATION led/O to/O people/O pouring/O out/O onto/O the/O streets/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> but/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> insists/O that/O the/O protests/O were/O peaceful/O ./O 
``/O Students/O and/O schoolchildren/O took/O part/O in/O the/O demonstrations/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
``/O They/O were/O carrying/O Chinese/O flags/O ./O 
They/O wanted/O to/O say/O `/O We/O are/O citizens/O of/O this/O state/O and/O we/O want/O to/O demonstrate/O peacefully/O but/O the/O incidents/O in/O Guangdong/LOCATION have/O to/O be/O investigated/O ./O '''/O 
200/O dead/O ,/O 1,600/O injured/O 
The/O protests/O turned/O deadly/O when/O fights/O broke/O out/O between/O the/O Uighurs/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
Over/O 200/O people/O were/O killed/O and/O over/O 1,600/O people/O were/O injured/O ./O 
Hundreds/O of/O people/O were/O arrested/O in/O the/O aftermath/O ./O 
Michael/PERSON Dillon/PERSON ,/O who/O teaches/O modern/O Chinese/O history/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Durham/ORGANIZATION and/O has/O written/O a/O book/O about/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> estimates/O that/O a/O total/O of/O 40/O people/O have/O gone/O on/O trial/O ./O 
``/O Of/O those/O ,/O 12/O have/O been/O sentenced/O to/O death/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O The/O charges/O include/O murder/O ,/O robbery/O and/O arson/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O said/O that/O they/O want/O to/O clamp/O down/O very/O heavily/O on/O this/O ./O ''/O 
However/O ,/O he/O added/O that/O because/O the/O trials/O had/O not/O been/O open/O to/O foreign/O journalists/O and/O international/O observers/O ,/O nobody/O really/O could/O confirm/O what/O had/O been/O going/O on/O exactly/O ./O 
The/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> authorities/O have/O said/O that/O the/O families/O of/O the/O defendants/O and/O the/O victims/O were/O allowed/O to/O attend/O the/O trials/O ./O 
``/O Unfair/O trials/O and/O forced/O confessions/O ''/O 
Uighurs/O have/O complained/O that/O the/O trials/O are/O not/O fair/O and/O that/O they/O have/O not/O been/O allowed/O to/O be/O represented/O by/O the/O lawyers/O of/O their/O choice/O ./O 
This/O has/O been/O confirmed/O by/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION which/O has/O said/O in/O a/O report/O that/O lawyers/O were/O effectively/O warned/O to/O be/O careful/O when/O accepting/O such/O cases/O ./O 
The/O watchdog/O also/O claims/O that/O the/O authorities/O exercised/O their/O influence/O on/O the/O judges/O and/O prosecutors/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> thinks/O that/O those/O who/O have/O been/O sentenced/O to/O death/O are/O not/O guilty/O and/O were/O forced/O to/O confess/O ./O 
``/O Cultural/O genocide/O ''/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 
She/O argues/O that/O the/O authorities/O are/O acting/O illegally/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
``/O After/O we/O were/O occupied/O by/O China/LOCATION ,/O we/O were/O given/O autonomy/O ,/O ''/O she/O explains/O ./O 
``/O And/O according/O to/O the/O autonomy/O law/O ,/O we/O can/O govern/O ourselves/O and/O maintain/O our/O traditions/O and/O identity/O ./O 
But/O now/O cultural/O genocide/O is/O taking/O place/O against/O us/O and/O anybody/O who/O is/O against/O that/O is/O labelled/O a/O terrorist/O and/O a/O separatist/O ./O ''/O 
<U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> insists/O that/O she/O favours/O only/O peaceful/O means/O as/O part/O of/O her/O fight/O for/O Uighur/O interests/O ./O 
She/O says/O that/O her/O several/O attempts/O to/O enter/O into/O dialogue/O with/O the/O Chinese/O government/O have/O not/O been/O successful/O ./O 
Executions/O would/O be/O counterproductive/O 
In/O her/O view/O ,/O an/O independent/O UN/ORGANIZATION commission/O should/O be/O allowed/O to/O go/O to/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> to/O form/O its/O own/O opinion/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O to/O look/O into/O the/O situation/O of/O Uighur/O prisoners/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
She/O has/O also/O called/O for/O the/O death/O penalty/O to/O be/O abolished/O ./O 
This/O view/O is/O supported/O by/O Michael/PERSON Dillon/PERSON who/O thinks/O any/O executions/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> would/O be/O counterproductive/O ./O 
``/O Although/O there/O might/O be/O some/O support/O if/O the/O death/O sentences/O are/O carried/O out/O from/O Han/O people/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O it/O 's/O going/O to/O lead/O to/O even/O further/O resentment/O among/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
It/O 's/O not/O necessarily/O going/O to/O have/O the/O desired/O effect/O because/O it/O 's/O likely/O to/O create/O more/O tension/O and/O more/O conflict/O in/O the/O future/O ./O ''/O 
Three/O of/O the/O 12/O people/O sentenced/O to/O death/O have/O been/O given/O a/O two-year/O reprieve/O ,/O suggesting/O that/O their/O sentences/O will/O be/O commuted/O to/O life/O in/O prison/O ./O 
Four/O more/O people/O have/O been/O given/O life/O imprisonment/O ./O 
Although/O it/O is/O not/O exactly/O clear/O who/O has/O been/O sentenced/O to/O death/O there/O appears/O to/O be/O at/O least/O one/O Han/O name/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Anne/PERSON Thomas/PERSON 
Editor/PERSON :/O Thomas/PERSON Bärthlein/PERSON
