The/O German/O government/O will/O conduct/O its/O own/O investigation/O into/O the/O security/O risks/O posed/O by/O Guantanamo/LOCATION detainees/O before/O allowing/O any/O of/O the/O released/O terrorism/O suspects/O into/O the/O country/O ./O 
Germany/LOCATION has/O indicated/O that/O it/O would/O be/O willing/O to/O take/O some/O of/O the/O terrorism/O suspects/O who/O would/O be/O released/O once/O a/O US/LOCATION detention/O center/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION ,/O Cuba/LOCATION is/O closed/O ./O 
But/O first/O ,/O German/O leaders/O want/O to/O assure/O themselves/O that/O the/O detainees/O do/O not/O pose/O a/O threat/O ./O 
US/LOCATION Vice/O President/O Joe/PERSON Biden/PERSON recently/O indicated/O that/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION will/O turn/O to/O its/O allies/O to/O take/O on/O some/O of/O the/O remaining/O 245/O prisoners/O ,/O all/O of/O whom/O were/O picked/O up/O during/O the/O US/LOCATION war/O on/O terror/O ./O 
``/O We/O will/O ask/O others/O to/O take/O responsibility/O for/O some/O of/O those/O now/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION ,/O as/O we/O determine/O to/O close/O it/O ,/O ''/O Biden/PERSON said/O at/O a/O recent/O security/O conference/O in/O Munich/LOCATION ,/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
Germany/LOCATION waiting/O for/O a/O request/O The/O US/LOCATION has/O indicated/O that/O approximately/O 60/O of/O the/O prisoners/O have/O been/O determined/O to/O not/O be/O terrorists/O ./O 
But/O they/O continue/O to/O be/O held/O as/O the/O US/LOCATION fears/O they/O would/O be/O tortured/O or/O killed/O if/O returned/O home/O ./O 
Germany/LOCATION is/O waiting/O for/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION to/O present/O a/O more/O specific/O request/O for/O help/O before/O doing/O anything/O ,/O a/O spokesman/O for/O the/O Interior/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION told/O the/O Stuttgarter/ORGANIZATION Nachrichten/ORGANIZATION in/O an/O article/O published/O on/O Wednesday/O ,/O Feb./O 11/O ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION fears/O prisoners/O may/O be/O harmed/O if/O returned/O to/O their/O homes/O ``/O Our/O focus/O is/O on/O whether/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O security/O is/O jeopardized/O ,/O ''/O the/O Interior/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O told/O the/O newspaper/O ./O 
``/O Nevertheless/O ,/O we/O 're/O waiting/O to/O see/O if/O there/O even/O are/O any/O requests/O from/O Washington/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Foreign/O Minister/O Frank-Walter/PERSON Steinmeier/PERSON has/O promised/O that/O each/O detainee/O will/O be/O ``/O very/O thoroughly/O ''/O investigated/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O newspaper/O report/O ./O 
But/O Germany/LOCATION still/O believes/O that/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION is/O legally/O responsible/O for/O taking/O in/O released/O detainees/O ./O 
Any/O reason/O for/O not/O wanting/O to/O do/O so/O needs/O to/O be/O thoroughly/O explained/O ,/O the/O spokesperson/O said/O ./O 
Sebastian/PERSON Edathy/PERSON ,/O a/O leading/O Social/O Democrat/O on/O the/O issue/O ,/O spoke/O out/O in/O favor/O of/O the/O government/O conducting/O thorough/O checks/O on/O individual/O detainees/O before/O allowing/O them/O into/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O but/O told/O the/O newspaper/O it/O 's/O important/O that/O ``/O a/O presumption/O of/O innocence/O not/O be/O turned/O upside/O down/O ./O ''/O 
A/O leader/O of/O the/O Green/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O Christian/PERSON Stroebele/PERSON ,/O renewed/O calls/O for/O the/O detainees/O to/O be/O released/O as/O soon/O as/O possible/O ./O 
He/O finds/O it/O unacceptable/O that/O innocent/O prisoners/O would/O be/O left/O to/O languish/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION while/O politicians/O ``/O argue/O over/O who/O is/O responsible/O ''/O for/O them/O ./O 
Help/O for/O the/O Uighurs/O 
The/O end/O to/O a/O long/O imprisonment/O may/O soon/O be/O near/O 
Germany/LOCATION seems/O most/O interested/O in/O helping/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O from/O far/O western/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O city/O of/O Munich/LOCATION ,/O which/O has/O the/O biggest/O community/O of/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O outside/O China/LOCATION ,/O has/O indicated/O it/O would/O be/O willing/O to/O host/O the/O 17/O <LOCATION>Guantanamo/O</LOCATION> inmates/O when/O they/O are/O released/O ./O 
All/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O have/O been/O cleared/O of/O terrorist/O activity/O ,/O but/O Washington/LOCATION has/O been/O reluctant/O to/O repatriate/O them/O to/O China/LOCATION for/O fear/O they/O would/O be/O persecuted/O or/O tortured/O ./O 
Although/O there/O has/O been/O no/O consensus/O from/O the/O European/LOCATION Union/LOCATION on/O how/O to/O deal/O with/O released/O <LOCATION>Guantanamo/O</LOCATION> detainees/O ,/O several/O other/O European/O countries/O have/O indicated/O they/O would/O be/O willing/O to/O accept/O a/O small/O number/O of/O the/O released/O prisoners/O ./O
