Several/O Uighurs/O held/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION prison/O have/O appealed/O to/O the/O German/O government/O for/O asylum/O ./O 
A/O remote/O Pacific/LOCATION island/O has/O agreed/O to/O accept/O them/O but/O only/O on/O a/O temporary/O basis/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Seema/PERSON Saifee/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O lawyer/O for/O the/O Uighur/O detainees/O ,/O told/O Spiegel/ORGANIZATION Online/ORGANIZATION that/O their/O case/O had/O been/O put/O to/O the/O German/O government/O ./O 
``/O Our/O clients/O implore/O the/O federal/O government/O to/O open/O the/O door/O of/O Germany/LOCATION for/O them/O and/O to/O persuade/O other/O European/O nations/O to/O give/O protection/O to/O many/O other/O stateless/O Guantanamo/LOCATION prisoners/O ,/O ''/O <U_PERSON>Saifee/PERSON</U_PERSON> said/O ./O 
Germany/LOCATION 's/O <OTHER>Interior/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Minister/O Wolfgang/PERSON Schaeuble/PERSON made/O it/O clear/O last/O week/O that/O a/O decision/O could/O not/O be/O made/O because/O Germany/LOCATION regarded/O the/O information/O provided/O by/O the/O <LOCATION>US/ORGANIZATION</LOCATION> State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION on/O the/O Uighurs/O as/O insufficient/O ./O 
The/O <OTHER>interior/ORGANIZATION ministry/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> has/O refused/O other/O applications/O from/O former/O Guantanamo/LOCATION inmates/O on/O national/O security/O grounds/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Saifee/PERSON</U_PERSON> said/O the/O men/O had/O been/O ``/O upset/O and/O disappointed/O ''/O by/O the/O critical/O attitude/O of/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O interior/O minister/O ./O 
``/O The/O Uighurs/O see/O Germany/LOCATION with/O the/O largest/O Uighur/O community/O in/O Europe/LOCATION as/O the/O best/O way/O to/O end/O their/O imprisonment/O for/O nearly/O a/O decade/O at/O Guantanmo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
Pacific/LOCATION island/O temporarily/O takes/O in/O Uighurs/O 
On/O Wednesday/O ,/O the/O small/O Pacific/LOCATION island/O of/O Palau/LOCATION agreed/O to/O accept/O the/O Uighers/O on/O a/O temporary/O basis/O but/O its/O government/O made/O it/O clear/O that/O it/O could/O not/O grant/O them/O permanent/O asylum/O ./O 
The/O detainees/O ,/O part/O of/O a/O <OTHER>Turkic/ORGANIZATION Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O that/O has/O long/O faced/O persecution/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O were/O part/O of/O a/O group/O of/O 22/O Uighurs/O living/O in/O a/O self-contained/O camp/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION when/O the/O US-led/O invasion/O was/O launched/O in/O October/O 2001/O as/O part/O of/O a/O military/O campaign/O in/O the/O wake/O of/O the/O September/O 11/O ,/O 2001/O attacks/O ./O 
When/O the/O bombings/O against/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION began/O ,/O the/O Uighurs/O fled/O to/O the/O mountains/O ,/O but/O they/O ended/O up/O in/O American/O hands/O after/O being/O turned/O over/O to/O Pakistani/O authorities/O ,/O in/O some/O cases/O by/O bounty/O hunters/O ./O 
The/O 17/O Muslims/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O remote/O northwestern/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O were/O accused/O of/O having/O trained/O in/O <ORGANIZATION>al/O Qaeda/O</ORGANIZATION> camps/O and/O were/O transferred/O to/O the/O notorious/O US/LOCATION military/O prison/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ,/O in/O southern/O Cuba/LOCATION ./O 
Uighurs/O free/O after/O US/LOCATION court/O upholds/O innocence/O 
The/O US/LOCATION has/O taken/O in/O some/O detainees/O but/O searches/O for/O other/O nations/O to/O do/O the/O same/O 
They/O were/O briefly/O declared/O ``/O enemy/O combatants/O ''/O before/O the/O administration/O of/O former/O President/O George/PERSON Bush/PERSON withdrew/O its/O claims/O ,/O as/O early/O as/O 2004/O for/O most/O of/O the/O detainees/O ./O 
US/LOCATION federal/O courts/O later/O upheld/O their/O innocence/O ./O 
The/O Defense/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION have/O tried/O unsuccessfully/O for/O several/O years/O to/O arrange/O the/O men/O 's/O transfer/O to/O a/O third/O country/O ,/O saying/O they/O face/O the/O risk/O of/O mistreatment/O if/O they/O return/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION regards/O the/O Uighur/O detainees/O as/O ``/O Chinese/O terrorists/O ''/O and/O has/O cracked/O down/O on/O Uighur/O separatists/O ./O 
In/O 2006/O ,/O Albania/LOCATION took/O in/O five/O Uighurs/O from/O Guantanamo/LOCATION ./O 
But/O since/O then/O ,/O no/O other/O country/O has/O stepped/O forward/O ./O 
US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON 's/O administration/O has/O asked/O Germany/LOCATION to/O take/O in/O some/O of/O the/O remaining/O inmates/O and/O is/O planning/O to/O release/O others/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O according/O to/O a/O US/LOCATION official/O ./O 
nda/O ,/O AFP/ap/O 
Editor/O :/O Sonia/PERSON Phalnikar/PERSON
