A/O night-time/O curfew/O was/O imposed/O on/O the/O capital/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> on/O Tuesday/O after/O police/O clamped/O down/O on/O clashing/O Han/O Chinese/O and/O Uighur/O protesters/O ./O 
Over/O a/O thousand/O people/O have/O been/O arrested/O since/O riots/O ,/O in/O which/O more/O than/O 150/O people/O died/O ,/O erupted/O on/O Sunday/O ./O 
Security/O was/O tight/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> on/O Tuesday/O ./O 
The/O atmosphere/O was/O tense/O ./O 
Thousands/O of/O protesters/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O predominant/O Han/O ethnic/O group/O took/O to/O the/O streets/O with/O chains/O ,/O steel/O bars/O and/O other/O weapons/O ,/O calling/O for/O revenge/O against/O the/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O --/O claiming/O they/O incited/O violence/O against/O them/O in/O the/O weekend/O protests/O ./O 
Police/O fired/O tear/O gas/O to/O disperse/O the/O crowd/O and/O the/O authorities/O imposed/O a/O curfew/O until/O Wednesday/O morning/O ./O 
Henrik/PERSON Bork/PERSON ,/O a/O journalist/O from/O the/O German/O Süddeutsche/ORGANIZATION Zeitung/ORGANIZATION daily/O was/O among/O a/O group/O of/O foreign/O journalists/O invited/O by/O the/O government/O to/O visit/O the/O city/O on/O Tuesday/O ./O 
He/O described/O the/O situation/O :/O ``/O The/O city/O is/O in/O chaos/O ./O 
We/O just/O saw/O a/O big/O group/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O trying/O to/O enter/O a/O mosque/O ./O 
They/O threw/O stones/O but/O the/O police/O stopped/O them/O ./O ''/O 
Earlier/O on/O in/O the/O day/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O Uighur/O women/O had/O also/O gone/O out/O onto/O the/O streets/O ./O 
They/O demanded/O the/O release/O of/O family/O members/O who/O have/O gone/O missing/O since/O Sunday/O ./O 
More/O than/O 1,400/O people/O are/O believed/O to/O have/O been/O arrested/O ./O 
Bork/PERSON said/O :/O ``/O When/O they/O saw/O us/O ,/O some/O Uighur/O women/O came/O running/O and/O screaming/O towards/O us/O ./O 
They/O had/O children/O with/O them/O ./O 
They/O said/O their/O family/O members/O had/O been/O arrested/O in/O the/O night/O but/O they/O had/O n't/O done/O anything/O ./O 
Suddenly/O the/O police/O arrived/O ./O 
The/O women/O started/O demonstrating/O again/O ./O 
This/O went/O on/O for/O about/O 1.5/O hours/O ./O 
It/O was/O very/O tense/O ./O 
But/O because/O there/O were/O over/O 100/O of/O us/O foreign/O journalists/O the/O police/O did/O not/O use/O force/O ./O ''/O 
Ethnic/O tensions/O run/O high/O The/O region/O has/O been/O simmering/O since/O a/O factory/O brawl/O in/O the/O southern/O Chinese/O city/O Shaoguan/LOCATION ./O 
last/O month/O that/O killed/O two/O Uighurs/O ./O 
Activists/O say/O that/O on/O Sunday/O ,/O peaceful/O Uighur/O demonstrators/O went/O out/O onto/O <U_LOCATION>People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Square/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> to/O demand/O an/O investigation/O into/O the/O deaths/O ./O 
They/O accuse/O the/O authorities/O of/O clamping/O down/O on/O them/O with/O violence/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O say/O that/O the/O protesters/O themselves/O were/O violent/O ,/O attacking/O people/O on/O the/O streets/O ,/O destroying/O shops/O and/O setting/O fire/O to/O cars/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O ethnically/O divided/O between/O Han/O Chinese/O and/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O ./O 
The/O latter/O claim/O they/O are/O discriminated/O against/O ./O 
``/O In/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O other/O places/O ,/O you/O have/O Uighurs/O living/O in/O a/O quarter/O of/O the/O towns/O and/O these/O have/O been/O completely/O sealed/O by/O the/O police/O ,/O ''/O said/O Rudolf/PERSON Wagner/PERSON from/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Heidelberg/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O So/O you/O get/O into/O a/O situation/O where/O the/O original/O population/O is/O ghettoised/O ./O ''/O 
Internet/O and/O phone/O lines/O down/O 
Some/O parts/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> have/O been/O totally/O cut/O off/O from/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O world/O since/O Sunday/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O have/O blocked/O access/O to/O the/O internet/O and/O cut/O telephone/O lines/O ./O 
They/O have/O justified/O these/O measures/O by/O saying/O they/O will/O prevent/O the/O spread/O of/O violence/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O accused/O exiled/O Uighurs/O of/O using/O electronic/O means/O to/O incite/O violence/O ./O 
The/O spokesman/O for/O the/O Chinese/O foreign/O ministry/O Qin/PERSON Gang/PERSON addressed/O reporters/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION on/O Tuesday/O :/O ``/O The/O truth/O will/O come/O to/O light/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O will/O soon/O reveal/O the/O figures/O and/O provide/O evidence/O ./O 
We/O hope/O that/O other/O countries/O will/O see/O the/O true/O face/O of/O the/O separatists/O and/O will/O stop/O supporting/O them/O ./O ''/O 
International/O community/O expresses/O concern/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> leader/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> has/O denied/O these/O claims/O and/O has/O demanded/O an/O international/O investigation/O into/O the/O deaths/O ./O 
The/O international/O community/O has/O expressed/O its/O concerns/O about/O the/O unrest/O ./O 
On/O Tuesday/O ,/O <OTHER>Navi/PERSON</OTHER> Pillay/PERSON ,/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION High/O Commissioner/O for/O Human/O Rights/O called/O on/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O and/O on/O ethnic/O groups/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> to/O refrain/O from/O using/O further/O violence/O ./O 
She/O also/O urged/O the/O authorities/O to/O treat/O those/O arrested/O in/O line/O with/O international/O law/O ./O 
German/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON also/O said/O she/O would/O raise/O the/O matter/O during/O her/O meeting/O with/O Chinese/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON at/O the/O G8/O summit/O in/O Italy/LOCATION later/O this/O week/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Disha/O Uppal/O 
Editor/O :/O Anne/PERSON Thomas/PERSON
