US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON is/O to/O deliver/O a/O speech/O on/O national/O security/O after/O his/O own/O Democrats/O joined/O with/O Senate/ORGANIZATION Republicans/O and/O voted/O overwhelmingly/O to/O block/O the/O closing/O of/O the/O controversial/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION prison/O ./O 
President/O Obama/PERSON will/O seek/O to/O regain/O control/O of/O the/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION discussion/O Thursday/O with/O a/O major/O address/O on/O national/O security/O ,/O just/O a/O day/O after/O a/O rare/O bipartisan/O defeat/O for/O the/O popular/O president/O ./O 
The/O Senate/ORGANIZATION voted/O 90-6/O to/O strip/O the/O $/O 80/O million/O -LRB-/O 58/O million/O euros/O -RRB-/O Obama/PERSON requested/O for/O the/O closing/O of/O the/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION prison/O from/O spending/O legislation/O for/O the/O wars/O in/O Iraq/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
This/O sharp/O rebuke/O puts/O Obama/PERSON in/O a/O political/O tight/O spot/O at/O home/O and/O abroad/O and/O could/O get/O in/O the/O way/O of/O the/O fulfilment/O of/O his/O promise/O to/O close/O the/O prison/O in/O the/O first/O year/O of/O his/O presidency/O ./O 
Obama/PERSON signed/O the/O executive/O order/O calling/O for/O the/O closure/O on/O January/O 22/O ,/O just/O days/O after/O taking/O office/O ,/O proving/O that/O he/O was/O serious/O about/O reversing/O some/O of/O the/O controversial/O policies/O of/O his/O predecessor/O George/PERSON W./PERSON Bush/PERSON ./O 
But/O now/O Obama/PERSON has/O just/O months/O to/O decide/O what/O to/O do/O with/O the/O 240/O remaining/O inmates/O ,/O many/O of/O whom/O have/O not/O been/O charged/O ./O 
``/O We/O 've/O made/O some/O hasty/O decisions/O that/O are/O now/O going/O to/O take/O some/O time/O to/O unwind/O ,/O ''/O said/O presidential/O spokesman/O Robert/PERSON Gibbs/PERSON ./O 
``/O And/O closing/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ,/O obviously/O ,/O is/O one/O of/O those/O decisions/O ./O ''/O 
Criticism/O from/O all/O sides/O 
While/O Obama/PERSON 's/O move/O to/O close/O the/O prison/O was/O welcomed/O internationally/O ,/O many/O Americans/O are/O skittish/O about/O having/O these/O suspected/O terrorists/O in/O their/O own/O states/O ./O 
Fearing/O a/O backlash/O from/O these/O voters/O ,/O members/O of/O the/O Senate/ORGANIZATION and/O House/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Representatives/ORGANIZATION from/O both/O parties/O have/O resisted/O bringing/O the/O detainees/O into/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Democrats/O under/O no/O circumstances/O will/O move/O forward/O without/O a/O comprehensive/O ,/O responsible/O plan/O from/O the/O president/O ,/O ''/O said/O Senate/ORGANIZATION majority/O leader/O Harry/PERSON Reid/PERSON ./O 
``/O We/O will/O never/O allow/O terrorists/O to/O be/O released/O into/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Many/O of/O the/O inmates/O have/O yet/O to/O be/O charged/O 
FBI/ORGANIZATION director/O Robert/PERSON Mueller/PERSON also/O has/O concerns/O about/O bringing/O the/O detainees/O into/O the/O American/O prison/O system/O ./O 
``/O The/O concerns/O we/O have/O about/O individuals/O who/O may/O support/O terrorism/O being/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION run/O from/O concerns/O about/O providing/O financing/O to/O terrorists/O ,/O radicalizing/O others/O with/O regard/O to/O violent/O extremism/O ,/O the/O potential/O for/O individuals/O undertaking/O attacks/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Mueller/PERSON said/O ./O 
Mueller/PERSON said/O he/O hoped/O Obama/PERSON 's/O speech/O would/O ``/O outline/O a/O comprehensive/O strategy/O for/O keeping/O America/LOCATION safe/O ./O ''/O 
Obama/PERSON has/O also/O come/O under/O fire/O for/O reversing/O his/O position/O on/O other/O related/O issues/O ./O 
Many/O Obama/PERSON supporters/O and/O civil/O liberties/O groups/O were/O angered/O when/O he/O announced/O plans/O to/O re-institute/O Bush-era/O military/O tribunals/O for/O terror/O suspects/O and/O to/O block/O the/O release/O of/O photos/O of/O prisoner/O abuse/O in/O Iraq/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
Little/O support/O from/O Europe/LOCATION 
Obama/PERSON 's/O failure/O to/O persuade/O his/O fellow/O Americans/O to/O accept/O Guantanamo/LOCATION inmates/O into/O their/O country/O could/O further/O undermine/O his/O administration/O 's/O efforts/O to/O get/O allies/O in/O Europe/LOCATION to/O take/O in/O some/O of/O the/O detainees/O themselves/O ./O 
Since/O Obama/PERSON took/O office/O ,/O one/O man/O has/O been/O transferred/O to/O Britain/LOCATION and/O another/O to/O France/LOCATION ,/O but/O other/O European/O nations/O have/O either/O refused/O entirely/O or/O given/O conflicting/O responses/O ./O 
Steinmeier/PERSON is/O n't/O sure/O former/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION inmates/O belong/O in/O Europe/LOCATION 
While/LOCATION Germany/LOCATION 's/O Interior/ORGANIZATION Minister/O Wolfgang/PERSON Schaeuble/PERSON has/O said/O Germany/LOCATION would/O consider/O taking/O in/O former/O inmates/O ,/O Foreign/O Minister/O Frank-Walter/PERSON Steinmeier/PERSON has/O repeatedly/O spoken/O out/O against/O the/O idea/O ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION has/O pushed/O Germany/LOCATION to/O take/O in/O a/O group/O of/O inmates/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uigher/O minority/O ,/O a/O mainly/O Muslim/O group/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION considers/O terrorists/O ./O 
Munich/LOCATION ,/O in/O the/O southern/O German/O state/O Bavaria/LOCATION ,/O is/O home/O to/O around/O 500/O Uighurs/O ,/O the/O largest/O known/O community/O in/O exile/O ./O 
Steinmeier/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O running/O as/O the/O Social/O Democrats/O '/O candidate/O for/O chancellor/O this/O year/O ,/O told/O the/O news/O magazine/O Der/ORGANIZATION Spiegel/ORGANIZATION this/O week/O that/O accepting/O any/O large/O number/O of/O Uighers/O would/O create/O political/O tensions/O with/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O 
hf/AFP/AP/O //O dpa/O 
Editor/O :/O Nick/PERSON Amies/PERSON
