China/LOCATION and/O Britain/LOCATION have/O a/O long/O history/O of/O relations/O ./O 
They/O have/O overcome/O major/O hurdles/O in/O the/O first/O and/O second/O Opium/O Wars/O mid/O 19th/O Century/O and/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Boxer/O Rebellion/O</ORGANIZATION> at/O the/O turn/O of/O the/O 20th/O Century/O ./O 
Joseph/PERSON Lee/PERSON ,/O a/O lecturer/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Nottingham/ORGANIZATION Business/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION ,/O is/O quite/O optimistic/O about/O the/O public/O perception/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
``/O I/O think/O to/O a/O certain/O extent/O that/O the/O British/O are/O happy/O about/O the/O economic/O rise/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
They/O do/O n't/O view/O that/O as/O a/O threat/O ./O ''/O 
He/O says/O China/LOCATION 's/O rise/O has/O given/O both/O sides/O an/O opportunity/O to/O cultivate/O their/O friendship/O ./O 
``/O I/O think/O people/O welcome/O China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O rise/O because/O it/O allows/O the/O British/O people/O to/O go/O to/O the/O country/O and/O they/O also/O see/O it/O as/O a/O positive/O gesture/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O open/O not/O only/O their/O economic/O market/O ,/O but/O also/O their/O country/O ./O 
It/O also/O allows/O the/O Chinese/O people/O to/O come/O to/O the/O UK/LOCATION to/O visit/O ,/O to/O understand/O the/O culture/O and/O to/O pursue/O their/O education/O ./O ''/O 
Not/O all/O feel/O the/O same/O ,/O as/O the/O shoe/O incident/O showed/O -/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON got/O hit/O with/O one/O during/O a/O visit/O 
Limited/O views/O 
Professor/O Andrew/PERSON Marton/PERSON of/O Nottingham/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION has/O been/O based/O in/O Qingbo/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION for/O the/O past/O three/O years/O ./O 
His/O stay/O there/O has/O given/O him/O a/O deeper/O perspective/O of/O China/LOCATION and/O what/O it/O means/O to/O the/O UK/LOCATION ./O 
He/O suggests/O the/O views/O of/O the/O general/O public/O in/O Britain/LOCATION are/O not/O in/O most/O cases/O as/O broad/O as/O a/O that/O of/O a/O person/O living/O abroad/O ./O 
He/O says/O they/O are/O probably/O more/O focused/O on/O economic/O issues/O like/O trade/O imbalances/O and/O European/O tariffs/O on/O trade/O ./O 
He/O says/O people/O think/O ``/O China/LOCATION makes/O a/O lot/O of/O goods/O that/O are/O exported/O all/O over/O the/O world/O ./O 
The/O public/O is/O probably/O framing/O their/O views/O more/O around/O topics/O such/O as/O quality/O ./O ''/O 
Marton/PERSON mentions/O trade/O issues/O relating/O to/O Chinese-made/O shoes/O that/O recently/O circulated/O in/O the/O European/O media/O ./O 
Akmal/PERSON Shaikh/PERSON ,/O a/O Briton/O executed/O in/O China/LOCATION for/O drug/O smuggling/O at/O the/O end/O of/O 2009/O Human/O rights/O There/O are/O a/O number/O of/O other/O issues/O highlighted/O in/O the/O media/O ./O 
There/O certainly/O is/O talk/O of/O Chinese/O human/O rights/O issues/O in/O Great/LOCATION Britain/LOCATION ./O 
Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O British-born/O human/O rights/O watchdog/O ,/O posts/O new/O pleas/O ,/O or/O issues/O calls/O for/O urgent/O action/O and/O condemns/O human/O rights/O abuses/O cases/O in/O China/LOCATION almost/O daily/O ./O 
Among/O them/O was/O a/O case/O that/O hit/O closer/O to/O home/O for/O the/O British/O population/O ./O 
Public/O opinion/O in/O the/O UK/LOCATION was/O outraged/O when/O in/O December/O last/O year/O a/O British/O national/O ,/O Akmal/PERSON Shaikh/PERSON ,/O was/O put/O to/O death/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O after/O being/O found/O guilty/O of/O smuggling/O four/O kilos/O of/O heroin/O -/O despite/O a/O record/O of/O mental/O illness/O ./O 
It/O was/O the/O first/O execution/O of/O a/O European/O citizen/O in/O China/LOCATION in/O 50/O years/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O judiciary/O system/O refused/O to/O hear/O numerous/O pleas/O and/O petitions/O made/O by/O doctors/O ,/O officials/O ,/O Akmal/PERSON Shaikh/PERSON 's/O family/O and/O the/O British/O Prime/O Minister/O ,/O Gordon/PERSON Brown/PERSON ./O 
But/O not/O too/O long/O after/O ,/O the/O range/O of/O media/O coverage/O returned/O to/O normal/O ,/O focussing/O mainly/O on/O economic/O issues/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O military/O growth/O has/O raised/O concerns/O in/O countries/O such/O as/O the/O US/LOCATION Military/O rival/O ?/O 
In/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O the/O UK/LOCATION 's/O close/O ally/O ,/O there/O is/O concern/O about/O China/LOCATION 's/O growth/O in/O the/O military/O sector/O ./O 
But/O Professor/O Marton/PERSON says/O most/O Brits/O do/O n't/O seem/O to/O share/O these/O concerns/O and/O that/O if/O anything/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O military/O growth/O seems/O inevitable/O after/O such/O dramatic/O economic/O growth/O ./O 
He/O says/O that/O any/O perceived/O threat/O would/O only/O pertain/O to/O the/O region/O ,/O for/O instance/O to/O Taiwan/LOCATION ,/O but/O ``/O I/O certainly/O do/O n't/O feel/O anyone/O in/O the/O UK/LOCATION would/O feel/O that/O UK/LOCATION territory/O is/O under/O threat/O in/O terms/O of/O military/O threat/O ./O ''/O 
Joseph/PERSON Lee/PERSON again/O points/O out/O that/O people/O 's/O views/O are/O shaped/O by/O what/O they/O read/O and/O hear/O in/O the/O media/O ./O 
``/O Within/O the/O media/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O there/O is/O extensive/O talk/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O military/O rise/O ./O 
The/O British/O people/O are/O not/O overly/O concerned/O with/O the/O issue/O of/O a/O military/O power/O ./O ''/O 
He/O says/O instead/O ,/O the/O British/O public/O seems/O to/O concentrate/O on/O matters/O they/O can/O influence/O ./O 
``/O They/O concentrate/O more/O on/O how/O we/O ,/O the/O British/O people/O ,/O can/O use/O trade/O relations/O and/O other/O elements/O of/O soft/O power/O to/O influence/O Chinese/O civil/O society/O and/O hopefully/O they/O will/O become/O a/O more/O responsible/O global/O player/O in/O terms/O of/O economic/O and/O military/O power/O ./O ''/O 
Author/O :/O Sarah/PERSON Berning/PERSON 
Editor/O :/O Grahame/PERSON Lucas/PERSON
