A/O city/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O has/O temporarily/O banned/O people/O with/O veils/O ,/O head/O scarves/O and/O long/O beards/O from/O boarding/O buses/O ./O 
Experts/O say/O attempts/O at/O repressing/O their/O culture/O are/O fueling/O violence/O and/O extremism/O ./O 
On/O August/O 4/O ,/O in/O the/O northwestern/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> city/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Karamay/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O authorities/O announced/O a/O ban/O on/O people/O with/O head/O coverings/O including/O hijabs/O ,/O niqabs/O and/O burkas/O ,/O or/O beards/O ,/O from/O taking/O local/O buses/O ./O 
The/O ban/O would/O apply/O for/O the/O duration/O of/O a/O sports/O competition/O ending/O on/O August/O 20/O ,/O state/O media/O reported/O ./O 
For/O Uighurs/O ,/O a/O Turkic-speaking/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O ,/O these/O restrictions/O are/O just/O the/O latest/O in/O years/O of/O oppression/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ,/O say/O analysts/O ./O 
Uighurs/O '/O rights/O ,/O culture/O and/O language/O have/O suffered/O for/O years/O under/O repressive/O policies/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O religion/O has/O remained/O a/O lifeline/O ,/O said/O <U_PERSON>Ümit/PERSON Hamit/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O vice/O president/O of/O the/O <U_PERSON>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_PERSON> -LRB-/O <U_PERSON>WUC/O</U_PERSON> -RRB-/O ./O 
``/O Now/O the/O Chinese/O government/O wants/O to/O destroy/O the/O only/O relief/O the/O Uighurs/O have/O left/O ./O ''/O 
The/O new/O rules/O ,/O which/O also/O forbid/O anyone/O wearing/O clothing/O with/O the/O Islamic/O star/O and/O crescent/O symbol/O from/O boarding/O buses/O in/O the/O area/O for/O the/O specified/O duration/O ,/O follow/O a/O ban/O last/O month/O by/O some/O schools/O and/O government/O offices/O in/O the/O region/O on/O students/O and/O staff/O fasting/O during/O the/O month/O of/O Ramadan/O ./O 
This/O was/O enforced/O as/O a/O measure/O to/O prevent/O the/O promotion/O of/O religion/O in/O schools/O and/O public/O offices/O ./O 
With/O an/O Uighur/O population/O of/O around/O 45/O percent/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O a/O majority/O Muslim/O region/O ./O 
Although/O China/LOCATION 's/O constitution/O states/O that/O citizen/O 's/O ``/O enjoy/O freedom/O of/O religious/O belief/O ''/O and/O condemns/O discrimination/O -LRB-/O article/O 36/O -RRB-/O ,/O the/O atheist/O ,/O Communist-run/O government/O pursues/O secular/O policies/O ./O 
Uighurs/O make/O up/O 45/O percent/O of/O the/O population/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 
Lack/LOCATION of/O ethnic/O integration/O ?/O 
Elsewhere/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minorities/O continue/O to/O practice/O their/O religion/O without/O the/O new/O restrictions/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O the/O Hui/O people/O ,/O a/O predominantly/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ethnic/O group/O ,/O speak/O Chinese/O as/O their/O mother/O tongue/O and/O practice/O a/O different/O form/O of/O Islam/ORGANIZATION ,/O strongly/O influenced/O by/O Chinese/O traditions/O ./O 
For/O this/O reason/O ,/O restrictions/O in/O the/O country/O 's/O northwest/O on/O expressions/O of/O Islam/O such/O as/O headscarves/O have/O been/O interpreted/O by/O experts/O and/O rights/O groups/O as/O yet/O another/O attack/O on/O Uighur/O culture/O ./O 
``/O This/O ban/O is/O not/O against/O Islam/ORGANIZATION per/O se/O but/O specifically/O targeting/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O ''/O says/O Enze/PERSON Han/PERSON ,/O a/O specialist/O on/O ethnic/O politics/O in/O China/LOCATION at/O the/O School/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Oriental/ORGANIZATION <ORGANIZATION>and/O African/O Studies/O</ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>SOAS/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O in/O London/LOCATION ./O 
It/O follows/O growing/O violence/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O including/O clashes/O which/O killed/O dozens/O last/O month/O ,/O an/O incident/O Beijing/LOCATION condemned/O as/O a/O terrorist/O attack/O by/O Islamist/O and/O separatist/O groups/O ,/O fueled/O by/O a/O lack/O of/O ethnic/O integration/O ./O 
``/O Recent/O policies/O are/O seen/O as/O a/O way/O of/O breaking/O down/O cultural/O barriers/O between/O Uighur/O and/O other/O Chinese/O communities/O ,/O ''/O said/O Edward/PERSON Schwarck/PERSON ,/O an/O Asia/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O <OTHER>UK-based/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Royal/ORGANIZATION United/ORGANIZATION Services/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Defense/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O Yet/O there/O is/O a/O clear/O failure/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O see/O that/O ,/O ultimately/O ,/O integration/O can/O not/O be/O brought/O about/O through/O coercion/O and/O violence/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O announced/O a/O one/O year/O crackdown/O on/O violence/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> after/O a/O bomb/O attack/O in/O May/O 
Vicious/O circle/O 
``/O There/O is/O clearly/O a/O causal/O link/O between/O hard-line/O law/O enforcement/O and/O Uighur/O violence/O ,/O ''/O says/O Schwarck/PERSON ,/O explaining/O that/O bans/O on/O everyday/O expressions/O of/O Uighur/O culture/O are/O ``/O deeply/O provocative/O and/O frequently/O spark/O violent/O reactions/O ./O ''/O 
Now/O there/O are/O fears/O that/O the/O increasing/O repression/O of/O their/O culture/O is/O leading/O to/O radicalization/O among/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O <U_ORGANIZATION>WUC/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> vice/O president/O <U_PERSON>Hamit/PERSON</U_PERSON> told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
The/O government/O then/O accuses/O them/O of/O terrorism/O ,/O leading/O to/O a/O vicious/O circle/O of/O violence/O ./O 
Accusations/O are/O flying/O from/O both/O sides/O -/O while/O Beijing/LOCATION blames/O recent/O attacks/O and/O violence/O on/O Uighur/O ``/O terrorists/O ,/O ''/O the/O Uighurs/O deny/O these/O claims/O ./O 
``/O At/O the/O moment/O there/O is/O no/O official/O radicalized/O or/O Islamist/O group/O who/O want/O to/O support/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O ''/O said/O <U_PERSON>Hamit/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O alleging/O that/O the/O government/O is/O even/O propagating/O this/O idea/O by/O setting/O up/O fake/O websites/O for/O terrorist/O organizations/O purporting/O to/O be/O Uighur-run/O groups/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O increased/O security/O in/O many/O parts/O of/O the/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O following/O some/O May/O 's/O attack/O ./O 
Radicalization/O The/O murder/O of/O a/O leading/O Imam/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O city/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O at/O the/O end/O of/O July/O ,/O has/O also/O contributed/O to/O concerns/O over/O religious/O extremism/O ./O 
Some/O Uighurs/O have/O travelled/O to/O countries/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O where/O religious/O extremism/O is/O widespread/O ,/O in/O order/O to/O be/O trained/O to/O act/O against/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Hamit/PERSON</U_PERSON> said/O ,/O suggesting/O that/O this/O could/O have/O disastrous/O consequences/O ./O 
According/O to/O Asia/LOCATION expert/O Schwarck/PERSON ,/O the/O real/O danger/O remains/O to/O be/O seen/O ./O 
``/O It/O is/O not/O yet/O clear/O to/O what/O extent/O Uighurs/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> are/O being/O exposed/O to/O Jihadi/O thinking/O from/O outside/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O
