At/O the/O Lima/LOCATION climate/O conference/O ,/O China/LOCATION promised/O to/O reduce/O its/O greenhouse/O gas/O emissions/O ./O 
But/O it/O has/O a/O long/O road/O ahead/O to/O free/O itself/O from/O its/O dependence/O on/O coal/O ./O 
Future/O climate/O stability/O depends/O on/O how/O fast/O it/O succeeds/O ./O 
China/LOCATION produces/O around/O 30/O percent/O of/O global/O emissions/O of/O carbon/O dioxide/O -/O more/O than/O any/O other/O country/O ./O 
It/O is/O the/O world/O 's/O largest/O greenhouse/O gas/O polluter/O and/O the/O country/O most/O responsible/O for/O any/O global/O temperature/O increase/O that/O might/O result/O ./O 
But/O until/O now/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O shown/O little/O interest/O in/O combating/O climate/O change/O ./O 
With/O some/O justification/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O leadership/O has/O long/O said/O that/O since/O the/O long-industrialized/O countries/O created/O their/O wealth/O at/O the/O expense/O of/O the/O environment/O ,/O they/O have/O an/O obligation/O to/O be/O the/O primary/O actors/O on/O decarbonising/O their/O economies/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O position/O was/O one/O of/O several/O key/O reasons/O for/O the/O failure/O of/O the/O 2009/O climate/O summit/O in/O Copenhagen/LOCATION ./O 
Shortly/O before/O the/O Lima/LOCATION climate/O talks/O began/O ,/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON signaled/O a/O new/O attitude/O in/O a/O joint/O statement/O with/O US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON at/O the/O APEC/ORGANIZATION Summit/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION :/O China/LOCATION plans/O to/O reach/O peak/O annual/O CO2/O emissions/O by/O no/O later/O than/O 2030/O ,/O and/O decrease/O emissions/O year-on-year/O thereafter/O ./O 
President/O <PERSON>X/O</PERSON> also/O said/O China/LOCATION would/O use/O non-fossil/O energy/O sources/O for/O 20/O percent/O of/O its/O total/O energy/O needs/O by/O that/O year/O ./O 
How/O quickly/O ?/O 
China/LOCATION is/O coming/O under/O increasing/O pressure/O from/O environmental/O groups/O It/O was/O an/O announcement/O that/O sent/O a/O strong/O signal/O ./O 
If/O China/LOCATION does/O not/O take/O action/O ,/O all/O climate/O efforts/O are/O doomed/O to/O failure/O ./O 
While/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>EU/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> and/O -/O to/O a/O lesser/O extent/O -/O the/O US/LOCATION are/O taking/O steps/O to/O cut/O emissions/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O increased/O its/O output/O this/O year/O by/O 500/O million/O tons/O -/O making/O China/LOCATION ``/O a/O unique/O global/O threat/O ,/O ''/O as/O ``/O The/O Economist/O ''/O put/O it/O ./O 
What/O matters/O is/O how/O fast/O and/O how/O comprehensively/O China/LOCATION can/O become/O independent/O of/O coal/O ./O 
Even/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O which/O sees/O itself/O as/O a/O leader/O of/O the/O green/O energy/O revolution/O ,/O is/O making/O this/O transition/O only/O slowly/O ./O 
At/O present/O ,/O China/LOCATION produces/O about/O 75/O percent/O of/O its/O electricity/O from/O coal/O ./O 
In/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O the/O figure/O is/O 44/O percent/O ./O 
China/LOCATION faces/O the/O bigger/O technical/O challenge/O ,/O since/O its/O total/O energy/O demand/O is/O greater/O and/O still/O growing/O fast/O -/O its/O demand/O for/O electricity/O is/O expected/O to/O grow/O by/O over/O 70/O percent/O by/O 2035/O ./O 
It/O 's/O an/O open/O question/O as/O to/O whether/O China/LOCATION can/O break/O the/O link/O between/O economic/O growth/O and/O consumption/O of/O coal/O -/O and/O thus/O carbon/O dioxide/O emissions/O ./O 
``/O It/O wo/O n't/O be/O possible/O to/O shake/O the/O dominance/O of/O coal/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O energy/O system/O for/O a/O long/O time/O ,/O ''/O environmental/O expert/O Björn/PERSON Conrad/PERSON ,/O analyst/O at/O the/O Berlin-based/O Mercator/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Chinese/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>MERICS/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ,/O wrote/O in/O a/O recent/O study/O ./O 
Although/O China/LOCATION is/O developing/O renewable/O energy/O sources/O on/O a/O large/O scale/O ,/O leaving/O coal/O behind/O will/O require/O decades/O of/O effort/O ,/O he/O said/O ./O 
Signs/O of/O a/O turnaround/O 
But/O Li/PERSON Shuo/PERSON ,/O a/O climate/O and/O energy/O campaigner/O at/O <ORGANIZATION>Greenpeace/LOCATION East/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> ,/O is/O optimistic/O that/O this/O is/O possible/O ./O 
``/O In/O the/O first/O three/O quarters/O of/O 2014/O ,/O China/LOCATION experienced/O a/O decline/O in/O coal/O consumption/O by/O 1-2/O percent/O ,/O while/O economic/O growth/O was/O still/O at/O around/O 7/O percent/O ,/O ''/O Li/PERSON told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ./O 
For/O the/O first/O time/O ,/O coal/O consumption/O has/O declined/O in/O absolute/O terms/O ,/O he/O said/O ./O 
And/O while/O this/O is/O not/O an/O energy/O transition/O on/O the/O German/O model/O ,/O it/O could/O the/O ``/O be/O the/O beginning/O of/O an/O ambitious/O turnaround/O ,/O ''/O Li/PERSON said/O ,/O calling/O the/O next/O Five-Year/O Plan/O ,/O from/O 2016/O to/O 2020/O ,/O ``/O absolutely/O critical/O ./O ''/O 
Li/PERSON expects/O that/O the/O plan/O will/O include/O a/O cap/O on/O coal/O consumption/O -/O thus/O reducing/O CO2/O emissions/O before/O 2030/O ./O 
``/O There/O is/O therefore/O a/O lot/O of/O scope/O for/O China/LOCATION to/O reach/O its/O emissions/O peak/O much/O earlier/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
Speaking/O in/O Lima/LOCATION ,/O German/O Environment/O Minister/O Gerd/PERSON Müller/PERSON put/O it/O in/O similar/O terms/O :/O ``/O China/LOCATION has/O now/O made/O environmental/O protection/O its/O number-one/O topic/O ,/O because/O the/O people/O demanded/O it/O ./O 
I/O think/O the/O Chinese/O will/O be/O much/O more/O ambitious/O than/O they/O are/O announcing/O now/O ./O ''/O 
Solar/O and/O wind/O energy/O not/O used/O efficiently/O 
Little/O is/O being/O done/O to/O stop/O pollution/O in/O China/LOCATION 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O withdrawal/O from/O coal/O has/O less/O to/O do/O with/O fear/O of/O climate/O change/O than/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION leadership/O 's/O fear/O of/O mass/O discontent/O over/O deadly/O smog/O ,/O like/O that/O which/O smothered/O Beijing/LOCATION in/O January/O 2013/O ./O 
Catastrophic/O air/O quality/O also/O has/O a/O negative/O effect/O on/O investment/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O leadership/O has/O realized/O that/O it/O can/O not/O go/O on/O this/O way/O -/O and/O for/O that/O reason/O ,/O it/O 's/O increasingly/O looking/O to/O non-fossil/O energy/O sources/O ./O 
In/O terms/O of/O new/O wind/O and/O solar/O power/O plants/O ,/O China/LOCATION was/O the/O world/O leader/O in/O 2013/O ./O 
But/O power/O transmission/O faces/O a/O bottleneck/O :/O The/O grid/O can/O not/O keep/O up/O with/O the/O installed/O wind/O power/O capacity/O ./O 
Eco-friendly/O current/O generated/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O interior/O is/O only/O partly/O able/O to/O reach/O coastal/O regions/O where/O demand/O is/O greatest/O ./O 
China/LOCATION needs/O an/O intelligent/O power/O system/O that/O is/O compatible/O with/O clean/O energy/O ,/O Li/PERSON said/O ./O 
But/O it/O is/O easier/O to/O move/O from/O zero/O clean/O energy/O to/O a/O 5/O per/O cent/O renewable/O electricity/O share/O ,/O he/O added/O ,/O than/O to/O go/O from/O 15/O to/O 20/O percent/O ,/O which/O would/O be/O the/O next/O step/O for/O China/LOCATION ./O 
A/O nuclear/O alternative/O 
Wind/O power/O will/O require/O a/O new/O electric/O grid/O In/O addition/O to/O water/O ,/O wind/O and/O solar/O power/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O also/O turning/O to/O a/O more/O controversial/O alternative/O to/O coal/O :/O Nuclear/O energy/O ./O 
After/O the/O initial/O shock/O from/O the/O <LOCATION>Fukushima/PERSON</LOCATION> reactor/O meltdown/O abated/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION gave/O the/O green/O light/O for/O nuclear/O power/O capacity/O to/O triple/O to/O 150/O megawatts/O by/O 2020/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O largest/O nuclear/O power/O company/O ,/O CGN/ORGANIZATION ,/O with/O revenues/O of/O $/O 3.2/O billion/O ,/O had/O this/O year/O 's/O second-largest/O <OTHER>IPO/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> in/O the/O Asia-Pacific/LOCATION region/O when/O it/O began/O trading/O on/O the/O Hong/ORGANIZATION Kong/ORGANIZATION Stock/ORGANIZATION Exchange/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Critics/O fear/O that/O with/O China/LOCATION 's/O new/O enthusiasm/O for/O ``/O clean/O ''/O nuclear/O energy/O ,/O safety/O issues/O are/O bound/O to/O come/O up/O short/O ./O 
Another/O alternative/O to/O conventional/O coal/O energy/O is/O coal/O gasification/O ./O 
This/O technology/O has/O been/O known/O for/O decades/O ,/O and/O Beijing/LOCATION plans/O to/O further/O promote/O and/O use/O it/O for/O the/O electricity/O and/O gas/O supply/O to/O large/O cities/O ./O 
It/O could/O in/O part/O replace/O conventional/O coal-fired/O power/O plants/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O also/O turning/O toward/O nuclear/O energy/O But/O there/O 's/O a/O catch/O ,/O Li/PERSON said/O :/O This/O energy-intensive/O technology/O produces/O even/O more/O carbon/O dioxide/O than/O normal/O combustion/O of/O coal/O ./O 
In/O addition/O ,/O water/O consumption/O is/O very/O high/O ,/O which/O is/O likely/O to/O become/O a/O major/O problem/O ,/O especially/O in/O the/O arid/O regions/O of/O central/O China/LOCATION and/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O where/O new/O plants/O are/O to/O be/O built/O ./O 
Germany/LOCATION 's/O Siemens/ORGANIZATION has/O built/O coal/O gasification/O plants/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O is/O planning/O more/O ./O 
The/O company/O says/O its/O operations/O are/O virtually/O carbon-neutral/O ,/O thanks/O to/O the/O latest/O technology/O ./O 
But/O these/O concepts/O are/O not/O currently/O being/O implemented/O in/O systems/O delivered/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O a/O Siemens/ORGANIZATION spokeswoman/O admitted/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
There/O are/O many/O signs/O China/LOCATION is/O trying/O to/O move/O beyond/O its/O conventional/O coal-driven/O energy/O supply/O ./O 
Germany/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION are/O currently/O pursuing/O an/O ``/O innovation/O partnership/O ./O ''/O 
But/O a/O great/O deal/O of/O innovation/O will/O be/O needed/O if/O wind/O ,/O water/O and/O solar/O power/O are/O to/O gain/O the/O upper/O hand/O ./O
