President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON 's/O visit/O to/O Brussels/LOCATION is/O a/O sign/O of/O intensifying/O economic/O relations/O between/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>EU/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> and/O China/LOCATION ,/O believes/O China/LOCATION expert/O Fraser/PERSON Cameron/PERSON ./O 
But/O Europeans/O have/O to/O keep/O raising/O political/O issues/O ,/O he/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION :/O This/O is/O the/O first/O visit/O of/O a/O Chinese/O president/O to/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION institutions/O ./O 
In/O your/O eyes/O ,/O what/O significance/O does/O it/O have/O ?/O 
Fraser/PERSON Cameron/PERSON :/O I/O think/O it/O 's/O very/O significant/O that/O the/O Chinese/O president/O comes/O to/O Europe/LOCATION because/O this/O will/O give/O him/O a/O first-hand/O impression/O -/O not/O only/O of/O EU/ORGANIZATION institutions/O and/O leaders/O ./O 
He/O has/O also/O been/O able/O to/O arrange/O a/O number/O of/O visits/O to/O member/O states/O ,/O including/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O France/LOCATION ,/O the/O Netherlands/LOCATION ,/O and/O Belgium/LOCATION ./O 
This/O will/O also/O give/O him/O an/O idea/O of/O the/O interplay/O between/O member/O states/O and/O European/O institutions/O ./O 
The/O focus/O of/O this/O visit/O to/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION and/O its/O member/O states/O is/O ,/O as/O always/O ,/O on/O economic/O relations/O ./O 
Will/O the/O talks/O go/O significantly/O beyond/O that/O ?/O 
Yes/O ,/O in/O the/O Netherlands/LOCATION for/O example/O is/O a/O pragmatic/O comprehensive/O partnership/O agreement/O that/O calls/O for/O consultation/O on/O a/O range/O of/O issues/O ,/O including/O human/O rights/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O 's/O important/O that/O member/O states/O do/O n't/O just/O concentrate/O on/O trade/O issues/O ,/O but/O also/O raise/O political/O issues/O ,/O including/O human/O rights/O as/O well/O ./O 
Human/O rights/O are/O often/O mentioned/O because/O that/O 's/O expected/O ./O 
But/O I/O get/O the/O impression/O that/O the/O Chinese/O side/O listens/O ,/O they/O know/O it/O 's/O coming/O ,/O they/O nod/O ./O 
That/O 's/O it/O ./O 
But/O that/O 's/O followed/O up/O at/O a/O lower/O level/O with/O consultations/O on/O human/O rights/O ,/O both/O at/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION level/O and/O the/O level/O of/O member/O states/O ./O 
<LOCATION>Germany/O</LOCATION> for/O example/O has/O been/O having/O a/O particularly/O intense/O dialogue/O on/O human/O rights/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O 
I/O think/O gradually/O ,/O it/O 's/O making/O some/O impact/O ./O 
And/O it/O 's/O important/O to/O remind/O the/O Chinese/O that/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION attaches/O importance/O to/O human/O rights/O ./O 
But/O what/O can/O be/O done/O apart/O from/O telling/O them/O they/O have/O to/O improve/O their/O human/O rights/O record/O ?/O 
What/O is/O being/O done/O to/O promote/O that/O in/O concrete/O terms/O ?/O 
Fraser/PERSON Cameron/PERSON is/O the/O Director/O of/O the/O Brussels-based/O think/O tank/O <ORGANIZATION>EU-Asia/O Centre/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Many/O things/O ./O 
Business/O schools/O have/O been/O set/O up/O with/O EU/ORGANIZATION support/O ,/O which/O involve/O facing/O issues/O head-on/O ,/O like/O corruption/O ,/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O ,/O media/O freedom/O ./O 
These/O are/O all/O important/O for/O human/O rights/O as/O well/O ./O 
Preaching/O is/O not/O really/O going/O to/O get/O anywhere/O ./O 
Yet/O ,/O it/O 's/O important/O to/O try/O and/O do/O everything/O possible/O to/O make/O sure/O that/O liberal/O reforms/O go/O on/O ,/O because/O the/O economic/O and/O the/O political/O side/O are/O so/O interrelated/O ./O 
In/O what/O other/O fields/O do/O you/O see/O potential/O for/O closer/O relations/O ?/O 
Urbanization/O is/O already/O doing/O quite/O well/O ;/O innovation/O will/O be/O a/O key/O issue/O ./O 
There/O 's/O a/O lot/O of/O EU/ORGANIZATION expertise/O available/O to/O help/O China/LOCATION move/O towards/O a/O green/O economy/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O lot/O of/O talk/O on/O Africa/LOCATION ./O 
As/O China/LOCATION expands/O its/O global/O footprint/O ,/O it/O 's/O going/O to/O run/O up/O against/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION more/O and/O more/O ./O 
So/O it/O 's/O important/O that/O the/O two/O sides/O talk/O and/O share/O views/O on/O issues/O like/O Sudan/LOCATION ,/O and/O development/O in/O Africa/LOCATION ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O the/O impression/O that/O China/LOCATION takes/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION as/O a/O joint/O political/O bloc/O seriously/O ,/O or/O is/O it/O more/O interested/O in/O bilateral/O relations/O with/O the/O member/O states/O ?/O 
Both/O ./O 
But/O like/O any/O major/O power/O ,/O including/O Russia/LOCATION and/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O it/O 's/O seeking/O opportunities/O to/O divide/O and/O conquer/O ./O 
It/O 's/O quite/O natural/O ,/O and/O of/O course/O it/O 's/O up/O to/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION to/O provide/O a/O united/O front/O in/O response/O ./O 
So/O while/O I/O think/O there/O 's/O some/O obvious/O competition/O within/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION for/O trade/O and/O investment/O ,/O I/O think/O they/O do/O recognize/O the/O importance/O of/O speaking/O with/O one/O voice/O against/O countries/O like/O China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
Would/O you/O say/O there/O 's/O been/O a/O visible/O change/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O policy/O -/O especially/O toward/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION -/O since/O the/O new/O government/O took/O office/O ?/O 
I/O think/O there/O 's/O recognition/O that/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION is/O their/O number-one/O trading/O partner/O ,/O that/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION is/O going/O to/O overcome/O its/O difficulties/O it/O had/O regarding/O sovereign/O debt/O ,/O that/O growth/O prospects/O are/O good/O ,/O that/O this/O is/O going/O to/O be/O a/O really/O important/O area/O for/O the/O Chinese/O -/O moving/O forward/O both/O in/O terms/O of/O helping/O them/O with/O their/O own/O economic/O development/O ,/O but/O also/O as/O a/O political/O partner/O ./O 
Would/O you/O say/O that/O 's/O happening/O because/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON is/O taking/O a/O different/O approach/O ,/O or/O would/O it/O also/O have/O happened/O under/O his/O predecessor/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ?/O 
In/O one/O trade/O conflict/O ,/O Chinese/O producers/O protested/O an/O import/O duty/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION imposed/O on/O solar/O cells/O His/O predecessor/O did/O n't/O take/O such/O a/O hands-on/O approach/O as/O President/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> ./O 
But/O the/O relationship/O previously/O had/O been/O put/O onto/O a/O higher/O level/O through/O -LSB-/O former/O -RSB-/O Prime/O Minister/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O the/O team/O now/O of/O President/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> and/O Premier/O Li/PERSON both/O have/O an/O interest/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O for/O a/O mixture/O of/O economic/O and/O political/O reasons/O ./O 
But/O above/O all/O ,/O it/O 's/O important/O as/O the/O largest/O market/O in/O the/O world/O ./O 
And/O China/LOCATION needs/O that/O market/O to/O ensure/O continued/O high/O employment/O at/O home/O ./O 
So/O you/O would/O say/O that/O the/O focus/O will/O remain/O on/O the/O economic/O aspect/O of/O the/O relationship/O ?/O 
This/O will/O be/O the/O prime/O driver/O of/O the/O relationship/O for/O the/O foreseeable/O future/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O 's/O important/O to/O understand/O that/O the/O investment/O agreement/O currently/O being/O negotiated/O will/O have/O a/O very/O important/O role/O in/O opening/O up/O the/O Chinese/O market/O ,/O tackling/O issues/O like/O protection/O of/O intellectual/O property/O and/O market/O access/O ./O 
This/O will/O then/O be/O the/O precursor/O to/O a/O potential/O free-trade/O area/O negotiation/O between/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>EU/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> and/O China/LOCATION ./O 
What/O are/O the/O Chinese/O most/O worried/O about/O when/O they/O look/O at/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION and/O developments/O here/O ?/O 
I/O think/O they/O were/O worried/O before/O whether/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION would/O continue/O to/O exist/O -/O this/O was/O the/O discourse/O in/O 2009/O and/O 2010/O ./O 
They/O now/O understand/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION is/O here/O to/O stay/O ,/O and/O that/O it/O 's/O a/O very/O stable/O environment/O ./O 
They/O want/O to/O increase/O their/O investment/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ./O 
And/O they/O also/O understand/O the/O importance/O and/O growing/O role/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION plays/O in/O international/O affairs/O ./O 
Speaking/O of/O international/O affairs/O :/O In/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O China/LOCATION abstained/O from/O condemning/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O moves/O to/O annex/O Crimea/LOCATION ./O 
Many/O people/O have/O interpreted/O this/O as/O China/LOCATION isolating/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O or/O moving/O away/O from/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
Would/O you/O see/O it/O the/O same/O way/O ?/O 
No/O ./O 
They/O are/O playing/O both/O sides/O ./O 
They/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O upset/O the/O Russians/O ,/O but/O they/O have/O an/O equally/O great/O fear/O of/O anything/O that/O upsets/O their/O core/O principles/O of/O territorial/O integrity/O and/O sovereignty/O ./O 
Of/O course/O they/O have/O great/O concerns/O about/O demands/O for/O a/O referendum/O -/O which/O might/O take/O place/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O Taiwan/LOCATION ,/O or/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Province/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
So/O they/O 're/O being/O very/O careful/O here/O trying/O to/O not/O antagonize/O either/O side/O ,/O nor/O to/O come/O down/O 100/O percent/O in/O favor/O of/O one/O or/O the/O other/O side/O ./O 
Fraser/PERSON Cameron/PERSON is/O director/O of/O the/O Brussels-based/O think/O tank/O <ORGANIZATION>EU-Asia/O Centre/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
He/O has/O lived/O and/O worked/O in/O Belgium/LOCATION for/O 20/O years/O ./O
A/O former/O British/O diplomat/O and/O EU/ORGANIZATION official/O ,/O he/O is/O also/O a/O visiting/O professor/O at/O several/O universities/O in/O Asia/LOCATION ./O
