The/O newly/O burgeoning/O relationship/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION is/O of/O mutual/O benefit/O ,/O writes/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON ./O 
If/O you/O want/O to/O see/O who/O is/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O new/O friend/O ,/O all/O you/O have/O to/O do/O is/O look/O at/O the/O new/O president/O 's/O travel/O schedule/O ./O 
Ashraf/PERSON Ghani/PERSON had/O hardly/O been/O in/O office/O for/O a/O month/O when/O he/O took/O off/O on/O his/O first/O foreign/O visit/O ./O 
Where/O did/O he/O go/O ?/O 
To/O China/LOCATION of/O course/O -/O which/O is/O ,/O politically/O and/O economically/O ,/O the/O strongest/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O neighbors/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O leader/O and/O Party/ORGANIZATION boss/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON received/O the/O Afghan/O president/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION last/O week/O ./O 
And/O not/O only/O was/O it/O Ghani/PERSON 's/O first/O state/O visit/O ,/O his/O final/O day/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION happened/O to/O coincide/O with/O the/O opening/O day/O of/O the/O Istanbul/LOCATION Process/O 2014/O ./O 
This/O was/O China/LOCATION 's/O first/O time/O as/O host/O for/O the/O coming/O together/O of/O 14/O Asian/O states/O ,/O including/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Azerbaijan/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION ,/O India/LOCATION ,/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ,/O Kyrgyzistan/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ,/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ,/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION and/O United/LOCATION Arab/LOCATION Emirates/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O fostered/O close/O ties/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION for/O decades/O ./O 
Now/O it/O is/O building/O a/O friendship/O with/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O country/O is/O simply/O too/O strategically/O important/O for/O China/LOCATION to/O ignore/O ./O 
It/O is/O indeed/O of/O such/O significance/O that/O in/O the/O 19th/O century/O ,/O the/O British/O tried/O to/O bring/O the/O divided/O land/O under/O their/O control/O ,/O followed/O by/O the/O Russians/O in/O the/O 20th/O century/O and/O the/O Americans/O and/O NATO/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O 21st/O ./O 
So/O Far/O Unsuccessful/O 
China/LOCATION ,/O however/O ,/O is/O not/O planning/O to/O control/O Afghanistan/LOCATION by/O military/O means/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O strategy/O is/O one/O of/O economic/O cooperation/O ./O 
While/O Western/O firms/O have/O neither/O the/O political/O back-up/O ,/O the/O money/O ,/O nor/O the/O economic/O interest/O ,/O Chinese/O companies/O have/O no/O such/O problems/O and/O are/O slated/O to/O move/O into/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON 
But/O they/O do/O have/O others/O ./O 
In/O 2007/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION paid/O $/O 3/O billion/O for/O a/O copper/O mine/O outside/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O 
This/O needled/O the/O Americans/O ,/O who/O then/O began/O to/O support/O archaeological/O excavations/O on/O the/O site/O with/O millions/O of/O US/O dollars/O ./O 
Lack/O of/O infrastructure/O and/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION attacks/O also/O took/O their/O toll/O on/O the/O project/O ./O 
As/O recently/O as/O September/O ,/O another/O Chinese/O delegation/O came/O by/O for/O a/O visit/O ./O 
A/O date/O for/O when/O they/O can/O get/O started/O with/O the/O extraction/O of/O copper/O has/O yet/O to/O be/O arranged/O ./O 
Another/O Chinese/O raw/O materials/O project/O which/O has/O had/O a/O bit/O of/O a/O bumpy/O ride/O is/O on/O the/O border/O to/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Chinese/O Petro-chemical/O company/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION has/O begun/O extracting/O oil/O in/O the/O Amu/LOCATION Darya/LOCATION oil/O field/O ./O 
Disputes/O about/O costs/O between/O Afghan/O authorities/O and/O Chinese/O sub-contractors/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O antiquated/O equipment/O ,/O have/O led/O to/O a/O standstill/O here/O ,/O too/O ./O 
Additionally/O ,/O China/LOCATION would/O like/O to/O build/O infrastructure/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O order/O to/O realize/O the/O dream/O of/O a/O new/O Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION ./O 
Afghanistan/LOCATION could/O then/O be/O at/O a/O crossroads/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O its/O partners/O further/O west/O including/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
`/O Could/O '/O ,/O though/O ,/O is/O the/O operative/O word/O :/O this/O project/O too/O is/O more/O theory/O than/O practice/O ./O 
Shared/O interest/O 
But/O there/O is/O another/O reason/O why/O Beijing/LOCATION remains/O so/O undeterred/O that/O it/O recently/O even/O earmarked/O a/O further/O $/O 3/O million/O for/O investment/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
On/O the/O one/O hand/O ,/O China/LOCATION -/O in/O time-honored/O fashion/O -/O is/O attempting/O to/O secure/O access/O to/O raw/O materials/O ./O 
But/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O also/O pursuing/O other/O interests/O ./O 
With/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O militants/O declaring/O their/O intention/O to/O liberate/O the/O autonomous/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O the/O urgency/O of/O maintaining/O stability/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION is/O greater/O than/O ever/O ./O 
Not/O least/O because/O Beijing/LOCATION believes/O that/O the/O terrorists/O who/O have/O been/O active/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O the/O past/O hailed/O from/O eastern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
Afghanistan/LOCATION itself/O could/O also/O benefit/O from/O a/O closer/O cooperation/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O which/O would/O help/O it/O banish/O the/O specter/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O Chinese/O have/O long/O nurtered/O a/O friendship/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O a/O bastion/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
A/O closer/O friendship/O between/O Kabul/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION boost/O the/O likelihood/O of/O constructive/O talks/O between/O Kabul/LOCATION and/O Islamabad/LOCATION on/O how/O to/O tackle/O the/O threat/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Taliban/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON has/O lived/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O 20/O years/O ./O
