China/LOCATION has/O staked/O its/O economic/O future/O on/O deeper/O integration/O with/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
But/O as/O the/O US/LOCATION withdraws/O from/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O concerned/O that/O a/O renewed/O civil/O war/O there/O could/O thwart/O regional/O development/O ./O 
As/O the/O US/LOCATION prepares/O to/O scale/O back/O its/O military/O presence/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION this/O year/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O begun/O to/O contemplate/O a/O geopolitical/O ``/O march/O westwards/O ''/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION hopes/O to/O trigger/O an/O economic/O boom/O in/O its/O restive/O western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O by/O re-vitalizing/O the/O ancient/O <U_LOCATION>Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O which/O runs/O through/O its/O Central/O and/O South/O Asian/O neighbors/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O largely/O taken/O a/O low-profile/O and/O cautious/O approach/O toward/O the/O conflict/O in/O neighboring/O Afghanistan/LOCATION since/O the/O overthrow/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION in/O 2001/O ./O 
But/O there/O is/O growing/O concern/O among/O the/O Chinese/O leadership/O that/O NATO/ORGANIZATION could/O leave/O behind/O a/O security/O vacuum/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O which/O would/O potentially/O jeopardize/O China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O investments/O in/O the/O broader/O region/O ./O 
``/O If/O they/O remain/O in/O a/O civil/O war/O ,/O we/O ca/O n't/O make/O any/O money/O there/O ,/O ''/O Jin/PERSON Canrong/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O on/O China/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O policy/O at/O Rinmin/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION 's/O stance/O is/O very/O simple/O :/O China/LOCATION would/O like/O to/O see/O a/O capable/O central/O government/O and/O wants/O to/O see/O a/O stable/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O open/O to/O the/O world/O market/O ./O ''/O 
China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O `/O march/O westwards/O '/O 
Since/O China/LOCATION 's/O leadership/O change/O last/O year/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O sought/O to/O accelerate/O its/O economic/O integration/O with/O its/O western/O neighbors/O ./O 
Chinese/O Premier/O Li/PERSON Keqiang/PERSON travelled/O to/O Islamabad/LOCATION in/O May/O 2013/O ,/O where/O he/O announced/O plans/O to/O build/O a/O <U_LOCATION>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Among/O other/O infrastructure/O projects/O ,/O the/O close/O allies/O plan/O to/O upgrade/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Karakoram/LOCATION Highway/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O which/O connects/O northern/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O western/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O following/O September/O ,/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON travelled/O to/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ,/O where/O he/O delivered/O a/O speech/O on/O regional/O development/O at/O Nazarbayev/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION in/O Astana/LOCATION ./O 
According/O to/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> ,/O Beijing/LOCATION wants/O to/O work/O with/O the/O Central/O Asian/O nations/O to/O revitalize/O the/O ancient/O <U_LOCATION>Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> trade/O route/O ,/O connecting/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION Ocean/LOCATION to/O the/O Baltic/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ./O 
In/O particular/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O sought/O to/O deepen/O its/O energy/O ties/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
China/LOCATION and/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION have/O built/O an/O oil/O pipeline/O that/O stretches/O more/O than/O 2,200/O kilometers/O from/O the/O Caspian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION to/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ./O 
China/LOCATION wants/O to/O build/O a/O modern/O version/O of/O the/O ancient/O <U_LOCATION>Silk/O Road/O</U_LOCATION> 
Since/O the/O overthrow/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O China/LOCATION has/O also/O increased/O its/O investment/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
In/O 2007/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION won/O the/O contract/O for/O the/O largest/O investment/O project/O in/O the/O county/O ,/O the/O <LOCATION>Aynak/O</LOCATION> copper/O mine/O ./O 
Located/O in/O eastern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O the/O mine/O is/O worth/O an/O estimated/O $/O 3/O billion/O -LRB-/O 2/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O ./O 
In/O 2011/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION also/O secured/O oil/O and/O gas/O exploration/O rights/O worth/O at/O least/O $/O 700/O million/O in/O the/O northeastern/O Sari/LOCATION Pul/LOCATION and/O Faryab/LOCATION provinces/O ./O 
``/O For/O China/LOCATION ,/O a/O lot/O of/O their/O concern/O with/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION stems/O from/O its/O concerns/O with/O respect/O to/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O sort/O of/O a/O long/O standing/O concern/O to/O integrate/O that/O region/O more/O fully/O with/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Michael/PERSON Clarke/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O on/O Chinese/O foreign/O policy/O at/O Griffith/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION in/O Australia/LOCATION ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
``/O A/O key/O aspect/O of/O that/O process/O over/O the/O last/O few/O decades/O has/O been/O an/O attempt/O to/O use/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O geopolitical/O position/O at/O the/O crossroads/O of/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION to/O facilitate/O the/O spread/O of/O Chinese/O influence/O into/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O mainly/O for/O strategic/O reasons/O related/O to/O energy/O security/O issues/O ,/O ''/O Clarke/PERSON said/O ./O 
Combating/O the/O `/O three/O evils/O '/O During/O his/O trip/O to/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ,/O President/O Xi/PERSON also/O called/O on/O China/LOCATION 's/O Central/O Asian/O neighbors/O to/O help/O in/O the/O regional/O fight/O against/O what/O Beijing/LOCATION calls/O the/O ``/O three/O evils/O ''/O :/O terrorism/O ,/O separatism/O and/O religious/O extremism/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O indigenous/O Uighur/O population/O ,/O who/O speak/O a/O Turkic/O language/O and/O are/O predominantly/O Sunni/O Muslim/O ,/O have/O long/O chaffed/O under/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O rule/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O border/O with/O Afghanistan/LOCATION is/O less/O than/O 100/O kilometers/O long/O and/O largely/O inaccessible/O due/O to/O rugged/O terrain/O ./O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O expressed/O concern/O that/O a/O resurgent/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION could/O embolden/O Muslim/O separatists/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION is/O concerned/O about/O stability/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 
The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O blamed/O a/O series/O of/O recent/O attacks/O ,/O including/O the/O knife/O massacre/O at/O the/O Kunming/LOCATION train/O station/O in/O February/O ,/O on/O Muslim/O separatists/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Twenty-nine/O people/O died/O in/O the/O train/O station/O massacre/O ,/O which/O state/O media/O has/O called/O ``/O China/LOCATION 's/O 9/11/O ./O ''/O 
The/O leader/O of/O the/O separatists/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Abdullah/PERSON Mansour/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O reportedly/O has/O taken/O refuge/O in/O North/LOCATION Waziristan/LOCATION along/O the/O Afghan-Pakistan/O border/O ./O 
``/O There/O is/O a/O genuine/O and/O serious/O concern/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION as/O well/O as/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O the/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O that/O perhaps/O some/O of/O the/O incidents/O of/O violent/O extremism/O and/O terrorism/O inside/O China/LOCATION .../O may/O have/O their/O roots/O .../O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O neighborhood/O -/O countries/O like/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Mushahid/PERSON Hussain/PERSON Syed/PERSON ,/O a/O Pakistani/O senator/O and/O director/O of/O the/O China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
New/O Great/O Game/O ?/O 
According/O to/O a/O recent/O report/O by/O <ORGANIZATION>The/O Guardian/O</ORGANIZATION> newspaper/O ,/O US/LOCATION officials/O believe/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O Washington/LOCATION are/O basically/O on/O the/O same/O page/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O combating/O Islamist/O militancy/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O opening/O the/O possibility/O of/O greater/O cooperation/O between/O the/O world/O 's/O two/O most/O powerful/O nations/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O already/O set/O up/O a/O fledgling/O security/O partnership/O with/O Kabul/LOCATION ,/O training/O at/O least/O 300/O Afghan/O police/O officers/O since/O 2012/O ./O 
In/O February/O ,/O Chinese/O Foreign/O Minister/O Wang/PERSON Yi/PERSON travelled/O to/O Kabul/LOCATION ,/O where/O he/O highlighted/O the/O central/O importance/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION to/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O broader/O interests/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
Despite/O its/O interest/O in/O fighting/O militancy/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION remains/O wary/O of/O a/O long-term/O American/O and/O NATO/ORGANIZATION military/O presence/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION is/O aware/O that/O there/O are/O certain/O lobbies/O ,/O there/O are/O certain/O constituencies/O ,/O there/O 's/O a/O certain/O school/O of/O thought/O in/O capitals/O like/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D.C./LOCATION or/O Brussels/LOCATION which/O talk/O of/O a/O China/LOCATION threat/O ,/O which/O talk/O of/O containment/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O talk/O of/O encirclement/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Hussain/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION does/O n't/O want/O that/O Afghanistan/LOCATION should/O become/O the/O center/O of/O a/O revived/O new/O great/O game/O that/O could/O in/O turn/O suck/O China/LOCATION into/O a/O debilitating/O tug/O of/O war/O strategically/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION or/O its/O proxies/O ./O ''/O
