State/O media/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O say/O blasts/O have/O killed/O at/O least/O two/O people/O but/O have/O given/O few/O details/O ./O 
In/O the/O past/O year/O scores/O have/O died/O in/O tensions/O between/O mainly-Muslim/O Uighurs/O and/O security/O forces/O ./O 
The/O communist-run/O <ORGANIZATION>Tianshan/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> news/O portal/O said/O explosions/O happened/O at/O three/O places/O ,/O including/O a/O shop/O ,/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Luntai/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> <OTHER>county/LOCATION</OTHER> ./O 
It/O lies/O in/O a/O desert/O area/O 360/O kilometers/O -LRB-/O 220/O miles/O -RRB-/O southwest/O of/O the/O western/O region/O 's/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
``/O Public/O security/O officers/O quickly/O handled/O the/O situation/O ,/O ''/O the/O portal/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O an/O unspecified/O number/O of/O injured/O had/O been/O taken/O to/O hospital/O ./O 
``/O Local/O social/O order/O is/O normal/O ,/O and/O the/O cases/O are/O being/O investigated/O ,/O ''/O <ORGANIZATION>Tianshan/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> said/O ./O 
Officials/O punished/O for/O `/O failures/O '/O On/O Sunday/O ,/O state/O media/O said/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION officials/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> had/O demoted/O or/O dismissed/O 17/O officials/O and/O police/O officers/O for/O alleged/O failures/O relating/O to/O two/O incidents/O in/O July/O ./O 
Tight/O security/O makes/O it/O difficult/O for/O foreign/O journalists/O to/O visit/O the/O region/O ./O 
Exiled/O Uighur/O groups/O say/O the/O government/O 's/O repressive/O policies/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O including/O curbs/O on/O <ORGANIZATION>Islam/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O have/O provoked/O unrest/O ,/O a/O claim/O denied/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Violent/O incidents/O On/O July/O 28/O ,/O the/O government/O said/O 37/O civilians/O were/O killed/O and/O 59/O alleged/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O were/O shot/O dead/O by/O security/O forces/O in/O two/O towns/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O far/O south/O ./O 
On/O June/O 30/O ,/O three/O assailants/O armed/O with/O knives/O and/O axes/O killed/O <U_PERSON>Juma/PERSON Tayir/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O the/O imam/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O biggest/O mosque/O in/O the/O old/O Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION city/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
ipj/lw/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
