A/O day/O after/O dozens/O of/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O clashes/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ,/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Uighur/ORGANIZATION World/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> '/O <U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> tells/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O account/O of/O events/O intends/O to/O depict/O peaceful/O protesters/O as/O ``/O terrorists/O ./O ''/O 
On/O July/O 29/O dozens/O of/O people/O died/O in/O clashes/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O volatile/O northwestern/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
According/O to/O state/O media/O ,/O a/O mob/O armed/O with/O knives/O and/O axes/O rampaged/O through/O <U_LOCATION>Shache/LOCATION County/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> near/O the/O city/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O police/O responded/O with/O gunfire/O ,/O leaving/O dozens/O of/O people/O dead/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O latest/O outbreak/O of/O violence/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION blames/O on/O Islamists/O and/O separatists/O from/O the/O restive/O region/O where/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O -/O also/O spelled/O Uyghur/O -/O make/O up/O around/O 45/O percent/O of/O the/O population/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O state-run/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O mob/O first/O attacked/O a/O police/O station/O and/O government/O offices/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Elixku/LOCATION Township/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O and/O before/O moving/O on/O to/O the/O nearby/O <U_LOCATION>Huangdi/LOCATION Township/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O attacking/O civilians/O and/O smashing/O vehicles/O as/O they/O passed/O ./O 
However/O ,/O it/O is/O difficult/O to/O verify/O the/O information/O independently/O and/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O official/O account/O of/O the/O latest/O clash/O is/O being/O disputed/O by/O exiled/O groups/O representing/O the/O Uighur/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
In/O a/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> interview/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O spokesman/O for/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>WUC/O</U_ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O says/O heavily-armed/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O opened/O fire/O and/O killed/O and/O wounded/O nearly/O 100/O Uighurs/O after/O hundreds/O of/O them/O protested/O en/O masse/O against/O China/LOCATION 's/O heavy-handed/O Ramadan/O crackdown/O ./O 
There/O seems/O to/O be/O some/O confusion/O about/O the/O recent/O clashes/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O <U_LOCATION>Shache/O</U_LOCATION> ,/O or/O <U_LOCATION>Yarkant/O</U_LOCATION> ,/O county/O ./O 
What/O can/O you/O tells/O us/O about/O the/O incident/O ?/O 
According/O to/O local/O Uighurs/O ,/O heavily-armed/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O opened/O fire/O and/O killed/O and/O wounded/O nearly/O 100/O Uighurs/O after/O hundreds/O of/O them/O protested/O en/O masse/O against/O China/LOCATION 's/O heavy-handed/O Ramadan/O crackdown/O for/O the/O past/O month/O and/O the/O extrajudicial/O killing/O of/O a/O Uighur/O family/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Yarkant/LOCATION County/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O early/O July/O ./O 
Since/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON became/O president/O ,/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O have/O been/O given/O the/O order/O to/O shoot/O and/O kill/O Uighur/O protestors/O with/O impunity/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O the/O Uighurs/O have/O been/O witnessing/O more/O and/O more/O killings/O and/O even/O massacres/O ./O 
``/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O have/O been/O given/O the/O order/O to/O shoot/O and/O kill/O Uighur/O protestors/O with/O impunity/O ,/O ''/O says/O <U_PERSON>Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O seen/O here/O -LRB-/O R/O -RRB-/O next/O to/O exiled/O Uighur/O leader/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON>
Beijing/PERSON is/O calling/O this/O a/O ``/O terror/O attack/O ./O ''/O 
What/O is/O your/O view/O on/O this/O ?/O 
China/LOCATION 's/O state/O media/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION always/O portrays/O illegal/O killings/O and/O massacres/O of/O Uighur/O people/O by/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O as/O acts/O of/O Uighur/O ``/O terrorism/O ./O ''/O 
If/O they/O were/O indeed/O ``/O terror/O attacks/O ''/O as/O described/O by/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O then/O China/LOCATION should/O have/O no/O problem/O in/O allowing/O foreign/O journalists/O and/O diplomats/O to/O visit/O <U_LOCATION>Yarkant/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> to/O investigate/O the/O incidents/O without/O harassment/O ./O 
However/O ,/O we/O know/O Beijing/LOCATION wo/O n't/O allow/O it/O as/O the/O government/O wants/O to/O hide/O what/O truly/O happened/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Yarkant/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
After/O the/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O opened/O fire/O ,/O killing/O or/O wounding/O nearly/O a/O hundred/O Uighurs/O ,/O some/O protestors/O fought/O back/O with/O whatever/O they/O had/O in/O their/O hands/O ,/O such/O as/O spades/O ,/O hammers/O or/O knives/O ./O 
Some/O Chinese/O police/O casualties/O are/O expected/O ,/O but/O the/O number/O is/O likely/O to/O be/O much/O lower/O than/O the/O Uighur/O civilian/O casualties/O ./O 
In/O the/O immediate/O aftermath/O of/O this/O violence/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O sealed/O off/O the/O area/O ,/O preventing/O Uighurs/O from/O entering/O or/O leaving/O the/O county/O ./O 
China/LOCATION shut/O down/O both/O the/O Internet/O and/O instant/O messaging/O services/O in/O order/O to/O prevent/O Uighurs/O from/O posting/O photos/O and/O videos/O of/O the/O massacre/O that/O contradict/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION 's/O spin/O of/O events/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Sangay/PERSON :/O `/O Tibetans/O seek/O genuine/O autonomy/O ,/O not/O independence/O '/O 
The/O leader/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION 's/O exiled/O government/O ,/O Lobsang/PERSON Sangay/PERSON ,/O spoke/O with/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> about/O his/O new/O campaign/O aimed/O at/O resuming/O long-stalled/O talks/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O softening/O China/LOCATION 's/O handling/O of/O his/O homeland/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 06.06.2014/O -RRB-/O 
<U_ORGANIZATION>WUC/O</U_ORGANIZATION> :/O China/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> policy/O `/O backfiring/O '/O 
A/O day/O after/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O suffered/O a/O major/O attack/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> from/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> tells/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> the/O area/O is/O witnessing/O a/O violent/O response/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O 65-year-long/O ``/O brutal/O repression/O ''/O of/O Uighurs/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 23.05.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Opinion/O :/O China/LOCATION 's/O iron/O fist/O comes/O down/O where/O it/O should/O n't/O Over/O 30/O people/O have/O died/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O in/O a/O pointless/O attack/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O ``/O iron/O fist/O ''/O politics/O have/O failed/O to/O put/O an/O end/O to/O such/O violence/O for/O a/O reason/O ,/O says/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Matthias/PERSON von/PERSON Hein/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O 22.05.2014/O -RRB-/O Uighur/O leader/O :/O `/O Highly/O suspicious/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O terror/O claim/O '/O 
After/O a/O fatal/O car/O crash/O at/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O Uighurs/O fear/O more/O restrictions/O by/O authorities/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Exiled/O leader/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> says/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O using/O the/O incident/O as/O an/O excuse/O to/O further/O oppress/O the/O ethnic/O minority/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 08.11.2013/O -RRB-/O 
According/O to/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O attacks/O were/O ``/O organized/O and/O premeditated/O ./O ''/O 
In/O your/O view/O ,/O who/O is/O responsible/O for/O the/O attack/O ?/O 
This/O is/O the/O standard/O language/O used/O by/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION to/O describe/O every/O act/O of/O violence/O somehow/O related/O to/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O it/O is/O the/O Chinese/O government/O 's/O one-year/O long/O anti-terror/O campaign/O ,/O which/O is/O ``/O organized/O and/O premeditated/O ./O ''/O 
Conceived/O by/O the/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON administration/O it/O is/O aimed/O at/O terrorizing/O and/O punishing/O the/O peaceful/O Uighur/O population/O ,/O especially/O during/O the/O Holy/O Month/O of/O Ramadan/O ./O 
The/O political/O violence/O and/O instability/O is/O the/O direct/O result/O of/O communist/O China/LOCATION 's/O 65-year/O long/O repressive/O policies/O in/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O especially/O the/O latest/O heavy-handed/O suppression/O of/O the/O Uighur/O people/O 's/O legitimate/O demands/O for/O human/O rights/O and/O democracy/O ./O 
Why/O are/O these/O clashes/O taking/O place/O in/O the/O first/O place/O and/O who/O are/O behind/O them/O ?/O 
The/O clashes/O are/O taking/O place/O because/O of/O the/O complete/O failure/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O ethnic/O policy/O in/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O systematic/O political/O repression/O and/O policies/O of/O cultural/O genocide/O are/O behind/O the/O high/O tensions/O ./O 
Simply/O put/O ,/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ,/O just/O like/O their/O next/O door/O neighbor/O Tibetans/O ,/O are/O fed/O up/O with/O China/LOCATION 's/O brutal/O repression/O ./O 
Enough/O is/O enough/O for/O them/O ./O 
They/O have/O borne/O repression/O for/O the/O past/O 65/O years/O and/O no/O longer/O want/O to/O endure/O state/O terrorism/O for/O the/O coming/O 65/O years/O ./O 
They/O want/O their/O rights/O ,/O dignity/O ,/O justice/O and/O freedom/O ./O 
Just/O last/O month/O ,/O two/O courts/O jailed/O 113/O people/O for/O terrorist/O activities/O and/O related/O offences/O ./O 
Four/O were/O handed/O life/O sentences/O ./O 
What/O is/O China/LOCATION 's/O hard-line/O approach/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> leading/O to/O ?/O 
The/O mass/O show/O trials/O are/O proof/O that/O Chinese/O rule/O in/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O similar/O to/O that/O of/O the/O days/O of/O Mao/PERSON 's/O notorious/O Cultural/O Revolution/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O sentenced/O these/O people/O in/O order/O to/O terrorize/O the/O entire/O Uighur/O population/O ./O 
In/O Chinese/O it/O is/O called/O ``/O kill/O the/O chicken/O to/O scare/O the/O monkey/O ./O ''/O 
China/LOCATION wanted/O the/O Uighurs/O to/O see/O the/O price/O paid/O by/O those/O daring/O to/O stand/O up/O to/O its/O colonial/O and/O apartheid-like/O rule/O in/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
How/O can/O the/O violence/O be/O stopped/O ?/O 
<U_PERSON>Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> :/O ``/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O using/O its/O massive/O security/O force/O to/O deal/O with/O any/O Uighur/O unrest/O ''/O 
First/O ,/O China/LOCATION must/O put/O an/O end/O to/O its/O anti-terror/O campaign/O ./O 
Second/O ,/O China/LOCATION must/O stop/O implementing/O policies/O of/O cultural/O genocide/O ,/O such/O as/O the/O so-called/O bilingual/O language/O policy/O ,/O which/O discriminate/O against/O Uighur/O identity/O and/O culture/O ./O 
Also/O ,/O it/O must/O cease/O to/O attack/O the/O Uighurs/O '/O religious/O beliefs/O and/O practices/O ./O 
Finally/O ,/O China/LOCATION should/O negotiate/O with/O the/O Uighur/O people/O for/O a/O peaceful/O settlement/O of/O the/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> issue/O ./O 
How/O is/O Beijing/LOCATION tightening/O its/O grip/O on/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ?/O 
Beijing/LOCATION is/O using/O a/O two-pronged/O strategy/O :/O First/O ,/O it/O is/O using/O its/O massive/O security/O force/O to/O deal/O with/O any/O Uighur/O unrest/O ./O 
Secondly/O ,/O it/O is/O portraying/O the/O ensuing/O discontent/O as/O ``/O separatism/O ,/O terrorism/O and/O religious/O extremism/O ''/O in/O order/O to/O win/O public/O opinion/O at/O home/O and/O the/O world/O ./O 
People/O in/O China/LOCATION have/O no/O choice/O but/O to/O accept/O the/O government/O 's/O narrative/O as/O facts/O because/O there/O is/O no/O alternative/O explanation/O ./O 
People/O in/O the/O <LOCATION>West/O</LOCATION> have/O a/O choice/O to/O study/O and/O find/O out/O the/O truth/O about/O what/O is/O happening/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O officially/O charged/O Professor/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> with/O ``/O separatism/O ''/O on/O July/O 30/O ,/O a/O move/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>WUC/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> condemns/O ./O 
This/O is/O a/O disgraceful/O and/O unlawful/O persecution/O of/O Professor/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> who/O had/O peacefully/O advocated/O racial/O reconciliation/O and/O fair/O treatment/O of/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O heavy-handed/O treatment/O should/O alert/O the/O international/O community/O about/O the/O fact/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O not/O fighting/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O in/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O but/O all/O Uighurs/O ,/O even/O those/O who/O express/O their/O views/O peacefully/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION commonly/O blames/O separatists/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> for/O carrying/O out/O terror/O attacks/O ./O 
Are/O the/O Uighurs/O willing/O to/O reach/O a/O compromise/O with/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ?/O 
<U_PERSON>Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> slammed/O the/O separatism/O charges/O pressed/O against/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> as/O part/O of/O ``/O a/O disgraceful/O and/O unlawful/O persecution/O ''/O 
The/O Uighur/O people/O compromised/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION when/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> was/O promised/O autonomy/O in/O 1955/O ;/O something/O which/O turned/O out/O to/O be/O a/O big/O political/O lie/O ./O 
What/O autonomy/O or/O preferential/O treatment/O do/O the/O Uighur/O people/O enjoy/O today/O ?/O 
They/O only/O enjoy/O the/O preferential/O treatment/O of/O political/O repression/O ,/O frequent/O massacres/O and/O extrajudicial/O killings/O ./O 
In/O spite/O of/O the/O current/O terrible/O situation/O ,/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> has/O called/O on/O China/LOCATION numerous/O times/O to/O negotiate/O for/O a/O peaceful/O settlement/O of/O the/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> issue/O ./O 
So/O far/O ,/O we/O have/O not/O seen/O any/O indication/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O genuinely/O interested/O in/O peace/O in/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> or/O a/O peaceful/O resolution/O of/O the/O dispute/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> is/O spokesperson/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> in/O Washington/LOCATION DC/LOCATION ./O
