Officials/O have/O refused/O to/O renew/O Beijing-based/O journalist/O Ursula/PERSON Gauthier/PERSON 's/O press/O visa/O unless/O she/O apologizes/O for/O a/O story/O ./O 
Gauthier/PERSON wrote/O criticially/O on/O China/LOCATION 's/O ``/O anti-terror/O ''/O operations/O against/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O Uighur/O Muslims/O ./O 
``/O They/O confirmed/O that/O if/O I/O did/O not/O make/O a/O public/O apology/O on/O all/O the/O points/O that/O had/O `/O hurt/O the/O Chinese/O people/O '/O .../O my/O press/O card/O would/O not/O be/O renewed/O and/O I/O would/O have/O to/O leave/O on/O December/O 31/O ,/O ''/O Gauthier/PERSON told/O news/O agency/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Gauthier/PERSON can/O not/O apply/O for/O a/O visa/O unless/O her/O press/O card/O is/O renewed/O ./O 
``/O If/O I/O had/O actually/O written/O what/O they/O accuse/O me/O of/O ,/O I/O deserve/O to/O be/O put/O in/O prison/O ,/O not/O expelled/O ,/O ''/O the/O reporter/O said/O ./O 
The/O attitude/O of/O Chinese/O officials/O was/O ``/O a/O pretext/O to/O intimidate/O foreign/O correspondents/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O particularly/O on/O issues/O concerning/O minorities/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O she/O would/O ``/O not/O deviate/O ''/O from/O her/O story/O ./O 
Watch/O video/O 01:38/O 
Share/O China/LOCATION expels/O French/O journalist/O Send/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION Twitter/ORGANIZATION Google/ORGANIZATION +/O <ORGANIZATION>Whatsapp/O</ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION>Tumblr/O</ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION>linkedin/O</ORGANIZATION> stumble/O <ORGANIZATION>Digg/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> reddit/O <ORGANIZATION>Newsvine/O</ORGANIZATION> Permalink/O http://dw.com/p/1HU4i/O
 China/LOCATION expels/O French/O journalist/O Gauthier/PERSON is/O based/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O works/O for/O the/O news/O magazine/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>L'Obs/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O ''/O formerly/O known/O as/O <ORGANIZATION>Le/PERSON Nouvel/PERSON Observateur/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Her/O essay/O ,/O published/O on/O November/O 18/O ,/O was/O called/O ``/O After/O the/O attacks/O -LSB-/O in/O Paris/LOCATION -RSB-/O ,/O Chinese/O solidarity/O is/O not/O without/O ulterior/O motives/O ./O ''/O 
The/O report/O discussed/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policies/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O where/O most/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O ethnic/O Uighur/O Muslim/O minority/O lives/O ./O 
The/O story/O also/O triggered/O abusive/O comments/O from/O social/O media/O users/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O was/O condemned/O by/O the/O state-run/O Global/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION and/O China/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION ./O 
`/O Campaign/O of/O intimidation/O '/O Chinese/O officials/O said/O the/O report/O justified/O violence/O against/O the/O government/O ./O 
``/O The/O article/O criticized/O China/LOCATION 's/O counterterrorism/O efforts/O and/O denigrated/O and/O slandered/O Chinese/O policies/O ./O 
It/O provoked/O the/O strong/O indignation/O of/O the/O Chinese/O public/O ,/O ''/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Hua/PERSON Chunying/PERSON said/O earlier/O this/O month/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O efforts/O by/O French/O officials/O ,/O including/O Paris/LOCATION '/O envoy/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O Maurice/PERSON Gourdault-Montagne/PERSON ,/O have/O produced/O no/O results/O ./O 
The/O foreign/O correspondents/O '/O club/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION said/O it/O was/O ``/O deeply/O concerned/O with/O the/O attempts/O of/O intimidation/O ./O ''/O 
Press/O organization/O Reporters/O Without/O Borders/O also/O denounced/O the/O incident/O ,/O calling/O it/O ``/O media/O lynching/O ''/O and/O ``/O campaign/O of/O defamation/O and/O intimidation/O ''/O against/O Gauthier/PERSON ./O 
Before/O Gauthier/PERSON ,/O Melissa/PERSON Chan/PERSON ,/O who/O works/O for/O television/O channel/O Al/ORGANIZATION Jazeera/ORGANIZATION ,/O was/O expelled/O in/O 2012/O ./O 
mg/msh/O -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>dpa/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
