A/O prominent/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION exile/O has/O entered/O the/O race/O for/O a/O seat/O in/O Taiwan/LOCATION 's/O parliament/O as/O an/O independent/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Wu'er/PERSON Kaixi/PERSON</U_PERSON> says/O he/O will/O take/O a/O tough/O line/O on/O Taiwan/LOCATION 's/O relations/O with/O mainland/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Former/O student/O co-leader/O <U_PERSON>Wu'er/PERSON Kaixi/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O who/O fled/O China/LOCATION after/O its/O 1989/O crackdown/O and/O later/O settled/O in/O Taiwan/LOCATION ,/O launched/O his/O candidacy/O on/O Friday/O aimed/O at/O winning/O a/O legislative/O seat/O in/O Taichung/LOCATION ,/O a/O major/O city/O on/O the/O island/O 's/O west/O coast/O ./O 
Taiwan/LOCATION votes/O for/O a/O new/O parliament/O and/O a/O new/O president/O next/O January/O ,/O with/O the/O ruling/O pro-China/ORGANIZATION Nationalist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O Kuomintang/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O KMT/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O on/O the/O back/O foot/O since/O its/O heavy/O losses/O in/O local/O elections/O last/O November/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Wu'er/PERSON Kaixi/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O now/O 47/O ,/O with/O links/O to/O western/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uighur/O peoples/O -LRB-/O pictured/O above/O -RRB-/O ,/O said/O he/O would/O take/O on/O the/O KMT/ORGANIZATION ,/O describing/O it/O as/O an/O ``/O enormous/O monster/O ,/O ''/O as/O part/O of/O his/O bid/O to/O ``/O deepen/O democracy/O ./O ''/O 
KTM/ORGANIZATION candidate/O Hung/PERSON is/O known/O as/O a/O straight/O talker/O
Earlier/O this/O month/O ,/O the/O Nationalists/O sought/O to/O end/O months/O of/O division/O by/O picking/O Hung/PERSON Hsiu-chu/PERSON as/O their/O presidential/O candidate/O ./O 
She/O is/O an/O advocate/O of/O closer/O ties/O with/O mainland/O China/LOCATION and/O is/O the/O current/O parliament/O 's/O deputy/O speaker/O ./O 
Her/O main/O challenger/O will/O be/O Tsai/PERSON Ing-wen/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O chairwoman/O of/O Taiwan/LOCATION 's/O Democratic/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O DPP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O which/O leans/O toward/O Taiwanese/O independence/O ./O 
Taiwan/LOCATION split/O from/O China/LOCATION in/O 1949/O after/O a/O civil/O war/O and/O became/O self-ruling/O ,/O but/O Beijing/LOCATION still/O sees/O the/O island/O aspart/O of/O its/O territory/O awaiting/O reunification/O --/O by/O force/O if/O necessary/O ./O 
Trade/O deals/O triggered/O protest/O 
Relations/O have/O improved/O under/O current/O president/O Ma/PERSON Ying-jeou/PERSON of/O the/O KMT/ORGANIZATION ,/O leading/O to/O a/O number/O of/O trade/O deals/O but/O triggering/O growing/O public/O unease/O ./O 
Last/O November/O ,/O thousands/O of/O young/O Taiwanese/O occupied/O the/O island/O 's/O parliament/O in/O an/O unprecedented/O protest/O against/O a/O planned/O China-Taiwan/O trade/O pact/O ./O 
That/O sentiment/O was/O fueled/O by/O clashes/O between/O police/O and/O pro-democracy/O protestors/O in/O China-ruled/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ./O 
At/O his/O press/O conference/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Wu'er/PERSON Kaixi/PERSON</U_PERSON> said/O China/LOCATION was/O the/O ``/O home/O of/O my/O parents/O ./O ''/O 
``/O Taiwan/LOCATION is/O the/O home/O of/O my/O children/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Wu'er/PERSON Kaixi/PERSON</U_PERSON> fled/O China/LOCATION in/O 1989/O after/O China/LOCATION 's/O military/O crushed/O student/O protests/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O killing/O hundreds/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Wu/PERSON 're/O</U_PERSON> berated/O Li/PERSON Peng/PERSON 
He/PERSON became/O the/O second/O most/O wanted/O student/O leader/O in/O China/LOCATION after/O he/O famously/O berated/O then-premier/O Li/PERSON Peng/PERSON during/O a/O televised/O meeting/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Wu'er/PERSON Kaixi/PERSON</U_PERSON> married/O a/O Taiwanese/O woman/O and/O settled/O on/O the/O island/O in/O 1996/O ./O 
Also/O standing/O for/O the/O same/O seat/O in/O Taichung/LOCATION is/O the/O opposition/O DDP/ORGANIZATION contender/O Chang/PERSON Liao/PERSON Wan-chien/PERSON ,/O a/O longtime/O city/O councilor/O in/O the/O island/O 's/O third/O largest/O city/O ./O 
Both/O men/O agreed/O to/O run/O their/O campaigns/O of/O policy/O issues/O with/O no/O mud-slinging/O ./O 
ipj/kms/O -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
