China/LOCATION is/O one/O of/O four/O countries/O directly/O involved/O in/O talks/O aimed/O at/O resuming/O the/O stalled/O peace/O process/O between/O the/O Afghan/O government/O and/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> takes/O a/O look/O at/O what/O 's/O driving/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O diplomatic/O push/O ./O 
Although/O China/LOCATION did/O n't/O take/O part/O in/O the/O US-led/O invasion/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O 2001/O -/O which/O toppled/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION regime/O -/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O n't/O remained/O completely/O on/O the/O sidelines/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O have/O long/O been/O interested/O in/O tapping/O into/O the/O <OTHER>South/LOCATION Asian/LOCATION</OTHER> nation/O 's/O mining/O sector/O ,/O signing/O various/O multibillion/O dollar/O deals/O with/O the/O Afghan/O government/O in/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O 
And/O since/O 2010/O ,/O they/O have/O been/O stepping/O up/O diplomatic/O efforts/O in/O a/O bid/O to/O start/O a/O peace/O process/O between/O Kabul/LOCATION and/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION insurgents/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O in/O early/O 2015/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION said/O it/O was/O ready/O to/O support/O Kabul/LOCATION in/O facilitating/O reconciliation/O discussions/O with/O militant/O Islamic/O groups/O ,/O with/O <OTHER>Chinese/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Minister/O Wang/PERSON Yi/PERSON stressing/O that/O ``/O broad-based/O and/O inclusive/O national/O reconciliation/O ''/O was/O vital/O to/O sustained/O stability/O in/O the/O conflict-ridden/O country/O ./O 
The/O first/O and/O second/O rounds/O of/O four-nation/O talks/O were/O held/O in/O January/O ,/O 2016/O ./O 
More/O recently/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O special/O envoy/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Deng/PERSON Xijun/PERSON ,/O has/O attended/O two/O rounds/O of/O four/O nation/O talks/O -/O involving/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION -/O aimed/O at/O reviving/O the/O Afghan/O peace/O process/O ./O 
Worries/O about/O Uighur/O sanctuaries/O Experts/O argue/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O increasing/O involvement/O in/O Afghan/O politics/O is/O driven/O not/O only/O by/O economic/O reasons/O ,/O but/O also/O by/O China/LOCATION 's/O own/O domestic/O problems/O with/O Islamic/O extremism/O in/O the/O form/O of/O Uighur/O militants/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION></ORGANIZATION> recommends/O
Why/O are/O the/O Afghans/O wary/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION ?/O 
Many/O Afghans/O associate/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION with/O neighboring/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O blame/O Islamabad/LOCATION for/O their/O misery/O and/O decades-long/O armed/O conflict/O in/O their/O country/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> analyzes/O the/O reasons/O behind/O the/O Afghans/O '/O wariness/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O -LRB-/O 24.08.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Can/O the/O high-level/O talks/O lead/O to/O peace/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ?/O 
Afghan/O officials/O and/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION representatives/O have/O met/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION for/O talks/O ./O 
But/O experts/O say/O such/O negotiations/O can/O only/O lead/O to/O peace/O if/O those/O involved/O are/O recognized/O by/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION leadership/O ./O -LRB-/O 08.07.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Why/O China/LOCATION is/O alarmed/O about/O IS/O presence/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION The/O leaders/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION and/O other/O countries/O will/O discuss/O the/O threat/O the/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O group/O poses/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION at/O a/O Eurasian/O security/O summit/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> spoke/O to/O analyst/O Borhan/PERSON Osman/PERSON about/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O concerns/O ./O -LRB-/O 08.07.2015/O -RRB-/O 
``/O China/LOCATION is/O worried/O about/O `/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> '/O -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O gaining/O a/O permanent/O foothold/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O establishing/O links/O to/O Uighur/O militants/O ,/O ''/O Wahid/PERSON Mazhdah/PERSON ,/O a/O former/O employee/O of/O the/O ousted/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION regime/O ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
The/O Uighurs/O ,/O mostly/O Sunni/O Muslims/O ,/O feel/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O attempting/O to/O undermine/O their/O cultural/O identity/O ,/O political/O rights/O ,/O religion/O and/O exploit/O what/O they/O view/O as/O their/O region/O 's/O natural/O resources/O ./O 
This/O has/O pushed/O many/O Uighurs/O towards/O radicalization/O and/O militancy/O ,/O say/O experts/O ./O 
Siegfried/PERSON O./PERSON Wolf/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O research/O at/O the/O Brussels-based/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION Democratic/O Forum/O -LRB-/O <OTHER>SADF/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> -RRB-/O ,/O said/O the/O claims/O by/O some/O Chinese/O sources/O that/O Uighur/O militants/O use/O fake/O Turkish/O passports/O to/O enter/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O join/O extremist/O groups/O makes/O Beijing/LOCATION increasingly/O concerned/O about/O the/O long/O war/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O In/O the/O Afghan/O and/O Pakistani/O camps/O ,/O which/O are/O heavily/O funded/O by/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ,/O Uighurs/O receive/O ideological/O indoctrination/O as/O well/O as/O military/O training/O ,/O ''/O said/O the/O analyst/O ./O 
Faiz/PERSON Mohammad/PERSON Zaland/PERSON ,/O a/O Kabul/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION lecturer/O who/O recently/O met/O with/O a/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION delegation/O in/O Qatar/LOCATION ,/O has/O a/O similar/O view/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION wants/O to/O make/O sure/O Uighur/O militants/O do/O not/O have/O sanctuaries/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION wants/O this/O issue/O to/O be/O part/O of/O the/O negotiations/O ,/O ''/O Zaland/PERSON told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Economic/O interests/O Another/O important/O reason/O behind/O the/O diplomatic/O push/O may/O be/O China/LOCATION 's/O level/O of/O economic/O engagement/O in/O these/O two/O countries/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O China/LOCATION signed/O deals/O worth/O $/O 46/O billion/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION last/O year/O ./O 
President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON also/O inaugurated/O the/O <OTHER>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> designed/O to/O create/O a/O network/O of/O roads/O ,/O railways/O and/O pipelines/O linking/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O west/O to/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION through/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Chinese/O mining/O company/O MCC/ORGANIZATION is/O in/O charge/O of/O exploiting/O the/O copper/O mine/O in/O Mes/LOCATION Aynak/LOCATION 
China/LOCATION has/O also/O signed/O multibillion/O dollar/O deals/O with/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O some/O of/O which/O involve/O the/O extraction/O of/O copper/O from/O the/O Mes/O Aynak/O mine/O in/O Logar/LOCATION Province/LOCATION -/O believed/O to/O be/O worth/O $/O 10/O billion/O ./O 
State-owned/O company/O China/ORGANIZATION Metallurgical/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION Corporation/ORGANIZATION acquired/O the/O extraction/O rights/O of/O the/O mine/O in/O 2007/O for/O $/O 3.5/O billion/O -LRB-/O 2.6/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O ,/O but/O the/O project/O has/O never/O actually/O kicked/O off/O given/O the/O deteriorating/O security/O situation/O and/O poor/O infrastructure/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
According/O to/O Afghan/O experts/O ,/O Chinese/O officials/O are/O striving/O to/O keep/O the/O situation/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION under/O control/O so/O Beijing/LOCATION can/O implement/O its/O economic/O projects/O and/O protect/O its/O investments/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION 's/O primary/O goal/O for/O its/O increased/O involvement/O in/O the/O Afghan/O peace/O process/O is/O to/O secure/O its/O economic/O interests/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O ''/O Zaland/PERSON said/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Zhu/PERSON Yongbiao/PERSON ,/O an/O associate/O professor/O at/O the/O Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION Asian/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION <OTHER>of/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Lanzhou/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O disagrees/O ./O 
He/O says/O China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O ,/O security/O and/O geopolitical/O interests/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION are/O overstated/O by/O Western/O and/O Chinese/O media/O ,/O and/O hence/O calls/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O ``/O keep/O its/O distance/O from/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O security-related/O issues/O ./O ''/O 
``/O In/O the/O recent/O years/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O interests/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION have/O been/O exaggerated/O ,/O thus/O making/O Chinese/O officials/O overestimate/O the/O impact/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O situation/O on/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Yongbiao/PERSON said/O ./O 
Additional/O reporting/O by/O Fang/PERSON Wan/PERSON ./O
