He/O was/O convicted/O for/O writing/O articles/O critical/O of/O the/O government/O online/O on/O issues/O like/O human/O and/O Uighur/O rights/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
He/O was/O denied/O the/O right/O to/O appoint/O a/O lawyer/O and/O was/O tried/O in/O camera/O ./O 
Some/O of/O Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O other/O children/O are/O also/O facing/O charges/O ./O 
She/O is/O in/O exile/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O 
A/O court/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O sentenced/O <U_PERSON>Ablikim/PERSON Abdiriyim/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O son/O of/O exiled/O Uighur/O activist/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O for/O nine/O years/O yesterday/O ,/O for/O instigating/O and/O engaging/O in/O secessionist/O activities/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/O</U_PERSON> said/O charges/O against/O her/O son/O were/O false/O and/O that/O he/O was/O tried/O without/O legal/O assistance/O ./O 
The/O court/O convicted/O <U_PERSON>Abdureyim/PERSON</U_PERSON> of/O spreading/O secessionist/O articles/O over/O the/O internet/O ,/O instigating/O the/O public/O against/O the/O government/O and/O writing/O articles/O that/O distorted/O China/LOCATION 's/O human/O rights/O and/O ethnic/O policies/O ./O 
Under/O Chinese/O law/O ,/O he/O will/O also/O be/O denied/O political/O rights/O for/O three/O years/O ,/O rights/O which/O include/O free/O speech/O and/O the/O ability/O to/O gather/O or/O protest/O ./O 
Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION reported/O last/O month/O that/O <U_PERSON>Ablikim/PERSON</U_PERSON> was/O ill/O from/O beatings/O suffered/O in/O detention/O and/O was/O being/O denied/O access/O to/O medical/O treatment/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O Muslim/O ethnic/O Uighur/O and/O a/O prominent/O businesswoman/O ,/O fell/O from/O grace/O for/O criticising/O the/O communist/O government/O 's/O treatment/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xingjian/O</U_LOCATION> 's/O Uighur/O community/O ./O 
Arrested/O in/O 1999/O on/O her/O way/O to/O meet/O US/LOCATION congressmen/O ,/O she/O was/O eventually/O released/O and/O allowed/O to/O leave/O for/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION in/O 2005/O where/O she/O now/O heads/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Uighur/ORGANIZATION American/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ``/O They/O would/O not/O appoint/O a/O lawyer/O for/O him/O and/O did/O n't/O give/O him/O an/O opportunity/O to/O defend/O himself/O ,/O and/O they/O held/O the/O hearing/O in/O secret/O ,/O ''/O Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> told/O the/O Washington/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Another/O son/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON Abdureyim/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O was/O sentenced/O to/O seven/O years/O in/O prison/O in/O September/O of/O last/O year/O on/O tax/O evasion/O charges/O ./O 
And/O another/O son/O was/O convicted/O of/O tax/O evasion/O but/O spared/O a/O jail/O term/O whilst/O a/O daughter/O has/O been/O placed/O under/O house/O arrest/O ./O
