Rescue/O workers/O are/O still/O trying/O to/O find/O survivors/O in/O the/O village/O of/O Nura/LOCATION on/O the/O border/O between/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION ,/O destroyed/O by/O a/O 6.6-mangitude/O quake/O that/O hit/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION yesterday/O ./O 
The/O quake/O was/O felt/O in/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ,/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION ,/O where/O minor/O damage/O was/O reported/O ./O 
Bishkek/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O 
A/O major/O earthquake/O has/O hit/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O killing/O more/O than/O 60/O people/O ./O 
The/O 6.6-magnitude/O quake/O struck/O at/O 21.52/O local/O time/O -LRB-/O 15.52/O GMT/O -RRB-/O ,/O on/O Sunday/O ./O 
Hardest/O hit/O was/O the/O southern/O province/O of/O Osh/LOCATION ,/O on/O the/O border/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION 's/O Emergency/ORGANIZATION Situations/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION said/O rescue/O workers/O were/O still/O searching/O for/O survivors/O ./O 
In/O the/O meantime/O an/O assessment/O of/O the/O damage/O is/O beginning/O ./O 
Whole/O buildings/O collapsed/O and/O rescue/O teams/O are/O still/O trying/O to/O find/O survivors/O under/O the/O rubble/O ./O 
Destruction/O was/O concentrated/O in/O Nura/LOCATION ,/O a/O remote/O village/O in/O the/O mountains/O close/O to/O the/O border/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Its/O isolated/O location/O is/O hampering/O rescue/O operations/O ./O 
The/O village/O has/O been/O literally/O razed/O to/O the/O ground/O with/O 128/O houses/O destroyed/O and/O 50/O people/O wounded/O ./O 
``/O The/O picture/O we/O saw/O was/O frightening/O ./O 
The/O village/O of/O <LOCATION>Nura/PERSON</LOCATION> is/O fully/O destroyed/O ,/O 100/O per/O cent/O ,/O there/O are/O many/O injured/O ,/O ''/O Emergency/O Situations/O Minister/O Kamchybek/PERSON Tashiyev/PERSON was/O quoted/O as/O saying/O ./O 
Residents/O throughout/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION felt/O the/O quake/O ,/O including/O Tajikistan/LOCATION and/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION as/O well/O as/O China/LOCATION 's/O north-western/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> where/O officials/O reported/O minor/O damage/O to/O houses/O but/O no/O casualties/O ./O 
In/O 1966/O ,/O the/O Uzbek/O capital/O of/O Tashkent/LOCATION was/O flattened/O by/O a/O 7.5/O earthquake/O and/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O people/O were/O left/O homeless/O ./O 
A/O 6.0/O magnitude/O quake/O rocked/O Tashkent/LOCATION this/O August/O but/O there/O were/O no/O dead/O ,/O nor/O damages/O ./O
