Speaking/O in/O Geneva/LOCATION ,/O Tibet/LOCATION 's/O spiritual/O leader/O stresses/O the/O failures/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O minority/O policies/O ,/O cause/O of/O misunderstandings/O and/O street/O protests/O ./O 
He/O insists/O that/O economic/O development/O is/O not/O enough/O ;/O honesty/O and/O moral/O authority/O are/O needed/O too/O ./O 
He/O wants/O to/O give/O dialogue/O another/O chance/O ./O 
Dharamsala/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O --/O 
China/LOCATION 's/O policies/O towards/O its/O ethnic/O minorities/O ``/O failed/O to/O .../O bring/O trust/O ''/O over/O the/O last/O six/O decades/O and/O must/O change/O ,/O exiled/O Tibetan/O spiritual/O leader/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON said/O at/O a/O press/O conference/O in/O Geneva/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION ,/O he/O believes/O ,/O must/O adopt/O a/O more/O holistic/O approach/O in/O its/O bid/O to/O win/O trust/O ,/O rather/O than/O just/O trying/O to/O buy/O the/O support/O of/O minorities/O ./O 
``/O Only/O money/O will/O not/O bring/O -LSB-/O about/O the/O -RSB-/O good/O image/O of/O China/LOCATION and/O trust/O ./O 
Trust/O is/O based/O on/O transparency/O and/O honesty/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O often/O been/O accused/O of/O repressive/O policies/O towards/O its/O ethnic/O minorities/O -LRB-/O Tibetans/O and/O Uyghurs/O ,/O for/O example/O -RRB-/O ,/O going/O so/O far/O as/O trying/O to/O eliminate/O their/O traditions/O and/O language/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O always/O countered/O that/O it/O brought/O more/O opportunities/O and/O greater/O economic/O development/O to/O these/O regions/O ./O 
For/O their/O parts/O ,/O ethnic/O minorities/O have/O rejected/O such/O arguments/O ,/O saying/O that/O economic/O development/O was/O meant/O to/O favour/O millions/O of/O Han/O settlers/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O to/O the/O extent/O that/O the/O indigenous/O population/O is/O being/O reduced/O to/O minority/O status/O in/O their/O own/O land/O ./O 
Instead/O for/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ``/O moral/O authority/O is/O very/O essential/O ''/O even/O if/O China/LOCATION were/O to/O become/O an/O economic/O superpower/O ./O 
The/O Tibetan/O leader/O is/O not/O out/O to/O get/O a/O quick/O condemnation/O of/O Chinese/O repression/O ,/O but/O he/O does/O insist/O that/O ``/O General/O harmony/O is/O very/O essential/O ,/O ''/O adding/O that/O that/O it/O ``/O is/O our/O mutual/O responsibility/O to/O find/O a/O solution/O ,/O without/O separation/O ''/O ./O 
For/O Beijing/PERSON Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON remains/O a/O dangerous/O terrorist/O who/O wants/O Tibet/LOCATION 's/O secession/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Tibet/LOCATION 's/O spiritual/O leader/O has/O instead/O always/O insisted/O that/O his/O demands/O are/O limited/O to/O greater/O autonomy/O for/O his/O homeland/O ./O 
Right/O now/O the/O Chinese/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION are/O engaged/O in/O a/O systematic/O crackdown/O following/O protests/O in/O March/O 2008/O ./O 
In/O the/O spring/O of/O that/O year/O ,/O when/O many/O foreign/O leaders/O threatened/O to/O boycott/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympics/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O relented/O ,/O accepting/O to/O open/O talks/O with/O representatives/O of/O the/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> ,/O only/O to/O renege/O once/O the/O Olympic/O Games/O over/O ./O 
Since/O talks/O with/O China/LOCATION 's/O leaders/O are/O near/O to/O impossible/O ,/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON is/O intensifying/O contact/O with/O Chinese/O intellectuals/O whose/O response/O has/O been/O ``/O very/O positive/O ''/O ,/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O Basically/O ,/O things/O are/O changing/O ''/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
``/O I/O have/O faith/O that/O Chinese/O intellectuals/O ''/O and/O ``/O Chinese/O people/O -LSB-/O will/O -RSB-/O see/O things/O more/O holistically/O ,/O more/O realistically/O .../O ./O 
I/O am/O very/O optimistic/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O anti-Chinese/O resentment/O continues/O ./O 
Last/O month/O dissatisfaction/O boiled/O over/O among/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O Uyghurs/O ,/O spilling/O into/O the/O streets/O ,/O generating/O urban/O unrest/O that/O led/O to/O more/O than/O 190/O dead/O and/O thousands/O of/O injured/O ./O
