Order/O maintained/O by/O 20/O thousand/O soldiers/O ./O 
Death/O penalty/O for/O those/O who/O have/O killed/O ,/O undermining/O coexistence/O between/O Han/O and/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
Campaign/O against/O ``/O plots/O ''/O of/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O accused/O of/O terrorism/O ./O 
Turkey/LOCATION will/O bring/O the/O issue/O of/O the/O Uyghurs/O before/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O fear/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O that/O the/O ethnic/O problem/O melds/O with/O other/O situations/O of/O discontent/O and/O crises/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
The/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> seems/O quiet/O this/O morning/O ,/O after/O the/O demonstrations/O and/O violence/O of/O recent/O days/O ./O 
The/O deployment/O of/O tens/O of/O thousands/O of/O soldiers/O has/O had/O the/O effect/O of/O stopping/O clashes/O between/O Uyghurs/O and/O Han/O ,/O although/O there/O are/O sporadic/O incidents/O ./O 
The/O moment/O of/O greatest/O tension/O so/O far/O was/O July/O 7/O ,/O when/O thousands/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O attacked/O Uyghurs/O '/O houses/O and/O shops/O ,/O seeking/O their/O own/O justice/O for/O the/O violence/O suffered/O by/O other/O Han/O Chinese/O when/O the/O Uyghurs/O demonstrations/O last/O week/O ,/O degenerated/O into/O attacks/O on/O shops/O and/O the/O burning/O of/O police/O cars/O ./O 
The/O Uyghur/O population/O accuses/O the/O police/O of/O having/O fired/O on/O a/O crowd/O of/O peaceful/O demonstrators/O ,/O provoking/O their/O reaction/O ./O 
President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON arrived/O yesterday/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O leaving/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>G8/O</ORGANIZATION> summit/O in/O Italy/LOCATION ,/O because/O of/O the/O dramatic/O developments/O in/O the/O situation/O ,/O which/O could/O lead/O to/O interethnic/O clashes/O throughout/O the/O country/O ./O 
Besides/O the/O deployment/O of/O the/O military/O ,/O calm/O is/O also/O being/O maintained/O with/O threats/O ./O 
Yesterday/O ,/O Li/PERSON Zhi/PERSON ,/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> Party/ORGANIZATION secretary/O ,/O said/O he/O would/O seek/O the/O death/O penalty/O for/O rioters/O who/O resorted/O to/O ``/O cruel/O means/O ''/O and/O murdered/O people/O ,/O threatening/O the/O coexistence/O between/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/LOCATION</OTHER> and/O Han/O ./O 
The/O death/O penalty/O is/O widely/O used/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> against/O the/O so-called/O ``/O Islamic/O terrorism/O ''/O of/O the/O Uyghurs/O ,/O an/O excuse/O that/O gives/O Beijing/LOCATION an/O iron/O grip/O on/O the/O questions/O of/O autonomy/O and/O justice/O for/O the/O Uyghurs/O ,/O marginalized/O and/O persecuted/O minority/O ./O 
According/O to/O international/O organizations/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O death/O sentences/O are/O imposed/O every/O year/O against/O the/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
In/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> thousands/O of/O students/O are/O under/O house/O arrest/O to/O prevent/O their/O participation/O in/O any/O event/O ./O 
The/O soldiers/O who/O occupy/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O from/O tanks/O and/O trucks/O full/O of/O troops/O ,/O use/O megaphones/O to/O launch/O a/O call/O to/O coexistence/O between/O ethnic/O groups/O ./O 
Even/O on/O TV/O there/O are/O images/O invoking/O friendship/O between/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/LOCATION</OTHER> and/O Han/O are/O being/O broadcast/O ./O 
Yu/PERSON Zhengsheng/PERSON ,/O secretary/O of/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Shanghai/LOCATION and/O the/O city/O mayor/O ,/O Han/PERSON Zheng/PERSON ,/O were/O shown/O on/O television/O while/O visiting/O a/O Uyghur/O restaurant/O ,/O chatting/O with/O the/O owner/O and/O preaching/O on/O ``/O stability/O and/O harmony/O ''/O ,/O without/O which/O there/O can/O not/O be/O ``/O well-being/O ''/O or/O ``/O economic/O development/O ''/O ./O 
According/O to/O a/O scheme/O that/O closely/O echoes/O the/O suppression/O of/O Tibetan/O revolts/O last/O year/O and/O the/O charges/O against/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ,/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION government/O and/O the/O national/O media/O are/O pointing/O the/O finger/O at/O ``/O external/O forces/O ''/O and/O in/O particular/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> and/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O in/O exile/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O for/O having/O planned/O and/O instigated/O the/O demonstrations/O and/O violence/O ./O 
According/O to/O Chinese/O newspapers/O ,/O there/O is/O also/O ``/O evidence/O ''/O that/O the/O U.S./ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION funds/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> for/O his/O terrorist/O plots/O ./O 
The/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O an/O entrepreneur/O originally/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O later/O disillusioned/O in/O her/O search/O for/O greater/O autonomy/O for/O the/O Uyghurs/O ,/O was/O arrested/O in/O 2000/O for/O having/O ``/O revealed/O state/O secrets/O ./O ''/O 
In/O 2005/O she/O received/O permission/O on/O medical/O reasons/O to/O abandon/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O sought/O refuge/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Her/O family/O remained/O in/O their/O homeland/O continually/O subjected/O to/O pressure/O and/O arrests/O ./O 
The/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION have/O called/O her/O ``/O corrupt/O ''/O ,/O committed/O to/O ``/O international/O terrorism/O ''/O ,/O ``/O separatism/O ''/O and/O ``/O extremist/O forces/O ''/O ,/O eager/O to/O ``/O sabotage/O activities/O to/O mark/O 60/O years/O of/O the/O founding/O of/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION ''/O ,/O in/O October/O this/O year/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O the/O Uyghurs/O '/O cause/O is/O gaining/O worldwide/O sympathy/O ./O 
Exiled/O Uyghurs/O have/O organized/O demonstrations/O in/O front/O of/O Chinese/O embassies/O in/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O France/LOCATION and/O Australia/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Turkish/O premier/O Erodgan/PERSON said/O yesterday/O that/O he/O intends/O to/O present/O the/O problem/O of/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/LOCATION</OTHER> in/O China/LOCATION before/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Turks/O and/O Uyghurs/O have/O historical/O as/O well/O as/O ethnic/O and/O linguistic/O ties/O ./O 
The/O tension/O that/O began/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> worries/O China/LOCATION ./O 
There/O is/O only/O the/O ethnic/O issue/O hanging/O in/O the/O balance/O ,/O but/O also/O the/O discontent/O of/O many/O groups/O of/O the/O Chinese/O population/O because/O of/O corruption/O ,/O economic/O crisis/O and/O repression/O of/O dissent/O ./O 
The/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> spark/O could/O inflame/O other/O crisis/O situations/O around/O the/O country/O ./O 
``/O In/O the/O context/O of/O China/LOCATION -/O said/O Calla/PERSON Weimer/PERSON ,/O academic/O in/O Singapore/LOCATION -/O ,/O when/O there/O are/O n't/O avenues/O for/O the/O expression/O of/O grievances/O and/O repression/O ,/O it/O all/O just/O simmers/O ready/O to/O explode/O ''/O ./O
