<U_PERSON>Dolkun/PERSON Isa/PERSON</U_PERSON> is/O the/O secretary-general/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> and/O a/O German/O citizen/O ./O 
He/O was/O held/O at/O the/O Seoul/LOCATION airport/O for/O 57/O hours/O and/O then/O sent/O back/O to/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
Seoul/LOCATION is/O giving/O in/O to/O Chinese/O pressure/O ./O 
For/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O he/O is/O a/O dangerous/O terrorist/O ./O 
Seoul/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O --/O 
The/O South/O Korean/O government/O is/O complying/O with/O Chinese/O requests/O at/O the/O expense/O of/O human/O rights/O ,/O South/O Korean/O daily/O <ORGANIZATION>Chosun/O Ilbo/O</ORGANIZATION> warned/O as/O it/O reported/O the/O unjustified/O detention/O of/O <U_PERSON>Dolkun/PERSON Isa/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O German/O citizen/O who/O is/O also/O secretary/O general/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O pictured/O -RRB-/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Isa/PERSON</U_PERSON> was/O held/O at/O the/O Seoul/LOCATION airport/O for/O 57/O hours/O and/O was/O never/O told/O why/O ./O 
Eventually/O ,/O he/O was/O sent/O back/O to/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
<U_PERSON>Isa/PERSON</U_PERSON> is/O on/O China/LOCATION 's/O ten/O most-wanted/O list/O ./O 
He/O is/O accused/O of/O being/O a/O troublemaker/O and/O of/O organising/O attacks/O against/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O the/O northwestern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
``/O Of/O course/O South/O Korean/O authorities/O never/O told/O me/O exactly/O very/O openly/O ,/O `/O Because/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O pressure/O we/O arrested/O you/O or/O we/O do/O n't/O let/O you/O in/O to/O South/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION ./O '/O 
They/O never/O told/O me/O that/O line/O ./O 
But/O actually/O it/O is/O the/O reason/O ,/O ''/O <U_PERSON>Isa/PERSON</U_PERSON> said/O on/O his/O return/O to/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
He/O had/O travelled/O to/O South/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION to/O attend/O a/O conference/O on/O democracy/O ./O 
South/O Korean/O authorities/O have/O not/O said/O anything/O about/O the/O incident/O ,/O but/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokeswoman/O Jiang/PERSON Yu/PERSON said/O that/O the/O two/O governments/O have/O had/O contacts/O over/O the/O Uyghur/O dissident/O ./O 
She/O said/O <U_PERSON>Isa/PERSON</U_PERSON> is/O a/O major/O leader/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ./O 
For/O some/O analysts/O ,/O South/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION 's/O decision/O to/O give/O in/O to/O Chinese/O pressure/O marks/O a/O turning/O point/O in/O Seoul/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O policy/O ./O 
After/O decades/O of/O harsh/O military/O dictatorship/O ,/O South/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION developed/O into/O a/O Western-styled/O democracy/O in/O the/O last/O two/O decades/O ,/O based/O on/O respect/O for/O human/O and/O civil/O rights/O ./O 
Hundreds/O of/O political/O refugees/O from/O China/LOCATION and/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION were/O welcomed/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O current/O economic/O downturn/O has/O changed/O the/O game/O ./O 
As/O a/O major/O carmaker/O ,/O South/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION needs/O access/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O vast/O domestic/O market/O to/O sell/O its/O vehicles/O and/O maintain/O a/O strong/O GDP/O ./O 
China/LOCATION ,/O which/O has/O survived/O almost/O without/O a/O scratch/O the/O plunge/O of/O financial/O markets/O ,/O is/O flexing/O its/O muscles/O to/O get/O its/O way/O on/O a/O number/O of/O very/O sensitive/O issues/O ./O
