7/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O the/O blast/O and/O another/O 14/O were/O injured/O ./O 
Of/O the/O two/O suspects/O ,/O one/O apparently/O died/O in/O the/O blast/O ./O 
Motive/O for/O attack/O still/O unknown/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
Authorities/O in/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> have/O identified/O two/O suspects/O in/O the/O bombing/O that/O yesterday/O hit/O <U_LOCATION>Aksu/PERSON</U_LOCATION> ,/O a/O <OTHER>Northern/LOCATION</OTHER> province/O ./O 
Two/O people/O ,/O a/O man/O and/O a/O woman/O ,/O were/O identified/O although/O the/O second/O seems/O to/O have/O died/O in/O the/O blast/O ,/O which/O caused/O seven/O deaths/O and/O 14/O wounded/O ./O 
Regional/O government/O spokesman/O Hou/PERSON Hanmin/PERSON ,/O stated/O the/O male/O author/O of/O the/O attack/O ,/O who/O belongs/O to/O the/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O ,/O has/O been/O arrested/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O spokesman/O ,/O the/O man/O threw/O a/O three-wheeled/O bicycle/O packed/O with/O explosives/O at/O a/O group/O of/O people/O in/O a/O street/O in/O the/O suburb/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Aksu/PERSON</U_LOCATION> ,/O 50/O meters/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Duolang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> bridge/O ./O 
Hou/PERSON said/O that/O it/O is/O unclear/O if/O the/O attack/O is/O linked/O to/O ethnic/O tensions/O ,/O but/O added/O that/O most/O of/O the/O victims/O were/O Uyghurs/O or/O from/O other/O minorities/O ./O 
Witnesses/O report/O that/O several/O policemen/O were/O wounded/O in/O their/O attempt/O to/O stop/O the/O man/O ./O 
The/O police/O also/O closed/O the/O area/O and/O the/O city/O centre/O ,/O inspecting/O the/O bags/O of/O all/O passersby/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Hou/PERSON denies/O that/O martial/O law/O is/O in/O force/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O home/O to/O a/O minority/O of/O eight/O million/O Uyghurs/O out/O of/O a/O population/O of/O 20/O million/O people/O ./O 
Last/O year/O the/O region/O was/O the/O scene/O of/O violence/O between/O Uyghurs/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O which/O caused/O the/O deaths/O of/O at/O least/O 200/O people/O ./O
