The/O incident/O in/O which/O 15/O police/O officers/O and/O 6/O civilians/O were/O killed/O remains/O unexplained/O ./O 
For/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O it/O was/O a/O ``/O cowardly/O terrorist/O attack/O ''/O ./O 
Exiled/O Uighur/O groups/O deny/O the/O allegations/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
Clashes/O between/O Uighur/O civilians/O and/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O police/O broke/O out/O in/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O leaving/O at/O least/O 21/O people/O dead/O ./O 
According/O to/O local/O sources/O ,/O the/O violence/O broke/O out/O last/O night/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Selibuya/LOCATION Township/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O near/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O areas/O of/O the/O province/O inhabited/O mostly/O by/O ethnic/O Uighur/O ,/O a/O predominantly/O Turkic/O and/O Muslim/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O claim/O that/O the/O six/O civilians/O who/O died/O in/O the/O incident/O were/O suspected/O terrorists/O ,/O but/O groups/O associated/O with/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O Uighur/O leader/O living/O in/O exile/O in/O Germany/LOCATION for/O the/O past/O three/O years/O for/O her/O pro-independence/O activities/O ,/O deny/O that/O claim/O ./O 
Indeed/O ,/O it/O is/O still/O unclear/O what/O actually/O happened/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O <ORGANIZATION>Communist/O China/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> 's/O official/O news/O agency/O ,/O the/O incidents/O broke/O out/O in/O the/O afternoon/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O about/O 1,200/O km/O from/O the/O capital/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O when/O three/O community/O workers/O saw/O suspected/O terrorists/O armed/O with/O knives/O ,/O hiding/O in/O the/O house/O of/O a/O local/O resident/O ./O 
The/O workers/O warned/O their/O superiors/O but/O were/O captured/O by/O the/O suspects/O ./O 
When/O police/O arrived/O ,/O they/O were/O attacked/O by/O the/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O ,/O who/O killed/O the/O three/O community/O workers/O they/O held/O and/O set/O fire/O the/O house/O where/O they/O had/O corned/O the/O police/O ./O 
Eight/O suspected/O terrorists/O were/O arrested/O ./O 
The/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> has/O long/O been/O the/O scene/O of/O clashes/O and/O ethnic/O tensions/O ./O 
In/O 2009/O ,/O it/O was/O placed/O under/O special/O rule/O by/O China/LOCATION 's/O police/O and/O army/O ,/O following/O riots/O that/O had/O left/O nearly/O 200/O people/O dead/O ./O 
After/O the/O bloody/O incident/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O people/O were/O convicted/O and/O sent/O to/O prison/O ;/O some/O people/O were/O given/O the/O death/O penalty/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O claim/O that/O the/O perpetrators/O of/O violence/O are/O Muslim/O extremists/O ,/O but/O Uighur/O exiles/O counter/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O exaggerated/O the/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O in/O order/O to/O justify/O its/O crackdown/O against/O the/O Uighur/O ./O
