At/O a/O meeting/O of/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Front/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O Chinese/O president/O reiterated/O the/O leadership/O role/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O religious/O matters/O ,/O warning/O against/O foreign/O forces/O ./O 
His/O targets/O include/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/PERSON</U_LOCATION> <OTHER>Muslims/PERSON</OTHER> ,/O Tibetan/O Buddhists/O and/O the/O Vatican/LOCATION ./O 
For/O a/O <OTHER>Chinese/ORGANIZATION Catholic/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ,/O doing/O so/O would/O distort/O the/O Catholic/O religion/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O 
Religions/O in/O China/LOCATION must/O be/O ``/O Chinese/O ''/O and/O free/O from/O any/O ``/O foreign/O influence/O ''/O ./O 
They/O must/O integrate/O into/O China/LOCATION 's/O ``/O socialist/O society/O ''/O and/O ,/O under/O the/O leadership/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O they/O must/O serve/O the/O nation/O 's/O development/O ,/O said/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON in/O a/O speech/O he/O delivered/O before/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Front/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O ended/O a/O three-day/O meeting/O yesterday/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>The/O</ORGANIZATION> United/ORGANIZATION Front/ORGANIZATION is/O an/O organisation/O that/O includes/O all/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O small/O but/O legally/O permitted/O political/O parties/O ,/O the/O All-China/ORGANIZATION Federation/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Industry/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Commerce/ORGANIZATION as/O well/O as/O associations/O representing/O various/O ethnic/O groups/O and/O religions/O ./O 
For/O analysts/O ,/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Front/ORGANIZATION represents/O the/O empty/O shell/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O democracy/O ,/O upholding/O the/O hegemony/O of/O the/O de/O facto/O single-party/O state/O ./O 
It/O has/O no/O real/O power/O and/O comes/O under/O the/O authority/O of/O the/O Central/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O CPC/ORGANIZATION ./O 
At/O the/O meeting/O held/O in/O the/O capital/O ,/O Xi/PERSON stressed/O the/O importance/O of/O maintaining/O the/O party/O 's/O leadership/O ./O 
Cooperation/O with/O smaller/O parties/O and/O political/O action/O should/O be/O led/O by/O the/O CPC/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Authorities/O must/O value/O the/O influence/O of/O people/O in/O the/O religious/O sphere/O and/O guide/O them/O to/O serve/O better/O the/O nation/O 's/O development/O ,/O harmony/O and/O unification/O ,/O Xi/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O Active/O efforts/O should/O be/O made/O to/O incorporate/O religions/O into/O socialist/O society/O ,/O ''/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> added/O ,/O noting/O that/O religions/O in/O China/LOCATION must/O be/O Chinese/O ,/O and/O the/O development/O of/O religions/O in/O China/LOCATION should/O be/O independent/O of/O foreign/O influence/O ./O 
<PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> '/O views/O are/O nothing/O new/O ,/O reflecting/O what/O other/O Chinese/O leaders/O have/O said/O before/O on/O many/O occasions/O ./O 
For/O example/O ,/O when/O he/O was/O general/O secretary/O of/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O 1990s/O ,/O Jiang/PERSON Zemin/PERSON expressed/O appreciation/O for/O the/O contribution/O of/O religions/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O socialist/O society/O ,/O but/O warned/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION against/O Western/O ``/O ideological/O pollution/O ''/O ,/O which/O included/O in/O Christianity/O ,/O seen/O as/O a/O western/O religion/O ./O 
A/O typical/O Maoist/O slogan/O ,/O that/O still/O resonates/O today/O ,/O underscores/O the/O alleged/O danger/O represented/O by/O religious/O groups/O whose/O action/O is/O designed/O to/O undermine/O China/LOCATION -LRB-/O or/O rather/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O Communist/O regime/O -RRB-/O ``/O under/O the/O cloak/O of/O religion/O ./O ''/O 
Even/O the/O Vatican/LOCATION ,/O described/O by/O Mao/PERSON as/O ``/O the/O running/O dog/O of/O capitalism/O ''/O ,/O is/O still/O seen/O as/O a/O foreign/O power/O that/O under/O the/O cloak/O of/O religion/O seeks/O to/O manipulate/O China/LOCATION 's/O internal/O affairs/O ./O 
Conspiracy/O theories/O tend/O to/O focus/O primarily/O on/O Muslims/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O Tibetan/O Buddhists/O who/O ,/O according/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O are/O incited/O by/O Islamic/O fundamentalist/O preachers/O and/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ./O 
However/O ,/O such/O theories/O have/O not/O spared/O Catholics/O ./O 
The/O papal/O mandate/O on/O episcopal/O appointments/O is/O deemed/O as/O ``/O interference/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O internal/O affairs/O ;/O ''/O hence/O ,/O the/O emphasis/O on/O ``/O localisation/O ''/O and/O ``/O sinicisation/O ''/O of/O every/O religion/O ./O 
However/O ,/O ``/O In/O this/O case/O ,/O sinicising/O means/O changing/O the/O nature/O of/O our/O religion/O ,/O whose/O spiritual/O unity/O is/O centred/O on/O the/O pope/O ,/O ''/O a/O <OTHER>Chinese/ORGANIZATION Catholic/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> said/O ./O 
Recently/O ,/O the/O Vatican/LOCATION and/O <OTHER>Pope/PERSON</OTHER> Francis/PERSON have/O signalled/O a/O desire/O for/O détente/O and/O friendship/O toward/O China/LOCATION ./O 
This/O has/O generated/O hope/O for/O diplomatic/O talks/O ,/O and/O created/O great/O optimism/O about/O a/O positive/O response/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ./O 
Yet/O ,/O based/O on/O what/O the/O Chinese/O president/O said/O recently/O ,/O there/O is/O little/O hope/O for/O an/O opening/O anytime/O soon/O ./O
