Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O President/O Pervez/PERSON Musharraf/PERSON has/O left/O for/O China/LOCATION on/O a/O five/O day/O official/O visit/O ./O
The/O trip/O ,/O at/O the/O invitation/O of/O Chinese/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ,/O aims/O at/O further/O strengthening/O ties/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION and/O Islamabad/LOCATION share/O decades-old/O friendship/O and/O co-operate/O in/O various/O fields/O ranging/O from/O trade/O to/O defence/O ./O
This/O is/O the/O first/O overseas/O visit/O of/O President/O Musharraf/PERSON after/O the/O newly/O formed/O coalition/O government/O took/O over/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
He/O is/O accompanied/O by/O his/O Foreign/O Minister/O Shah/PERSON Mahmood/PERSON Qureshi/PERSON and/O Defence/O Minister/O Chaudhry/PERSON Ahmed/PERSON Mukhtar/PERSON ,/O as/O well/O as/O chairman/O of/O Trade/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Authority/ORGANIZATION of/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O other/O top/O officials/O ./O
The/O five/O day/O visit/O will/O include/O discussions/O between/O Musharraf/PERSON and/O his/O Chinese/O counterpart/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON on/O various/O regional/O and/O global/O issues/O ,/O especially/O nuclear/O cooperation/O ./O
China/LOCATION has/O helped/O Pakistan/LOCATION build/O its/O civil/O nuclear/O plants/O and/O Pakistan/LOCATION clearly/O wants/O to/O enhance/O this/O partnership/O ./O
The/O two/O countries/O are/O also/O expected/O to/O sign/O a/O number/O of/O agreements/O on/O further/O economic/O cooperation/O ./O
Minam/PERSON Jaffrey/PERSON is/O the/O secretary/O of/O the/O Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION in/O Karachi/LOCATION ./O
He/O explains/O the/O significance/O of/O the/O visit/O :/O ``/O China/LOCATION is/O deeply/O involved/O in/O various/O projects/O including/O the/O energy/O corridor/O ./O
Right/O now/O we/O have/O financial/O crisis/O and/O China/LOCATION has/O recently/O supported/O with/O 500/O million/O dollars/O in/O funding/O ./O
So/O President/O Musharraf/PERSON is/O there/O to/O ensure/O the/O continuation/O of/O the/O support/O and/O aid/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O
And/O this/O visit/O also/O reflects/O the/O continuation/O of/O our/O old/O relationship/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O
Defence/O co-operation/O
China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION regard/O themselves/O as/O old/O friends/O ./O
China/LOCATION is/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O major/O arms/O supplier/O ./O
The/O Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Air/ORGANIZATION Force/ORGANIZATION 's/O latest/O fighter/O aircraft/O ,/O the/O JF-17/O Thunder/O has/O been/O developed/O with/O the/O help/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O
Earlier/O this/O week/O ,/O a/O Shanghai/LOCATION shipyard/O inaugurated/O the/O first/O of/O four/O F-22P/O frigates/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O building/O for/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
The/O project/O is/O due/O to/O be/O completed/O by/O 2013/O ./O
Bilateral/O trade/O between/O the/O two/O sides/O have/O also/O flourished/O in/O recent/O years/O and/O both/O sides/O hope/O to/O achieve/O the/O trade/O target/O of/O $/O 15/O billion/O within/O the/O next/O five/O years/O ./O
The/O current/O trip/O will/O take/O Musharraf/PERSON to/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O an/O area/O bordering/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O northern/O areas/O ./O
Islamabad/LOCATION is/O particularly/O keen/O to/O attract/O direct/O investment/O from/O this/O region/O ./O
Musharraf/PERSON is/O also/O expected/O to/O address/O the/O region/O 's/O huge/O Muslim/O population/O ,/O urging/O them/O to/O shun/O their/O agitation/O against/O China/LOCATION ./O
The/O Uighurs/O living/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION have/O been/O calling/O for/O an/O independent/O state/O ./O
`/O Time-tested/O '/O friendship/O
President/O Musharraf/PERSON 's/O visit/O also/O comes/O at/O a/O time/O ,/O when/O relations/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION have/O also/O been/O warming/O up/O ,/O sparking/O fears/O that/O they/O can/O have/O an/O effect/O on/O the/O ties/O between/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O
However/O Islamabad/LOCATION insists/O its/O ties/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION are/O `/O all/O weather/O -/O and/O time-tested/O '/O and/O can/O not/O be/O affected/O by/O any/O other/O country/O ./O
Expert/O Minam/PERSON Jaffrey/PERSON agrees/O :/O ``/O China/LOCATION has/O made/O it/O clear/O many/O times/O that/O its/O ties/O with/O India/LOCATION are/O not/O at/O the/O cost/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
Pakistan/LOCATION has/O a/O very/O special/O relationship/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O
And/O there/O are/O certain/O strategic/O areas/O where/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O involved/O with/O China/LOCATION ,/O but/O India/LOCATION does/O n't/O come/O in/O ./O
``/O During/O his/O stay/O ,/O Musharraf/PERSON will/O also/O attend/O the/O Boao/ORGANIZATION Forum/ORGANIZATION -/O a/O regional/O meeting/O initiated/O by/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O starts/O from/O Friday/O ./O
The/O four/O day/O meeting/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O southernmost/O province/O of/O Hainan/LOCATION will/O bring/O together/O the/O state/O leaders/O ,/O businessmen/O and/O prominent/O personalities/O from/O Australia/LOCATION and/O Asia/LOCATION ./O
President/O Musharraf/PERSON will/O also/O be/O a/O keynote/O speaker/O at/O the/O Forum/ORGANIZATION and/O is/O due/O to/O meet/O several/O leaders/O ,/O including/O the/O president/O of/O Sri/LOCATION Lanka/LOCATION and/O prime/O ministers/O of/O Australia/LOCATION and/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION during/O the/O conference/O ./O
