On/O Monday/O ,/O a/O Chinese/O delegation/O stood/O before/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION in/O Geneva/LOCATION for/O a/O review/O of/O its/O human/O rights/O situation/O ./O
At/O the/O meeting/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION denied/O all/O accusations/O of/O torture/O ,/O death/O penalty/O or/O imprisonment/O of/O political/O opponents/O ./O
Meanwhile/O Chinese/O human/O rights/O activists/O claim/O the/O situation/O does/O not/O seem/O to/O show/O any/O signs/O of/O improvement/O ./O
Outside/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION building/O in/O Geneva/LOCATION ,/O hundreds/O of/O exiled/O Tibetans/O shouted/O protests/O against/O the/O torture/O and/O human/O rights/O violations/O inflicted/O by/O Chinese/O authorities/O in/O their/O homeland/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O
Just/O a/O short/O distance/O away/O ,/O within/O the/O protected/O walls/O of/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION building/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O ambassador/O to/O Geneva/LOCATION Li/PERSON Baodong/PERSON maintained/O there/O had/O been/O no/O torture/O ,/O since/O torture/O was/O prohibited/O by/O law/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
The/O Chinese/O ambassador/O was/O speaking/O before/O the/O Universal/O Periodic/O Review/O ,/O a/O process/O recently/O launched/O by/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O under/O which/O all/O UN/ORGANIZATION member/O nations/O are/O expected/O to/O submit/O themselves/O to/O scrutiny/O of/O their/O human/O rights/O records/O ./O
At/O the/O review/O ,/O China/LOCATION came/O under/O fire/O from/O Western/O countries/O for/O alleged/O torture/O ,/O death/O penalties/O and/O imprisonment/O of/O political/O opponents/O ./O
Other/O issues/O brought/O up/O were/O the/O improper/O treatment/O of/O minorities/O like/O the/O Muslim/O Uighur/O community/O and/O the/O suppression/O of/O Tibetan/O protestors/O ./O
Rights/O violations/O still/O rampant/O in/O China/LOCATION
Beijing/LOCATION rejected/O all/O the/O claims/O ,/O saying/O it/O was/O just/O an/O attempt/O to/O destroy/O China/LOCATION 's/O image/O through/O political/O propaganda/O ./O
Yet/O human/O rights/O activist/O Tienchi/PERSON Martin-Liao/PERSON from/O the/O US-based/O Laogai/ORGANIZATION Research/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION said/O that/O many/O inhuman/O practices/O were/O still/O in/O force/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O like/O the/O Laogai/O system/O of/O labour/O camps/O for/O prisoners/O ,/O or/O the/O Laojiao/O system/O ./O
``/O Laojiao/O means/O the/O authority/O ,/O security/O or/O police/O can/O put/O everyone/O ,/O every/O single/O citizen/O into/O jail/O for/O 3-4/O years/O without/O any/O legal/O process/O ./O
This/O is/O actually/O not/O a/O part/O of/O the/O legal/O system/O ,/O it/O is/O an/O administrative/O measure/O ,/O ''/O says/O Liao/PERSON ./O
China/LOCATION also/O had/O a/O few/O supporters/O at/O the/O Universal/ORGANIZATION Periodic/ORGANIZATION Review/ORGANIZATION ,/O among/O them/O countries/O like/O Sudan/LOCATION ,/O Sri/LOCATION Lanka/LOCATION ,/O Vietnam/LOCATION and/O Myanmar/LOCATION ,/O themselves/O under/O criticism/O for/O their/O human/O rights/O records/O ./O
Chinese/O delegation/O members/O from/O various/O government/O ministries/O declared/O that/O the/O people/O of/O China/LOCATION enjoyed/O free/O speech/O and/O that/O the/O country/O lived/O in/O peace/O and/O harmony/O ./O
No/O improvement/O possible/O without/O transparency/O
Yet/O the/O situation/O on/O the/O ground/O seems/O to/O be/O far/O from/O peaceful/O ./O
Rights/O activists/O say/O that/O many/O lawyers/O are/O becoming/O bolder/O and/O are/O speaking/O out/O against/O the/O injustice/O ./O
But/O still/O ,/O many/O of/O these/O lawyers/O are/O also/O being/O put/O into/O prison/O ,/O says/O Liao/PERSON ./O
Liao/PERSON says/O that/O China/LOCATION will/O crack/O down/O hard/O on/O the/O freedom/O of/O the/O people/O ,/O if/O it/O feels/O insecure/O about/O controlling/O the/O situation/O in/O the/O country/O ./O
``/O But/O I/O am/O afraid/O that/O this/O year/O has/O been/O very/O hard/O for/O China/LOCATION ./O
The/O economic/O crisis/O has/O hit/O China/LOCATION very/O hard/O ,/O and/O millions/O of/O workers/O have/O lost/O their/O jobs/O ./O
And/O this/O will/O challenge/O the/O government/O ./O
I/O do/O n't/O think/O there/O will/O be/O any/O improvement/O in/O the/O human/O rights/O this/O year/O ,/O ''/O says/O Liao/PERSON ./O
The/O human/O rights/O activists/O argue/O that/O as/O long/O there/O is/O information/O control/O and/O lack/O of/O transparency/O on/O the/O part/O of/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O ,/O there/O is/O little/O that/O can/O be/O done/O to/O improve/O the/O human/O rights/O situation/O ./O
