After/O Bollywood/O and/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION is/O the/O third/O biggest/O movie/O producer/O in/O the/O world/O ./O
Despite/O problems/O with/O copyright/O infringement/O ,/O it/O is/O also/O fast/O emerging/O as/O one/O of/O the/O biggest/O markets/O for/O the/O industry/O ./O
World/O famous/O directors/O such/O as/O Zhang/PERSON Yimou/PERSON have/O contributed/O greatly/O to/O the/O revival/O of/O Chinese/O film/O with/O successes/O at/O major/O international/O festivals/O ./O
At/O this/O year/O 's/O Chinese/O Film/O Festival/O in/O Cologne/LOCATION ,/O it/O was/O the/O turn/O of/O other/O talented/O Chinese/O filmmakers/O to/O try/O to/O make/O a/O name/O for/O themselves/O ./O
The/O Chinese/O movie/O industry/O is/O growing/O steadily/O ./O
More/O than/O 500/O films/O are/O produced/O each/O year/O --/O mainly/O in/O Shanghai/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
Cologne/LOCATION 's/O Filmhaus/ORGANIZATION chose/O the/O title/O ``/O Visions/O of/O China/LOCATION ''/O for/O its/O third/O Chinese/O film/O festival/O ./O
The/O annual/O festival/O offers/O young/O Chinese/O directors/O to/O show/O their/O work/O to/O a/O wide/O audience/O ./O
17/O full-length/O films/O as/O well/O as/O several/O short/O films/O are/O being/O shown/O this/O year/O ./O
The/O organisers/O have/O focused/O on/O works/O that/O deal/O with/O ethnic/O minorities/O with/O ,/O for/O example/O ,/O films/O about/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION and/O the/O Muslim/O area/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
``/O We/O did/O not/O get/O a/O general/O overview/O of/O Chinese/O cinema/O but/O only/O saw/O a/O small/O selection/O of/O the/O films/O that/O are/O produced/O there/O ,/O ''/O said/O Dirk/PERSON Werner/PERSON ,/O one/O of/O the/O festival/O 's/O curators/O ./O
``/O Then/O ,/O we/O made/O a/O further/O selection/O and/O we/O decided/O to/O show/O films/O from/O different/O parts/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O
We/O also/O decided/O to/O show/O films/O from/O remote/O provinces/O ./O ''/O
Rapid/O developments/O over/O the/O past/O few/O years/O Chinese/O cinema/O has/O developed/O rapidly/O in/O the/O past/O few/O years/O and/O more/O and/O more/O films/O have/O found/O their/O way/O to/O international/O film/O festivals/O ,/O where/O they/O are/O proving/O to/O be/O very/O popular/O and/O receiving/O good/O reviews/O ./O
They/O also/O have/O a/O huge/O amount/O of/O fans/O ./O
Zheng/PERSON Yi/PERSON ,/O a/O 28-year-old/O director/O in/O Cologne/LOCATION to/O show/O his/O films/O ,/O does/O not/O think/O the/O new/O developments/O are/O only/O positive/O :/O ``/O I/O think/O that/O in/O recent/O years/O Chinese/O movies/O have/O become/O more/O and/O more/O commercial/O ./O
There/O is/O no/O filmmaking/O without/O money/O ./O
It/O is/O not/O like/O drawing/O ,/O where/O all/O you/O need/O is/O a/O pencil/O and/O some/O paper/O ./O
The/O movie/O business/O has/O changed/O as/O China/LOCATION has/O developed/O economically/O ./O
Many/O see/O movies/O as/O an/O investment/O ./O ''/O
Zheng/PERSON Yi/PERSON did/O acknowledge/O ,/O however/O ,/O that/O the/O developments/O also/O mean/O that/O more/O directors/O can/O make/O films/O as/O there/O are/O more/O and/O more/O film/O studios/O and/O production/O companies/O ./O
No/O commercial/O films/O in/O Cologne/LOCATION
There/O are/O no/O commercial/O films/O to/O be/O seen/O at/O Cologne/LOCATION 's/O festival/O ./O
Instead/O ,/O it/O offers/O viewers/O the/O chance/O to/O see/O films/O that/O have/O been/O censored/O by/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O and/O banned/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
``/O We/O are/O not/O toeing/O the/O party/O line/O and/O only/O showing/O what/O China/LOCATION has/O approved/O ,/O ''/O insists/O Werner/PERSON ./O
``/O We/O did/O n't/O do/O it/O last/O time/O either/O ./O
We/O want/O other/O voices/O also/O to/O have/O a/O chance/O to/O be/O heard/O ./O ''/O
Author/O :/O Chi/PERSON Viet/PERSON Giang/PERSON
Editor/O :/O Anne/PERSON Thomas/PERSON
