Munich/LOCATION 's/O municipal/O council/O is/O backing/O a/O motion/O submitted/O by/O the/O Green/ORGANIZATION party/O to/O host/O 17/O members/O of/O the/O Chinese/O minority/O held/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ./O
The/O controversial/O offer/O still/O has/O to/O be/O approved/O by/O the/O Chancellor/O ./O
The/O Bavarian/O city/O has/O the/O largest/O population/O of/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O outside/O of/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O motion/O now/O must/O gain/O approval/O from/O German/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON 's/O cross-party/O government/O before/O it/O can/O accept/O the/O inmates/O ./O
US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON is/O closing/O the/O prison/O that/O was/O established/O on/O Cuba/LOCATION to/O house/O terror/O suspects/O ./O
But/O several/O European/O countries/O have/O expressed/O a/O disinterest/O in/O accepting/O prisoners/O ,/O claiming/O they/O are/O the/O US/LOCATION government/O 's/O responsibility/O ./O
Some/O European/O countries/O say/O the/O inmates/O are/O the/O US/LOCATION government/O 's/O responsibility/O only/O
Gaining/O approval/O to/O accept/O the/O Uighur/O inmates/O in/O Munich/LOCATION will/O not/O be/O easy/O because/O the/O German/O government/O is/O divided/O on/O the/O issue/O of/O hosting/O Guantanamo/LOCATION inmates/O ./O
Social/O Democrat/O Foreign/O Minister/O Frank-Walter/PERSON Steinmeier/PERSON is/O in/O favor/O of/O taking/O in/O some/O freed/O prisoners/O while/O Christian/O Democrat/O Interior/O Minister/O Wolfgang/PERSON Schaueble/PERSON is/O against/O it/O ./O
The/O Uighurs/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION were/O arrested/O after/O the/O US/LOCATION invaded/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O have/O been/O imprisoned/O there/O for/O seven/O years/O ./O
Washington/LOCATION has/O cleared/O them/O of/O any/O terrorist/O activity/O ,/O but/O has/O n't/O repatriated/O them/O to/O China/LOCATION for/O fear/O they/O would/O be/O persecuted/O or/O tortured/O upon/O their/O return/O ./O
China/LOCATION outraged/O
This/O has/O angered/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O says/O the/O group/O of/O 17/O are/O part/O of/O a/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations-listed/O terror/O group/O seeking/O an/O independent/O homeland/O in/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O ./O
The/O latter/O lies/O in/O the/O northwest/O of/O China/LOCATION and/O is/O home/O to/O the/O largest/O Uighur/O population/O ./O
Uighurs/O are/O mostly/O Muslim/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION has/O demanded/O that/O the/O Uighurs/O be/O returned/O and/O it/O issued/O a/O warning/O on/O Thursday/O after/O learning/O that/O three/O of/O the/O prisoners/O have/O applied/O for/O refugee/O status/O in/O Canada/LOCATION ./O
Most/O Uighurs/O are/O Muslim/O and/O reside/O in/O northwest/O China/LOCATION
``/O We/O have/O expressed/O our/O position/O many/O times/O about/O those/O Chinese/O terrorists/O detained/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION ./O
We/O are/O opposed/O to/O any/O country/O accepting/O those/O people/O ,/O ''/O Chinese/O foreign/O ministry/O spokeswoman/O Jiang/PERSON Yu/PERSON told/O reporters/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
``/O We/O hope/O the/O parties/O concerned/O can/O resolve/O conveniently/O this/O issue/O according/O to/O the/O international/O laws/O and/O regulations/O ./O ''/O
