Now/O that/O the/O US/LOCATION request/O for/O Germany/LOCATION to/O accept/O as/O many/O as/O 17/O Uighur/O detainees/O from/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION is/O official/O ,/O reaction/O from/O across/O the/O political/O spetrum/O has/O been/O mixed/O ./O
German/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON has/O said/O that/O Germany/LOCATION has/O an/O obligation/O to/O help/O US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON in/O his/O efforts/O to/O close/O the/O American/O military/O prison/O camp/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ,/O Cuba/LOCATION ./O
But/O reservations/O about/O accepting/O former/O detainees/O have/O been/O expressed/O ,/O even/O from/O within/O her/O own/O Christian/ORGANIZATION Democratic/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION party/O ./O
Lower/LOCATION Saxony/LOCATION Interior/O Minister/O Uwe/PERSON Schuenemann/PERSON -LRB-/O CDU/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O told/O Die/ORGANIZATION Welt/ORGANIZATION newspaper/O that/O ``/O security/O must/O come/O before/O diplomacy/O ./O ''/O
Dissent/O within/O CDU/ORGANIZATION
Members/O of/O the/O CDU/ORGANIZATION 's/O Bavaria-based/O sister/O party/O ,/O the/O Christian/ORGANIZATION Social/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ,/O have/O also/O voiced/O concerns/O ./O
Senior/O CSU/ORGANIZATION politician/O Peter/PERSON Ramsauer/PERSON said/O on/O Tuesday/O in/O Berlin/LOCATION that/O Germany/LOCATION is/O neither/O politically/O nor/O legally/O bound/O to/O take/O in/O the/O prisoners/O ./O
``/O We/O are/O not/O ready/O to/O either/O help/O or/O support/O the/O government/O on/O this/O issue/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O
On/O Tuesday/O ,/O Saxony-Anhalt/LOCATION Interior/O Minister/O Holger/PERSON Hoevelman/PERSON from/O the/O CDU/ORGANIZATION 's/O coalition/O partners/O ,/O the/O Social/O Democrats/O ,/O told/O the/O Frankfurter/ORGANIZATION Rundschau/ORGANIZATION newspaper/O that/O the/O detainees/O were/O an/O American/O problem/O ./O
He/O had/O ``/O no/O interest/O in/O adding/O a/O potential/O risk/O to/O the/O country/O by/O taking/O in/O the/O prisoners/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O
Munich/LOCATION ,/O Bavaria/LOCATION at/O odds/O In/O support/O of/O the/O resettlement/O efforts/O ,/O German/O government/O spokesman/O Ulrich/PERSON Wilhelm/PERSON noted/O that/O Munich/LOCATION would/O be/O the/O appropriate/O location/O to/O resettle/O the/O prisoners/O as/O there/O is/O a/O large/O Uighur/O community/O there/O ,/O and/O that/O the/O city/O council/O had/O voted/O to/O accept/O the/O Uighurs/O back/O in/O February/O ./O
In/O contrast/O ,/O Bavarian/O Interior/O Minister/O Joachim/PERSON Herrmann/PERSON -LRB-/O CSU/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O said/O on/O Monday/O that/O his/O state/O would/O not/O offer/O to/O welcome/O the/O detainees/O ./O
The/O Uighurs/O are/O a/O Chinese/O Muslim/O minority/O from/O the/O remote/O northwestern/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
The/O Obama/PERSON administration/O says/O that/O the/O Uighurs/O can/O not/O return/O to/O China/LOCATION because/O they/O risk/O persecution/O as/O the/O Chinese/O government/O regards/O them/O as/O terrorists/O ./O
The/O US/LOCATION government/O has/O classified/O the/O Uighurs/O as/O not/O posing/O a/O security/O threat/O ./O
