As/O the/O Chinese/O Prime/O Minister/O visits/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O he/O has/O a/O delicate/O task/O of/O improving/O ties/O with/O India/LOCATION without/O displeasing/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
Wen/PERSON is/O starting/O the/O second/O leg/O of/O his/O South/O Asian/O tour/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION on/O Friday/O ./O
China/LOCATION has/O a/O reputation/O of/O being/O an/O `/O all-weather/O '/O partner/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
However/O ,/O it/O has/O recently/O moved/O closer/O towards/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O arch-rival/O India/LOCATION ./O
As/O the/O Chinese/O premier/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON signs/O bumper/O trade/O deals/O with/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION on/O his/O India/LOCATION visit/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION too/O is/O hoping/O to/O receive/O maximum/O trade/O benefits/O to/O aid/O its/O frayed/O economy/O ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O closer/O ties/O with/O India/LOCATION are/O looked/O at/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION with/O some/O suspicion/O ./O
India/LOCATION ,/O too/O ,/O is/O critical/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O various/O proposed/O contracts/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION that/O are/O going/O to/O be/O finalized/O during/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON 's/O visit/O to/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O nuclear/O weapon/O program/O has/O Chinese/O backing/O
Controversial/O nuclear/O deal/O
India/LOCATION views/O the/O proposed/O one-gigawatt/O nuclear/O plant/O deal/O between/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION with/O a/O lot/O of/O concern/O ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O investment/O in/O the/O nuclear/O facilities/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O whose/O track/O record/O in/O nuclear/O non-proliferation/O has/O been/O marred/O by/O controversies/O ,/O is/O enough/O to/O raise/O the/O eyebrows/O of/O Western/O powers/O ./O
But/O according/O to/O Moonis/PERSON Ahmar/PERSON ,/O professor/O of/O international/O relations/O at/O Karachi/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O NPT/O is/O irrelevant/O in/O the/O case/O of/O the/O Sino-Pakistani/O nuclear/O deal/O ,/O as/O its/O purpose/O is/O to/O generate/O energy/O ./O
``/O It/O is/O true/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O nuclear/O record/O has/O been/O controversial/O ,/O particularly/O in/O the/O case/O of/O A.Q./PERSON Khan/PERSON ,/O but/O the/O fact/O is/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION faces/O a/O serious/O energy/O deficit/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O the/O reason/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION are/O going/O to/O sign/O a/O deal/O ,/O ''/O Ahmar/PERSON told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ./O
India/LOCATION ,/O too/O ,/O has/O not/O signed/O the/O NPT/O ./O
Islamabad/LOCATION believes/O that/O if/O the/O US/LOCATION could/O give/O nuclear/O concessions/O to/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION ,/O it/O has/O an/O equal/O right/O to/O attain/O nuclear/O energy/O ,/O and/O if/O it/O does/O not/O come/O from/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O a/O tried/O and/O tested/O regional/O ally/O ./O
China/LOCATION is/O the/O major/O supplier/O of/O conventional/O weapons/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O it/O is/O also/O believed/O that/O it/O helped/O Pakistan/LOCATION in/O building/O its/O nuclear/O weapons/O program/O ./O
Many/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION believe/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O moved/O closer/O towards/O India/LOCATION
Kashmir/LOCATION dispute/O
India/LOCATION is/O unhappy/O about/O China/LOCATION 's/O practice/O of/O giving/O stapled/O visas/O to/O travelers/O from/O Jammu/LOCATION and/O Kashmir/LOCATION ,/O as/O well/O as/O China/LOCATION 's/O role/O in/O building/O dams/O in/O Pakistan-administered/O Kashmir/LOCATION ./O
India/LOCATION wants/O China/LOCATION to/O be/O more/O sensitive/O on/O the/O Kashmir/LOCATION issue/O ./O
However/O ,/O many/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION point/O out/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O already/O changed/O its/O stance/O ./O
``/O China/LOCATION has/O somehow/O amended/O its/O position/O on/O Kashmir/LOCATION ./O
35/O to/O 40/O years/O ago/O ,/O China/LOCATION was/O openly/O supporting/O Pakistan/LOCATION on/O the/O issue/O of/O Kashmir/LOCATION ,/O but/O now/O it/O advises/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O resolve/O the/O conflict/O through/O dialogue/O and/O negotiations/O ,/O and/O avoid/O any/O kind/O of/O militaristic/O adventure/O ./O
So/O it/O is/O a/O different/O policy/O on/O Kashmir/LOCATION now/O ,/O ''/O said/O Moonis/PERSON Ahmar/PERSON ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O influence/O
The/O State/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION of/O Pakistan/LOCATION has/O given/O a/O green/O signal/O to/O ICBC/ORGANIZATION to/O operate/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION
According/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O office/O spokesman/O Abdul/PERSON Basit/PERSON ,/O the/O Chinese/O premier/O is/O expected/O to/O sign/O 36/O development/O projects/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O which/O will/O include/O projects/O in/O energy/O ,/O infrastructure/O ,/O and/O finance/O ./O
The/O Pakistani/O government/O has/O also/O approved/O the/O licence/O of/O the/O Industrial/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Commercial/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O ICBC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O
In/O the/O face/O of/O a/O severe/O economic/O crisis/O and/O massive/O floods/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O looking/O to/O China/LOCATION for/O greater/O economic/O support/O ./O
The/O annual/O bilateral/O trade/O between/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION was/O about/O $/O 6.8/O billion/O in/O 2009/O and/O the/O two/O countries/O aim/O to/O increase/O it/O to/O $/O 15/O billion/O by/O 2011/O ./O
Islamist/O extremism/O
India/LOCATION wants/O China/LOCATION to/O play/O a/O role/O in/O curbing/O Islamist/O militancy/O and/O hopes/O that/O the/O Chinese/O PM/O will/O use/O his/O influence/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O regularly/O blamed/O by/O India/LOCATION for/O cross-border/O terrorism/O ./O
China/LOCATION ,/O too/O ,/O has/O concerns/O about/O the/O issue/O of/O Islamist/O militancy/O in/O its/O northwestern/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O ,/O bordering/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
China/LOCATION has/O been/O urging/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O take/O action/O against/O Uighur/O militants/O who/O have/O possible/O links/O with/O the/O Islamists/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
Islamabad/LOCATION denies/O any/O connections/O with/O Islamist/O militants/O ./O
Author/O :/O Shamil/PERSON Shams/PERSON
Editor/O :/O Thomas/PERSON Baerthlein/PERSON
