China/LOCATION is/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O closest/O ally/O ./O
As/O a/O permanent/O member/O of/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O calling/O for/O a/O diplomatic/O approach/O towards/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O nuclear/O program/O and/O for/O a/O stop/O to/O the/O sanctions/O ./O
Iran/LOCATION is/O the/O second/O largest/O supplier/O of/O oil/O to/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION and/O within/O the/O first/O nine/O months/O of/O 2009/O ,/O it/O became/O largest/O market/O for/O the/O investment/O of/O Chinese/O companies/O in/O construction/O and/O projects/O ./O
Fariborz/PERSON Laghaie/PERSON likes/O to/O trade/O with/O the/O Chinese/O ./O
The/O successful/O businessman/O from/O Teheran/LOCATION imports/O a/O number/O of/O goods/O ,/O among/O them/O ,/O electronics/O ./O
Iranian/O President/O Mahmoud/PERSON Ahmadinejad/PERSON ,/O left/O ,/O greets/O Chinese/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON
He/O has/O been/O flying/O frequently/O to/O China/LOCATION for/O the/O past/O three/O years/O ./O
He/O says/O China/LOCATION 's/O influence/O on/O the/O Iranian/O market/O is/O growing/O by/O the/O day/O ./O
``/O Of/O course/O sanctions/O against/O Iran/LOCATION play/O a/O big/O role/O ./O
But/O those/O who/O do/O business/O with/O the/O Chinese/O know/O the/O saying/O :/O the/O Chinese/O never/O say/O no/O to/O anyone/O ./O
Chinese/O companies/O have/O won/O many/O jobs/O in/O various/O sectors/O in/O Iran/LOCATION in/O the/O past/O years/O ./O ''/O
The/O Iranian/O market/O is/O flooded/O with/O `/O cheap/O products/O '/O from/O China/LOCATION -/O from/O textiles/O and/O toys/O to/O DVD/O players/O and/O the/O latest/O models/O of/O mobile/O phones/O ./O
Experts/O in/O Iran/LOCATION have/O cautioned/O against/O the/O Chinese/O competition/O ,/O saying/O it/O jeopardizes/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O industry/O and/O job/O market/O ./O
But/O it/O has/O been/O in/O vain/O ,/O says/O Laghaie/PERSON :/O ``/O We/O still/O do/O n't/O have/O strict/O laws/O governing/O the/O volume/O and/O quality/O of/O imports/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O
The/O majority/O of/O Iranians/O can/O not/O afford/O to/O buy/O expensive/O ,/O high-quality/O products/O ./O
On/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O do/O not/O have/O the/O capacities/O to/O control/O everything/O that/O is/O produced/O in/O and/O exported/O from/O such/O a/O large/O country/O ./O
So/O everyone/O just/O does/O what/O they/O want/O ./O ''/O
A/O view/O of/O phase/O five/O of/O the/O South/LOCATION Pars/LOCATION gas/O field/O in/O the/O southern/O port/O of/O Assaluyeh/LOCATION ,/O Iran/LOCATION
Oil/O deals/O with/O China/LOCATION are/O kept/O secret/O
The/O Iranian/O economy/O is/O mostly/O centralized/O and/O is/O almost/O completely/O state-controlled/O ./O
In/O the/O Iranian/O economy/O ,/O corruption/O is/O a/O wide-spread/O problem/O ./O
In/O its/O latest/O corruption/O index/O ,/O Transparency/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION has/O ranked/O Iran/LOCATION 168/O of/O 180/O countries/O ./O
This/O year/O ,/O China/LOCATION became/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O number/O one/O trade/O partner/O ./O
China/LOCATION exports/O mainly/O weapons/O to/O the/O isolated/O country/O in/O return/O for/O oil/O and/O gas/O ./O
The/O oppositional/O journalist/O Mehdi/PERSON Mohseni/PERSON is/O surprised/O ./O
``/O Nobody/O knows/O about/O oil/O deals/O with/O China/LOCATION in/O Iran/LOCATION ./O
Outside/O of/O Iran/LOCATION is/O where/O I/O heard/O about/O it/O and/O I/O was/O really/O shocked/O ./O
China/LOCATION is/O only/O known/O to/O us/O in/O our/O country/O because/O of/O its/O cheap/O products/O ./O ''/O
Aside/O from/O cheap/O products/O ,/O people/O in/O Iran/LOCATION hardly/O know/O anything/O about/O China/LOCATION ,/O although/O both/O cultures/O have/O been/O linked/O by/O the/O Silk/U_LOCATION Road/U_LOCATION for/O centuries/O ./O
Iranians/O do/O n't/O hear/O about/O things/O like/O the/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Massacre/O nor/O about/O the/O brutal/O crackdown/O of/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O on/O demonstrators/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
Chinese/O and/O Iranian/O officials/O hold/O talks/O
Iranian/O lawyer/O ,/O human/O rights/O defender/O and/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O winner/O ,/O Shirin/PERSON Ebadi/PERSON ,/O criticizes/O the/O country/O 's/O blindness/O ./O
``/O The/O Chinese/O government/O exploits/O the/O rights/O of/O its/O people/O to/O a/O great/O extent/O -/O just/O like/O the/O Iranian/O government/O ./O
Whenever/O a/O Moslem/O is/O killed/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O the/O Iranian/O government/O makes/O a/O huge/O deal/O out/O of/O it/O ./O
But/O when/O thousands/O of/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O are/O killed/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O they/O say/O nothing/O ./O
And/O they/O make/O sure/O the/O press/O says/O nothing/O ./O ''/O
Shirin/PERSON Ebadi/PERSON has/O observed/O how/O the/O Iranian/O people/O are/O starting/O to/O see/O through/O the/O government/O despite/O censored/O media/O coverage/O ./O
She/O says/O now/O ,/O when/O the/O state/O marches/O on/O the/O streets/O shouting/O ``/O down/O with/O America/LOCATION and/O down/O with/O Israel/LOCATION ''/O ,/O the/O people/O shout/O instead/O ,/O ``/O down/O with/O Russia/LOCATION ''/O and/O ``/O down/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O
Author/O :/O Nourian/O ,/O Shabnam/PERSON //O sb/O
Editor/O :/O Thomas/PERSON Baerthlein/PERSON
