On/O July/O 15/O the/O fourth/O and/O last/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O state-owned/O banks/O will/O float/O its/O shares/O in/O Shanghai/LOCATION ,/O and/O one/O day/O later/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ./O
The/O stock/O market/O launch/O of/O the/O Agricultural/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION is/O likely/O to/O be/O the/O largest/O of/O all/O time/O ./O
The/O Chinese/O love/O records/O ./O
The/O initial/O plan/O was/O that/O the/O IPO/O would/O raise/O 30/O billion/O US/O dollars/O for/O the/O Agricultural/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O ABC/ORGANIZATION or/O AgBank/ORGANIZATION for/O short/O -RRB-/O ,/O the/O third/O largest/O Chinese/O state/O bank/O ./O
But/O as/O the/O financial/O markets/O have/O been/O shaky/O recently/O ,/O the/O AgBank/ORGANIZATION is/O now/O likely/O to/O receive/O ``/O only/O ''/O 22.1/O billion/O dollars/O ./O
This/O would/O still/O be/O more/O than/O the/O biggest/O IPO/O of/O all/O time/O so/O far/O ,/O the/O 21.9/O billion/O dollars/O resulting/O from/O the/O launch/O of/O the/O Industrial/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Commercial/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION in/O 2006/O ./O
The/O exact/O figures/O do/O n't/O really/O matter/O ,/O though/O ,/O argues/O Andreas/PERSON Schmitz/PERSON ,/O the/O president/O of/O the/O Association/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION German/ORGANIZATION Banks/ORGANIZATION :/O ``/O It/O will/O be/O a/O fabulously/O large/O amount/O of/O money/O and/O a/O huge/O success/O anyway/O that/O they/O are/O able/O to/O go/O ahead/O with/O the/O listing/O in/O these/O troubled/O times/O ./O
I/O do/O n't/O think/O you/O could/O go/O through/O with/O a/O bank/O IPO/O in/O Europe/LOCATION or/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION right/O now/O ./O ''/O
State/O banks/O successfully/O reformed/O
The/O bank/O has/O 23,000/O branches/O ,/O more/O than/O any/O other/O in/O the/O world/O The/O IPO/O also/O marks/O an/O end/O to/O the/O reform/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O state/O banks/O ./O
The/O central/O government/O had/O to/O pump/O billions/O into/O the/O banks/O to/O relieve/O them/O of/O the/O burden/O of/O bad/O loans/O ./O
The/O Agricultural/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION was/O considered/O the/O weakest/O among/O the/O four/O ,/O which/O is/O why/O its/O IPO/O is/O coming/O last/O ./O
State/O assistance/O helped/O reduce/O the/O share/O of/O bad/O loans/O in/O the/O AgBank/ORGANIZATION portfolio/O from/O 24/O to/O 3/O per/O cent/O between/O 2007/O and/O 2009/O ./O
The/O bank/O has/O 23,000/O branches/O ,/O more/O than/O any/O other/O in/O the/O world/O ,/O and/O 320/O million/O customers/O ./O
They/O are/O mostly/O based/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O rural/O areas/O ,/O as/O the/O name/O already/O suggests/O ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O plans/O to/O boost/O rural/O development/O might/O appeal/O to/O potential/O investors/O ./O
But/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O the/O Agricultural/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION will/O have/O to/O continue/O offering/O loans/O at/O low/O interest/O rates/O to/O Chinese/O peasants/O ./O
This/O political/O directive/O once/O again/O highlights/O the/O dilemma/O Chinese/O state/O banks/O find/O themselves/O in/O :/O They/O are/O expected/O to/O become/O more/O efficient/O and/O earn/O more/O revenues/O ,/O while/O at/O the/O same/O time/O toeing/O the/O party/O line/O ./O
Attractive/O for/O investors/O Andreas/PERSON Schmitz/PERSON says/O with/O the/O IPO/O at/O this/O juncture/O ,/O the/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O sending/O a/O clear/O signal/O to/O the/O world/O :/O ``/O First/O of/O all/O ,/O that/O the/O Chinese/O economy/O is/O developing/O very/O well/O ./O
That/O it/O is/O continuing/O to/O open/O up/O to/O financial/O markets/O and/O managing/O to/O attract/O capital/O for/O its/O banks/O from/O outside/O as/O well/O ,/O not/O just/O from/O the/O state/O ,/O which/O in/O turn/O makes/O these/O banks/O more/O attractive/O ./O ''/O
Stocks/O in/O Shanghai/LOCATION have/O lost/O 20/O per/O cent/O in/O value/O this/O year/O
The/O Chinese/O media/O have/O reported/O that/O a/O number/O of/O high-profile/O investors/O have/O agreed/O to/O buy/O substantial/O shares/O in/O the/O AgBank/ORGANIZATION ./O
Among/O them/O are/O state/O funds/O from/O Kuwait/LOCATION and/O Qatar/LOCATION ./O
Singapore/LOCATION 's/O state/O fund/O ,/O Temasek/ORGANIZATION ,/O is/O planning/O to/O invest/O 300/O million/O dollars/O ./O
Major/O Chinese/O companies/O are/O also/O said/O to/O be/O participating/O ,/O including/O the/O largest/O oil/O and/O gas/O producer/O PetroChina/ORGANIZATION and/O insurance/O giant/O China/ORGANIZATION Life/ORGANIZATION ./O
These/O strategic/O investors/O will/O be/O crucial/O ,/O as/O most/O observers/O believe/O that/O private/O investors/O might/O be/O reluctant/O to/O take/O the/O risk/O ./O
After/O almost/O doubling/O in/O 2009/O ,/O the/O Shanghai/LOCATION Composite/O Index/O has/O lost/O more/O than/O 20/O per/O cent/O in/O value/O in/O 2010/O ./O
And/O whereas/O the/O AgBank/ORGANIZATION listing/O is/O going/O ahead/O with/O strong/O government/O backing/O ,/O five/O companies/O have/O already/O had/O to/O cancel/O their/O IPO/O plans/O during/O the/O past/O two/O months/O ,/O including/O China/LOCATION 's/O second-largest/O wind/O turbine/O maker/O ,/O Xinjiang/U_ORGANIZATION Goldwind/U_ORGANIZATION ./O
Author/O :/O Zhang/PERSON Danhong/PERSON //O tb/O
Editor/O :/O Grahame/PERSON Lucas/PERSON
