Pakistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION are/O celebrating/O 60/O years/O of/O close/O diplomatic/O relations/O ./O
While/O economic/O ties/O are/O growing/O ,/O experts/O agree/O the/O Pak-China/O is/O a/O friendship/O based/O more/O on/O strategic/O purposes/O than/O on/O business/O ./O
In/O a/O matter/O of/O only/O a/O few/O weeks/O ,/O US-Pakistani/O relations/O have/O taken/O a/O series/O of/O hard/O hits/O ./O
There/O is/O growing/O mutual/O distrust/O since/O the/O US/LOCATION special/O forces/O operation/O that/O killed/O al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION chief/O Osama/PERSON bin/PERSON Laden/PERSON at/O the/O beginning/O of/O May/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
The/O US/LOCATION was/O quick/O to/O point/O the/O finger/O at/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O accusing/O Islamabad/LOCATION of/O not/O doing/O enough/O to/O fight/O terrorism/O ,/O whereas/O Beijing/LOCATION -/O in/O a/O show/O of/O support/O -/O was/O quick/O to/O defend/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
With/O China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION celebrate/O 60/O years/O of/O close/O diplomatic/O relations/O this/O year/O ,/O the/O question/O is/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O openly/O celebrated/O Pak-China/O friendship/O is/O really/O as/O positive/O as/O the/O leaders/O of/O the/O two/O countries/O would/O like/O others/O to/O believe/O ./O
China/LOCATION is/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O largest/O supplier/O of/O arms/O
American/O experts/O are/O not/O so/O sure/O ./O
China/LOCATION has/O concerns/O of/O its/O own/O ,/O says/O Jonathan/PERSON Pollack/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O Brookings/ORGANIZATION Institution/ORGANIZATION in/O Washington/LOCATION D.C./LOCATION ,/O especially/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O its/O own/O Muslim/O Uighur/O population/O ./O
He/O says/O ,/O ``/O evidence/O of/O uncertainty/O and/O instability/O ,/O the/O fragile/O nature/O of/O ruling/O authority/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION --/O these/O are/O things/O that/O I/O believe/O the/O Chinese/O worry/O about/O a/O great/O deal/O ./O ''/O
But/O one/O main/O difference/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O other/O ally/O ,/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O is/O that/O China/LOCATION 's/O rulers/O take/O a/O very/O different/O approach/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O differences/O of/O opinion/O ./O
Pollack/PERSON says/O Beijing/LOCATION prefers/O to/O keeps/O its/O concerns/O or/O criticism/O quiet/O ./O
``/O The/O Chinese/O are/O very/O averse/O to/O going/O public/O with/O those/O kinds/O of/O issues/O and/O not/O just/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
They/O will/O not/O subject/O long-term/O partners/O or/O seldom/O subject/O them/O to/O anything/O that/O could/O be/O seen/O as/O explicit/O ,/O overt/O criticism/O ./O
If/O they/O have/O issues/O ,/O they/O discuss/O them/O with/O them/O privately/O ./O ''/O
More/O than/O just/O words/O of/O comfort/O
That/O is/O one/O reason/O Pakistan/LOCATION might/O want/O to/O rely/O less/O on/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O more/O on/O China/LOCATION for/O financial/O aid/O ,/O for/O example/O ./O
But/O Stephen/PERSON Cohen/PERSON ,/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O Brookings/ORGANIZATION Institution/ORGANIZATION ,/O argues/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O unfortunately/O for/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O can/O not/O take/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O place/O ./O
He/O says/O Beijing/LOCATION follows/O its/O own/O interests/O and/O sees/O Pakistan/LOCATION as/O ``/O a/O valuable/O strategic/O partner/O ,/O as/O an/O access/O point/O to/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O ''/O
But/O in/O terms/O of/O aid/O and/O development/O and/O in/O terms/O of/O ``/O serious/O economic/O development/O or/O promoting/O democratization/O or/O normalization/O of/O Pakistani/O politics/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O keep/O their/O hands/O off/O of/O that/O completely/O ./O
And/O the/O Pakistanis/O appreciate/O it/O ./O
They/O 're/O tired/O of/O being/O lectured/O to/O by/O Americans/O ./O ''/O
Beijing/LOCATION has/O agreed/O to/O deliver/O 50/O fighter/O jets/O to/O Islamabad/LOCATION
Especially/O now/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION must/O be/O happy/O to/O be/O able/O to/O turn/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O for/O more/O than/O just/O words/O of/O comfort/O ./O
In/O addition/O to/O agreeing/O to/O increase/O bilateral/O trade/O to/O 10/O billion/O USD/O by/O 2012/O and/O to/O work/O more/O closely/O in/O fighting/O terrorism/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O also/O helping/O Pakistan/LOCATION expand/O its/O nuclear/O capacities/O --/O a/O new/O reactor/O has/O just/O been/O built/O and/O two/O more/O are/O being/O planned/O --/O and/O also/O to/O deliver/O twenty/O fighter/O jets/O to/O its/O good/O friend/O ./O
Pakistani/O Prime/O Minister/O Gilani/PERSON recently/O went/O on/O a/O four-day/O trip/O to/O China/LOCATION and/O expressed/O his/O gratitude/O by/O saying/O that/O Pakistanis/O appreciate/O that/O in/O all/O difficult/O circumstances/O China/LOCATION has/O stood/O with/O them/O ./O
He/O called/O China/LOCATION a/O true/O ,/O time-tested/O and/O all-weather/O friend/O ./O
Through/O thick/O and/O thin/O
Imtiaz/PERSON Gul/PERSON ,/O a/O DW/ORGANIZATION correspondent/O based/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O believes/O that/O ``/O all-weather/O ''/O is/O indeed/O the/O appropriate/O term/O for/O the/O Pak-China/O friendship/O ,/O especially/O if/O you/O compare/O it/O to/O the/O US//LOCATION O -/O Pakistan/LOCATION relationship/O ./O
Gul/PERSON thinks/O there/O is/O a/O big/O difference/O between/O how/O the/O two/O giants/O treat/O their/O little/O friend/O ./O
He/O says/O Pakistan/LOCATION has/O always/O treated/O China/LOCATION as/O a/O friendly/O country/O because/O on/O many/O awkward/O occasions/O ,/O China/LOCATION remained/O the/O ``/O only/O contact/O for/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O ''/O
Compared/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O ``/O there/O is/O a/O long/O history/O of/O going/O back/O on/O promises/O by/O the/O US/LOCATION on/O many/O occasions/O ./O
And/O also/O I/O think/O the/O continued/O string/O of/O allegations/O from/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O the/O Pentagon/ORGANIZATION and/O CIA/ORGANIZATION also/O fuels/O this/O anti-American/O sentiment/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O ''/O
As/O China/LOCATION is/O expanding/O its/O nuclear/O power/O ,/O it/O is/O also/O helping/O Pakistan/LOCATION build/O new/O nuclear/O power/O plants/O Pakistan/LOCATION foreign/O policy/O experts/O believe/O it/O best/O for/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O balance/O its/O partnerships/O --/O last/O but/O not/O least/O to/O keep/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION in/O check/O ./O
Tanveer/PERSON Ahmad/PERSON Khan/PERSON ,/O a/O former/O federal/O secretary/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION ,/O says/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O in/O a/O difficult/O situation/O with/O regards/O to/O its/O relationship/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O
He/O says/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION has/O relied/O heavily/O on/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O the/O West/LOCATION in/O the/O past/O 10/O years/O ./O
But/O ``/O at/O the/O moment/O ,/O the/O relationship/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION is/O not/O all/O that/O good/O and/O naturally/O there/O is/O pressure/O coming/O from/O the/O Pakistani/O parliament/O and/O Pakistani/O public/O opinion/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION should/O also/O strengthen/O its/O other/O relationships/O ,/O that/O we/O have/O been/O too/O preoccupied/O ,/O that/O we/O have/O put/O all/O our/O eggs/O in/O the/O American/O basket/O ./O ''/O
Nonetheless/O ,/O US-Experts/O like/O Stephen/PERSON Cohen/PERSON from/O the/O Brookings/ORGANIZATION Institution/ORGANIZATION believes/O the/O Chinese/O are/O concerned/O about/O a/O ``/O breakdown/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O as/O instability/O could/O possibly/O lead/O to/O a/O nuclear/O confrontation/O in/O the/O region/O ./O
That/O is/O why/O the/O promotion/O of/O stability/O is/O of/O vital/O importance/O and/O that/O ,/O Cohen/PERSON points/O out/O ,/O is/O one/O issue/O on/O which/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION can/O all/O agree/O ./O
Author/O :/O Sarah/PERSON Berning/PERSON
Editor/O :/O Grahame/PERSON Lucas/PERSON
