The/O whereabouts/O of/O Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON ,/O a/O well-known/O Chinese/O lawyer/O and/O dissident/O ,/O have/O been/O made/O public/O after/O his/O brother/O released/O details/O of/O an/O official/O letter/O ,/O ending/O a/O two-year/O mystery/O ./O
Gao/PERSON Zhiyi/PERSON ,/O Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON 's/O elder/O brother/O ,/O received/O a/O court/O notice/O on/O Sunday/O confirming/O his/O brother/O was/O being/O held/O in/O Shaya/U_LOCATION prison/O in/O the/O remote/O northwestern/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION ./O
He/O read/O the/O letter/O to/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION over/O the/O telephone/O :/O ``/O the/O letter/O I/O received/O on/O January/O 1/O from/O Shaya/U_LOCATION prison/O reads/O :/O `/O Dear/O Gao/PERSON Zhiyi/PERSON ,/O your/O younger/O brother/O Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON committed/O the/O crime/O of/O subversion/O ./O
He/O has/O been/O sentenced/O to/O three/O years/O imprisonment/O by/O the/O Beijing/ORGANIZATION Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION ./O
He/O was/O sent/O to/O Shaya/PERSON prison/O for/O reformation/O ./O ''/O
In/O the/O hope/O that/O Chinese/O internet/O users/O will/O travel/O to/O his/O prison/O to/O visit/O the/O detained/O dissident/O ,/O a/O human/O rights/O organization/O announced/O the/O news/O immediately/O upon/O receiving/O confirmation/O that/O Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON is/O being/O held/O in/O a/O remote/O prison/O ./O
The/O detention/O center/O is/O located/O in/O the/O Taklamakan/U_LOCATION desert/O ,/O far/O away/O from/O Chinese/O inland/O ,/O where/O many/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O dissidents/O are/O locked/O up/O ./O
Activist/O lawyer/O
As/O a/O prominent/O lawyer/O supporting/O the/O rights/O of/O his/O clients/O ,/O Gao/PERSON was/O originally/O arrested/O in/O 2006/O and/O sentenced/O to/O three/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O ``/O inciting/O subversion/O of/O state/O power/O ,/O ''/O but/O was/O given/O five/O years/O on/O probation/O ,/O during/O which/O period/O he/O was/O repeatedly/O arrested/O ./O
Chinese/O dissident/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON was/O awarded/O the/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O in/O 2010/O
He/O was/O arrested/O again/O and/O held/O in/O an/O undisclosed/O location/O in/O 2009/O and/O briefly/O released/O in/O April/O of/O 2010/O before/O being/O arrested/O again/O ./O
Last/O month/O ,/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O official/O Chinese/O news/O agency/O ,/O reported/O that/O Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON had/O been/O arrested/O and/O sentenced/O to/O three/O years/O in/O jail/O for/O ``/O seriously/O violating/O ''/O his/O probation/O ./O
``/O We/O have/O n't/O heard/O anything/O about/O him/O since/O last/O year/O ./O
Whenever/O we/O inquired/O about/O his/O whereabouts/O ,/O they/O said/O he/O had/O disappeared/O and/O that/O they/O had/O no/O idea/O where/O he/O was/O ,/O ''/O Gao/PERSON Zhiyi/PERSON told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ./O
He/O also/O said/O he/O was/O worried/O about/O his/O younger/O brother/O :/O ``/O how/O can/O we/O feel/O good/O about/O the/O news/O ?/O
I/O am/O an/O old/O farmer/O ./O
I/O do/O n't/O understand/O what/O he/O does/O ./O
Now/O our/O family/O is/O incomplete/O and/O he/O is/O suffering/O in/O jail/O ./O
What/O is/O he/O aiming/O at/O ?/O ''/O
Despite/O his/O disappointment/O ,/O Gao/PERSON Zhiyi/PERSON says/O he/O is/O ready/O to/O make/O the/O long/O trip/O and/O visit/O his/O brother/O in/O prison/O ./O
``/O We/O want/O to/O see/O how/O he/O is/O doing/O ./O
We/O can/O do/O nothing/O but/O accept/O the/O fact/O that/O he/O is/O in/O prison/O ./O ''/O
`/O Worse/O than/O usual/O '/O
Although/O the/O Chinese/O government/O is/O tough/O on/O dissent/O ,/O Hu/PERSON Jia/PERSON ,/O a/O Chinese/O human/O rights/O activist/O ,/O says/O Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON 's/O sentence/O is/O worse/O than/O usual/O ./O
``/O Two/O weeks/O before/O his/O sentence/O was/O up/O ,/O the/O authorities/O decided/O to/O send/O him/O back/O to/O prison/O ./O
His/O case/O reflects/O the/O arbitrariness/O and/O abuse/O of/O power/O of/O the/O Chinese/O system/O ./O
Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON has/O not/O been/O judged/O by/O a/O judge/O ,/O but/O by/O the/O party/O and/O its/O power/O ./O ''/O
Chinese/O artist/O and/O dissident/O Ai/PERSON Weiwei/PERSON
Albert/PERSON Ho/PERSON ,/O a/O politician/O from/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION Gao/PERSON 's/O case/O is/O ``/O a/O humiliation/O to/O the/O Chinese/O legal/O system/O ,/O ''/O adding/O ,/O ``/O over/O the/O past/O few/O years/O he/O had/O no/O freedom/O ,/O just/O as/O if/O he/O were/O living/O in/O jail/O ./O
But/O still/O the/O authorities/O accused/O him/O of/O violating/O the/O rules/O ./O
I/O think/O this/O is/O a/O real/O invasion/O of/O Gao/PERSON Zhisheng/PERSON 's/O human/O rights/O ./O ''/O
Being/O under/O constant/O surveillance/O ,/O his/O wife/O ,/O Geng/PERSON He/PERSON ,/O and/O children/O have/O fled/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O where/O politicians/O have/O spoken/O in/O his/O favor/O ./O
Rights/O groups/O and/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION as/O well/O as/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION have/O called/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O release/O him/O ,/O as/O his/O detention/O goes/O against/O international/O laws/O ./O
Author/O :/O Sarah/PERSON Berning/PERSON //O wy/O //O mw/O
Editor/O :/O Arun/PERSON Chowdhury/PERSON
