Despite/O security/O concerns/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O set/O to/O invest/O heavily/O in/O Pakistani/O infrastructure/O projects/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION is/O looking/O for/O new/O ways/O to/O import/O energy/O and/O support/O in/O its/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O ./O
Last/O week/O ,/O Pakistani/O Prime/O Minister/O Nawaz/PERSON Sharif/PERSON met/O with/O China/LOCATION 's/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON during/O his/O first/O official/O visit/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION aimed/O at/O courting/O Chinese/O investment/O in/O his/O country/O 's/O ailing/O transport/O and/O electricity/O generating/O sectors/O ./O
During/O the/O five-day/O visit/O ,/O a/O total/O of/O eight/O pacts/O were/O signed/O ,/O including/O one/O for/O the/O construction/O of/O an/O ``/O economic/O corridor/O ,/O ''/O a/O 2,000-kilometer/O -LRB-/O 1,200-mile/O -RRB-/O transport/O project/O connecting/O the/O city/O of/O Kashgar/U_LOCATION in/O northwestern/O China/LOCATION to/O the/O Pakistani/O port/O of/O Gwadar/LOCATION ,/O likely/O by/O road/O in/O the/O beginning/O and/O possibly/O by/O rail/O later/O ./O
Security/O concerns/O Project/O developers/O will/O have/O to/O surmount/O huge/O obstacles/O to/O build/O the/O corridor/O
But/O project/O developers/O will/O not/O only/O have/O to/O surmount/O enormous/O geographical/O obstacles/O ,/O but/O also/O to/O deal/O with/O the/O terror/O threat/O coming/O from/O different/O militant/O extremist/O groups/O within/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O particularly/O in/O Balochistan/LOCATION province/O ./O
``/O The/O chances/O of/O the/O plan/O succeeding/O will/O largely/O depend/O on/O the/O security/O situation/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O Christan/PERSON Wagner/PERSON ,/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O Berlin-based/O German/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SWP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O
Liu/PERSON Xiaoxue/PERSON ,/O from/O the/O Beijing-based/O Institute/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Asia-Pacific/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION ,/O explains/O that/O there/O have/O been/O many/O abductions/O and/O attacks/O on/O Chinese/O citizens/O in/O the/O region/O ./O
But/O she/O also/O emphasized/O that/O China/LOCATION had/O no/O other/O choice/O if/O it/O wanted/O to/O remain/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O largest/O contractor/O ./O
``/O China/LOCATION can/O only/O hope/O that/O by/O investing/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O the/O economy/O of/O the/O South/O Asian/O nation/O will/O bounce/O back/O ,/O ''/O Liu/PERSON told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
But/O the/O more/O pressing/O issue/O is/O what/O will/O happen/O in/O the/O long/O run/O ./O
Senior/O Pakistani/O journalist/O Absaar/PERSON Alam/PERSON ,/O who/O accompanied/O Sharif/PERSON on/O this/O trip/O ,/O said/O in/O a/O DW/ORGANIZATION interview/O that/O the/O Chinese/O were/O not/O only/O concerned/O about/O the/O security/O situation/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O but/O also/O with/O Islamabad/LOCATION 's/O lack/O of/O follow-up/O ./O
``/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O government/O seems/O to/O not/O take/O this/O seriously/O ./O
They/O do/O n't/O complete/O the/O agreed/O projects/O ,/O ''/O Alam/PERSON said/O ./O
An/O alternative/O route/O for/O oil/O imports/O
The/O Pakistani/O port/O of/O Gwadar/LOCATION is/O set/O to/O restart/O operations/O with/O help/O from/O the/O Chinese/O But/O there/O is/O another/O reason/O why/O China/LOCATION is/O interested/O in/O going/O ahead/O with/O the/O transport/O project/O ./O
According/O to/O Liu/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION is/O keen/O on/O finding/O new/O routes/O for/O oil/O imports/O and/O circumventing/O the/O Strait/LOCATION of/LOCATION Malacca/LOCATION near/O Singapore/LOCATION ./O
``/O The/O new/O economic/O corridor/O will/O stretch/O from/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION to/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O and/O could/O be/O used/O for/O transporting/O crude/O oil/O from/O West/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION to/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O
South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION expert/O Wagner/PERSON is/O of/O the/O opinion/O that/O the/O project/O wo/O n't/O be/O finished/O within/O the/O next/O five/O to/O ten/O years/O due/O to/O the/O volatile/O conditions/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
But/O he/O thinks/O that/O an/O increased/O cooperation/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION will/O have/O a/O positive/O effect/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION by/O helping/O it/O improve/O its/O infrastructure/O and/O overcome/O its/O energy/O crisis/O ./O
Pakistani/O experts/O ,/O however/O ,/O are/O less/O optimistic/O ./O
``/O Considering/O a/O power-theft/O rate/O between/O 30/O to/O 40/O percent/O ,/O and/O that/O the/O national/O grid/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION has/O not/O been/O modernized/O for/O the/O past/O 50/O years/O ,/O no/O power/O in/O the/O world/O can/O help/O us/O ,/O ''/O economist/O Farrukh/PERSON Saleem/PERSON told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
Nonetheless/O ,/O PM/O Sharif/PERSON wrote/O on/O Twitter/O after/O the/O trip/O :/O ``/O A/O respectful/O relationship/O and/O strategic/O alliance/O will/O help/O to/O stabilize/O the/O economy/O ./O ''/O
China/LOCATION wants/O help/O from/O Pakistan/LOCATION in/O the/O fight/O against/O militant/O extremists/O During/O the/O meeting/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O both/O leaders/O also/O spoke/O about/O cooperating/O in/O the/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O ,/O an/O issue/O China/LOCATION is/O particularly/O interested/O in/O ,/O according/O to/O Wagner/PERSON ./O
China/LOCATION is/O concerned/O that/O the/O separatist/O East/U_ORGANIZATION Turkestan/U_ORGANIZATION Islamic/U_ORGANIZATION Movement/U_ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O seeks/O an/O independent/O homeland/O for/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O ,/O is/O training/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
