But/O many/O are/O pointing/O to/O corruption/O ,/O stagnation/O and/O environmental/O devastation/O ./O
For/O months/O ,/O a/O generational/O and/O leadership/O change/O has/O been/O underway/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
In/O November/O ,/O the/O party/O leadership/O was/O replaced/O ,/O and/O a/O week/O ago/O ,/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION convened/O to/O anoint/O the/O country/O 's/O new/O political/O leadership/O ./O
At/O the/O end/O of/O this/O week/O ,/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON and/O Prime/O Minister/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON are/O expected/O to/O step/O aside/O to/O make/O room/O for/O a/O younger/O team/O ./O
The/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION hopes/O to/O gain/O prestige/O from/O projects/O like/O the/O space/O program/O
Hu/PERSON and/O Wen/PERSON have/O ruled/O China/LOCATION for/O ten/O years/O ./O
If/O Chinese/O propaganda/O is/O to/O be/O believed/O ,/O China/LOCATION experienced/O a/O ``/O golden/O decade/O ''/O under/O their/O leadership/O ./O
In/O that/O time/O ,/O the/O country/O grew/O to/O become/O the/O second-largest/O economy/O in/O the/O world/O ./O
It/O was/O an/O era/O of/O prosperity/O for/O millions/O of/O people/O ,/O with/O new/O skyscraper-dotted/O cities/O ,/O vast/O new/O freeways/O and/O high-speed/O railways/O ,/O the/O country/O 's/O first/O astronauts/O ,/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympics/O and/O a/O new/O sense/O of/O importance/O on/O the/O world/O stage/O ./O
Few/O dispute/O the/O country/O 's/O unprecedented/O economic/O boom/O -/O at/O least/O not/O in/O the/O coastal/O cities/O that/O have/O been/O its/O main/O beneficiaries/O ./O
As/O one/O Beijing/LOCATION retiree/O said/O ,/O ``/O They/O have/O done/O a/O good/O job/O ./O
Everyone/O can/O feel/O the/O improvements/O in/O living/O standards/O ./O ''/O
The/O problems/O of/O prosperity/O
The/O 2011/O high-speed/O rail/O disaster/O unveiled/O corruption/O and/O poor/O standards/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O vast/O new/O infrastructure/O
But/O with/O that/O boom/O have/O come/O the/O problems/O of/O unchecked/O and/O unexpected/O growth/O -/O inflation/O ,/O speculation/O ,/O corruption/O and/O pollution/O ./O
And/O while/O many/O Chinese/O are/O enjoying/O their/O modest/O share/O of/O the/O prosperity/O ,/O these/O problems/O also/O afflict/O their/O daily/O lives/O ./O
As/O another/O resident/O of/O the/O Chinese/O capital/O described/O it/O ,/O ``/O The/O home/O prices/O are/O constantly/O rising/O and/O falling/O ,/O they/O are/O not/O stable/O ./O
Inflation/O is/O high/O ./O
And/O the/O air/O pollution/O in/O cities/O such/O as/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O terrible/O ./O ''/O
Critics/O say/O the/O price/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O growth/O has/O been/O high/O ./O
The/O most/O visible/O victim/O is/O the/O environment/O ,/O which/O has/O faced/O devastation/O on/O a/O massive/O scale/O ./O
But/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION leadership/O as/O firmly/O anchored/O as/O ever/O ,/O little/O has/O been/O done/O to/O address/O the/O social/O problems/O resulting/O from/O a/O far/O wealthier/O country/O that/O remains/O under/O an/O essentially/O unchanged/O dictatorial/O system/O ./O
Dissident/O Yu/PERSON Jie/PERSON settled/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION last/O year/O after/O years/O of/O harassment/O by/O the/O authorities/O ./O
``/O We/O will/O also/O be/O paying/O a/O high/O price/O for/O the/O corruption/O ,/O the/O huge/O income/O disparities/O ,/O the/O demoralization/O and/O the/O hatred/O between/O the/O little/O people/O and/O the/O privileged/O ./O ''/O
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O air/O pollution/O is/O among/O the/O worst/O in/O the/O world/O
Critical/O intellectuals/O are/O particularly/O disappointed/O that/O there/O has/O been/O no/O progress/O in/O the/O past/O decade/O towards/O greater/O freedom/O of/O expression/O ,/O press/O freedom/O or/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O ./O
They/O talk/O of/O a/O lost/O decade/O of/O missed/O opportunities/O ./O
Veteran/O legal/O scholar/O Jiang/PERSON Ping/PERSON of/O the/O China/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Science/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Law/ORGANIZATION belongs/O to/O the/O reformist/O wing/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O The/O biggest/O mistake/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O is/O that/O there/O were/O no/O political/O reforms/O in/O the/O system/O ,/O no/O progress/O -/O in/O some/O areas/O they/O even/O regressed/O ./O
This/O is/O a/O disgrace/O ./O ''/O
A/O boom/O for/O secret/O police/O Instead/O ,/O by/O arguing/O the/O need/O to/O preserve/O stability/O in/O the/O country/O ,/O the/O security/O apparatus/O expanded/O ./O
China/LOCATION now/O spends/O more/O on/O internal/O security/O than/O for/O national/O defense/O ./O
Only/O Prime/O Minister/O Wen/PERSON ,/O who/O always/O liked/O to/O present/O himself/O as/O close/O to/O the/O people/O ,/O sometimes/O spoke/O of/O a/O need/O for/O political/O reform/O ./O
That/O 's/O something/O many/O give/O him/O credit/O for/O ,/O even/O if/O he/O was/O unable/O ,/O or/O unwilling/O ,/O to/O push/O anything/O through/O ./O
China/LOCATION leads/O the/O world/O in/O executions/O ,/O but/O its/O legal/O standards/O are/O poor/O
The/O more/O wooden/O President/O Hu/PERSON ,/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O consistently/O gets/O poor/O marks/O ./O
Writer/O and/O historian/O Zhang/PERSON Lifan/PERSON is/O among/O the/O disappointed/O :/O ``/O His/O greatest/O achievement/O is/O that/O at/O the/O end/O he/O gave/O all/O the/O power/O ,/O and/O all/O his/O offices/O ,/O to/O his/O successor/O ./O
Otherwise/O ,/O in/O ten/O years/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON achieved/O next/O to/O nothing/O ./O ''/O
Yet/O Hu/PERSON and/O Wen/PERSON managed/O crises/O that/O would/O have/O long/O ago/O cost/O politicians/O in/O other/O countries/O their/O jobs/O :/O These/O include/O the/O earthquake/O in/O Sichuan/LOCATION ,/O with/O 80,000/O dead/O and/O the/O tainted/O baby/O milk/O powder/O scandal/O that/O made/O 300,000/O children/O sick/O and/O killed/O six/O ./O
There/O was/O the/O unrest/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O the/O predominantly/O Muslim/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
And/O the/O global/O economic/O and/O financial/O crisis/O ,/O which/O also/O hit/O China/LOCATION hard/O ./O
Wen/PERSON is/O himself/O one/O of/O the/O first/O to/O admit/O that/O not/O everything/O went/O smoothly/O ./O
In/O his/O last/O major/O press/O conference/O a/O year/O ago/O ,/O he/O admitted/O emotionally/O ,/O ``/O I/O am/O responsible/O for/O the/O problems/O that/O occurred/O in/O the/O economy/O and/O society/O during/O my/O tenure/O ./O ''/O
But/O he/O is/O now/O leaving/O behind/O the/O problems/O that/O have/O accumulated/O :/O A/O growth/O model/O that/O has/O reached/O its/O limits/O ,/O state-owned/O enterprises/O that/O are/O unwilling/O to/O reform/O ,/O gigantic/O environmental/O problems/O and/O massive/O social/O tensions/O ./O
It/O is/O not/O an/O easy/O job/O for/O his/O heirs/O ,/O the/O new/O team/O of/O incoming/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON and/O Prime/O Minister/O Li/PERSON Keqiang/PERSON ./O
