The/O fight/O against/O international/O terror/O wo/O n't/O be/O won/O without/O international/O cooperation/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION is/O having/O to/O rethink/O its/O counter-terrorism/O strategies/O ,/O says/O DW/ORGANIZATION columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON ./O
It/O is/O n't/O quite/O over/O ,/O but/O 2014/O has/O already/O gone/O down/O in/O history/O as/O the/O year/O in/O which/O China/LOCATION experienced/O a/O record/O number/O of/O terrorist/O attacks/O ,/O and/O saw/O them/O claim/O a/O record/O number/O of/O people/O 's/O lives/O ./O
Terrorism/O in/O China/LOCATION has/O long/O been/O restricted/O to/O the/O restive/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O in/O the/O far/O west/O ,/O home/O to/O the/O Muslim/O Uighur/O minority/O group/O ,/O and/O was/O perpetrated/O by/O lone/O fanatics/O or/O small/O cells/O ./O
But/O what/O has/O happened/O this/O year/O is/O different/O ./O
The/O country/O 's/O leaders/O and/O the/O general/O public/O alike/O are/O becoming/O aware/O that/O terrorism/O is/O no/O longer/O just/O something/O that/O happens/O on/O the/O evening/O news/O ,/O but/O outside/O their/O front/O door/O ./O
In/O March/O ,/O 29/O civilians/O were/O killed/O at/O the/O main/O railway/O station/O in/O Kunming/LOCATION in/O southern/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O according/O to/O the/O official/O investigation/O ,/O the/O attack/O was/O carried/O out/O by/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION separatists/O ./O
Four/O of/O the/O Uighur/O Muslims/O responsible/O were/O shot/O by/O police/O at/O the/O scene/O ,/O while/O three/O more/O assailants/O were/O apprehended/O and/O sentenced/O to/O death/O ./O
A/O female/O perpetrator/O who/O was/O pregnant/O was/O sentenced/O to/O life/O in/O prison/O ./O
Terrorism/O has/O well/O and/O truly/O arrived/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O so/O it/O is/O hardly/O surprising/O that/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O November/O published/O a/O controversial/O draft/O counter-terrorism/O law/O ./O
Paragraph/O 76/O authorizes/O the/O army/O and/O the/O paramilitary/O police/O to/O carry/O out/O counterterrorism/O missions/O abroad/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON
Re-thinking/O the/O strategy/O
This/O is/O not/O unusual/O :/O the/O fight/O against/O international/O terrorism/O requires/O international/O efforts/O ,/O and/O Beijing/LOCATION believes/O that/O international/O Islamists/O are/O behind/O the/O growing/O threat/O to/O its/O national/O security/O -/O even/O though/O it/O has/O no/O concrete/O evidence/O to/O back/O this/O up/O ./O
It/O is/O no/O longer/O enough/O just/O to/O increase/O the/O police/O presence/O ,/O especially/O if/O the/O attacks/O are/O organized/O abroad/O ./O
For/O the/O Chinese/O ,/O who/O for/O some/O time/O have/O only/O operated/O within/O their/O own/O borders/O and/O have/O hardly/O seen/O foreign/O missions/O as/O an/O option/O ,/O this/O is/O new/O territory/O ./O
So/O far/O ,/O only/O the/O Chinese/O police/O has/O taken/O part/O in/O UN/ORGANIZATION peace/O missions/O ./O
But/O it/O is/O clear/O that/O since/O the/O US/LOCATION has/O largely/O withdrawn/O from/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O terrorist/O activities/O in/O China/LOCATION have/O increased/O ./O
Sending/O goods/O rather/O than/O weapons/O and/O promoting/O economic/O development/O is/O still/O a/O sensible/O strategy/O and/O has/O eroded/O support/O for/O terrorists/O among/O the/O population/O in/O many/O regions/O ./O
But/O it/O can/O be/O slow/O to/O take/O effect/O ,/O and/O in/O the/O meantime/O the/O terrorists/O are/O n't/O wasting/O time/O ./O
``/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION ''/O militants/O have/O already/O declared/O that/O freeing/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION is/O on/O their/O agenda/O ./O
China/LOCATION is/O now/O confronted/O with/O a/O problem/O that/O the/O West/LOCATION ,/O particularly/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O has/O suffered/O from/O for/O some/O time/O ./O
New/O problems/O ,/O new/O plans/O In/O comparison/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O flanked/O by/O two/O oceans/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O at/O a/O disadvantage/O :/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION are/O neighbors/O ./O
A/O narrow/O corridor/O connects/O the/O troublesome/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION with/O an/O eastern/O Afghan/O region/O in/O which/O many/O terrorists/O have/O sought/O refuge/O and/O where/O they/O undergo/O training/O ./O
Weapons/O can/O easily/O be/O brought/O into/O China/LOCATION ./O
And/O as/O long/O as/O Beijing/LOCATION does/O not/O want/O to/O cross/O the/O border/O the/O source/O of/O weapons/O and/O ammunition/O will/O not/O run/O dry/O ./O
The/O president/O 's/O remarks/O earlier/O this/O year/O about/O how/O the/O Chinese/O public/O must/O build/O a/O ``/O wall/O of/O bronze/O and/O iron/O ''/O to/O fight/O terrorism/O ,/O and/O ``/O make/O terrorists/O become/O like/O rats/O scurrying/O across/O a/O street/O ,/O with/O everybody/O shouting/O `/O beat/O them/O '/O ,/O ''/O did/O not/O bode/O well/O ./O
The/O new/O draft/O law/O ,/O however/O ,/O shows/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O not/O about/O to/O act/O recklessly/O ./O
It/O contains/O a/O clause/O stating/O that/O soldiers/O and/O armed/O police/O should/O only/O be/O deployed/O to/O countries/O whose/O governments/O have/O agreed/O to/O the/O operation/O ./O
It/O is/O therefore/O highly/O unlikely/O that/O Chinese/O special/O forces/O will/O soon/O be/O showing/O up/O uninvited/O in/O foreign/O countries/O alongside/O US/LOCATION Seals/O ,/O or/O that/O Chinese/O drones/O will/O start/O violating/O foreign/O airspace/O ,/O as/O American/O ones/O do/O ./O
Not/O for/O the/O time/O being/O ,/O anyway/O ./O
One/O of/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O leading/O experts/O on/O China/LOCATION ,/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON has/O lived/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O 20/O years/O ./O
