Following/O in/O the/O footsteps/O of/O neighboring/O Honk/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O activist/O groups/O in/O Macau/LOCATION are/O planning/O to/O hold/O their/O own/O pro-democracy/O referendum/O ./O
But/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O likely/O to/O do/O what/O it/O can/O to/O prevent/O the/O vote/O ,/O Rebecca/PERSON Liao/PERSON tells/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
In/O what/O could/O prove/O to/O be/O one/O of/O the/O biggest/O challenges/O to/O Chinese/O authority/O yet/O ,/O three/O activist/O groups/O in/O Macau/LOCATION ,/O a/O special/O administrative/O region/O of/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O world/O 's/O biggest/O gambling/O hub/O ,/O are/O planning/O to/O hold/O an/O unofficial/O referendum/O on/O electoral/O reform/O ./O
The/O announcement/O came/O in/O the/O wake/O of/O a/O similar/O referendum/O in/O nearby/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION where/O more/O than/O 10/O percent/O of/O the/O city/O 's/O population/O voted/O for/O the/O public/O to/O be/O able/O to/O nominate/O candidates/O for/O the/O territory/O 's/O top/O position/O ./O
The/O former/O Portuguese/O colony/O -/O returned/O to/O China/LOCATION in/O 1999/O -/O has/O a/O legal/O and/O economic/O system/O separate/O from/O the/O mainland/O ./O
But/O just/O as/O in/O nearby/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O Macau/LOCATION 's/O chief/O executive/O is/O not/O chosen/O by/O universal/O suffrage/O ,/O but/O by/O an/O electoral/O committee/O made/O up/O of/O 400/O ,/O mostly/O pro-Beijing/O ,/O residents/O ./O
In/O their/O poll/O slated/O to/O run/O between/O August/O 24/O and/O August/O 30/O -/O just/O ahead/O of/O the/O election/O for/O chief/O executive/O on/O August/O 31/O -/O the/O activist/O groups/O say/O they/O want/O to/O ask/O Macau/LOCATION 's/O residents/O questions/O ,/O including/O whether/O there/O should/O be/O universal/O suffrage/O for/O the/O 2019/O chief/O executive/O elections/O and/O how/O confident/O voters/O are/O in/O the/O sole/O candidate/O Fernando/PERSON Chui/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O been/O in/O the/O position/O since/O 2009/O ./O
But/O the/O move/O has/O already/O been/O slammed/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION as/O ``/O illegal/O ./O ''/O
In/O a/O DW/ORGANIZATION interview/O ,/O Rebecca/PERSON Liao/PERSON ,/O a/O corporate/O attorney/O and/O writer/O specialized/O in/O Chinese/O politics/O and/O culture/O ,/O says/O that/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O '/O ultimate/O fear/O is/O that/O a/O successful/O attempt/O by/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION and/O Macau/LOCATION to/O politically/O distance/O themselves/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION would/O also/O embolden/O pro-democracy/O activists/O on/O the/O mainland/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION :/O After/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O now/O the/O special/O administrative/O region/O of/O Macau/LOCATION is/O planning/O a/O referendum/O on/O democracy/O ,/O is/O this/O a/O new/O headache/O for/O Beijing/LOCATION ?/O
Rebecca/PERSON Liao/PERSON :/O Absolutely/O ./O
Historically/O ,/O Taiwan/LOCATION ,/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION have/O presented/O the/O greatest/O challenges/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O political/O control/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O ultimate/O fear/O is/O that/O pro-democracy/O activists/O on/O the/O mainland/O will/O be/O emboldened/O ,/O if/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION and/O Macau/LOCATION succeed/O in/O securing/O greater/O democratic/O freedom/O ,/O says/O Liao/PERSON
While/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O aware/O since/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O handover/O in/O 1997/O that/O the/O ``/O one/O country/O ,/O two/O systems/O ''/O solution/O would/O come/O to/O a/O head/O one/O day/O since/O it/O satisfies/O neither/O the/O mainland/O 's/O desire/O for/O complete/O reunification/O nor/O the/O former/O colony/O 's/O insistence/O on/O its/O democratic/O way/O of/O life/O ,/O it/O has/O not/O been/O prepared/O for/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O open/O protest/O in/O the/O last/O few/O years/O ./O
As/O for/O Macau/LOCATION ,/O the/O region/O 's/O populace/O is/O generally/O apathetic/O about/O politics/O ,/O and/O so/O its/O sudden/O mobilization/O comes/O as/O an/O even/O greater/O shock/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION has/O responded/O with/O harsh/O words/O ,/O from/O editorials/O in/O its/O prominent/O newspapers/O to/O a/O white/O paper/O warning/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION to/O tread/O lightly/O in/O defense/O of/O its/O autonomy/O ./O
It/O is/O telling/O ,/O however/O ,/O that/O the/O only/O concrete/O action/O taken/O so/O far/O against/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION referendum/O has/O been/O the/O arrest/O of/O five/O organizers/O of/O a/O sit-in/O a/O few/O days/O after/O ./O
China/LOCATION is/O concerned/O and/O alarmed/O at/O the/O open/O rebellion/O ,/O but/O it/O has/O stayed/O its/O hand/O so/O far/O ./O
Most/O likely/O ,/O it/O recognizes/O escalation/O is/O not/O wise/O at/O this/O point/O ,/O nor/O necessary/O ./O
The/O economies/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION and/O Macau/LOCATION are/O too/O dependent/O on/O business/O from/O the/O mainland/O ./O
What/O would/O the/O Macau/LOCATION referendum/O symbolize/O ?/O
The/O Macau/LOCATION and/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION referenda/O are/O motivated/O by/O completely/O different/O concerns/O ./O
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION sees/O mainland/O China/LOCATION encroaching/O on/O its/O way/O of/O life/O and/O reneging/O on/O the/O promises/O of/O democracy/O made/O during/O the/O handover/O ./O
The/O Macanese/O ,/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O are/O angry/O about/O increasing/O income/O inequality/O and/O corruption/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION recommends/O
AI/ORGANIZATION :/O HK/LOCATION mass/O arrests/O send/O `/O disturbing/O signal/O for/O future/O protests/O '/O
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION police/O arrested/O over/O 500/O protesters/O who/O staged/O a/O sit-in/O after/O a/O pro-democracy/O rally/O ,/O described/O as/O the/O city/O 's/O largest/O in/O years/O ./O
In/O a/O DW/ORGANIZATION interview/O ,/O AI/ORGANIZATION 's/O Mabel/PERSON Au/PERSON slams/O the/O police/O action/O as/O hasty/O and/O unnecessary/O ./O
-LRB-/O 02.07.2014/O -RRB-/O
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O pro-democracy/O movement/O gains/O momentum/O
Waving/O colonial-era/O flags/O ,/O tens/O of/O thousands/O of/O pro-democracy/O protesters/O have/O staged/O a/O massive/O rally/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION demanding/O full/O electoral/O freedom/O ./O
But/O will/O this/O be/O enough/O for/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O back/O down/O ?/O
-LRB-/O 01.07.2014/O -RRB-/O
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION rally/O sends/O `/O clear/O message/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION '/O
Thousands/O of/O Hong/O Kongers/O have/O taken/O to/O the/O streets/O to/O show/O their/O support/O for/O democratic/O reform/O ./O
Professor/O Joseph/PERSON Cheng/PERSON ,/O who/O took/O part/O in/O the/O rally/O ,/O tells/O DW/ORGANIZATION the/O high/O turnout/O is/O proof/O of/O people/O 's/O desire/O for/O democracy/O ./O
-LRB-/O 01.07.2014/O -RRB-/O
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION referendum/O reflects/O `/O people/O want/O democracy/O '/O
Over/O 700,000/O Hong/O Kongers/O have/O cast/O their/O ballots/O in/O an/O unofficial/O referendum/O on/O democratic/O reform/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION calls/O a/O farce/O ./O
Analyst/O Joseph/PERSON Cheng/PERSON tells/O DW/ORGANIZATION Beijing/LOCATION fears/O the/O vote/O may/O set/O a/O precedent/O for/O other/O regions/O ./O
-LRB-/O 23.06.2014/O -RRB-/O
For/O them/O ,/O it/O can/O still/O be/O said/O that/O democracy/O is/O a/O means/O to/O an/O end/O ,/O not/O a/O sacred/O right/O ./O
If/O their/O referendum/O focuses/O the/O government/O 's/O attention/O on/O improving/O their/O living/O standards/O ,/O they/O will/O probably/O be/O pretty/O satisfied/O ./O
What/O kind/O of/O people/O are/O behind/O these/O civic/O movements/O both/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION and/O Macau/LOCATION ?/O
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O pro-democracy/O movements/O are/O led/O by/O activists/O whose/O main/O goals/O are/O to/O promote/O the/O region/O 's/O autonomy/O and/O push/O for/O greater/O democracy/O ,/O rule/O of/O law/O and/O press/O freedoms/O ./O
Political/O movements/O are/O relatively/O new/O in/O Macau/LOCATION ,/O and/O so/O they/O are/O organized/O by/O more/O eclectic/O groups/O of/O civil/O society/O organizations/O ./O
How/O are/O Chinese/O authorities/O likely/O to/O react/O to/O a/O referendum/O in/O Macau/LOCATION ?/O
Chinese/O authorities/O ,/O including/O Macau/LOCATION 's/O government/O ,/O have/O condemned/O the/O referendum/O as/O illegal/O and/O unconstitutional/O ./O
It/O 's/O likely/O that/O negotiations/O are/O beginning/O to/O happen/O behind/O the/O scenes/O between/O the/O local/O government/O and/O the/O organizers/O to/O prevent/O the/O referendum/O from/O taking/O place/O ./O
Should/O the/O referendum/O go/O through/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O likely/O to/O ignore/O the/O results/O and/O repeat/O its/O current/O rhetoric/O ./O
This/O has/O been/O the/O strategy/O for/O dealing/O with/O unrest/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O and/O it/O may/O be/O sufficient/O for/O this/O latest/O development/O in/O Macau/LOCATION ./O
What/O Beijing/LOCATION must/O realize/O soon/O ,/O however/O ,/O is/O that/O its/O understanding/O of/O the/O situation/O is/O completely/O different/O from/O that/O of/O the/O Hong/O Konger/O or/O the/O Macanese/O ./O
For/O mainland/O China/LOCATION ,/O those/O living/O in/O the/O former/O colonies/O are/O Chinese/O and/O should/O be/O grateful/O to/O have/O been/O reunited/O with/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION ./O
This/O demand/O for/O self-governance/O and/O barely/O concealed/O nostalgia/O for/O colonial/O rule/O is/O absolutely/O mystifying/O ./O
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION and/O Macau/LOCATION ,/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O do/O not/O see/O this/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O patriotism/O ,/O but/O of/O trust/O ./O
Unlike/O Taiwan/LOCATION ,/O neither/O will/O ever/O deny/O that/O it/O is/O a/O part/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O
However/O ,/O certain/O agreements/O vis-a-vis/O autonomy/O have/O been/O made/O ,/O and/O profound/O cultural/O and/O political/O differences/O should/O be/O respected/O ./O
How/O similar/O to/O and/O how/O different/O from/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION is/O Macau/LOCATION ,/O in/O terms/O of/O its/O legal/O system/O and/O political/O system/O ?/O
Both/O are/O afforded/O greater/O press/O and/O political/O freedoms/O than/O the/O mainland/O ./O
Each/O has/O a/O committee/O of/O elites/O stacked/O with/O pro-Beijing/O conservatives/O that/O elect/O the/O chief/O executives/O ./O
Importantly/O ,/O however/O ,/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O Basic/O Law/O explicitly/O calls/O for/O universal/O suffrage/O by/O 2017/O ./O
Macau/LOCATION possesses/O no/O such/O legal/O right/O to/O the/O vote/O ./O
Tens/O of/O thousands/O turn/O out/O for/O pro-democracy/O protest/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION
Beijing/LOCATION was/O quick/O to/O slam/O the/O referendum/O as/O illegal/O ./O
What/O is/O Beijing/LOCATION mainly/O concerned/O about/O ?/O
Beijing/LOCATION does/O not/O want/O to/O lose/O control/O of/O its/O special/O administrative/O regions/O ./O
Political/O self-determination/O on/O the/O level/O demanded/O by/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION and/O Macau/LOCATION referenda/O will/O be/O interpreted/O by/O the/O mainland/O as/O a/O near-declaration/O of/O independence/O and/O an/O attack/O on/O China/LOCATION 's/O sovereignty/O by/O foreign/O -LRB-/O i.e./O Western/O -RRB-/O powers/O sympathetic/O to/O democratic/O movements/O and/O eager/O to/O contain/O the/O country/O 's/O growing/O power/O ./O
The/O ultimate/O fear/O is/O that/O if/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION and/O Macau/LOCATION succeed/O in/O distancing/O themselves/O further/O from/O the/O mainland/O and/O securing/O greater/O democratic/O freedom/O ,/O pro-democracy/O activists/O on/O the/O mainland/O will/O be/O emboldened/O as/O well/O ./O
Rebecca/PERSON Liao/PERSON is/O a/O corporate/O attorney/O and/O writer/O based/O in/O Silicon/LOCATION Valley/LOCATION ,/O focusing/O on/O Chinese/O politics/O and/O culture/O ./O
