Despite/O human/O rights/O concerns/O ,/O a/O deal/O has/O been/O signed/O that/O will/O see/O refugees/O who/O sought/O asylum/O in/O Australia/LOCATION resettled/O in/O Cambodia/LOCATION instead/O ;/O a/O move/O regarded/O by/O AI/ORGANIZATION 's/O Rupert/PERSON Abbott/PERSON as/O violating/O human/O rights/O obligations/O ./O
The/O deal/O was/O signed/O by/O Australian/O Immigration/O Minister/O Scott/PERSON Morrison/PERSON and/O Cambodian/O Interior/O Minister/O Sar/PERSON Kheng/PERSON on/O Friday/O ,/O September/O 26/O ,/O to/O resettle/O an/O unspecified/O number/O of/O refugees/O currently/O held/O at/O an/O Australian-run/O detention/O camp/O on/O the/O tiny/O Pacific/LOCATION island/O nation/O of/O Nauru/LOCATION ./O
Most/O of/O the/O detainees/O arrived/O by/O boat/O from/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION and/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O
Under/O the/O deal/O ,/O Australia/LOCATION will/O pay/O Cambodia/LOCATION 35/O million/O USD/O over/O four/O years/O ,/O plus/O carry/O the/O costs/O of/O resettlement/O ;/O a/O move/O by/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O conservative/O government/O to/O deter/O asylum/O seekers/O from/O reaching/O the/O country/O ./O
Australia/LOCATION 's/O conservative/O government/O has/O been/O facing/O growing/O international/O scrutiny/O over/O its/O policy/O of/O turning/O back/O boats/O carrying/O potential/O refugees/O ./O
Rupert/PERSON Abbott/PERSON ,/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION 's/O -LRB-/O AI/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O Deputy/O Asia/LOCATION Pacific/LOCATION Director/O ,/O says/O in/O a/O DW/ORGANIZATION interview/O that/O the/O relocation/O of/O refugees/O by/O Australia/LOCATION to/O Nauru/LOCATION and/O then/O on/O to/O Cambodia/LOCATION is/O a/O blatant/O violation/O of/O international/O law/O as/O it/O puts/O the/O lives/O of/O asylum/O seekers/O at/O risk/O for/O the/O sake/O of/O short-term/O political/O interests/O ./O
Abbott/PERSON :/O `/O We/O are/O calling/O for/O the/O Cambodian/O and/O Australian/O governments/O to/O cancel/O this/O poorly/O considered/O agreement/O '/O DW/ORGANIZATION :/O Why/O is/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O asylum/O seeker/O resettlement/O deal/O with/O Cambodia/LOCATION so/O controversial/O ?/O
Rupert/PERSON Abbott/PERSON :/O The/O deal/O puts/O the/O short-term/O political/O interests/O of/O the/O Australian/O government/O ahead/O of/O the/O protection/O of/O people/O seeking/O protection/O from/O persecution/O in/O their/O home/O countries/O ./O
It/O 's/O a/O new/O low/O in/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O already/O inhumane/O and/O deplorable/O treatment/O of/O asylum/O seekers/O and/O refugees/O ./O
The/O relocation/O of/O refugees/O is/O a/O blatant/O violation/O of/O international/O law/O ,/O particularly/O the/O Refugee/O Convention/O ,/O which/O obliges/O Australia/LOCATION to/O process/O and/O host/O refugees/O who/O arrive/O in/O its/O territory/O or/O come/O within/O its/O effective/O control/O ,/O for/O example/O if/O they/O are/O intercepted/O at/O sea/O by/O Australia/LOCATION ./O
Australia/LOCATION has/O the/O capacity/O to/O take/O in/O these/O refugees/O ,/O while/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O there/O are/O significant/O concerns/O about/O Cambodia/LOCATION 's/O capacity/O to/O provide/O the/O legal/O protections/O ,/O support/O and/O services/O that/O refugees/O need/O to/O live/O a/O safe/O ,/O stable/O life/O ,/O particularly/O given/O the/O country/O 's/O own/O troubling/O track/O record/O on/O human/O rights/O ./O
Why/O is/O Cambodia/LOCATION regarded/O as/O an/O unsafe/O third/O country/O for/O refugees/O ?/O
Cambodia/LOCATION has/O a/O chequered/O record/O in/O protecting/O and/O supporting/O refugees/O ./O
In/O December/O 2009/O ,/O it/O received/O almost/O universal/O condemnation/O when/O it/O forcibly/O returned/O a/O group/O of/O 20/O ethnic/O Uighur/O asylum/O seekers/O ,/O including/O a/O pregnant/O woman/O and/O two/O children/O ,/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O
Cambodia/LOCATION 's/O existing/O population/O of/O 70/O refugees/O has/O limited/O rights/O and/O support/O services/O ./O
The/O agreement/O with/O Australia/LOCATION also/O comes/O at/O a/O troubling/O time/O for/O human/O rights/O in/O Cambodia/LOCATION ,/O a/O situation/O that/O Australia/LOCATION itself/O has/O criticized/O ./O
Since/O a/O violent/O crackdown/O by/O security/O forces/O on/O striking/O workers/O and/O activists/O in/O January/O this/O year/O saw/O at/O least/O four/O people/O killed/O ,/O scores/O injured/O and/O one/O boy/O left/O apparently/O disappeared/O ,/O the/O rights/O to/O freedom/O of/O expression/O and/O peaceful/O assembly/O have/O been/O increasingly/O ignored/O ./O
Peaceful/O assemblies/O by/O workers/O ,/O land/O activists/O ,/O human/O rights/O defenders/O and/O opposition/O party/O supporters/O are/O regularly/O broken/O up/O or/O denied/O altogether/O ./O
Why/O did/O Phnom/LOCATION Penh/LOCATION agree/O to/O sign/O the/O controversial/O deal/O ?/O
DW/ORGANIZATION recommends/O
Australia/LOCATION -/O Cambodia/LOCATION refugee/O resettlement/O deal/O slammed/O by/O rights/O groups/O
-LRB-/O 26.09.2014/O -RRB-/O
Refugee/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION calls/O on/O Canberra/LOCATION to/O release/O `/O all/O children/O from/O detention/O '/O
The/O Australian/O government/O has/O defended/O its/O continued/O detention/O of/O asylum/O seeker/O children/O in/O camps/O ,/O a/O policy/O which/O Refugee/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION CEO/O Paul/PERSON Power/PERSON says/O in/O a/O DW/ORGANIZATION interview/O `/O unquestionably/O '/O breaches/O children/O 's/O rights/O ./O
-LRB-/O 22.08.2014/O -RRB-/O
No/O place/O to/O go/O for/O asylum/O seekers/O in/O Australia/LOCATION
Long/O before/O Sri/O Lankan/O asylum/O seekers/O reach/O their/O destination/O ,/O Australian/O navy/O boats/O stop/O them/O ,/O refuse/O their/O asylum/O requests/O ,/O and/O send/O them/O back/O home/O ./O
But/O there/O is/O growing/O resistance/O against/O this/O policy/O ./O
-LRB-/O 12.07.2014/O -RRB-/O
Asylum/O seekers/O in/O Australia/LOCATION raise/O their/O voices/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O treatment/O of/O asylum/O seekers/O ,/O including/O its/O policy/O of/O turning/O back/O boats/O at/O sea/O ,/O is/O under/O scrutiny/O ./O
Those/O who/O do/O reach/O Australia/LOCATION face/O new/O obstacles/O ,/O but/O a/O unique/O choir/O is/O helping/O them/O make/O their/O voices/O heard/O ./O
-LRB-/O 11.07.2014/O -RRB-/O
Under/O the/O memorandum/O of/O understanding/O ,/O the/O Australian/O government/O will/O cover/O all/O costs/O related/O to/O the/O relocation/O of/O refugees/O to/O Cambodia/LOCATION ./O
In/O addition/O ,/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O aid/O to/O Cambodia/LOCATION will/O apparently/O increase/O by/O 40/O million/O AUD/O -LRB-/O 35/O million/O USD/O -RRB-/O over/O four/O years/O ./O
There/O is/O a/O clear/O financial/O incentive/O for/O Cambodia/LOCATION ./O
For/O the/O Australian/O government/O ,/O it/O is/O an/O opportunity/O to/O further/O deter/O refugees/O from/O seeking/O asylum/O in/O Australia/LOCATION ./O
Why/O do/O you/O claim/O there/O is/O a/O lack/O of/O transparency/O over/O the/O terms/O of/O the/O agreement/O ?/O
No/O details/O of/O the/O terms/O of/O the/O deal/O were/O released/O until/O after/O it/O had/O been/O signed/O ,/O and/O no/O consultation/O was/O carried/O out/O with/O civil/O society/O in/O either/O country/O ,/O independent/O human/O rights/O organizations/O ,/O affected/O communities/O or/O the/O people/O of/O Cambodia/LOCATION or/O Australia/LOCATION ./O
As/O far/O as/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION is/O aware/O ,/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION High/O Commissioner/O for/O Refugees/O ,/O though/O referred/O to/O in/O the/O agreement/O ,/O was/O not/O consulted/O on/O the/O deal/O -/O indeed/O ,/O it/O has/O publicly/O condemned/O it/O ./O
This/O lack/O of/O transparency/O is/O unacceptable/O when/O dealing/O with/O the/O human/O rights/O and/O lives/O of/O men/O ,/O women/O and/O children/O ./O
How/O would/O the/O deal/O make/O Cambodia/LOCATION complicit/O in/O what/O you/O regard/O as/O ``/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O human/O rights/O breaches/O and/O seriously/O flawed/O offshore/O processing/O system/O ''/O ?/O
The/O relocation/O of/O refugees/O by/O Australia/LOCATION to/O Nauru/LOCATION and/O then/O on/O to/O Cambodia/LOCATION ,/O violates/O the/O Refugee/O Convention/O ,/O which/O obliges/O Australia/LOCATION to/O process/O and/O host/O refugees/O who/O arrive/O in/O its/O territory/O ./O
The/O offshore/O processing/O system/O ,/O in/O which/O Cambodia/LOCATION is/O set/O to/O participate/O ,/O has/O seen/O asylum/O seekers/O '/O human/O rights/O routinely/O violated/O ./O
For/O example/O ,/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION 's/O research/O has/O revealed/O that/O conditions/O for/O asylum/O seekers/O at/O the/O Australian-run/O detention/O center/O on/O Papua/LOCATION New/LOCATION Guinea/LOCATION 's/O Manus/LOCATION Island/LOCATION were/O harsh/O ,/O humiliating/O and/O designed/O to/O pressure/O asylum/O seekers/O to/O return/O to/O the/O countries/O they/O had/O fled/O ./O
Who/O will/O be/O the/O people/O taken/O to/O Cambodia/LOCATION and/O what/O will/O await/O them/O there/O ?/O
The/O agreement/O states/O that/O a/O small/O number/O of/O refugees/O will/O be/O relocated/O from/O Nauru/LOCATION to/O Cambodia/LOCATION on/O a/O trial/O basis/O ,/O with/O an/O unspecified/O number/O being/O transferred/O later/O depending/O on/O Cambodia/LOCATION 's/O capacity/O to/O support/O them/O ./O
It/O is/O not/O clear/O what/O life/O will/O be/O like/O for/O these/O refugees/O in/O Cambodia/LOCATION ./O
The/O 70/O refugees/O already/O living/O in/O Cambodia/LOCATION are/O denied/O some/O freedoms/O ,/O necessary/O documentation/O and/O pathways/O to/O citizenship/O ./O
While/O the/O agreement/O says/O that/O a/O range/O of/O documentation/O ,/O support/O and/O services/O will/O be/O provided/O to/O the/O relocated/O refugees/O ,/O which/O to/O some/O extent/O match/O UN/ORGANIZATION standards/O ,/O the/O Australian/O Government/O has/O a/O poor/O record/O of/O ensuring/O that/O its/O practices/O meet/O the/O standards/O it/O puts/O on/O paper/O ./O
Australia/LOCATION will/O be/O complicit/O in/O any/O human/O rights/O violations/O that/O the/O refugees/O relocated/O to/O Cambodia/LOCATION may/O suffer/O ./O
Abbott/PERSON :/O `/O There/O is/O a/O clear/O financial/O incentive/O for/O Cambodia/LOCATION '/O This/O not/O the/O first/O time/O Australia/LOCATION has/O made/O a/O controversial/O resettlement/O deal/O with/O a/O neighboring/O country/O ./O
What/O are/O you/O calling/O for/O ?/O
We/O are/O calling/O for/O the/O Cambodian/O and/O Australian/O governments/O to/O cancel/O this/O poorly/O considered/O agreement/O ,/O and/O for/O Australia/LOCATION to/O process/O and/O offer/O protection/O to/O all/O refugees/O who/O seek/O protection/O in/O its/O territory/O or/O who/O fall/O under/O its/O effective/O control/O ,/O for/O example/O those/O whose/O boats/O are/O intercepted/O at/O sea/O by/O Australia/LOCATION ./O
It/O 's/O crucial/O that/O Australia/LOCATION ,/O Nauru/LOCATION and/O Papua/LOCATION New/LOCATION Guinea/LOCATION end/O the/O offshore/O detention/O of/O asylum/O seekers/O -/O a/O harsh/O ,/O humiliating/O policy/O practiced/O by/O no/O other/O governments/O in/O the/O world/O ./O
The/O Australian/O government/O should/O instead/O work/O with/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION High/O Commissioner/O for/O Refugees/O ,/O other/O governments/O in/O the/O Asia-Pacific/LOCATION region/O and/O civil/O society/O groups/O to/O develop/O a/O regional/O solution/O which/O genuinely/O protects/O the/O rights/O of/O asylum/O seekers/O and/O refugees/O ,/O in/O line/O with/O international/O human/O rights/O and/O refugee/O law/O ./O
Rupert/PERSON Abbott/PERSON is/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION 's/O Deputy/O Asia/LOCATION Pacific/LOCATION Director/O ./O
