The/O Norwegian/O capital/O could/O n't/O secure/O the/O full/O backing/O of/O its/O Conservative-led/O government/O for/O a/O bid/O for/O the/O 2022/O Winter/O Games/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION and/O Almaty/LOCATION are/O the/O two/O remaining/O bidders/O ./O
Norwegian/O capital/O Oslo/LOCATION has/O decided/O not/O to/O bid/O for/O the/O 2022/O Winter/O Olympic/O Games/O ,/O citing/O finances/O as/O its/O sole/O reason/O for/O withdrawing/O ./O
Only/O China/LOCATION 's/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION 's/O Almaty/LOCATION remain/O in/O the/O running/O for/O host/O city/O status/O ./O
Norway/LOCATION has/O a/O proud/O connection/O to/O the/O Winter/O Olympics/O ,/O winning/O more/O medals/O than/O any/O other/O country/O ,/O whilst/O hosting/O the/O event/O on/O two/O occasions/O in/O 1952/O and/O 1994/O ./O
The/O country/O 's/O Conservative/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION has/O been/O split/O on/O whether/O to/O sanction/O 35/O billion/O kroner/O -LRB-/O $/O 5.4/O billion/O -RRB-/O in/O funding/O to/O support/O the/O bid/O for/O the/O event/O ./O
``/O There/O is/O n't/O a/O big/O enough/O support/O to/O carry/O out/O such/O a/O big/O project/O ,/O ''/O Prime/O Minister/O Erna/PERSON Solberg/PERSON told/O Norwegian/O public/O broadcaster/O NRK/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O We/O 've/O received/O clear/O advice/O and/O there/O is/O no/O reason/O not/O to/O follow/O this/O advice/O ./O
A/O big/O project/O like/O this/O ,/O which/O is/O so/O expensive/O ,/O requires/O broad/O popular/O support/O and/O there/O is/O n't/O enough/O support/O for/O it/O ./O ''/O
Christoph/PERSON Dubi/PERSON ,/O meanwhile/O ,/O the/O IOC/ORGANIZATION 's/O -LRB-/O International/ORGANIZATION Olympic/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O Executive/O Director/O for/O the/O Games/O ,/O accused/O the/O Norwegian/O parliament/O of/O not/O briefing/O its/O politicians/O on/O the/O full/O details/O of/O Oslo/LOCATION 's/O potential/O bid/O ./O
``/O This/O is/O a/O missed/O opportunity/O for/O the/O city/O of/O Oslo/LOCATION and/O for/O all/O the/O people/O of/O Norway/LOCATION who/O are/O known/O worldwide/O for/O being/O huge/O fans/O of/O winter/O sports/O ,/O ''/O said/O Dubi/PERSON in/O a/O statement/O ./O
``/O And/O it/O is/O mostly/O a/O missed/O opportunity/O for/O the/O outstanding/O Norwegian/O athletes/O who/O will/O not/O be/O able/O to/O reach/O new/O Olympic/O heights/O in/O their/O home/O country/O ./O ''/O
Sochi/LOCATION 's/O Winter/O Games/O were/O the/O most/O expensive/O in/O history/O
Oslo/LOCATION follows/O Stockholm/LOCATION -LRB-/O Sweden/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O Krakow/LOCATION -LRB-/O Poland/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O Lviv/LOCATION -LRB-/O Ukraine/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O Munich/LOCATION -LRB-/O Germany/LOCATION -RRB-/O and/O St/LOCATION Moritz/LOCATION -LRB-/O Switzerland/LOCATION -RRB-/O in/O withdrawing/O plans/O to/O host/O the/O Winter/O Olympics/O in/O 2022/O ./O
What/O next/O ?/O
It/O 's/O another/O blow/O for/O the/O reputation/O of/O the/O IOC/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O Winter/O Olympics/O with/O both/O China/LOCATION and/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION breaching/O human/O rights/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O HRW/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O
Kazakhstan/LOCATION 's/O human/O rights/O record/O has/O sharply/O deteriorated/O in/O recent/O years/O with/O ``/O authorities/O cracking/O down/O on/O free/O speech/O ./O ''/O
China/LOCATION 's/O human/O rights/O record/O falls/O into/O the/O spotlight/O after/O already/O hosting/O the/O 2008/O Olympic/O Games/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION with/O little/O social/O and/O political/O benefits/O materializing/O ./O
The/O ``/O authoritarian/O ''/O government/O carries/O ``/O repressive/O policies/O in/O ethnic/O minority/O areas/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O and/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION ,/O ''/O according/O to/O HRW/ORGANIZATION ,/O with/O the/O spotlight/O currently/O on/O the/O handling/O of/O public/O protests/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ./O
The/O IOC/ORGANIZATION moved/O last/O month/O to/O crackdown/O on/O `/O anti-discriminatory/O policies/O '/O in/O or/O around/O future/O events/O with/O the/O addition/O of/O a/O new/O binding/O clause/O added/O to/O contracts/O between/O the/O IOC/ORGANIZATION and/O budding/O host/O cities/O ./O
``/O An/O express/O reference/O was/O included/O to/O the/O prohibition/O of/O any/O form/O of/O discrimination/O ,/O using/O the/O wording/O of/O Fundamental/O Principle/O Six/O of/O the/O Olympic/O Charter/O ,/O ''/O Budi/PERSON said/O ./O
Chapter/O Six/O reads/O that/O ,/O ``/O any/O form/O of/O discrimination/O with/O regards/O to/O a/O country/O or/O a/O person/O on/O grounds/O of/O race/O ,/O religion/O ,/O politics/O ,/O gender/O or/O otherwise/O is/O incompatible/O with/O belonging/O to/O the/O Olympic/O Movement/O ./O ''/O
The/O bidders/O for/O the/O 2022/O Games/O have/O until/O January/O 7/O ,/O 2015/O to/O submit/O official/O bids/O before/O evaluations/O of/O each/O candidate/O take/O place/O in/O February/O and/O March/O ./O
A/O final/O decision/O will/O be/O taken/O by/O the/O IOC/ORGANIZATION in/O July/O ,/O 2015/O in/O Kuala/LOCATION Lumpur/LOCATION ,/O Malaysia/LOCATION ./O
rd/msh/O -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O dpa/O -RRB-/O
