China/LOCATION has/O been/O a/O mere/O spectator/O during/O the/O decades-long/O conflict/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
However/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O been/O playing/O a/O more/O active/O role/O recently/O ;/O an/O approach/O welcomed/O by/O the/O recently/O elected/O Afghan/O President/O Ashraf/PERSON Ghani/PERSON ./O
Ghani/PERSON 's/O first/O overseas/O trip/O has/O led/O him/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O
The/O Afghan/O president/O -LRB-/O main/O picture/O ,/O right/O -RRB-/O was/O greeted/O by/O his/O Chinese/O counterpart/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON in/O Beijing/LOCATION on/O Tuesday/O ,/O October/O 28/O ./O
The/O last/O day/O of/O his/O four-day/O trip/O to/O the/O neighboring/O country/O coincides/O with/O the/O Fourth/ORGANIZATION Ministerial/ORGANIZATION Conference/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Istanbul/ORGANIZATION Process/ORGANIZATION on/O Afghanistan/LOCATION which/O is/O set/O to/O bring/O together/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O 14/O neighbors/O ,/O including/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O Turkey/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION ./O
The/O aim/O of/O the/O initiative/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O to/O promote/O a/O stable/O development/O of/O the/O South/O Asian/O nation/O ./O
According/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O state-run/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O meeting/O has/O special/O significance/O ,/O as/O it/O is/O ``/O the/O first/O international/O meeting/O on/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O first/O since/O the/O change/O of/O government/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O ''/O
Beijing/LOCATION has/O gradually/O increased/O its/O engagement/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION since/O 2012/O ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O former/O head/O of/O internal/O security/O ,/O Zhou/PERSON Yongkang/PERSON ,/O traveled/O to/O Kabul/LOCATION ,/O with/O both/O governments/O agreeing/O ,/O among/O other/O things/O ,/O to/O the/O training/O of/O 300/O Afghan/O police/O officers/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
Former/O Afghan/O President/O Hamid/PERSON Karzai/PERSON visited/O Beijing/LOCATION in/O 2010/O after/O his/O controversial/O re-election/O
Beijing/LOCATION wants/O secure/O borders/O
As/O the/O withdrawal/O of/O ISAF/ORGANIZATION combat/O troops/O approaches/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION now/O has/O to/O consider/O the/O possibility/O that/O the/O already/O precarious/O political/O and/O security/O situation/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION might/O further/O deteriorate/O ./O
``/O For/O China/LOCATION ,/O geopolitics/O plays/O a/O major/O role/O ,/O ''/O says/O Pan/PERSON Zhiping/PERSON ,/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Academy/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Social/ORGANIZATION Sciences/ORGANIZATION in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
``/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O stability/O is/O important/O for/O China/LOCATION 's/O security/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION wants/O to/O prevent/O that/O Uighur/O extremists/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION receive/O any/O assistance/O from/O ``/O like-minded/O people/O ''/O located/O in/O border/O areas/O ,/O especially/O in/O terms/O of/O logistics/O ,/O propaganda/O and/O personnel/O ./O
Back/O in/O the/O days/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION had/O established/O contact/O with/O the/O militants/O seeking/O a/O guarantee/O that/O no/O attacks/O by/O Uighur/O separatists/O would/O be/O launched/O from/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
Talks/O with/O the/O Taliban/LOCATION
Beijing/LOCATION has/O kept/O this/O pragmatic/O approach/O towards/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION to/O this/O day/O ,/O Jochen/PERSON Hippler/PERSON ,/O political/O scientist/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Duisburg-Essen/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O Should/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION indicate/O that/O they/O are/O ready/O to/O cooperate/O with/O China/LOCATION economically/O ,/O then/O Chinese/O condemnation/O of/O the/O militant/O group/O will/O likely/O be/O mild/O or/O even/O non-existent/O ./O
But/O if/O Beijing/LOCATION finds/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION to/O be/O an/O obstacle/O to/O the/O exploitation/O of/O Afghan/O mineral/O resources/O -/O or/O even/O potential/O supporters/O of/O Muslim/O militants/O in/O China/LOCATION -/O then/O they/O will/O be/O rejected/O ,/O ''/O said/O Hippler/PERSON ./O
The/O Chinese/O mining/O company/O MCC/ORGANIZATION is/O in/O charge/O of/O exploiting/O the/O copper/O mine/O in/O Mes/LOCATION Aynak/LOCATION
However/O ,/O that/O does/O not/O mean/O that/O China/LOCATION will/O get/O engaged/O militarily/O to/O fill/O the/O security/O vacuum/O left/O by/O the/O NATO/ORGANIZATION troop/O drawdown/O ./O
``/O Whoever/O sends/O soldiers/O to/O such/O a/O complicated/O country/O ,/O will/O soon/O find/O itself/O in/O trouble/O ,/O ''/O said/O Pan/PERSON Zhiping/PERSON ,/O referring/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O view/O of/O the/O issue/O ./O
Instead/O ,/O China/LOCATION will/O seek/O to/O stabilize/O the/O Ghani/PERSON government/O through/O economic/O development/O and/O regional/O initiatives/O such/O as/O the/O ``/O Istanbul/ORGANIZATION Process/ORGANIZATION ./O ''/O
New/O partners/O
From/O Kabul/LOCATION 's/O perspective/O ,/O the/O expansion/O of/O economic/O relations/O with/O China/LOCATION and/O cooperation/O in/O the/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O are/O just/O two/O sides/O of/O the/O same/O coin/O ./O
``/O China/LOCATION can/O play/O an/O important/O role/O to/O achieve/O peace/O and/O security/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Ghani/PERSON 's/O spokesman/O Fayeq/PERSON Wahedi/PERSON told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O We/O see/O China/LOCATION both/O as/O a/O neighbor/O and/O regional/O power/O which/O can/O support/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O all/O areas/O ,/O including/O the/O economy/O ,/O trade/O and/O security/O ./O ''/O
Terrorism/O is/O now/O a/O common/O threat/O to/O both/O the/O countries/O ,/O so/O it/O is/O important/O that/O the/O two/O cooperate/O to/O that/O end/O ,/O ''/O the/O spokesman/O added/O ./O
Political/O scientist/O Hippler/PERSON believes/O that/O Kabul/LOCATION 's/O rapprochement/O with/O China/LOCATION following/O the/O withdrawal/O of/O NATO/ORGANIZATION forces/O is/O only/O logical/O ./O
``/O Ghani/PERSON wants/O to/O reduce/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O strong/O dependency/O on/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O other/O NATO/ORGANIZATION countries/O ./O
Moreover/O ,/O China/LOCATION -/O unlike/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION -/O is/O politically/O flexible/O and/O will/O not/O burden/O the/O Afghans/O with/O issues/O of/O ``/O good/O governance/O ''/O as/O long/O as/O economic/O ties/O flourish/O ,/O ''/O said/O Hippler/PERSON ./O
Risky/O investments/O
Afghanistan/LOCATION needs/O foreign/O investment/O and/O could/O use/O its/O vast/O untapped/O natural/O resources/O to/O this/O end/O ./O
An/O agreement/O with/O China/LOCATION on/O the/O exploitation/O of/O a/O copper/O mine/O in/O Mes/LOCATION Aynak/LOCATION in/O Logar/LOCATION Province/LOCATION ,/O south/O of/O Kabul/LOCATION ,/O has/O been/O in/O place/O since/O 2007/O ./O
However/O ,/O due/O to/O the/O precarious/O security/O situation/O and/O lack/O of/O infrastructure/O ,/O the/O multibillion-dollar/O project/O is/O currently/O on/O hold/O ./O
The/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION have/O stepped/O up/O their/O campaign/O of/O terror/O following/O the/O inauguration/O of/O President/O Ghani/PERSON
A/O delegation/O of/O the/O Chinese/O mining/O company/O MCC/ORGANIZATION ,/O responsible/O for/O the/O mine/O ,/O traveled/O to/O Kabul/LOCATION in/O September/O ./O
But/O while/O both/O sides/O expressed/O their/O intention/O to/O hold/O on/O to/O the/O project/O ,/O they/O acknowledged/O some/O difficulties/O ./O
But/O this/O is/O not/O the/O only/O Chinese/O project/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
The/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Petrochemical/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION CNPC/ORGANIZATION has/O been/O extracting/O oil/O from/O the/O Amu/LOCATION Darya/LOCATION basin/O on/O the/O border/O with/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION ./O
However/O ,/O there/O is/O an/O ongoing/O dispute/O between/O the/O Afghan/O authorities/O and/O Chinese/O contractors/O over/O cost/O ./O
The/O mining/O technology/O dates/O back/O to/O Soviet/LOCATION times/O ./O
Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION expert/O Pan/PERSON Zhiping/PERSON says/O that/O economic/O cooperation/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O should/O be/O regarded/O as/O a/O long-term/O project/O ,/O adding/O that/O stability/O will/O be/O the/O prerequisite/O for/O economic/O development/O ./O
``/O While/O Chinese/O leaders/O are/O interested/O in/O the/O mineral/O resources/O ,/O they/O will/O have/O to/O wait/O until/O the/O situation/O stabilizes/O and/O the/O Afghan/O government/O has/O the/O situation/O under/O control/O ,/O ''/O Zhiping/PERSON told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
