Washington/LOCATION has/O renewed/O its/O call/O for/O China/LOCATION to/O release/O a/O Christian/O rights/O activist/O and/O an/O underage/O boy/O suspected/O to/O be/O under/O house/O arrest/O ./O
Secretary/O of/O State/O John/PERSON Kerry/PERSON attacked/O China/LOCATION for/O imprisoning/O people/O without/O cause/O ./O
The/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION on/O Wednesday/O called/O on/O China/LOCATION to/O release/O human/O rights/O lawyer/O Zhang/PERSON Kai/PERSON and/O said/O it/O was/O concerned/O by/O reports/O that/O the/O son/O of/O another/O detained/O rights/O lawyer/O had/O been/O put/O under/O house/O arrest/O ./O
In/O releasing/O the/O State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION 's/O annual/O International/O Religious/O Freedom/O Report/O ,/O US/LOCATION Secretary/O of/O State/O John/PERSON Kerry/PERSON said/O Zhang/PERSON ,/O a/O Chinese/O Christian/O ,/O was/O detained/O shortly/O before/O a/O meeting/O in/O August/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION ambassador/O for/O international/O religious/O freedom/O ,/O who/O was/O visiting/O China/LOCATION at/O the/O time/O ./O
The/O US/LOCATION envoy/O told/O reporters/O in/O Washington/LOCATION that/O three/O human/O rights/O lawyers/O ,/O four/O pastors/O and/O three/O or/O four/O other/O activists/O had/O been/O detained/O before/O he/O could/O meet/O them/O ./O
``/O I/O urge/O the/O release/O of/O men/O and/O women/O detained/O or/O imprisoned/O anywhere/O in/O the/O world/O for/O the/O peaceful/O expression/O and/O practice/O of/O their/O religious/O beliefs/O ,/O ''/O Kerry/PERSON told/O reporters/O ./O
``/O This/O includes/O Mr./O Zhang/PERSON Kai/PERSON ,/O a/O Chinese/O Christian/O human/O rights/O lawyer/O who/O was/O detained/O in/O late/O August/O just/O prior/O to/O a/O scheduled/O meeting/O with/O Ambassador/O -LSB-/O David/PERSON -RSB-/O Saperstein/PERSON ,/O and/O whose/O present/O whereabouts/O are/O unknown/O ./O ''/O
Teenage/O boy/O suspected/O under/O house/O arrest/O
Separately/O ,/O the/O State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION said/O it/O was/O concerned/O with/O reports/O that/O Bao/PERSON Zhuoxuan/PERSON ,/O the/O 16-year-old/O son/O of/O detained/O rights/O lawyer/O Wang/PERSON Yu/PERSON and/O her/O detained/O husband/O Bao/PERSON Longjun/PERSON ,/O had/O been/O put/O under/O house/O arrest/O in/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION ./O
Human/O right/O lawyer/O Wang/PERSON Yu/PERSON was/O put/O under/O arrest/O earlier/O this/O year/O
Wang/PERSON Yu/PERSON ,/O a/O lawyer/O at/O the/O Fengrui/ORGANIZATION law/O firm/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O which/O defends/O prominent/O dissidents/O such/O as/O Uighur/O economist/O Ilham/U_PERSON Tohti/U_PERSON ,/O was/O rounded/O up/O with/O her/O husband/O and/O son/O by/O state/O authorities/O in/O June/O ./O
Her/O son/O was/O later/O released/O but/O was/O barred/O from/O travel/O ./O
``/O We/O urge/O China/LOCATION to/O uphold/O its/O international/O human/O rights/O commitments/O and/O protect/O the/O health/O and/O safety/O of/O this/O minor/O child/O ,/O ''/O State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O John/PERSON Kirby/PERSON said/O in/O a/O statement/O ./O
He/O added/O that/O China/LOCATION should/O allow/O Bao/PERSON to/O leave/O the/O country/O and/O to/O study/O overseas/O as/O his/O family/O wanted/O ./O
Kirby/PERSON said/O that/O the/O US/LOCATION was/O ``/O disturbed/O by/O a/O seemingly/O systematic/O campaign/O by/O China/LOCATION to/O target/O family/O members/O of/O Chinese/O citizens/O who/O peacefully/O challenge/O official/O policy/O and/O work/O to/O protect/O the/O rights/O of/O others/O ./O ''/O
Since/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON came/O to/O power/O in/O 2013/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O taken/O a/O harder/O line/O towards/O civil/O and/O religious/O society/O ./O
More/O than/O 200/O lawyers/O and/O activists/O ,/O including/O Zhang/PERSON ,/O were/O questioned/O or/O detained/O in/O July/O as/O part/O of/O a/O sweeping/O nationwide/O crackdown/O ./O
The/O move/O has/O been/O condemned/O by/O many/O foreign/O governments/O ./O
ss/cmk/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O dpa/O ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
