A/O strong/O earthquake/O has/O hit/O China/LOCATION 's/O far/O western/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O killing/O and/O injuring/O several/O people/O ,/O Chinese/O officials/O say/O ./O
The/O region/O has/O a/O mainly/O ethnic/O Uighur/O population/O ./O
The/O epicenter/O of/O the/O shallow/O 6.4-magnitude/O earthquake/O was/O in/O Pishan/U_LOCATION county/O ,/O about/O 160/O km/O -LRB-/O 100/O miles/O -RRB-/O northwest/O of/O the/O southern/O city/O of/O Hotan/U_LOCATION ,/O the/O US/ORGANIZATION Geological/ORGANIZATION Survey/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O
``/O Currently/O ,/O the/O earthquake/O has/O resulted/O in/O three/O deaths/O ,/O including/O a/O father/O and/O son/O ,/O and/O more/O than/O 20/O injuries/O ,/O ''/O China/ORGANIZATION National/ORGANIZATION Emergency/ORGANIZATION Broadcasting/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CNEB/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O said/O on/O its/O website/O ./O
According/O to/O the/O China/ORGANIZATION Earthquake/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O deaths/O occurred/O in/O Pishan/U_LOCATION ,/O which/O has/O a/O population/O of/O 258,000/O ,/O mostly/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O ,/O an/O ethnic/O minority/O within/O China/LOCATION ./O
The/O USGS/ORGANIZATION said/O the/O earthquake/O was/O just/O 20/O kilometers/O deep/O ,/O and/O initially/O gave/O the/O magnitude/O as/O 6.1/O ./O
The/O China/ORGANIZATION Earthquake/ORGANIZATION Network/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION put/O the/O magnitude/O at/O 6.5/O ./O
The/O initial/O quake/O was/O followed/O by/O a/O series/O of/O aftershocks/O ,/O with/O the/O strongest/O measuring/O 4.8/O ./O
Several/O traditional/O houses/O were/O reported/O to/O have/O collapsed/O ./O
China/LOCATION is/O regularly/O hit/O by/O earthquakes/O ,/O with/O the/O southwestern/O provinces/O of/O Sichuan/LOCATION and/O Yunnan/LOCATION being/O particularly/O prone/O ./O
In/O May/O 2008/O ,/O almost/O 70,000/O people/O in/O Sichuan/LOCATION were/O killed/O by/O a/O 7.9/O magnitude/O quake/O there/O ,/O while/O 600/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O a/O 6.1/O magnitude/O quake/O in/O Yunnan/LOCATION last/O August/O ./O
Authorities/O say/O they/O are/O optimistic/O that/O the/O death/O toll/O in/O Friday/O 's/O quake/O would/O not/O be/O high/O ,/O as/O the/O region/O is/O relatively/O sparsely/O populated/O ./O
tj/kms/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
