China/LOCATION 's/O new/O anti-terrorism/O laws/O ,/O likely/O to/O be/O passed/O the/O end/O of/O this/O month/O ,/O would/O pose/O further/O restrictions/O on/O media/O freedom/O and/O freedom/O of/O speech/O ,/O analysts/O have/O told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O top/O legislative/O body/O ,/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O NPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O is/O currently/O reviewing/O the/O third/O draft/O of/O the/O law/O ,/O which/O was/O first/O proposed/O in/O October/O last/O year/O ./O
The/O NPC/ORGANIZATION Standing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION 's/O current/O meeting/O is/O set/O to/O end/O this/O Sunday/O ,/O and/O according/O to/O state/O media/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O package/O of/O laws/O is/O ``/O already/O quite/O mature/O ''/O and/O is/O likely/O to/O be/O passed/O ./O
New/O clause/O addressing/O individuals/O
The/O new/O draft/O of/O the/O law/O includes/O a/O provision/O stating/O that/O ``/O no/O institutions/O or/O individuals/O ''/O shall/O report/O or/O disseminate/O details/O of/O terrorist/O activities/O that/O might/O lead/O to/O ``/O imitation/O ./O ''/O
It/O would/O also/O prohibit/O people/O from/O publishing/O scenes/O of/O ``/O cruelty/O and/O inhumanity/O ''/O in/O terrorist/O activities/O ./O
Xinhua/ORGANIZATION reported/O that/O the/O clause/O was/O especially/O revised/O from/O the/O previous/O draft/O to/O restrict/O the/O distribution/O of/O terrorism-related/O information/O by/O individual/O users/O on/O social/O media/O ./O
``/O The/O law/O raises/O serious/O concerns/O about/O restriction/O on/O freedom/O of/O expression/O ,/O as/O the/O definition/O of/O terrorism/O in/O China/LOCATION is/O vague/O and/O broad/O ,/O ''/O Patrick/PERSON Poon/PERSON China/LOCATION researcher/O of/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
Reporting/O or/O discussing/O restless/O states/O like/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION could/O become/O more/O risky/O once/O the/O laws/O pass/O
``/O It/O would/O expose/O NGOs/O and/O individuals/O who/O talk/O about/O terrorism-related/O issues/O such/O as/O the/O situation/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION Uighur/U_LOCATION Autonomous/U_LOCATION Region/U_LOCATION ,/O ''/O Poon/PERSON added/O ,/O referring/O to/O particularly/O restless/O state/O in/O China/LOCATION with/O a/O high/O proportion/O of/O Muslim/O Uighur/O inhabitants/O ./O
Broad/O definitions/O ,/O and/O implications/O Terrorism/O ,/O as/O defined/O by/O the/O new/O draft/O law/O ,/O refers/O to/O ``/O any/O proposition/O or/O activity/O -/O that/O ,/O by/O means/O of/O violence/O ,/O sabotage/O or/O threat/O ,/O generates/O social/O panic/O ,/O undermines/O public/O security/O ,/O infringes/O on/O personal/O and/O property/O rights/O ,/O and/O menaces/O government/O organs/O and/O international/O organization/O -/O with/O the/O aim/O to/O realize/O certain/O political/O and/O ideological/O purpose/O ./O ''/O
This/O definition/O has/O drawn/O criticism/O from/O analysts/O and/O human/O rights/O groups/O ./O
``/O Terrorism/O here/O is/O defined/O in/O very/O vague/O terms/O ,/O ''/O Moritz/PERSON Rudolf/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O terrorism/O at/O the/O Berlin-based/O Mercator/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O MERICS/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O In/O accordance/O with/O the/O draft/O ,/O a/O single/O tweet/O which/O causes/O an/O outcry/O on/O social/O media/O could/O be/O classified/O as/O an/O act/O of/O terrorism/O ./O ''/O
DW/ORGANIZATION recommends/O
Amnesty/ORGANIZATION :/O China/LOCATION 's/O draft/O anti-terror/O law/O `/O contravenes/O international/O human/O rights/O law/O '/O
The/O overly/O broad/O definition/O of/O extremism/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O proposed/O anti-terrorism/O law/O could/O mean/O that/O almost/O any/O behavior/O or/O speech/O that/O the/O government/O dislikes/O could/O qualify/O as/O ``/O extremism/O ,/O ''/O AI/ORGANIZATION 's/O William/PERSON Nee/PERSON tells/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O -LRB-/O 05.03.2015/O -RRB-/O
Chinese/O rights/O lawyer/O avoids/O prison/O time/O with/O three-year/O suspended/O sentence/O
A/O Chinese/O court/O has/O given/O prominent/O human/O rights/O lawyer/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON a/O suspended/O three-year/O sentence/O for/O making/O comments/O critical/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O
The/O ruling/O will/O likely/O keep/O him/O out/O of/O prison/O for/O now/O ./O -LRB-/O 22.12.2015/O -RRB-/O
Apart/O from/O the/O problematic/O definition/O of/O ``/O terrorism/O ,/O ''/O Sophie/PERSON Richardson/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION director/O at/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O DW/ORGANIZATION that/O there/O is/O also/O a/O need/O to/O define/O the/O meaning/O of/O ``/O generating/O social/O panic/O ./O ''/O
``/O When/O such/O harsh/O consequences/O flow/O from/O such/O vaguely-defined/O laws/O ,/O it/O leaves/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ,/O already/O deeply/O dismissive/O of/O basic/O human/O rights/O protection/O ,/O all/O the/O more/O room/O to/O violate/O rights/O ,/O ''/O says/O Richardson/PERSON ./O
More/O infringement/O on/O freedom/O of/O speech/O
Analyst/O Rudolf/PERSON also/O said/O the/O new/O laws/O would/O make/O it/O more/O difficult/O for/O media/O to/O report/O on/O terrorist/O incidents/O ,/O as/O they/O include/O a/O clause/O stating/O that/O only/O outlets/O approved/O by/O the/O state/O 's/O counterterrorism/O authorities/O can/O disseminate/O information/O about/O hostages/O or/O any/O reaction/O plans/O from/O the/O authorities/O ./O
As/O the/O use/O of/O social/O media/O to/O express/O one/O 's/O opinions/O has/O been/O more/O common/O in/O the/O country/O ,/O observers/O fear/O the/O laws/O could/O be/O turned/O against/O rights/O activists/O ./O
At/O an/O estimated/O 668/O million/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O online/O population/O is/O the/O world/O 's/O largest/O
``/O The/O new/O law/O would/O even/O legitimize/O the/O currently/O vaguely-defined/O criminal/O charges/O against/O dissidents/O ,/O such/O as/O inciting/O subversion/O of/O state/O power/O and/O separatism/O ,/O ''/O says/O Poon/PERSON ./O
``/O Anyone/O can/O easily/O fall/O into/O this/O trap/O if/O she/O or/O he/O posted/O comments/O like/O what/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON did/O ./O ''/O
Human/O rights/O lawyer/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON was/O found/O guilty/O of/O ``/O inciting/O ethnic/O hatred/O ''/O and/O ``/O picking/O quarrels/O and/O provoking/O trouble/O ``/O early/O on/O Tuesday/O ,/O for/O his/O comments/O on/O social/O media/O over/O China/LOCATION 's/O ethnic/O policies/O and/O criticism/O of/O officials/O ./O
He/O was/O given/O a/O three-year/O suspended/O sentence/O ./O
``/O The/O latest/O amendment/O is/O especially/O disturbing/O ,/O given/O the/O incredibly/O harsh/O penalties/O that/O could/O be/O handed/O down/O under/O the/O new/O law/O ,/O ''/O HRW/ORGANIZATION 's/O Richardson/PERSON added/O ./O
International/O criticism/O
The/O latest/O draft/O also/O included/O a/O provision/O of/O clauses/O that/O require/O telecommunication/O and/O Internet/O service/O providers/O to/O install/O special/O so-called/O ``/O backdoors/O ''/O in/O their/O software/O ,/O enabling/O government/O access/O ./O
They/O are/O required/O to/O provide/O Beijing/LOCATION with/O their/O encryption/O keys/O ,/O so/O that/O the/O Chinese/O government/O can/O ``/O prevent/O ''/O and/O ``/O investigate/O ''/O terrorist/O activities/O ./O
These/O clauses/O ,/O which/O are/O applied/O to/O both/O domestic/O and/O foreign/O firms/O ,/O were/O already/O established/O in/O its/O initial/O draft/O ,/O and/O have/O drawn/O criticism/O ./O
US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON said/O earlier/O this/O year/O ,/O after/O the/O new/O laws/O '/O second/O reading/O ,/O that/O he/O had/O raised/O concerns/O with/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O and/O urged/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O change/O the/O law/O ./O
Yet/O no/O such/O changes/O were/O seen/O in/O the/O latest/O draft/O ./O
