Often/O portrayed/O as/O a/O challenge/O to/O a/O Western-led/O order/O ,/O this/O year/O 's/O simultaneous/O SCO/ORGANIZATION and/O BRICS/ORGANIZATION summits/O are/O set/O to/O reveal/O Chinese/O and/O Russian/O plans/O for/O closer/O political/O and/O economic/O engagement/O in/O Eurasia/LOCATION ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION examines/O ./O
With/O a/O broad/O range/O of/O issues/O on/O the/O agenda/O -/O from/O the/O war/O on/O terror/O to/O economic/O development/O -/O Russian/O President/O Vladimir/PERSON Putin/PERSON will/O be/O hosting/O both/O the/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Organization/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SCO/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O and/O BRICS/ORGANIZATION summits/O -LRB-/O an/O acronym/O standing/O for/O Brazil/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O India/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION and/O South/LOCATION Africa/LOCATION -RRB-/O on/O 9-10/O July/O in/O the/O Russian/O city/O of/O Ufa/LOCATION ./O
Often/O seen/O as/O either/O too/O politically/O divided/O to/O warrant/O attention/O or/O ,/O alternatively/O ,/O considered/O as/O posing/O a/O great/O challenge/O to/O the/O Western-dominated/O world/O order/O ,/O analysts/O believe/O the/O upcoming/O summits/O will/O offer/O an/O opportunity/O for/O both/O Russia/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION to/O showcase/O both/O their/O resilience/O and/O intentions/O to/O play/O an/O increasing/O role/O in/O global/O financing/O and/O international/O politics/O ./O
The/O SCO/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O groups/O China/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ,/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O Tajikistan/LOCATION and/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION ,/O is/O expected/O to/O announce/O a/O rare/O expansion/O ,/O with/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION -LRB-/O two/O of/O currently/O six/O states/O with/O ``/O observer/O status/O ''/O -RRB-/O on/O schedule/O to/O become/O new/O members/O -/O the/O first/O countries/O outside/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION since/O the/O institution/O was/O founded/O in/O 2001/O ./O
Analysts/O argue/O that/O this/O year/O 's/O meetings/O -/O which/O come/O amid/O a/O series/O of/O crises/O ,/O including/O a/O worsening/O security/O environment/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O the/O volatile/O situation/O in/O Ukraine/LOCATION -/O will/O demonstrate/O the/O fact/O that/O ,/O despite/O all/O the/O differences/O between/O the/O countries/O involved/O ,/O there/O are/O aspects/O where/O they/O agree/O and/O where/O experts/O see/O room/O for/O tangible/O progress/O ./O
Block-building/O So/O what/O exactly/O do/O Russia/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION want/O ?/O
``/O There/O seems/O to/O be/O an/O attempt/O to/O boost/O cooperation/O between/O the/O SCO/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O BRICS/ORGANIZATION ./O
Especially/O a/O 90-minute/O session/O between/O the/O leaders/O of/O the/O Eurasian/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O EEU/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O BRICS/ORGANIZATION and/O SCO/ORGANIZATION as/O well/O as/O from/O Azerbaijan/LOCATION and/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION ,/O is/O a/O sign/O that/O Russia/LOCATION is/O aiming/O for/O political/O block-building/O ,/O ''/O Moritz/PERSON Rudolf/PERSON ,/O a/O China/LOCATION foreign/O policy/O expert/O at/O the/O Berlin-based/O Mercator/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O MERICS/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
SCO/ORGANIZATION and/O BRICS/ORGANIZATION member/O states/O are/O among/O the/O largest/O shareholders/O in/O the/O newly/O established/O AIIB/ORGANIZATION
The/O BRICS/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O SCO/ORGANIZATION are/O widely/O viewed/O as/O the/O two/O most/O prominent/O non-western/O groupings/O at/O the/O moment/O ,/O so/O the/O alignment/O of/O the/O meetings/O will/O tend/O to/O place/O even/O greater/O emphasis/O on/O some/O important/O trends/O such/O as/O China/LOCATION 's/O grand/O ambitions/O to/O reshape/O the/O economic/O geography/O of/O Eurasia/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O rise/O of/O new/O non-western/O financing/O and/O development/O institutions/O ./O
For/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O an/O increased/O focus/O on/O the/O region/O is/O likely/O to/O not/O only/O strengthen/O its/O ties/O with/O these/O states/O ,/O but/O also/O help/O to/O ease/O the/O pressure/O it/O is/O feeling/O to/O its/O east/O and/O south/O over/O territorial/O disputes/O with/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O Vietnam/LOCATION and/O the/O Philippines/LOCATION ./O
Russia/LOCATION ,/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O will/O likely/O use/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O summits/O will/O be/O held/O simultaneously/O to/O send/O a/O diplomatic/O response/O to/O Western/O attempts/O to/O politically/O isolate/O Russia/LOCATION ./O
``/O Hosting/O the/O heads/O of/O state/O from/O the/O most/O important/O emerging/O countries/O is/O a/O clear/O sign/O that/O Russia/LOCATION has/O not/O been/O completely/O isolated/O after/O all/O ,/O ''/O said/O Rudolf/PERSON ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O `/O Silk/U_LOCATION Road/U_LOCATION '/O In/O terms/O of/O economic/O development/O ,/O the/O BRICS/ORGANIZATION recently/O launched/O their/O New/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O the/O members/O of/O the/O two/O groups/O are/O also/O among/O the/O largest/O shareholders/O in/O the/O newly/O established/O China-led/O Asian/ORGANIZATION Infrastructure/ORGANIZATION Investment/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O AIIB/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O placing/O financing/O and/O infrastructure/O plans/O high/O on/O the/O agenda/O of/O the/O two-day/O summits/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION recommends/O
Trade/O and/O investment/O -/O New/O priorities/O for/O Asian-African/O ties/O
At/O a/O summit/O in/O Indonesia/LOCATION ,/O leaders/O of/O Asia/LOCATION and/O Africa/LOCATION have/O pledged/O to/O cooperate/O more/O closely/O and/O called/O for/O a/O financial/O world/O order/O more/O open/O to/O their/O emerging/O economies/O ./O
But/O is/O this/O a/O relationship/O between/O equal/O partners/O ?/O
-LRB-/O 23.04.2015/O -RRB-/O
How/O China-led/O banks/O could/O help/O plug/O Asia/LOCATION 's/O infrastructure/O gap/O The/O new/O China-led/O financial/O institutions/O are/O set/O to/O provide/O funding/O for/O infrastructure/O projects/O in/O underdeveloped/O Asian/O countries/O ./O
But/O how/O badly/O is/O regional/O development/O financing/O needed/O ?/O
DW/ORGANIZATION speaks/O to/O WRI/ORGANIZATION 's/O Denise/PERSON Leung/PERSON ./O
-LRB-/O 15.04.2015/O -RRB-/O
Russia/LOCATION 's/O pivot/O to/O Asia/LOCATION -/O A/O Sino-Russian/O Entente/O ?/O
The/O rupture/O between/O Russia/LOCATION and/O the/O West/LOCATION stemming/O from/O the/O Ukraine/LOCATION crisis/O has/O led/O Moscow/LOCATION to/O expand/O ties/O with/O Asia/LOCATION ,/O especially/O China/LOCATION ./O
Dmitri/PERSON Trenin/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O Carnegie/ORGANIZATION Moscow/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION ,/O talks/O to/O DW/ORGANIZATION about/O the/O implications/O ./O
-LRB-/O 15.04.2015/O -RRB-/O
A/O look/O at/O the/O new/O China-led/O financial/O institutions/O Touted/O as/O alternatives/O to/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION and/O IMF/ORGANIZATION ,/O many/O nations/O seek/O to/O join/O China-led/O financial/O institutions/O such/O as/O the/O AIIB/ORGANIZATION ./O
But/O what/O do/O they/O offer/O and/O what/O challenges/O do/O they/O face/O ?/O
DW/ORGANIZATION speaks/O to/O economist/O Rajiv/PERSON Biswas/PERSON ./O
-LRB-/O 20.03.2015/O -RRB-/O
Draft/O law/O `/O underscores/O China/LOCATION 's/O concern/O to/O protect/O overseas/O interests/O '/O
As/O China/LOCATION 's/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION gets/O underway/O ,/O lawmakers/O may/O decide/O on/O allowing/O armed/O forces/O to/O be/O deployed/O abroad/O to/O counter/O terrorism/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION talks/O to/O analyst/O Andrew/PERSON Scobell/PERSON about/O the/O draft/O law/O and/O its/O implications/O ./O
-LRB-/O 05.03.2015/O -RRB-/O
In/O fact/O ,/O China/LOCATION will/O be/O looking/O to/O consolidate/O support/O for/O its/O ambitious/O Silk/U_LOCATION Road/U_LOCATION schemes/O ,/O the/O so-called/O ``/O One/U_LOCATION Belt/U_LOCATION ,/U_LOCATION One/U_LOCATION Road/U_LOCATION Initiative/O ''/O which/O composes/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON 's/O signature/O foreign/O policy/O initiative/O ,/O as/O Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON ,/O a/O fellow/O with/O the/O Asia/LOCATION program/O of/O German/ORGANIZATION Marshall/ORGANIZATION Fund/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O Many/O of/O the/O new/O financing/O instruments/O that/O the/O summits/O will/O showcase/O are/O going/O to/O be/O directly/O involved/O in/O these/O plans/O ,/O and/O a/O number/O of/O the/O infrastructure/O projects/O under/O discussion/O will/O fall/O under/O the/O auspices/O of/O the/O scheme/O ./O
The/O SCO/ORGANIZATION 's/O members/O and/O observers/O compose/O almost/O all/O the/O important/O countries/O along/O the/O land/O routes/O running/O from/O China/LOCATION to/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O making/O it/O the/O ideal/O setting/O for/O many/O of/O these/O discussions/O ./O ''/O
Analyst/O Rudolf/PERSON has/O a/O similar/O view/O :/O ``/O Formally/O linking/O the/O `/O Silk/U_LOCATION Road/U_LOCATION Economic/U_LOCATION Belt/U_LOCATION '/O with/O the/O EEU/ORGANIZATION under/O the/O SCO/ORGANIZATION umbrella/O is/O one/O of/O the/O primary/O goals/O of/O Xi/PERSON 's/O Ufa/LOCATION visit/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION will/O encourage/O BRICS/ORGANIZATION states/O to/O endorse/O its/O initiative/O ,/O possibly/O in/O return/O for/O generous/O infrastructure/O investments/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O other/O likely/O outcomes/O on/O the/O economic/O front/O will/O be/O additional/O incremental/O steps/O to/O remove/O obstacles/O for/O interregional/O border/O trade/O ./O
The/O Chinese/O leadership/O also/O seems/O set/O on/O strengthening/O the/O economic/O dimension/O of/O the/O SCO/ORGANIZATION ./O
There/O has/O been/O talk/O of/O establishing/O a/O SCO/ORGANIZATION development/O bank/O -/O about/O which/O Russia/LOCATION had/O formerly/O been/O skeptical/O ./O
``/O Generally/O speaking/O China/LOCATION considers/O the/O BRICS/ORGANIZATION and/O SCO/ORGANIZATION groupings/O as/O important/O parallel-structures/O to/O existing/O US-led/O institutions/O ./O
Strengthening/O these/O institutions/O will/O help/O Beijing/LOCATION in/O its/O pursuit/O to/O establish/O a/O multi-polar/O world/O ,/O ''/O said/O the/O MERICS/ORGANIZATION expert/O ./O
Moreover/O ,/O the/O BRICS/ORGANIZATION may/O advance/O cautiously/O on/O other/O elements/O of/O an/O agenda/O designed/O to/O strengthen/O the/O non-western-led/O financial/O system/O ,/O including/O an/O alternative/O to/O SWIFT/O -LRB-/O the/O Belgium-based/O secure/O messaging/O system/O that/O facilitates/O cross-border/O financial/O transactions/O -RRB-/O aimed/O at/O reducing/O dependencies/O from/O the/O West/LOCATION ./O
China/LOCATION could/O also/O propose/O more/O application/O of/O local/O currencies/O in/O intra-BRICS/O trade/O and/O even/O the/O financial/O fate/O of/O Greece/LOCATION may/O feature/O in/O the/O discussions/O ,/O say/O analysts/O ./O
Security/O concerns/O
But/O in/O order/O to/O achieve/O these/O economic/O goals/O ,/O there/O are/O a/O number/O of/O security/O concerns/O that/O first/O need/O to/O be/O addressed/O ./O
China/LOCATION ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O is/O keen/O on/O stabilizing/O its/O western/O periphery/O in/O order/O to/O minimize/O the/O spillover/O of/O militant/O threats/O into/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O and/O developing/O alternative/O transportation/O corridors/O that/O reduce/O its/O exposure/O to/O key/O maritime/O routes/O ./O
``/O China/LOCATION 's/O hope/O is/O that/O a/O grand-scale/O set/O of/O infrastructure/O investments/O will/O help/O to/O develop/O its/O western/O provinces/O ,/O build/O new/O markets/O ,/O outsource/O excess/O industrial/O capacity/O ,/O provide/O more/O viable/O economic/O connections/O to/O its/O major/O markets/O and/O resource/O suppliers/O ,/O and/O bring/O development/O to/O an/O unstable/O arc/O of/O countries/O -/O quite/O a/O challenge/O ,/O ''/O said/O analyst/O Small/PERSON ./O
This/O is/O why/O ,/O given/O the/O spread/O of/O the/O ``/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION ''/O to/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION will/O also/O be/O looking/O to/O have/O the/O SCO/ORGANIZATION step/O up/O its/O involvement/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O particularly/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION following/O the/O NATO/ORGANIZATION drawdown/O and/O an/O increase/O in/O deadly/O attacks/O by/O the/O militant/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION throughout/O the/O war-torn/O nation/O ./O
Russia/LOCATION 's/O plans/O are/O less/O dramatic/O -/O it/O has/O less/O money/O to/O play/O with/O -/O and/O its/O security/O goals/O are/O more/O about/O retaining/O Russian/O influence/O than/O stabilizing/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
But/O while/O there/O may/O be/O differences/O in/O the/O two/O nations/O '/O security/O concerns/O in/O Eurasia/LOCATION ,/O analyst/O Small/PERSON explains/O that/O Russia/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION have/O always/O seen/O the/O SCO/ORGANIZATION as/O a/O vehicle/O for/O consolidating/O their/O political/O model/O -/O still/O perhaps/O the/O most/O important/O ultimate/O security/O objective/O for/O the/O leadership/O in/O both/O capitals/O ./O
Cooperation/O or/O competition/O ?/O
But/O are/O these/O countries/O better/O off/O following/O the/O Chinese/O or/O Russian/O model/O ?/O
Given/O that/O most/O Central/O Asian/O states/O are/O known/O to/O act/O pragmatically/O when/O pursuing/O their/O own/O political/O and/O economic/O ambitions/O ,/O analysts/O argue/O it/O does/O n't/O make/O that/O much/O of/O a/O difference/O whether/O they/O decide/O for/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O or/O Moscow/LOCATION 's/O development/O model/O ./O
India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION are/O expected/O to/O become/O new/O members/O of/O the/O SCO/ORGANIZATION grouping/O this/O year/O
``/O While/O countries/O may/O benefit/O from/O Chinese/O investments/O ,/O especially/O in/O the/O infrastructure/O sector/O ,/O they/O also/O profit/O from/O better/O trade-conditions/O with/O Russia/LOCATION as/O members/O of/O the/O EEU/ORGANIZATION ./O
In/O terms/O of/O investments/O and/O loans/O China/LOCATION has/O more/O to/O offer/O than/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O Rudolf/PERSON ,/O adding/O that/O improving/O ties/O with/O either/O Beijing/LOCATION or/O Moscow/LOCATION can/O also/O turn/O into/O a/O valuable/O bargaining/O chip/O for/O these/O countries/O vis-à-vis/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O
``/O This/O ,/O in/O turn/O ,/O can/O lead/O to/O more/O attention/O by/O the/O West/LOCATION ,/O and/O result/O in/O more/O economic/O support/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O
And/O while/O there/O may/O have/O been/O discreet/O tensions/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION over/O the/O Silk/U_LOCATION Road/U_LOCATION schemes/O and/O the/O EEU/ORGANIZATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O challenged/O economic/O circumstances/O have/O forced/O the/O country/O into/O a/O closer/O embrace/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O
There/O are/O already/O a/O host/O of/O indications/O that/O the/O rupture/O between/O Russia/LOCATION and/O the/O West/LOCATION stemming/O from/O the/O Ukraine/LOCATION crisis/O has/O led/O Moscow/LOCATION to/O look/O east/O and/O expand/O ties/O with/O Asia/LOCATION ,/O especially/O China/LOCATION ./O
This/O became/O clear/O with/O President/O Vladimir/PERSON Putin/PERSON 's/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION on/O May/O 20/O ,/O during/O which/O a/O multi-billion/O dollar/O gas/O supply/O deal/O was/O signed/O ,/O among/O other/O things/O ./O
``/O Moscow/LOCATION 's/O approach/O has/O been/O provisionally/O to/O acquiesce/O to/O the/O Chinese/O initiative/O ./O
In/O some/O respects/O there/O is/O an/O even/O greater/O risk/O that/O if/O Russia/LOCATION treats/O the/O projects/O purely/O as/O competitors/O ,/O the/O EEU/ORGANIZATION will/O be/O weakened/O even/O more/O quickly/O than/O if/O it/O bandwagons/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O agenda/O ./O
Russia/LOCATION is/O also/O set/O to/O benefit/O from/O Chinese/O investments/O that/O will/O support/O many/O of/O its/O own/O infrastructure/O plans/O ,/O ''/O said/O Small/PERSON ./O
