US/LOCATION Secretary/O of/O State/O John/PERSON Kerry/PERSON has/O arrived/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION on/O a/O five-nation/O tour/O to/O reassure/O ex-Soviet/O republics/O of/O US/LOCATION interest/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O
Human/O rights/O groups/O demand/O that/O he/O call/O for/O an/O end/O to/O repressive/O regimes/O ./O
Kerry/PERSON arrived/O Saturday/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O facing/O economic/O slumps/O and/O fears/O of/O social/O unrest/O following/O earnings/O declines/O for/O the/O region/O 's/O oil/O exporters/O and/O the/O withdrawal/O of/O all/O but/O remnant/O US-led/O forces/O from/O neighboring/O Afghanistan/LOCATION to/O the/O south/O ./O
Analysts/O see/O the/O ex-Soviet/O republics/O as/O the/O latest/O venue/O of/O geopolitical/O rivalry/O between/O Washington/LOCATION and/O Moscow/LOCATION -/O alongside/O Ukraine/LOCATION and/O Syria/LOCATION -/O amid/O NATO/ORGANIZATION doubts/O over/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O global/O intentions/O and/O the/O Kremlin/LOCATION 's/O bid/O to/O tackle/O what/O it/O perceives/O as/O local/O Islamist/O insurgency/O ./O
Until/O last/O year/O ,/O the/O US/LOCATION ran/O a/O massive/O air/O base/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O which/O served/O as/O a/O ``/O northern/O distribution/O network/O ''/O for/O NATO/ORGANIZATION troops/O sent/O to/O fight/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O back/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O government/O ./O
New/O campus/O
In/O the/O Kyrgyz/O capital/O Bishkek/LOCATION ,/O Kerry/PERSON was/O due/O to/O open/O the/O campus/O of/O a/O new/O American/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION and/O a/O new/O US/LOCATION embassy/O compound/O ./O
A/O US/LOCATION official/O traveling/O with/O Kerry/PERSON described/O Kyrgystan/LOCATION 's/O recent/O election/O as/O ``/O very/O robust/O ''/O and/O ``/O competitive/O ''/O and/O played/O down/O doubts/O among/O foreign/O observers/O ./O
On/O Sunday/O ,/O Kerry/PERSON travels/O on/O to/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION to/O meet/O regional/O foreign/O ministers/O as/O part/O of/O what/O Washington/LOCATION calls/O a/O ``/O C5+1/O ''/O initiative/O to/O engage/O with/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O
Geopolitical/O ambitions/O
A/O senior/O fellow/O at/O the/O Washington/LOCATION think/O tank/O CSIS/ORGANIZATION ,/O Jeffrey/PERSON Mankoff/PERSON ,/O said/O Kerry/PERSON 's/O visit/O was/O connected/O to/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O ``/O geopolitical/O ambitions/O ,/O ''/O including/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O suspicion/O that/O Moscow/LOCATION could/O be/O trying/O to/O re-establish/O its/O former/O Cold/O War/O empire/O ./O
Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O Tajikistan/LOCATION and/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION are/O within/O Moscow/LOCATION 's/O orbit/O ,/O while/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION and/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION could/O be/O courted/O by/O the/O US/LOCATION as/O ostensibly/O more/O open-minded/O ,/O he/O said/O ./O
For/O years/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION and/O Washington/LOCATION had/O maintained/O an/O uneasy/O truce/O over/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION in/O the/O wake/O of/O the/O 2001/O al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION airline/O hijacker/O attacks/O on/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O Washington/LOCATION and/O the/O subsequent/O US-led/O invasion/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
In/O recent/O months/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION sent/O extra/O aircraft/O to/O a/O Russian/O air/O base/O in/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ,/O while/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION deployed/O troops/O and/O aircraft/O to/O Syria/LOCATION to/O back/O President/O Bashar/PERSON al-Assad/PERSON in/O his/O fight/O with/O a/O multitude/O of/O rebel/O forces/O ./O
``/O Not/O all/O Central/O Asian/O nations/O back/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O Temir/PERSON Sariyev/PERSON ,/O an/O analyst/O based/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ./O
``/O Kerry/PERSON will/O attempt/O to/O isolate/O Moscow/LOCATION ./O ''/O
From/O Syria/LOCATION to/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION
Kerry/PERSON arrived/O in/O Bishkek/LOCATION from/O Vienna/LOCATION ,/O where/O diplomats/O from/O 17/O nations/O as/O well/O as/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION and/O UN/ORGANIZATION on/O Friday/O sought/O ways/O to/O end/O Syria/LOCATION 's/O four-year-long/O civil/O war/O ./O
For/O the/O first/O time/O since/O 2011/O ,/O those/O talks/O involved/O Assad/PERSON 's/O ally/O Iran/LOCATION ./O
Former/O US/LOCATION assistant/O secretary/O of/O defense/O Derek/PERSON Chollet/PERSON said/O Friday/O 's/O announcement/O by/O Washington/LOCATION that/O 50/O special/O operations/O troops/O would/O be/O sent/O to/O Syria/LOCATION to/O fight/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O IS/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O militants/O was/O also/O a/O bid/O to/O ``/O give/O us/O leverage/O for/O the/O diplomatic/O track/O ./O ''/O
Chollet/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O now/O a/O senior/O adviser/O at/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Marshall/ORGANIZATION Fund/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O the/O diplomacy/O also/O set/O up/O momentum/O for/O US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON 's/O visit/O to/O Turkey/LOCATION in/O November/O for/O a/O G-20/ORGANIZATION summit/O along/O with/O Russian/O President/O Vladimir/PERSON Putin/PERSON ./O
Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION on/O Friday/O urged/O Kerry/PERSON to/O push/O Central/O Asian/O leaders/O ,/O such/O as/O Tajikistan/LOCATION 's/O President/O Emomali/PERSON Rahmon/PERSON ,/O to/O improve/O their/O countries/O '/O rights/O records/O ./O
Tajikistan/LOCATION 's/O main/O opposition/O party/O was/O recently/O banned/O ./O
Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION said/O torture/O and/O disappearances/O were/O endemic/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O
Debate/O over/O causes/O
Researcher/O Edward/PERSON Lemon/PERSON of/O Britain/LOCATION 's/O Exeter/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION told/O the/O news/O agency/O AFP/ORGANIZATION that/O persecution/O provoked/O radicalization/O ./O
``/O The/O danger/O posed/O by/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION is/O in/O fact/O less/O than/O the/O danger/O posed/O by/O the/O regime/O ,/O ''/O said/O Lemon/PERSON ,/O referring/O to/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ./O
``/O There/O 's/O this/O kind/O of/O Soviet/LOCATION system/O of/O close/O regulation/O of/O religious/O practices/O ,/O and/O that/O 's/O more/O likely/O to/O cause/O people/O to/O turn/O to/O resort/O to/O violence/O and/O rebel/O against/O the/O state/O ,/O ''/O Lemon/PERSON added/O ./O
Also/O watching/O is/O China/LOCATION ,/O whose/O restive/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O borders/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION and/O which/O is/O present/O in/O several/O Kyrgyz/O industries/O ,/O including/O energy/O and/O mining/O ./O
ipj/ng/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
