Thai/O police/O have/O issued/O an/O arrest/O warrant/O for/O an/O ethnic/O `/O Uighur/O '/O man/O over/O last/O month/O 's/O deadly/O shrine/O blast/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ./O
It/O is/O the/O first/O time/O authorities/O have/O identified/O a/O suspect/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Chinese/O minority/O group/O ./O
Thai/O authorities/O on/O Saturday/O issued/O an/O arrest/O warrant/O for/O a/O 12th/O suspect/O wanted/O in/O connection/O with/O the/O bombing/O at/O Bangkok/LOCATION 's/O Erawan/LOCATION Shrine/LOCATION last/O month/O ,/O in/O which/O 20/O people/O ,/O mostly/O ethnic/O Chinese/O visitors/O ,/O were/O killed/O ./O
In/O a/O statement/O ,/O immigration/O police/O said/O the/O suspect/O was/O ``/O the/O one/O who/O plotted/O ,/O ordered/O ,/O and/O funded/O the/O attack/O ,/O ''/O and/O referred/O to/O the/O arrest/O warrant/O as/O mentioning/O the/O man/O 's/O Uighur/O ethnicity/O ./O
Later/O on/O Saturday/O ,/O police/O seemed/O to/O backtrack/O on/O the/O question/O of/O ethnicity/O ,/O and/O released/O a/O new/O photo/O of/O him/O along/O with/O a/O request/O asking/O media/O ``/O to/O drop/O the/O word/O Uighur/O ./O ''/O
Police/O spokesman/O Lt./O Gen./O Prawut/PERSON Thavornsiri/PERSON said/O the/O man/O left/O Thailand/LOCATION a/O day/O before/O the/O blast/O and/O was/O ``/O not/O the/O mastermind/O ''/O of/O the/O attack/O ,/O but/O was/O wanted/O on/O the/O charge/O of/O ``/O jointly/O possessing/O illegal/O military/O supplies/O ./O ''/O
Accusations/O of/O repression/O
Speculation/O has/O been/O growing/O in/O the/O country/O that/O the/O attack/O may/O have/O been/O carried/O out/O by/O militants/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uighur/O minority/O -/O or/O from/O among/O their/O supporters/O -/O in/O revenge/O for/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O forced/O deportation/O of/O 109/O Uighur/O refugees/O in/O July/O ./O
The/O Uighurs/O ,/O many/O of/O whom/O have/O their/O home/O in/O the/O northwestern/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O have/O long/O accused/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O discrimination/O as/O well/O as/O religious/O and/O cultural/O repression/O ,/O with/O scores/O fleeing/O to/O Turkey/LOCATION via/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION in/O recent/O years/O ./O
Up/O to/O now/O ,/O Thai/O authorities/O have/O avoided/O suggesting/O that/O Chinese/O nationals/O were/O deliberately/O targeted/O in/O the/O August/O 17/O attack/O and/O have/O declined/O to/O mention/O the/O word/O Uighur/O in/O briefings/O to/O reporters/O for/O fear/O of/O harming/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O vital/O tourism/O industry/O and/O ties/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O
Thai/O authorities/O have/O already/O detained/O two/O foreign/O male/O suspects/O ,/O whose/O nationalities/O have/O not/O been/O confirmed/O ,/O over/O the/O attack/O ./O
The/O Hindu/O Erawan/LOCATION shrine/O ,/O where/O the/O blast/O occurred/O ,/O is/O located/O in/O the/O Thai/O capital/O 's/O busy/O downtown/O district/O and/O is/O highly/O popular/O with/O Chinese/O tourists/O ,/O who/O believe/O praying/O there/O brings/O good/O luck/O ./O
tj/rc/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
