A/O human/O rights/O lawyer/O has/O been/O charged/O with/O ``/O picking/O quarrels/O and/O provoking/O trouble/O ''/O for/O criticizing/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O
Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON -/O who/O has/O spent/O 19/O months/O in/O custody/O -/O faces/O eight/O years/O in/O prison/O ,/O if/O convicted/O ./O
Pu/PERSON appeared/O Sunday/O before/O the/O 2nd/ORGANIZATION Beijing/ORGANIZATION Intermediate/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION in/O a/O case/O that/O international/O rights/O groups/O have/O criticized/O as/O political/O persecution/O ./O
He/O is/O a/O public/O figure/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O was/O instrumental/O in/O pushing/O for/O the/O eventual/O abolishment/O of/O the/O labor/O camp/O system/O ,/O which/O allowed/O police/O to/O jail/O people/O for/O up/O to/O four/O years/O without/O a/O trial/O ./O
``/O If/O they/O decide/O to/O be/O harsh/O against/O him/O ,/O I/O 'd/O say/O it/O 'll/O signify/O a/O further/O escalation/O of/O hostility/O towards/O human/O rights/O activism/O ./O ''/O
His/O case/O revolves/O around/O a/O number/O of/O posts/O on/O China/LOCATION 's/O Twitter-like/O Sina/ORGANIZATION Weibo/ORGANIZATION that/O questioned/O the/O ruling/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION 's/O policies/O toward/O the/O Tibetan/O and/O Uighur/O ethnic/O minorities/O in/O the/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION regions/O ,/O and/O mocked/O political/O figures/O ./O
If/O convicted/O ,/O Pu/PERSON faces/O up/O to/O eight/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O
Police/O forcefully/O barred/O observers/O -/O including/O diplomats/O ,/O journalists/O and/O supporters/O -/O from/O entering/O the/O courtroom/O ./O
Some/O 40/O well-wishers/O gathered/O outside/O the/O courthouse/O and/O chanted/O slogans/O to/O show/O solidarity/O with/O the/O accused/O ./O
``/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON is/O not/O a/O criminal/O ./O
He/O will/O be/O judged/O by/O history/O ,/O ''/O Qu/PERSON Biao/PERSON ,/O a/O 53-year-old/O teacher/O from/O the/O northern/O Shaanxi/LOCATION province/O ,/O told/O the/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O ./O
``/O The/O Chinese/O constitution/O protects/O freedom/O of/O speech/O ,/O so/O putting/O him/O on/O trial/O is/O unjust/O and/O shameless/O ./O
If/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON is/O guilty/O ,/O then/O we/O are/O all/O guilty/O ./O ''/O
A/O woman/O is/O caught/O in/O a/O scuffle/O on/O a/O spring/O day/O in/O 1989/O ./O
Later/O that/O night/O ,/O the/O 38th/O army/O would/O open/O fire/O on/O unarmed/O civilians/O in/O one/O of/O the/O bloodiest/O crackdowns/O of/O the/O 20th/O century/O
Arrested/O at/O illegal/O commemoration/O of/O 1989/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION massacre/O
China/LOCATION routinely/O prosecutes/O activists/O and/O dissidents/O under/O a/O law/O forbidding/O ``/O picking/O quarrels/O and/O provoking/O trouble/O ''/O and/O dismisses/O any/O criticism/O of/O its/O rights/O record/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION has/O launched/O a/O crackdown/O on/O online/O rumors/O over/O the/O past/O two/O years/O ,/O detained/O hundreds/O of/O human/O rights/O lawyers/O in/O a/O nationwide/O sweep/O and/O jailed/O a/O reporter/O on/O a/O charge/O of/O leaking/O state/O secrets/O ./O
The/O 50-year-old/O attorney/O was/O taken/O into/O custody/O in/O May/O 2014/O after/O he/O attended/O a/O meeting/O in/O a/O private/O home/O to/O commemorate/O the/O bloody/O 1989/O crackdown/O on/O pro-democracy/O protesters/O on/O the/O capital/O 's/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ./O
Pu/PERSON ,/O who/O had/O participated/O in/O the/O protests/O ,/O had/O vowed/O to/O commemorate/O the/O anniversary/O every/O year/O in/O memory/O of/O the/O hundreds/O killed/O by/O security/O services/O ./O
jar/gsw/O -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
