As/O China/LOCATION 's/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION gets/O underway/O ,/O lawmakers/O may/O decide/O on/O allowing/O armed/O forces/O to/O be/O deployed/O abroad/O to/O counter/O terrorism/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION talks/O to/O analyst/O Andrew/PERSON Scobell/PERSON about/O the/O draft/O law/O and/O its/O implications/O ./O
An/O anti-terrorism/O bill/O is/O likely/O to/O be/O among/O a/O host/O of/O policy/O matters/O China/LOCATION 's/O parliament/O ,/O derided/O as/O ``/O rubber/O stamp/O ''/O legislature/O ,/O will/O discuss/O over/O the/O next/O 11/O days/O ./O
The/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O NPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O attended/O by/O some/O 3,000/O delegates/O ,/O convenes/O once/O a/O year/O ./O
The/O draft/O law/O is/O aimed/O at/O better/O countering/O terrorist/O activity/O at/O home/O and/O it/O has/O reportedly/O been/O reviewed/O by/O a/O parliamentary/O committee/O ./O
Chinese/O authorities/O claim/O the/O legislation/O ,/O when/O passed/O ,/O could/O strengthen/O the/O country/O 's/O counter-terrorism/O efforts/O and/O bolster/O intelligence/O ./O
However/O ,/O it/O is/O not/O limited/O to/O that/O ./O
A/O clause/O in/O the/O draft/O law/O also/O enables/O the/O Chinese/O administration/O to/O send/O forces/O abroad/O to/O undertake/O counter-terrorism/O missions/O ,/O if/O approved/O by/O the/O host/O nation/O ./O
In/O a/O DW/ORGANIZATION interview/O ,/O Andrew/PERSON Scobell/PERSON ,/O a/O Senior/O Political/O Scientist/O at/O the/O RAND/ORGANIZATION Corporation/ORGANIZATION ,/O says/O that/O the/O anti-terrorism/O bill/O underscores/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O concern/O about/O how/O to/O protect/O the/O country/O 's/O expanding/O overseas/O interests/O ,/O including/O the/O security/O of/O Chinese/O citizens/O living/O ,/O working/O ,/O and/O travelling/O abroad/O ./O
Scobell/PERSON :/O `/O The/O bill/O is/O an/O effort/O by/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON to/O further/O clarify/O and/O codify/O Chinese/O counter-terrorism/O efforts/O '/O
DW/ORGANIZATION :/O What/O is/O the/O purpose/O of/O this/O draft/O law/O ?/O
Andrew/PERSON Scobell/PERSON :/O The/O bill/O appears/O to/O mark/O an/O effort/O by/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON to/O further/O clarify/O and/O codify/O Chinese/O counter-terrorism/O efforts/O ./O
What/O would/O this/O bill/O allow/O and/O when/O is/O it/O expected/O to/O become/O law/O ?/O
This/O bill/O could/O be/O voted/O on/O by/O the/O current/O session/O of/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION and/O become/O a/O law/O very/O soon/O ./O
However/O ,/O some/O aspects/O of/O the/O law/O appear/O to/O be/O controversial/O within/O China/LOCATION and/O this/O might/O mean/O a/O postponement/O of/O passage/O ./O
Reportedly/O ,/O one/O element/O of/O the/O law/O permits/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O dispatch/O security/O forces/O beyond/O China/LOCATION 's/O borders/O to/O conduct/O counter-terrorism/O operations/O ./O
If/O such/O a/O provision/O is/O included/O then/O this/O would/O be/O significant/O ./O
However/O ,/O Chinese/O forces/O already/O appear/O to/O have/O conducted/O limited/O counter-terrorism/O actions/O beyond/O China/LOCATION 's/O borders/O ./O
In/O which/O places/O outside/O China/LOCATION have/O the/O country/O 's/O forces/O conducted/O such/O operations/O ?/O
DW/ORGANIZATION recommends/O
Sieren/PERSON 's/O China/LOCATION :/O What/O the/O public/O expects/O of/O the/O upcoming/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION
Eyes/O are/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O the/O annual/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O
But/O the/O priorities/O of/O the/O international/O community/O do/O n't/O quite/O dovetail/O with/O the/O issues/O the/O Chinese/O hope/O will/O be/O addressed/O ,/O says/O DW/ORGANIZATION columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON ./O
-LRB-/O 04.03.2015/O -RRB-/O
China/LOCATION seeking/O to/O use/O greater/O power/O to/O influence/O status/O quo/O
China/LOCATION 's/O defense/O budget/O will/O rise/O by/O 10/O percent/O this/O year/O as/O Beijing/LOCATION vows/O to/O improve/O conditions/O for/O the/O world/O 's/O largest/O military/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION talks/O to/O SIPRI/ORGANIZATION 's/O Sam/PERSON Perlo-Freeman/PERSON about/O how/O the/O move/O may/O exacerbate/O regional/O tensions/O ./O
-LRB-/O 04.03.2015/O -RRB-/O
New/O Internet/O rules/O reflect/O China/LOCATION 's/O `/O intent/O to/O target/O individuals/O online/O '/O
China/LOCATION has/O introduced/O new/O rules/O requiring/O Internet/O users/O to/O use/O their/O real/O names/O when/O registering/O for/O online/O accounts/O ./O
A/O move/O Rogier/PERSON Creemers/PERSON views/O as/O another/O attempt/O by/O the/O authorities/O to/O control/O the/O Chinese/O cyberspace/O ./O
-LRB-/O 02.03.2015/O -RRB-/O
China/LOCATION has/O become/O a/O `/O major/O donor/O '/O in/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION Islands/LOCATION region/O
China/LOCATION is/O on/O track/O to/O overtake/O Japan/LOCATION as/O the/O third/O largest/O donor/O to/O Pacific/LOCATION Island/LOCATION nations/O ./O
In/O some/O countries/O ,/O Chinese/O aid/O amounts/O are/O already/O rivaling/O that/O of/O traditional/O partners/O ,/O as/O analyst/O Philippa/PERSON Brant/PERSON tells/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
-LRB-/O 03.03.2015/O -RRB-/O
The/O prime/O examples/O that/O come/O immediately/O to/O mind/O are/O :/O
1./O China/LOCATION 's/O unprecedented/O efforts/O to/O capture/O a/O Southeast/O Asian/O drug/O lord/O who/O was/O believed/O responsible/O for/O the/O 2011/O cold/O blooded/O murder/O of/O Chinese/O sailors/O on/O the/O Mekong/LOCATION River/LOCATION in/O 2011/O ./O
The/O following/O year/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O tracked/O him/O through/O the/O jungles/O of/O Myanmar/LOCATION -LRB-/O also/O formerly/O known/O as/O Burma/LOCATION -RRB-/O and/O Laos/LOCATION ,/O seized/O him/O and/O brought/O him/O back/O to/O China/LOCATION and/O put/O him/O on/O trial/O ./O
2./O The/O nearly/O annual/O military/O and/O paramilitary/O exercises/O that/O China/LOCATION conducts/O with/O the/O security/O forces/O of/O Russia/LOCATION and/O Central/O Asian/O states/O under/O the/O auspices/O of/O the/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Organization/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SCO/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O since/O 2003/O ./O
These/O exercises/O are/O officially/O all/O counter-terrorism/O focused/O ./O
The/O first/O time/O China/LOCATION conducted/O military/O exercises/O with/O other/O countries/O either/O within/O or/O beyond/O its/O borders/O was/O as/O part/O of/O this/O SCO/ORGANIZATION series/O ./O
What/O concerns/O have/O triggered/O the/O draft/O legislation/O 's/O inception/O ?/O
Actually/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O concerned/O about/O terrorism/O for/O several/O decades/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION has/O tended/O to/O conflate/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O with/O ``/O separatism/O ''/O and/O ``/O extremism/O ''/O and/O dubbed/O them/O the/O ``/O three/O evils/O ./O ''/O
China/LOCATION has/O used/O the/O attacks/O of/O September/O 11/O ,/O 2001/O to/O engage/O with/O Washington/LOCATION and/O other/O capitals/O insisting/O that/O China/LOCATION too/O has/O been/O a/O victim/O of/O terrorism/O and/O offering/O to/O cooperate/O on/O counter-terrorism/O initiatives/O ./O
Also/O in/O 2001/O ,/O China/LOCATION took/O the/O lead/O in/O establishing/O the/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Organization/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SCO/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O along/O with/O Russia/LOCATION and/O Central/O Asian/O states/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION insists/O that/O the/O SCO/ORGANIZATION was/O the/O first/O multilateral/O organization/O established/O to/O have/O counter-terrorism/O as/O a/O central/O focus/O ./O
China/LOCATION has/O faced/O a/O low/O intensity/O conflict/O within/O its/O own/O borders/O -/O in/O its/O westernmost/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION for/O at/O least/O three/O decades/O ./O
This/O is/O a/O manifestation/O of/O significant/O disaffection/O among/O some/O 10/O million-strong/O ethnic/O minority/O Uighurs/O ./O
The/O situation/O has/O become/O more/O acute/O since/O 2009/O as/O discrimination/O and/O repression/O against/O this/O Turkic/O minority/O has/O increased/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O settlers/O have/O flowed/O into/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
The/O result/O has/O been/O growing/O alienation/O ,/O radicalization/O ,/O and/O greater/O attention/O to/O Islam/ORGANIZATION as/O a/O central/O component/O of/O Uighur/O identity/O ./O
Violence/O in/O response/O to/O harsh/O Chinese/O crackdowns/O against/O Uighurs/O and/O acts/O of/O terrorism/O by/O extremists/O seem/O to/O have/O become/O more/O frequent/O both/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION in/O other/O parts/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O
What/O would/O be/O the/O implications/O of/O the/O law/O and/O of/O having/O Chinese/O troops/O involved/O in/O such/O operations/O abroad/O ?/O
If/O a/O provision/O for/O the/O employment/O of/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O abroad/O is/O included/O in/O a/O counter-terrorism/O law/O then/O this/O might/O lead/O to/O an/O increase/O in/O actions/O by/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O abroad/O but/O it/O would/O almost/O certainly/O be/O an/O extremely/O modest/O increase/O ./O
China/LOCATION has/O faced/O a/O low/O intensity/O conflict/O in/O its/O westernmost/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION for/O at/O least/O three/O decades/O
More/O importantly/O ,/O what/O inclusion/O of/O such/O a/O provision/O would/O underscore/O is/O greater/O concern/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION about/O how/O to/O protect/O China/LOCATION 's/O expanding/O overseas/O interests/O ,/O including/O the/O security/O of/O Chinese/O citizens/O living/O ,/O working/O ,/O and/O travelling/O abroad/O ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O official/O military/O budget/O will/O grow/O by/O about/O 10/O percent/O in/O the/O coming/O year/O ,/O amid/O unease/O among/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O neighbors/O about/O its/O growing/O might/O and/O territorial/O ambitions/O ./O
What/O will/O be/O the/O impact/O of/O the/O defense/O budget/O hike/O ?/O
The/O announced/O increase/O is/O consistent/O with/O annual/O increases/O over/O the/O past/O few/O decades/O ./O
Virtually/O every/O year/O the/O defense/O budget/O has/O experienced/O double/O digit/O growth/O ./O
Moreover/O ,/O this/O announcement/O by/O itself/O is/O unlikely/O to/O increase/O tension/O among/O China/LOCATION 's/O neighbors/O ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O neighbors/O will/O pay/O more/O attention/O to/O what/O China/LOCATION does/O economically/O ,/O diplomatically/O ,/O and/O militarily/O to/O further/O its/O power/O and/O influence/O in/O the/O Asia-Pacific/LOCATION Region/LOCATION ./O
Andrew/PERSON Scobell/PERSON is/O a/O Senior/O Political/O Scientist/O at/O the/O RAND/ORGANIZATION Corporation/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O non-profit/O think/O tank/O ./O
