China/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O the/O US/LOCATION are/O negotiating/O how/O to/O sit/O at/O one/O table/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION to/O curb/O the/O terror/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O mediating/O role/O is/O increasingly/O important/O ,/O says/O DW/ORGANIZATION 's/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON ./O
Stability/O through/O mediation/O ,/O without/O rocking/O the/O balance/O of/O power/O -/O that/O 's/O China/LOCATION 's/O attitude/O towards/O the/O peace/O process/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
China/LOCATION has/O concrete/O interests/O in/O the/O war-torn/O country/O and/O wants/O to/O prevent/O Islamist/O terrorism/O from/O spilling/O over/O from/O its/O western/O neighbor/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION assumes/O that/O the/O most/O recent/O terrorist/O attacks/O in/O the/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION were/O planned/O from/O eastern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
China/LOCATION also/O urgently/O needs/O a/O stable/O Afghanistan/LOCATION to/O put/O its/O ambitious/O ``/O New/U_LOCATION Silk/U_LOCATION Road/U_LOCATION ''/O plans/O into/O effect/O ./O
Moreover/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O more/O appropriate/O as/O a/O mediating/O role/O than/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O which/O has/O tried/O -/O and/O failed/O -/O to/O overturn/O the/O balance/O of/O power/O in/O the/O Afghanistan/LOCATION conflict/O ./O
As/O Washington/LOCATION has/O had/O to/O accept/O that/O Syria/LOCATION can/O not/O be/O solved/O without/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O it/O also/O has/O to/O accept/O that/O Afghanistan/LOCATION can/O not/O be/O solved/O without/O China/LOCATION ./O
One/O common/O goal/O at/O least/O
At/O the/O beginning/O of/O the/O week/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O special/O envoy/O on/O Afghan/O affairs/O ,/O Deng/PERSON Xijun/PERSON ,/O met/O Afghan/O Deputy/O Foreign/O Minister/O Hekmat/PERSON Karzai/PERSON ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION Foreign/O Secretary/O Aizaz/PERSON Chaudhry/PERSON and/O the/O US/LOCATION Special/O Representative/O for/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Richard/PERSON Olson/PERSON ,/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O
All/O four/O have/O one/O goal/O in/O common/O :/O They/O want/O to/O bring/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION to/O the/O negotiating/O table/O so/O that/O there/O can/O be/O direct/O talks/O with/O the/O Afghan/O government/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION 's/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON
This/O is/O most/O difficult/O for/O the/O US/LOCATION -/O after/O all/O they/O marched/O into/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O 2001/O to/O get/O rid/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O
By/O contrast/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION never/O broke/O off/O contact/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION even/O if/O they/O were/O considered/O a/O difficult/O dialogue/O partner/O ./O
The/O situation/O has/O not/O improved/O since/O the/O end/O of/O the/O NATO/ORGANIZATION mission/O in/O late/O 2014/O :/O The/O radical/O Islamist/ORGANIZATION Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O willingness/O to/O use/O violence/O has/O actually/O increased/O since/O the/O death/O of/O leader/O Mullah/PERSON Mohammed/PERSON Omar/PERSON ,/O who/O had/O a/O $/O 10/O million/O -LRB-/O 9.21/O million/O euro/O -RRB-/O US/LOCATION government/O bounty/O on/O his/O head/O ./O
The/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION seems/O to/O be/O more/O at/O odds/O with/O each/O other/O than/O ever/O ./O
Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O which/O hosted/O the/O talks/O ,/O has/O been/O accused/O by/O the/O Afghan/O and/O US/LOCATION governments/O of/O supporting/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION both/O financially/O and/O materially/O and/O offering/O them/O refuge/O ./O
The/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION headquarters/O are/O thought/O to/O be/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
At/O the/O start/O of/O the/O talks/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O the/O Pakistani/O Foreign/O Affairs/O Adviser/O Sartaj/PERSON Aziz/PERSON argued/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O influence/O over/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION was/O overestimated/O ./O
All/O hope/O rests/O on/O China/LOCATION
This/O is/O why/O there/O are/O high/O hopes/O about/O China/LOCATION 's/O role/O in/O the/O negotiations/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION not/O only/O wants/O to/O build/O up/O the/O infrastructure/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O but/O also/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
There/O are/O plans/O to/O build/O a/O new/O economic/O corridor/O with/O new/O roads/O ,/O power/O stations/O and/O industrial/O parks/O ,/O on/O which/O China/LOCATION intends/O to/O spend/O $/O 46/O billion/O ./O
However/O ,/O no/O money/O will/O flow/O as/O long/O as/O the/O region/O remains/O unstable/O ./O
China/LOCATION is/O now/O wondering/O whether/O Pakistan/LOCATION wields/O enough/O influence/O to/O stabilize/O the/O situation/O and/O whether/O indeed/O it/O even/O has/O an/O interest/O in/O Afghan/O stability/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O most/O important/O success/O thus/O far/O is/O that/O two/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION representatives/O from/O the/O Gulf/LOCATION state/O of/O Qatar/LOCATION recently/O agreed/O to/O meet/O Chinese/O and/O Pakistani/O negotiators/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O
This/O was/O an/O important/O step/O ,/O but/O did/O not/O lead/O to/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION sitting/O at/O the/O same/O table/O ./O
There/O is/O one/O encouraging/O sign/O however/O -/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O US/LOCATION are/O already/O planning/O to/O meet/O again/O for/O talks/O on/O January/O 18/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION 's/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON has/O lived/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O over/O 20/O years/O ./O
