While/O the/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O are/O increasingly/O being/O persecuted/O ,/O the/O largest/O Chinese-Muslim/O minority/O ,/O the/O Hui/O ,/O are/O under/O less/O scrutiny/O and/O thriving/O as/O a/O religious/O community/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION examines/O the/O reasons/O behind/O this/O phenomenon/O ./O
Walking/O through/O the/O Muslim/O quarter/O of/O Xi'an/LOCATION is/O a/O fascinating/O venture/O into/O a/O hodge-podge/O of/O cultures/O ./O
The/O smell/O of/O lamb/O skewers/O and/O hot/O spices/O wafts/O through/O the/O crowded/O streets/O ./O
Chinese-looking/O women/O in/O headscarfs/O stretch/O noodles/O ,/O while/O an/O old/O man/O with/O a/O white/O prayer/O hat/O stands/O in/O front/O of/O a/O mosque/O with/O a/O distinctly/O Chinese/O arched/O roof/O ./O
This/O is/O the/O home/O of/O the/O Xi'an/LOCATION Hui/O Muslim/O people/O ,/O where/O Islam/ORGANIZATION was/O introduced/O to/O China/LOCATION for/O the/O first/O time/O in/O the/O 7th/O century/O ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O Muslim/O population/O now/O numbers/O 23/O million/O ,/O of/O which/O over/O 10/O million/O are/O estimated/O to/O be/O Hui/O ,/O and/O a/O little/O under/O 10/O million/O Uighur/O ./O
While/O their/O fellow/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O in/O the/O Xingjiang/U_LOCATION Uighur/U_LOCATION Autonomous/U_LOCATION Region/U_LOCATION are/O experiencing/O severe/O restrictions/O on/O their/O religious/O freedoms/O ,/O the/O Hui/O mostly/O practice/O their/O faith/O openly/O ,/O and/O in/O certain/O areas/O are/O enjoying/O a/O resurgence/O in/O their/O religious/O participation/O ./O
The/O reason/O for/O their/O success/O has/O to/O do/O with/O centuries/O of/O remarkable/O assimilation/O ,/O while/O also/O maintaining/O their/O identity/O ./O
A/O history/O of/O assimilation/O
Historically/O ,/O the/O Hui/O people/O are/O descendants/O of/O Persian/O ,/O Arab/O and/O Mongol/O merchants/O on/O the/O Silk/U_LOCATION Road/U_LOCATION ,/O who/O came/O to/O China/LOCATION over/O 1,200/O years/O ago/O ./O
Since/O then/O ,/O intermarriages/O with/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O have/O meant/O that/O the/O Hui/O became/O ethnically/O mixed/O and/O spread/O across/O the/O country/O ./O
Hui/O Muslims/O were/O allowed/O to/O practice/O Ramadan/O ,/O while/O Uighurs/O were/O not/O
Over/O the/O centuries/O ,/O the/O Han/O and/O Hui/O have/O lived/O relatively/O peacefully/O next/O to/O and/O with/O each/O other/O ./O
The/O Hui/O took/O the/O path/O of/O assimilation/O ,/O speak/O Mandarin/O and/O adapted/O their/O religious/O traditions/O to/O the/O local/O customs/O ./O
One/O of/O the/O most/O visual/O examples/O of/O this/O is/O the/O great/O mosque/O of/O Xi'an/LOCATION ,/O said/O to/O be/O one/O of/O the/O largest/O and/O oldest/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
The/O place/O of/O worship/O is/O built/O up/O of/O multiple/O courtyards/O and/O sports/O arches/O and/O tiled/O roofs/O that/O clearly/O show/O influences/O of/O traditional/O Chinese/O architecture/O ./O
While/O some/O Hui/PERSON now/O live/O a/O life/O culturally/O and/O religiously/O indistinguishable/O from/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O first-tier/O cities/O such/O as/O Shanghai/LOCATION or/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O many/O cities/O in/O China/LOCATION have/O a/O significant/O Hui/O Muslim/O minority/O population/O with/O close-knit/O communities/O ,/O especially/O in/O the/O northern/O provinces/O of/O Ningxia/LOCATION ,/O Gangsu/LOCATION or/O Quinghai/O ./O
Traditionally/O traders/O ,/O many/O Hui/O people/O are/O also/O economically/O successful/O today/O ,/O and/O according/O to/O estimates/O ,/O their/O religious/O participation/O is/O growing/O ./O
Increasing/O religiosity/O
Dru/PERSON Gladney/PERSON ,/O professor/O at/O Pomona/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION in/O California/LOCATION and/O leading/O scholar/O on/O the/O Hui/O people/O ,/O estimates/O that/O today/O there/O are/O twice/O as/O many/O mosques/O in/O China/LOCATION as/O there/O were/O in/O 1950/O ,/O of/O which/O a/O majority/O were/O built/O by/O Hui/O Muslims/O ./O
``/O The/O amount/O of/O practising/O Muslims/O among/O the/O Hui/O is/O rising/O ,/O ''/O Gladney/PERSON told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O For/O example/O ,/O there/O is/O a/O dramatic/O increase/O in/O the/O number/O of/O Hui/O women/O wearing/O the/O Hijab/O ./O ''/O
Gladley/PERSON adds/O that/O ``/O the/O numbers/O of/O Hui/O going/O on/O the/O Haj/O are/O going/O up/O constantly/O ./O ''/O
DW/ORGANIZATION recommends/O
China/LOCATION 's/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION Muslims/O `/O require/O DNA/O samples/O '/O for/O travel/O documents/O
Residents/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Muslim-majority/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O must/O provide/O DNA/O samples/O when/O applying/O for/O travel/O documents/O ,/O according/O to/O new/O rules/O ./O
Local/O authorities/O have/O also/O put/O restrictions/O on/O fasting/O during/O Ramadan/O ./O -LRB-/O 08.06.2016/O -RRB-/O
Targeting/O of/O Islamic/O customs/O reflects/O `/O misdiagnosis/O '/O of/O Uighur/O discontent/O
Chinese/O authorities/O have/O reportedly/O ordered/O Muslim/O shopkeepers/O in/O a/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION village/O to/O sell/O alcohol/O and/O cigarettes/O in/O a/O bid/O to/O undermine/O Islam/ORGANIZATION 's/O hold/O on/O local/O residents/O ./O
But/O will/O this/O work/O ?/O
DW/ORGANIZATION speaks/O to/O James/PERSON Millward/PERSON ./O
-LRB-/O 11.05.2015/O -RRB-/O
Why/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uighurs/O are/O joining/O jihadists/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION
What/O is/O driving/O the/O Uighur/O Muslims/O to/O increasingly/O join/O the/O ranks/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ?/O
Analyst/O Siegfried/PERSON O./PERSON Wolf/PERSON tells/O DW/ORGANIZATION why/O the/O Uighur/O issue/O has/O expanded/O far/O beyond/O China/LOCATION 's/O borders/O ./O -LRB-/O 24.07.2015/O -RRB-/O
One/O of/O the/O reasons/O for/O this/O is/O the/O increased/O communication/O with/O other/O Muslim/O groups/O and/O the/O ensuing/O influence/O of/O outside/O Islam/ORGANIZATION --/O either/O through/O Hui/O scholars/O returning/O from/O the/O Haj/O or/O from/O increased/O business/O relationships/O with/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O
Trade/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION is/O growing/O ever/O more/O important/O for/O the/O communist/O country/O ./O
As/O a/O measure/O to/O attract/O Arab/O business/O ,/O Yinchuan/LOCATION ,/O the/O capital/O city/O of/O Ningxia/LOCATION and/O one/O of/O the/O Hui/O hubs/O ,/O has/O gotten/O a/O makeover/O ./O
Construction/O of/O a/O new/O $/O 3.7/O billion/O Islamic/O theme/O park/O called/O World/LOCATION Muslim/LOCATION City/LOCATION is/O underway/O ,/O and/O Arabic/O lettering/O has/O been/O added/O to/O the/O city/O 's/O street/O signs/O ./O
Haiyun/PERSON Ma/PERSON ,/O a/O Hui/O scholar/O at/O Frostberg/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION takes/O a/O critical/O position/O with/O regard/O to/O the/O Chinese/O government/O 's/O perceived/O friendliness/O toward/O the/O Hui/O ./O
She/O told/O DW/ORGANIZATION that/O it/O is/O more/O of/O a/O sign/O of/O ``/O business/O interest/O ,/O not/O of/O religious/O tolerance/O ./O ''/O
On/O the/O business/O side/O ,/O Hui/O Muslims/O do/O play/O a/O role/O as/O middlemen/O in/O trade/O between/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION ./O
Because/O of/O their/O knowledge/O of/O Arabic/O ,/O numerous/O Hui/O people/O are/O working/O in/O Dubai/LOCATION ,/O and/O for/O Middle/O Eastern/O businesses/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
Keeping/O out/O of/O politics/O
Another/O reason/O for/O the/O Hui/O 's/O relative/O freedom/O are/O the/O characteristics/O that/O distinguish/O them/O from/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O
The/O second-largest/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O is/O ethnically/O distinct/O ,/O and/O does/O not/O speak/O Mandarin/O as/O a/O first/O language/O ./O
Most/O importantly/O ,/O they/O have/O a/O homeland/O that/O they/O wish/O to/O claim/O ./O
The/O majority/O of/O Uighurs/O live/O in/O the/O far-western/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
Many/O of/O the/O ethno-religious/O group/O seek/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O Uighurs/O as/O such/O are/O oppressed/O for/O it/O ./O
During/O this/O year/O 's/O Ramadan/O ,/O they/O were/O forced/O to/O break/O fast/O and/O parts/O of/O their/O community/O were/O not/O allowed/O to/O attend/O prayers/O or/O travel/O ./O
Most/O recently/O ,/O all/O citizens/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION were/O ordered/O to/O hand/O in/O their/O passports/O ./O
Many/O big/O cities/O like/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O pictured/O here/O ,/O house/O a/O minority/O of/O Hui/O Muslims/O
But/O the/O Hui/O ,/O partly/O also/O due/O to/O their/O diversity/O and/O geographic/O diaspora/O ,/O and/O partly/O because/O of/O their/O cultural/O closeness/O to/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O have/O no/O political/O aspirations/O of/O independence/O ,/O Gladney/PERSON said/O ./O
Periods/O of/O turmoil/O
This/O does/O not/O mean/O that/O the/O Han/O and/O Hui/O have/O always/O got/O along/O well/O ./O
The/O Dungan/O revolt/O in/O the/O 1860s/O and/O 1870s/O saw/O an/O uprising/O of/O Muslim/O and/O Hui/O people/O against/O the/O Han/O ./O
The/O Hui/O were/O also/O oppressed/O by/O the/O government/O during/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O ,/O along/O with/O most/O religious/O and/O ethnic/O minorities/O ./O
In/O 1975/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O Hui/O were/O killed/O when/O a/O separatist/O movement/O was/O suppressed/O by/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O southern/O town/O of/O Shadian/LOCATION ./O
While/O friendliness/O toward/O outside/O Muslims/O with/O business/O intentions/O is/O mounting/O ,/O and/O numbers/O suggest/O that/O religious/O activities/O are/O on/O the/O rise/O ,/O the/O Hui/O may/O have/O to/O be/O on/O the/O watch/O out/O for/O another/O shift/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
``/O In/O the/O last/O few/O years/O ,/O it/O has/O become/O increasingly/O difficult/O for/O Hui/O Muslims/O in/O provinces/O such/O as/O Ningxia/PERSON to/O apply/O for/O passports/O ,/O and/O religious/O education/O has/O been/O restricted/O ,/O ''/O the/O Hui/O scholar/O Ma/PERSON observed/O ./O
``/O The/O control/O and/O mounting/O nationalism/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O are/O a/O threat/O to/O the/O Hui/O ./O ''/O
