Separate/O twin/O bomb/O blasts/O have/O hit/O Thailand/LOCATION ,/O killing/O at/O least/O two/O people/O and/O injuring/O many/O more/O ./O
The/O explosions/O come/O days/O after/O a/O referendum/O approving/O a/O military/O constitution/O ./O
A/O twin/O bomb/O blast/O in/O the/O southern/O province/O of/O Surat/LOCATION Thani/LOCATION killed/O at/O least/O one/O person/O and/O injured/O two/O others/O ,/O Thai/O police/O said/O ./O
The/O double/O bombing/O ,/O at/O 8/O a.m./O -LRB-/O 0100/O UTC/O -RRB-/O on/O Friday/O morning/O ,/O came/O less/O than/O 12/O hours/O after/O separate/O twin/O bomb/O attacks/O in/O central/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O
Four/O bombs/O exploded/O on/O Thursday/O evening/O in/O the/O seaside/O resort/O of/O Hua/LOCATION Hin/LOCATION ,/O 198/O kilometers/O south/O -LRB-/O 125/O miles/O -RRB-/O of/O Bangkok/LOCATION ./O
The/O victims/O included/O Thais/O and/O foreigners/O ,/O police/O said/O ./O
Two/O more/O blasts/O were/O reported/O in/O the/O popular/O tourist/O destination/O of/O Phuket/LOCATION ./O
Authorities/O are/O unsure/O of/O a/O motive/O or/O who/O carried/O out/O the/O attacks/O ./O
It/O is/O unclear/O whether/O the/O attacks/O were/O related/O ./O
The/O blasts/O come/O several/O days/O before/O the/O one-year/O anniversary/O of/O the/O last/O major/O attack/O on/O tourists/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O
A/O bomb/O in/O the/O Thai/O capital/O ripped/O through/O a/O Hindi/O shrine/O and/O killed/O 20/O people/O on/O August/O 17/O ,/O mostly/O foreigners/O ./O
Chinese/O Uighurs/O accused/O
Thai/O authorities/O accused/O two/O Uighur/O men/O from/O western/O China/LOCATION of/O the/O bombing/O ,/O the/O deadliest/O attack/O of/O its/O kind/O Thailand/LOCATION in/O recent/O years/O ./O
The/O two/O accused/O have/O denied/O involvement/O in/O the/O attack/O and/O their/O trial/O is/O set/O to/O begin/O later/O this/O month/O ./O
They/O come/O a/O week/O after/O a/O referendum/O put/O forward/O by/O the/O military/O junta/O was/O approved/O ,/O paving/O the/O way/O for/O a/O new/O constitution/O and/O elections/O next/O year/O ./O
Junta/O chief/O and/O Prime/O Minister/O Prayuth/PERSON Chan-ocha/PERSON said/O on/O Wednesday/O he/O had/O brought/O stability/O back/O to/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O
Opponents/O of/O the/O military/O drafted/O constitution/O argue/O it/O is/O laced/O with/O undemocratic/O principles/O and/O was/O designed/O to/O keep/O the/O military/O in/O power/O for/O five/O more/O years/O ./O
The/O attacks/O come/O ahead/O of/O weekend/O celebrations/O to/O celebrate/O Queen/O Sirikit/PERSON 's/O birthday/O on/O Friday/O ./O
The/O ruling/O junta/O supports/O the/O monarchy/O ./O
A/O bombing/O took/O place/O earlier/O on/O Thursday/O ,/O in/O the/O southern/O province/O of/O Trang/LOCATION ,/O which/O killed/O one/O person/O and/O injured/O six/O ./O
cw/rc/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O dpa/O -RRB-/O
