German/O investigators/O are/O expected/O in/O China/LOCATION to/O examine/O allegations/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION that/O exiles/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uighur/O minority/O are/O planning/O terrorist/O activities/O from/O German/O soil/O ,/O the/O weekly/O Der/ORGANIZATION Spiegel/ORGANIZATION said/O in/O its/O edition/O to/O appear/O on/O Monday/O ./O
Germany/LOCATION has/O so/O far/O refused/O to/O follow/O up/O China/LOCATION 's/O demand/O that/O it/O ban/O two/O Uighur/O groups/O based/O on/O its/O territory/O and/O ban/O its/O leaders/O ,/O on/O the/O grounds/O that/O it/O lacks/O enough/O evidence/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O magazine/O ./O
The/O Muslim/O ,/O Turkish-speaking/O Uighurs/O advocate/O separatism/O for/O the/O Islamic/O ,/O northwestern/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O of/O China/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O already/O classified/O four/O Uighur/O groups/O as/O terrorists/O ./O
Two/O German/O investigators/O are/O due/O to/O travel/O to/O China/LOCATION to/O consult/O the/O evidence/O collected/O by/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O ,/O the/O weekly/O reported/O ./O
German/O Chancellor/O Gerhard/PERSON Schröder/PERSON this/O week/O visited/O China/LOCATION for/O the/O sixth/O time/O in/O as/O many/O years/O ,/O as/O China/LOCATION and/O Germany/LOCATION step/O up/O their/O cooperation/O both/O economically/O and/O politically/O ./O
