German/O engineering/O conglomerate/O Linde/ORGANIZATION said/O Wednesday/O it/O had/O won/O a/O contract/O worth/O 140/O million/O euros/O -LRB-/O $/O 172/O million/O -RRB-/O to/O build/O the/O world/O 's/O largest/O ethylene/O plant/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
The/O contract/O was/O awarded/O by/O PetroChina/ORGANIZATION international/O and/O was/O signed/O by/O the/O two/O companies/O on/O Sunday/O ,/O Linde/ORGANIZATION said/O in/O a/O statement/O ./O
The/O plant/O ,/O which/O would/O go/O onstream/O in/O the/O second/O half/O of/O 2008/O ,/O will/O produce/O one/O million/O tons/O of/O ethylene/O each/O year/O and/O 500,000/O tons/O of/O propylene/O ,/O Linde/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O
It/O will/O be/O situated/O in/O Dushanzi/U_LOCATION in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O north/O west/O China/LOCATION ./O
