After/O seven/O years/O ,/O the/O controversial/O US/LOCATION military/O prison/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION is/O set/O to/O close/O ./O
Not/O just/O the/O camp/O but/O the/O entire/O system/O which/O violates/O international/O law/O needs/O to/O disappear/O ,/O says/O DW/ORGANIZATION 's/O Daniel/PERSON Scheschkewitz/PERSON ./O
In/O the/O beginning/O ,/O there/O were/O chains/O and/O cages/O which/O later/O gave/O way/O to/O a/O highly/O sophisticated/O high/O security/O complex/O ./O
The/O prison/O camp/O ,/O which/O prompted/O outrage/O among/O human/O rights/O lawyers/O around/O the/O world/O ,/O systematically/O circumvented/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O for/O over/O seven/O years/O ./O
Daniel/PERSON Scheschkewitz/PERSON
Terror/O suspects/O in/O the/O camp/O were/O subjected/O to/O questionable/O interrogation/O practices/O in/O an/O attempt/O to/O force/O confessions/O ./O
If/O at/O all/O charges/O were/O brought/O against/O a/O suspect/O ,/O the/O trial/O took/O place/O in/O military/O courts/O whose/O make-up/O and/O rules/O were/O unworthy/O of/O a/O constitutional/O country/O like/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O
Erasing/O a/O stain/O
The/O Guantanamo/LOCATION system/O ,/O introduced/O by/O President/O George/PERSON W/PERSON Bush/PERSON after/O the/O terrorist/O attacks/O on/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O Washington/LOCATION and/O the/O toppling/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION regime/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O is/O now/O set/O to/O end/O ./O
The/O Pentagon/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O oversees/O the/O prison/O 's/O functioning/O ,/O is/O now/O preparing/O for/O its/O closure/O ./O
That/O will/O hopefully/O permanently/O erase/O the/O blemish/O on/O the/O international/O reputation/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O a/O country/O without/O whom/O there/O would/O be/O no/O internationally/O valid/O human/O rights/O ./O
It/O 's/O also/O likely/O to/O satisfy/O all/O democratic/O countries/O and/O their/O citizens/O ./O
But/O a/O simple/O announcement/O to/O close/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION is/O n't/O enough/O ./O
The/O US/LOCATION government/O will/O now/O have/O to/O deal/O with/O dismantling/O the/O prison/O camp/O in/O such/O a/O manner/O that/O real/O terrorists/O continue/O to/O remain/O in/O custody/O and/O are/O sentenced/O according/O to/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O ,/O terror/O suspects/O face/O trial/O in/O proper/O courts/O and/O the/O innocent/O are/O released/O without/O fearing/O for/O their/O lives/O ./O
Or/O if/O he/O deported/O prisoners/O ,/O who/O are/O proven/O innocent/O ,/O to/O countries/O where/O they/O are/O threatened/O with/O imprisonment/O or/O torture/O ./O
Germany/LOCATION must/O step/O up/O
This/O is/O where/O countries/O such/O as/O Germany/LOCATION and/O other/O EU/ORGANIZATION nations/O should/O take/O responsibility/O and/O offer/O refuge/O to/O groups/O such/O as/O the/O small/O number/O of/O Uighurs/O held/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION --/O a/O Muslim/O minority/O that/O faces/O persecution/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
The/O military/O trials/O should/O also/O be/O replaced/O by/O proper/O legal/O proceedings/O in/O US/LOCATION civilian/O courts/O --/O a/O right/O that/O America/LOCATION 's/O highest/O court/O upheld/O for/O Guantanamo/LOCATION prisoners/O in/O a/O ruling/O more/O than/O two/O years/O ago/O ./O
Complicated/O decisions/O
Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON 's/O legal/O advisors/O face/O complicated/O decisions/O that/O involve/O balancing/O national/O security/O imperatives/O with/O the/O principles/O of/O a/O constitutional/O state/O ./O
Fighting/O terrorism/O can/O no/O longer/O involve/O psychological/O torture/O and/O law-free/O zones/O ./O
It/O 's/O only/O then/O that/O the/O US/LOCATION can/O be/O led/O back/O permanently/O on/O the/O track/O to/O upholding/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O after/O years/O of/O understandably/O straying/O from/O it/O ./O
Daniel/PERSON Scheschkewitz/PERSON is/O a/O reporter/O for/O DW-RADIO/ORGANIZATION and/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION 's/O former/O Washington/LOCATION correspondent/O -LRB-/O sp/O -RRB-/O
