The/O International/ORGANIZATION Olympic/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION praised/O China/LOCATION 's/O newfound/O openness/O when/O it/O hosted/O the/O 2008/O Olympics/O ./O
With/O the/O Games/O over/O ,/O many/O wonder/O if/O these/O new/O freedoms/O will/O be/O extinguished/O along/O with/O the/O Olympic/O flame/O ./O
During/O the/O last/O two/O weeks/O ,/O the/O world/O has/O watched/O in/O awe/O as/O athletes/O from/O around/O the/O globe/O broke/O records/O ,/O leapt/O to/O new/O heights/O and/O swam/O faster/O than/O ever/O ./O
Along/O with/O its/O record/O number/O of/O gold/O medalists/O ,/O host/O country/O China/LOCATION likewise/O had/O its/O shining/O moment/O as/O countless/O news/O features/O reported/O on/O the/O billion-dollar/O polishing/O of/O the/O communist/O nation/O 's/O image/O ./O
From/O the/O uniquely-designed/O Birds/LOCATION '/LOCATION Nest/LOCATION stadium/O to/O the/O efforts/O to/O eliminate/O smog/O in/O the/O one/O of/O the/O world/O 's/O most/O polluted/O cities/O ,/O nothing/O --/O not/O even/O China/LOCATION 's/O approach/O to/O human/O rights/O issues/O --/O was/O left/O undiscussed/O ./O
Despite/O efforts/O to/O bring/O the/O world/O 's/O focus/O onto/O positive/O developments/O in/O the/O nation/O ,/O however/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O faced/O stream/O of/O criticism/O about/O its/O policies/O ,/O most/O notably/O from/O journalists/O frustrated/O by/O a/O lack/O of/O press/O freedom/O ./O
Small/O success/O for/O free/O speech/O
After/O stories/O appeared/O lamenting/O the/O censorship/O of/O certain/O Web/O sites/O ,/O including/O the/O Chinese/O language/O version/O of/O DW-WORLD.DE/O ,/O in/O the/O Olympic/O press/O center/O ,/O restrictions/O on/O foreign/O journalists/O seemed/O to/O loosen/O ./O
Bans/O on/O several/O Web/O sites/O were/O lifted/O in/O the/O press/O center/O and/O requirements/O for/O registering/O interviews/O with/O government/O authorities/O were/O theoretically/O removed/O ./O
Web/O censorship/O had/O many/O journalists/O up/O in/O arms/O
Human/O rights/O activists/O applauded/O this/O step/O toward/O transparency/O ./O
``/O We/O had/O a/O small/O success/O ,/O ''/O said/O Annette/PERSON Hartmetz/PERSON ,/O campaign/O coordinator/O for/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION Germany/ORGANIZATION ,/O whose/O Web/O site/O was/O one/O of/O those/O banned/O by/O Chinese/O officials/O ./O
``/O We/O hope/O it/O stays/O that/O way/O after/O the/O Games/O ./O ''/O
The/O popular/O Beijing/ORGANIZATION Youth/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION took/O Binjie/PERSON 's/O sentiments/O one/O step/O further/O ./O
``/O Even/O though/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Games/O have/O ended/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O opening/O up/O and/O exchanges/O with/O the/O world/O will/O not/O cease/O ,/O and/O the/O Chinese/O people/O 's/O participation/O in/O the/O development/O and/O improvement/O of/O mankind/O will/O not/O change/O ,/O ''/O it/O wrote/O ./O
Cracking/O down/O in/O the/O background/O ?/O
But/O while/O the/O world/O watched/O Michael/PERSON Phelps/PERSON achieve/O an/O Olympic/O first/O ,/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O instituted/O a/O crackdown/O in/O the/O country/O 's/O separatist/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O ./O
Representatives/O of/O the/O Muslim/O Uighur/O minority/O group/O ,/O the/O exiled/O Uighur/U_ORGANIZATION World/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O over/O 500/O activists/O were/O detained/O there/O ./O
The/O remote/O Himalayan/O prefecture/O of/O Garze/LOCATION ,/O one/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O most/O volatile/O and/O isolated/O Tibetan/O regions/O ,/O likewise/O saw/O an/O increase/O in/O oppression/O as/O armed/O soldiers/O set/O up/O checkpoints/O throughout/O the/O province/O and/O plainclothes/O policemen/O monitored/O Buddhist/O temples/O for/O signs/O of/O dissent/O ./O
Authorities/O arrested/O 10/O Pro-Tibet/O demonstrators/O during/O the/O Games/O
Those/O are/O just/O two/O in/O a/O laundry/O list/O of/O accusations/O human/O rights/O groups/O have/O leveled/O at/O the/O socialist/O regime/O ,/O begging/O the/O question/O of/O just/O how/O much/O the/O government/O has/O changed/O ./O
One/O foreign/O journalist/O working/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION told/O Reporters/ORGANIZATION Without/ORGANIZATION Borders/ORGANIZATION she/O was/O surveyed/O very/O closely/O in/O the/O run-up/O to/O the/O Games/O ./O
``/O They/O constantly/O follow/O me/O ,/O taking/O photos/O and/O video/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O
``/O I/O have/O to/O think/O twice/O about/O who/O I/O speak/O with/O about/O delicate/O issues/O because/O I/O 'm/O afraid/O afterward/O they/O 'll/O be/O arrested/O ./O ''/O
Reporters/ORGANIZATION Without/ORGANIZATION Borders/ORGANIZATION reported/O that/O this/O year/O 31/O journalists/O ,/O bloggers/O and/O free/O speech/O activists/O have/O been/O arrested/O or/O put/O in/O jail/O ./O
Public/O protests/O quashed/O
Though/O the/O government/O established/O three/O protest/O areas/O in/O public/O parks/O to/O respond/O to/O the/O IOC/ORGANIZATION 's/O concerns/O that/O public/O speech/O against/O the/O government/O would/O be/O quashed/O ,/O no/O protests/O were/O held/O ./O
Potential/O protestors/O were/O made/O to/O register/O with/O the/O authorities/O ,/O who/O then/O denied/O all/O of/O the/O 77/O applications/O ./O
Two/O of/O the/O applicants/O ,/O women/O in/O their/O late/O 70s/O ,/O were/O sentenced/O to/O re-education/O camps/O for/O trying/O to/O protest/O a/O land/O dispute/O ./O
``/O Of/O all/O the/O ways/O in/O which/O we/O tried/O to/O game/O out/O what/O rock/O bottom/O would/O look/O like/O ,/O even/O we/O would/O not/O have/O anticipated/O that/O two/O septuagenarians/O would/O be/O sentenced/O to/O re-education/O through/O labor/O while/O the/O Games/O were/O going/O on/O ,/O ''/O Sophie/PERSON Richardson/PERSON ,/O Asia/LOCATION advocacy/O director/O at/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION said/O in/O a/O statement/O ./O
Olympic/O venues/O like/O the/O Birds/LOCATION '/LOCATION Nest/LOCATION stadium/O led/O to/O the/O relocation/O of/O 1.5/O million/O residents/O
With/O such/O developments/O taking/O place/O while/O the/O cameras/O were/O still/O rolling/O ,/O some/O are/O concerned/O about/O what/O will/O become/O of/O the/O human/O rights/O issues/O when/O the/O international/O spotlight/O is/O n't/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
``/O As/O happy/O as/O we/O may/O be/O about/O the/O progress/O that/O was/O made/O ,/O the/O Olympics/O have/O also/O created/O new/O human/O rights/O problems/O and/O that/O makes/O for/O a/O lousy/O balancing/O of/O accounts/O ,/O ''/O said/O Hartmetz/PERSON ./O
``/O But/O China/LOCATION has/O always/O been/O a/O big/O place/O for/O us/O to/O continue/O our/O work/O and/O of/O course/O we/O 'll/O carry/O on/O ./O ''/O
Herta/PERSON Daeubler-Gmelin/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O German/O parliament/O 's/O human/O rights/O committee/O ,/O reaffirmed/O her/O commitment/O to/O continuing/O the/O discussion/O about/O China/LOCATION 's/O human/O rights/O in/O an/O interview/O with/O DW-WORLD.DE/O ./O
``/O We/O 'll/O be/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION in/O October/O and/O carefully/O observe/O the/O human/O rights/O situation/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O
``/O But/O I/O 'm/O against/O lecturing/O people/O ./O
We/O should/O clearly/O and/O unequivocally/O demand/O human/O rights/O ,/O and/O we/O have/O to/O keep/O doing/O so/O ,/O also/O as/O human/O rights/O activists/O and/O politicians/O ./O
.../O It/O 's/O very/O important/O to/O me/O that/O the/O question/O of/O human/O rights/O does/O n't/O get/O taken/O off/O the/O agenda/O ./O ''/O
