Germany/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O minister/O is/O opposed/O to/O his/O country/O accepting/O a/O group/O of/O Guantanamo/LOCATION prisoners/O of/O Uigher/O origin/O ,/O telling/O a/O German/O news/O magazine/O that/O he/O 's/O worried/O that/O taking/O them/O in/O will/O cause/O trouble/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O
In/O an/O interview/O with/O the/O news/O magazine/O Der/ORGANIZATION Spiegel/ORGANIZATION ,/O German/O Foreign/O Minister/O Frank-Walter/PERSON Steinmeier/PERSON said/O that/O while/O he/O was/O in/O favor/O of/O taking/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION inmates/O ,/O he/O wants/O to/O keep/O the/O number/O of/O Uighurs/O accepted/O to/O a/O minimum/O ./O
According/O to/O the/O report/O ,/O senior/O US/LOCATION diplomat/O Daniel/PERSON Fried/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O responsible/O for/O finding/O new/O homes/O for/O the/O inmates/O of/O the/O soon-to-be-closed/O Guantanamo/LOCATION prison/O ,/O had/O asked/O Germany/LOCATION at/O the/O end/O of/O April/O to/O take/O in/O the/O nine/O men/O ./O
The/O men/O are/O members/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uighur/O minority/O ,/O a/O mainly/O Muslim/O group/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION considers/O to/O be/O terrorists/O ./O
Steinmeier/PERSON worries/O that/O accepting/O the/O inmates/O would/O cause/O a/O political/O fight/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O which/O has/O been/O demanding/O that/O they/O be/O extradited/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O
Conditional/O acceptance/O
Beijing/LOCATION considers/O some/O Uighurs/O to/O be/O terrorists/O
According/O to/O Der/ORGANIZATION Spiegel/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reinhard/PERSON Silberberg/PERSON ,/O a/O senior/O official/O with/O the/O German/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O the/O US/LOCATION Berlin/LOCATION would/O take/O in/O the/O nine/O provided/O that/O other/O European/O nations/O accept/O Uighurs/O as/O well/O ,/O thereby/O lessening/O the/O pressure/O on/O Germany/LOCATION ./O
Steinmeier/PERSON has/O received/O support/O for/O his/O statement/O from/O former/O German/O Chancellor/O Gerhard/PERSON Schroeder/PERSON ,/O who/O told/O Der/ORGANIZATION Spiegel/ORGANIZATION that/O accepting/O Uighurs/O would/O certainly/O put/O a/O strain/O on/O German-Chinese/O relations/O ./O
Schroeder/PERSON said/O that/O while/O he/O is/O in/O favor/O of/O supporting/O US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON in/O his/O efforts/O to/O close/O Guantanamo/LOCATION ,/O only/O the/O US/LOCATION is/O in/O a/O position/O to/O take/O in/O the/O Uighurs/O without/O suffering/O any/O political/O consequences/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O
mrm/O //O Reuters/ORGANIZATION //O AFP/ORGANIZATION
Editor/O :/O Nancy/PERSON Isenson/PERSON
