As/O Afghan/O President/O Karzai/PERSON continued/O his/O three-day/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O he/O met/O his/O Chinese/O counterpart/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
They/O discussed/O issues/O ranging/O from/O regional/O security/O to/O Chinese/O investment/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
Three/O agreements/O on/O trade/O and/O economic/O co-operation/O were/O signed/O in/O the/O presence/O of/O Afghan/O President/O Hamid/PERSON Karzai/PERSON and/O his/O Chinese/O counterpart/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON on/O Wednesday/O ./O
One/O was/O for/O more/O economic/O aid/O to/O war-torn/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
China/LOCATION ,/O which/O has/O no/O troops/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O has/O already/O given/O aid/O worth/O 130/O million/O euros/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION since/O 2002/O ./O
The/O money/O has/O mainly/O been/O used/O for/O reconstruction/O projects/O ./O
President/O Karzai/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O travelling/O with/O some/O 20/O business/O executives/O ,/O is/O keen/O for/O China/LOCATION to/O invest/O even/O more/O ./O
In/O 2004/O ,/O 11/O Chinese/O road/O workers/O were/O killed/O in/O Afganistan/LOCATION and/O four/O were/O injured/O
``/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O attempts/O to/O boost/O ties/O with/O neighboring/O countries/O in/O areas/O such/O as/O business/O will/O be/O good/O for/O security/O and/O peace/O ./O
More/O importantly/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O only/O interested/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION from/O an/O economics/O point/O of/O view/O ,/O not/O political/O ,/O ''/O said/O Saifuddin/PERSON Saihoon/PERSON ,/O an/O economics/O expert/O in/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O
Karzai/PERSON thanks/O China/LOCATION for/O support/O and/O aid/O
The/O Chinese/O state/O media/O reported/O during/O the/O closed-door/O talks/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION that/O the/O Afghan/O president/O had/O thanked/O China/LOCATION for/O its/O support/O and/O aid/O and/O said/O that/O it/O had/O a/O very/O important/O role/O to/O play/O for/O stability/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O the/O region/O ./O
Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ,/O for/O his/O part/O ,/O said/O China/LOCATION wanted/O to/O ``/O advance/O practical/O cooperation/O ''/O with/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O ``/O lift/O the/O two/O countries/O '/O comprehensive/O partnership/O to/O new/O levels/O ./O ''/O
In/O part/O ,/O this/O ``/O comprehensive/O partnership/O ''/O involves/O China/LOCATION tapping/O into/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O vast/O natural/O resources/O ./O
``/O China/LOCATION will/O increasingly/O buy/O natural/O and/O mineral/O resources/O from/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O explained/O Niklas/PERSON Swanstroem/PERSON from/O the/O Central/ORGANIZATION Asia-Caucasus/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION and/O Silk/ORGANIZATION Road/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION Program/ORGANIZATION in/O Stockholm/LOCATION ./O
``/O The/O problem/O is/O that/O Afghanistan/LOCATION does/O n't/O have/O the/O infrastructure/O to/O transport/O them/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O
A/O practical/O measure/O would/O be/O to/O improve/O infrastructure/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O ''/O
In/O 2008/O ,/O a/O group/O of/O Chinese/O firms/O won/O a/O contract/O to/O develop/O the/O vast/O Aynak/LOCATION copper/O mine/O south/O of/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O
The/O mine/O is/O expected/O to/O start/O production/O in/O three/O or/O four/O years/O ,/O although/O violence/O in/O the/O country/O has/O hampered/O progress/O ./O
A/O delegation/O from/O the/O state-owned/O China/ORGANIZATION Metallurgical/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION Corporation/ORGANIZATION visits/O the/O copper/O mine/O in/O Aynak/LOCATION south/O of/O Kabul/LOCATION
Fighting/O terrorism/O and/O organized/O cross-border/O crime/O
In/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION talks/O on/O Wednesday/O ,/O the/O two/O sides/O agreed/O to/O cooperate/O more/O in/O combating/O terrorism/O in/O the/O region/O and/O tackling/O organized/O cross-border/O crime/O ./O
China/LOCATION thinks/O a/O stable/O Afghanistan/LOCATION could/O help/O curb/O the/O threat/O of/O violence/O in/O its/O far-western/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
There/O has/O also/O been/O speculation/O that/O Karzai/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O trying/O to/O garner/O international/O support/O for/O his/O attempts/O to/O hold/O peace/O talks/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O also/O wants/O China/LOCATION to/O put/O pressure/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION --/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O key/O ally/O --/O to/O help/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O these/O efforts/O ./O
However/O ,/O experts/O doubt/O that/O China/LOCATION will/O do/O this/O ./O
``/O They/O are/O afraid/O of/O having/O problems/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O the/O West/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Niklas/PERSON Swanstroem/PERSON pointed/O out/O ./O
``/O Moreover/O ,/O once/O China/LOCATION engages/O in/O the/O security/O of/O other/O countries/O ,/O it/O will/O create/O a/O sort/O of/O fear/O that/O it/O is/O intervening/O in/O the/O internal/O affairs/O of/O other/O states/O and/O China/LOCATION does/O n't/O want/O to/O do/O this/O ./O ''/O
President/O Karzai/PERSON is/O due/O to/O meet/O Premier/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON on/O Thursday/O ./O
He/O is/O also/O scheduled/O to/O hold/O a/O speech/O at/O Beijing/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION later/O this/O week/O ./O
Author/O :/O Disha/PERSON Uppal/PERSON
Editor/O :/O Anne/PERSON Thomas/PERSON
