Chinese/O security/O forces/O have/O shot/O dead/O two/O men/O suspected/O of/O fomenting/O deadly/O ethnic/O unrest/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O ./O
The/O police/O have/O vowed/O a/O further/O crackdown/O on/O religious/O extremists/O ./O
The/O two/O suspects/O ,/O Memtieli/U_PERSON Tiliwaldi/U_PERSON and/O Turson/U_PERSON Hasan/U_PERSON ,/O were/O shot/O by/O police/O late/O on/O Monday/O in/O corn/O fields/O on/O the/O outskirts/O of/O Kashgar/U_LOCATION city/O ./O
The/O men/O were/O both/O from/O the/O Muslim/O Uighur/O minority/O that/O makes/O up/O around/O half/O the/O population/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O ./O
The/O deaths/O bring/O to/O 21/O the/O number/O of/O people/O reported/O killed/O in/O Kashgar/U_LOCATION ,/O a/O city/O on/O the/O ancient/O Silk/U_LOCATION Road/U_LOCATION in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O in/O the/O latest/O bout/O of/O unrest/O that/O began/O at/O the/O weekend/O ./O
Tensions/O are/O running/O high/O after/O the/O weekend/O violence/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
Police/O earlier/O issued/O warrants/O for/O the/O two/O and/O a/O reward/O of/O 100,000/O yuan/O -LRB-/O about/O 15,000/O US/O dollars/O -RRB-/O for/O information/O leading/O to/O their/O arrests/O ./O
They/O were/O accused/O of/O involvement/O in/O an/O attack/O Sunday/O in/O which/O six/O civilians/O were/O killed/O when/O a/O restaurant/O was/O set/O ablaze/O ,/O apparently/O after/O explosives/O were/O thrown/O at/O it/O ./O
Kashgar/U_LOCATION authorities/O said/O Monday/O that/O the/O leaders/O of/O the/O group/O behind/O Sunday/O 's/O attack/O had/O learned/O explosive-and/O firearm-making/O skills/O in/O camps/O run/O by/O the/O East/U_ORGANIZATION Turkestan/U_ORGANIZATION Islamic/U_ORGANIZATION Movement/U_ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O ETIM/U_ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
Chinese/O authorities/O have/O accused/O the/O ETIM/U_ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O wants/O an/O independent/O homeland/O for/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION 's/O Uighurs/O ,/O of/O orchestrating/O attacks/O in/O the/O region/O on/O many/O occasions/O ./O
Violent/O Weekend/O
Tensions/O were/O running/O high/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O remote/O Kashgar/U_LOCATION city/O Tuesday/O after/O the/O latest/O outburst/O of/O violence/O to/O rattle/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
Many/O of/O the/O minority/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O there/O resent/O the/O presence/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O and/O the/O controls/O imposed/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
``/O Look/O at/O the/O Han/O and/O the/O Uighurs/O -/O who/O is/O rich/O and/O who/O is/O poor/O ?/O
Some/O Uighurs/O go/O to/O university/O in/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION 's/O capital/O -RRB-/O ,/O they/O graduate/O ,/O come/O back/O and/O ca/O n't/O find/O jobs/O ./O
These/O all/O go/O to/O the/O Han/O ./O
And/O even/O when/O they/O do/O find/O jobs/O ,/O their/O salaries/O are/O low/O ./O
``/O said/O one/O Uighur/O man/O aged/O in/O his/O 20s/O ,/O who/O spoke/O on/O condition/O of/O anonymity/O ./O
Muslim/O Uighur/O community/O is/O unhappy/O with/O the/O ``/O political/O and/O religious/O repression/O ''/O ./O
Thirteen/O of/O the/O people/O killed/O in/O the/O last/O few/O days/O were/O civilians/O while/O the/O other/O eight/O were/O alleged/O militants/O ./O
Xinjiang/U_LOCATION 's/O government/O has/O pledged/O to/O firmly/O punish/O acts/O of/O violence/O and/O crack/O down/O on/O religious/O extremists/O in/O the/O wake/O of/O the/O attacks/O ,/O which/O came/O just/O weeks/O after/O deadly/O clashes/O in/O Hotan/U_LOCATION ,/O another/O city/O in/O the/O vast/O region/O ./O
Rife/O with/O Tension/O
On/O Tuesday/O ,/O there/O was/O a/O heavy/O police/O presence/O on/O the/O streets/O of/O Kashgar/U_LOCATION ,/O with/O some/O shops/O and/O businesses/O remaining/O closed/O ./O
The/O tension/O has/O triggered/O sporadic/O bouts/O of/O unrest/O in/O the/O resource-rich/O and/O strategically/O vital/O region/O that/O borders/O eight/O countries/O ,/O including/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
In/O July/O 2009/O ,/O China/LOCATION was/O hit/O by/O its/O worst/O ethnic/O violence/O in/O decades/O when/O Uighurs/O savagely/O attacked/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ./O
It/O led/O to/O deadly/O reprisals/O by/O Han/O on/O Uighurs/O several/O days/O later/O ./O
The/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION have/O listed/O the/O group/O suspected/O of/O the/O attacks/O as/O a/O ``/O terrorist/O ''/O organisation/O ,/O and/O China/LOCATION has/O previously/O said/O it/O has/O operations/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION as/O well/O as/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
Chinese/O state-run/O media/O has/O devoted/O little/O space/O to/O the/O attacks/O ,/O and/O the/O words/O ``/O Kashgar/U_LOCATION ''/O and/O ``/O terrorist/O attacks/O ''/O appear/O to/O be/O blocked/O on/O China/LOCATION 's/O Twitter-like/O social/O networking/O sites/O ./O
Author/O :/O Sachin/PERSON Gaur/PERSON -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
Editor/O :/O Grahame/PERSON Lucas/PERSON
