Approximately/O 2.6/O million/O square/O meters/O of/O land/O in/O China/LOCATION consist/O of/O only/O sand/O or/O rock/O desert/O ./O
That/O is/O an/O area/O about/O seven/O times/O the/O size/O of/O Germany/LOCATION ./O
Efforts/O to/O stop/O the/O sand/O from/O spreading/O are/O tedious/O and/O slow/O ./O
Sand/O dunes/O reach/O as/O far/O as/O the/O eyes/O can/O see/O in/O Shapotou/LOCATION in/O the/O northwestern/O province/O of/O Ningxia/LOCATION ./O
At/O the/O edge/O of/O the/O desert/O ,/O people/O are/O fixing/O square-shaped/O straw/O mats/O to/O the/O ground/O to/O stabilize/O it/O ./O
Each/O square/O measures/O around/O one/O by/O one/O meter/O ./O
The/O straw/O mats/O cover/O the/O edge/O of/O the/O desert/O like/O giant/O fishing/O nets/O ./O
Tree/O planting/O has/O become/O a/O key/O government/O effort/O to/O fight/O desertification/O
Yong/PERSON Xu/PERSON Cheng/PERSON of/O the/O local/O government/O administration/O says/O the/O method/O seems/O to/O be/O working/O ./O
But/O he/O adds/O that/O they/O can/O only/O do/O so/O much/O ./O
He/O says/O it/O is/O ``/O very/O difficult/O to/O stop/O the/O sand/O from/O spreading/O ./O
We/O can/O only/O work/O at/O the/O edge/O of/O the/O desert/O ,/O around/O the/O railway/O and/O streets/O and/O around/O the/O peripheries/O of/O villages/O and/O cities/O ./O ''/O
But/O the/O efforts/O are/O crucial/O ,/O he/O believes/O :/O ``/O We/O do/O n't/O have/O a/O choice/O ./O
We/O have/O to/O keep/O the/O sand/O at/O bay/O to/O ensure/O our/O survival/O ./O ''/O
Desert/O plantations/O and/O vineyards/O
The/O square/O mats/O stabilize/O the/O sand/O so/O that/O grass/O can/O be/O planted/O ./O
That/O will/O prepare/O the/O ground/O for/O larger/O plants/O to/O be/O planted/O later/O on/O ./O
Using/O this/O method/O ,/O people/O in/O and/O around/O Shapotou/LOCATION have/O been/O able/O to/O cultivate/O fruit/O plantations/O and/O grapevines/O ./O
But/O in/O other/O parts/O of/O the/O Province/O Ningxia/LOCATION ,/O people/O have/O already/O lost/O the/O battle/O against/O the/O desert/O ./O
Inner/O Mongolia/LOCATION ,/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O Gansu/LOCATION ,/O Qinghai/LOCATION ,/O Ningxia/LOCATION ,/O Shaanxi/LOCATION ,/O Heilongjiang/LOCATION and/O Hebei/LOCATION are/O fighting/O severe/O desertification/O In/O the/O province/O there/O are/O new/O settlements/O ./O
Ma/PERSON Dengpeng/PERSON lives/O in/O one/O ,/O though/O ,/O as/O he/O explains/O ,/O he/O had/O not/O originally/O wanted/O to/O move/O away/O from/O his/O previous/O home/O ./O
``/O When/O the/O sand/O came/O it/O looked/O like/O black/O wind/O ./O
It/O could/O n't/O be/O stopped/O ./O
We/O had/O to/O stay/O in/O our/O house/O --/O we/O could/O n't/O leave/O the/O house/O ./O ''/O
Ma/PERSON says/O he/O and/O his/O family/O had/O to/O flee/O and/O that/O the/O government/O offered/O to/O relocate/O them/O ./O
Overgrazing/O Ningxia/LOCATION was/O not/O always/O as/O arid/O as/O it/O is/O now/O ./O
Large/O parts/O of/O northern/O China/LOCATION used/O to/O be/O vast/O areas/O of/O grassland/O ./O
Part/O of/O the/O reason/O these/O grasslands/O are/O gone/O is/O due/O to/O climate/O change/O but/O also/O because/O too/O much/O water/O was/O wasted/O over/O a/O long/O period/O of/O time/O ./O
Over-grazing/O ,/O logging/O ,/O farms/O and/O population/O pressure/O ,/O and/O droughts/O have/O turned/O fertile/O grasslands/O into/O sandy/O plains/O
The/O American/O agrarian-economist/O Lester/PERSON Brown/PERSON also/O believes/O that/O agriculture/O played/O a/O role/O ./O
Brown/PERSON explains/O the/O economic/O reforms/O of/O the/O late/O 1970s/O ,/O ``/O when/O agriculture/O shifted/O away/O from/O production/O teams/O into/O families/O ,/O ''/O and/O the/O government/O lost/O control/O of/O livestock/O ./O
He/O says/O that/O led/O to/O ``/O a/O classic/O sort/O of/O tragedy/O of/O the/O commons/O where/O each/O family/O want/O -LSB-/O ed/O -RSB-/O to/O keep/O expanding/O the/O number/O of/O sheep/O and/O goats/O but/O with/O no/O one/O looking/O at/O the/O entire/O effect/O of/O this/O and/O what/O happens/O is/O once/O the/O vegetation/O is/O removed/O entirely/O from/O overgrazing/O ,/O once/O the/O land/O is/O bare/O ,/O then/O the/O wind/O takes/O over/O ./O ''/O
The/O blink/O of/O an/O eye/O
Desertification/O is/O a/O great/O threat/O to/O human/O life/O
Land/O which/O was/O once/O arable/O thus/O becomes/O steppe/O and/O then/O desert/O ./O
The/O government/O has/O been/O fighting/O this/O process/O for/O years/O ./O
It/O has/O made/O it/O illegal/O for/O herders/O to/O let/O their/O sheep/O graze/O outside/O ,/O and/O it/O has/O started/O the/O so-called/O ``/O green/O wall/O ''/O -/O a/O project/O to/O plant/O millions/O of/O trees/O in/O northern/O China/LOCATION ./O
Yong/PERSON Xu/PERSON Cheng/PERSON says/O it/O has/O become/O a/O flagship/O project/O ./O
He/O is/O hopeful/O and/O says/O that/O one/O day/O ,/O mankind/O will/O conquer/O the/O desert/O completely/O ./O
Though/O China/LOCATION has/O had/O some/O success/O in/O pushing/O back/O the/O desert/O ,/O it/O is/O sure/O to/O take/O a/O lot/O of/O time/O and/O hard/O work/O to/O conquer/O it/O completely/O ./O
According/O to/O official/O estimates/O ,/O China/LOCATION will/O be/O able/O to/O regain/O one/O fifth/O of/O its/O desert/O land/O --/O but/O it/O will/O take/O around/O 300/O years/O to/O do/O so/O ./O
Author/O :/O Ruth/PERSON Kirchner/PERSON -LRB-/O sb/O -RRB-/O
Editor/O :/O Manasi/PERSON Gopalakrishnan/PERSON
