China/LOCATION has/O admitted/O shortcomings/O at/O a/O UN/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION review/O in/O Geneva/LOCATION ./O
Rights/O advocates/O continue/O to/O rebuke/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O arresting/O dissidents/O ,/O suppressing/O ethnic/O minorities/O and/O widespread/O use/O of/O the/O death/O penalty/O ./O
A/O Chinese/O envoy/O told/O the/O 47-member/O UN/ORGANIZATION council/O on/O Tuesday/O that/O China/LOCATION had/O ``/O many/O difficulties/O ''/O in/O promoting/O human/O rights/O ./O
Wu/PERSON Hailong/PERSON said/O reducing/O poverty/O was/O the/O priority/O among/O China/LOCATION 's/O 1.3/O billion/O people/O ./O
Hours/O before/O the/O council/O began/O its/O four-yearly/O review/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O rights/O record/O ,/O Tibetan/O activists/O slipped/O past/O guards/O at/O Geneva/LOCATION 's/O Palais/LOCATION des/LOCATION Nations/LOCATION and/O unfurled/O a/O banner/O reading/O :/O ``/O China/LOCATION fails/O human/O rights/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION --/O UN/ORGANIZATION stand/O up/O for/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O ''/O
They/O also/O displayed/O a/O mock/O head/O -LRB-/O pictured/O above/O -RRB-/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O new/O president/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ./O
China/LOCATION faces/O persistent/O criticism/O ,/O mainly/O from/O Western/O countries/O ,/O for/O repression/O ,/O including/O crackdowns/O on/O Tibetans/O and/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O in/O the/O western/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O ./O
Wu/PERSON ,/O a/O special/O envoy/O for/O China/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O ministry/O ,/O claimed/O in/O his/O speech/O that/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ``/O ensures/O that/O minority/O ethnic/O groups/O in/O China/LOCATION enjoy/O extensive/O human/O rights/O ./O ''/O
`/O Many/O difficulties/O '/O
``/O We/O are/O soberly/O aware/O that/O China/LOCATION still/O faces/O many/O difficulties/O and/O challenges/O in/O promoting/O and/O protecting/O human/O rights/O ,/O ''/O Wu/PERSON added/O ./O
China/LOCATION envoy/O Wu/PERSON admits/O `/O difficulties/O '/O
The/O non-binding/O review/O process/O -/O led/O by/O Poland/LOCATION ,/O Sierra/LOCATION Leone/LOCATION and/O the/O United/LOCATION Arab/LOCATION Emirates/LOCATION --/O also/O focused/O on/O the/O failure/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O parliament/O to/O ratify/O the/O International/O Covenant/O on/O Civil/O and/O Political/O Rights/O -LRB-/O ICCPR/O -RRB-/O ./O
China/LOCATION signed/O it/O in/O 1998/O but/O its/O parliament/O never/O ratified/O the/O treaty/O which/O stresses/O freedom/O of/O religion/O ,/O assembly/O and/O speech/O ./O
The/O review/O is/O the/O first/O since/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON took/O office/O in/O March/O ./O
`/O Backwards/O ,/O '/O says/O critic/O
Prominent/O rights/O lawyer/O Mo/PERSON Shaoping/PERSON said/O Xi/PERSON had/O ``/O definitely/O taken/O the/O country/O backwards/O on/O human/O rights/O ./O ''/O
DW/ORGANIZATION recommends/O
New/O group/O aims/O to/O eradicate/O modern-day/O slavery/O
Some/O 30/O million/O people/O still/O live/O in/O slavery/O ./O
A/O new/O foundation/O wants/O to/O see/O that/O number/O drop/O dramatically/O as/O quickly/O as/O possible/O ./O
Its/O well-heeled/O supporters/O might/O be/O more/O effective/O than/O existing/O organizations/O ./O
-LRB-/O 19.10.2013/O -RRB-/O
Opinion/O :/O Xi/PERSON and/O China/LOCATION 's/O seven/O taboos/O
Despite/O China/LOCATION 's/O pledge/O to/O commit/O to/O news/O ideas/O ,/O the/O country/O 's/O universities/O have/O been/O ordered/O to/O steer/O clear/O of/O seven/O `/O unmentionable/O '/O topics/O ,/O including/O civil/O rights/O ./O
The/O move/O is/O seen/O by/O some/O as/O a/O `/O stunning/O retrogression/O ./O '/O
-LRB-/O 10.06.2013/O -RRB-/O
Chinese/O authorities/O recently/O detained/O at/O least/O 16/O activists/O who/O had/O demanded/O that/O officials/O publicly/O disclose/O their/O wealth/O ./O
Last/O week/O ,/O police/O arrested/O an/O influential/O blogger/O and/O a/O cartoonist/O in/O a/O crackdown/O on/O online/O ``/O rumor-mongering/O ./O ''/O
Rights/O groups/O say/O hundreds/O of/O have/O been/O arrested/O since/O August/O on/O similar/O charges/O ./O
`/O Abolish/O '/O death/O penalty/O
British/O ambassador/O Karen/PERSON Pierce/PERSON called/O on/O China/LOCATION to/O further/O reduce/O the/O number/O of/O crimes/O carrying/O the/O death/O penalty/O ./O
German/O Ambassador/O Hanns/PERSON Schumacher/PERSON also/O urged/O China/LOCATION to/O ``/O publish/O figures/O on/O death/O verdicts/O ''/O and/O spur/O public/O debate/O in/O China/LOCATION toward/O ``/O abolition/O ''/O of/O capital/O punishment/O ./O
China/LOCATION must/O continue/O to/O reform/O its/O criminal/O justice/O system/O ,/O in/O particular/O to/O abolish/O the/O Reeducation/O through/O Labor/O system/O ,/O Schumacher/PERSON added/O ./O
China/LOCATION puts/O around/O 4,000/O people/O to/O death/O every/O year/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION campaign/O group/O the/O Dui/ORGANIZATION Hua/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION ./O
Chinese/O state/O media/O on/O Tuesday/O said/O China/LOCATION had/O convicted/O nearly/O 150,000/O people/O for/O corruption/O since/O 2008/O ./O
ipj/dr/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
