For/O the/O first/O time/O China/LOCATION 's/O Communist/O party/O has/O discussed/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O at/O its/O annual/O assembly/O ./O
There/O are/O improvements/O ,/O but/O they/O are/O unlikely/O to/O change/O the/O mood/O among/O the/O Chinese/O people/O ,/O says/O DW/ORGANIZATION 's/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON ./O
It/O has/O by/O now/O acquired/O a/O reputation/O as/O one/O of/O the/O world/O 's/O most/O important/O political/O meetings/O :/O the/O assembly/O of/O the/O Central/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O usually/O convenes/O every/O fall/O to/O discuss/O new/O policies/O ./O
The/O main/O issue/O of/O the/O fourth/O convention/O of/O the/O 18th/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O drew/O to/O a/O close/O on/O October/O 23/O ,/O was/O the/O modernization/O of/O the/O judicial/O system/O ./O
For/O the/O first/O time/O in/O the/O history/O of/O the/O party/O ,/O the/O agenda/O was/O set/O by/O the/O assembly/O ,/O which/O is/O a/O step/O forward/O in/O itself/O ./O
Head/O of/O state/O and/O party/O leader/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON had/O already/O set/O the/O tone/O prior/O to/O the/O meeting/O ,/O not/O leaving/O any/O doubt/O that/O he/O was/O determined/O to/O make/O headway/O on/O the/O issue/O ./O
He/O said/O he/O intended/O to/O lock/O ``/O power/O in/O a/O cage/O ''/O and/O establish/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O ./O
His/O demand/O for/O ``/O constitutional/O governance/O ''/O caused/O a/O similar/O sensation/O ./O
Even/O so/O ,/O it/O would/O have/O been/O wrong/O to/O expect/O too/O much/O from/O the/O assembly/O ./O
After/O all/O ,/O it/O had/O to/O deal/O with/O a/O contradiction/O at/O the/O core/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O political/O system/O :/O On/O the/O one/O hand/O ,/O there/O are/O the/O power/O claims/O of/O the/O party/O as/O the/O decisive/O political/O force/O ./O
On/O the/O other/O ,/O there/O is/O a/O judicial/O system/O in/O which/O laws/O are/O supposed/O to/O be/O adhered/O to/O ,/O independent/O of/O party/O interests/O ./O
Slowly/O ,/O too/O slowly/O -/O and/O not/O just/O for/O Western/O tastes/O -/O the/O great/O party/O is/O moving/O the/O vast/O country/O towards/O a/O more/O independent/O judicial/O system/O ./O
Unlike/O a/O bicycle/O ,/O an/O oil/O tanker/O is/O simply/O unable/O to/O take/O a/O quick/O turn/O ./O
Lack/O of/O will/O may/O be/O playing/O its/O part/O here/O ,/O but/O first/O and/O foremost/O it/O is/O all/O down/O to/O the/O laws/O of/O physics/O ./O
The/O consequences/O of/O the/O decisions/O made/O will/O only/O be/O visible/O after/O some/O time/O has/O elapsed/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION 's/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON
Less/O influence/O on/O regional/O courts/O
However/O ,/O in/O future/O the/O party/O intends/O to/O punish/O those/O who/O exert/O influence/O on/O court/O decisions/O ./O
In/O addition/O ,/O such/O people/O will/O find/O themselves/O on/O a/O kind/O of/O blacklist/O ./O
Certainly/O this/O applies/O only/O to/O the/O kind/O of/O influence/O which/O can/O not/O be/O overseen/O by/O party/O leaders/O ;/O for/O instance/O ,/O if/O a/O local/O cadre/O wants/O to/O cover/O up/O local/O problems/O ./O
If/O the/O party/O decides/O to/O clamp/O down/O ,/O for/O example/O ,/O on/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O the/O cadre/O responsible/O for/O implementing/O this/O decision/O will/O certainly/O not/O find/O himself/O on/O one/O of/O the/O blacklists/O ./O
So/O this/O decision/O is/O ,/O simultaneously/O ,/O about/O obedience/O to/O the/O party/O and/O independence/O of/O the/O judicial/O system/O ./O
It/O is/O easier/O for/O the/O Chinese/O citizen/O than/O for/O foreign/O observers/O to/O see/O this/O as/O a/O step/O forward/O ./O
But/O the/O question/O remains/O :/O Are/O those/O decisions/O in/O line/O with/O the/O expectations/O of/O the/O modern/O man/O and/O woman/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O capital/O ?/O
People/O do/O support/O the/O anti-corruption/O campaign/O ,/O but/O they/O are/O also/O left/O bewildered/O ,/O realizing/O that/O trials/O of/O corrupt/O cadres/O are/O impenetrable/O ./O
It/O is/O not/O even/O clear/O why/O one/O is/O arrested/O while/O another/O remains/O at/O large/O ./O
Xi/PERSON believes/O the/O Chinese/O judicial/O system/O is/O still/O in/O its/O infancy/O ,/O admitting/O to/O its/O considerable/O flaws/O ,/O and/O he/O demanded/O ,/O shortly/O after/O taking/O office/O ,/O that/O no/O one/O put/O themselves/O above/O the/O law/O ./O
A/O long/O process/O It/O took/O four/O assemblies/O to/O get/O this/O far/O ./O
The/O first/O assembly/O ,/O which/O took/O place/O in/O 2012/O ,/O was/O devoted/O to/O the/O election/O of/O its/O members/O ./O
This/O was/O followed/O by/O a/O special/O assembly/O in/O spring/O 2013/O ,/O focussed/O on/O changing/O governments/O ,/O and/O the/O usual/O autumn/O assembly/O which/O kickstarted/O the/O new/O policy/O as/O a/O whole/O ./O
Now/O ,/O a/O year/O later/O ,/O the/O party/O is/O able/O to/O set/O priorities/O and/O achieve/O progress/O in/O specific/O areas/O ./O
Thus/O ,/O in/O the/O medium/O term/O ,/O an/O independent/O anti-corruption/O office/O is/O going/O to/O be/O set/O up/O ,/O which/O -/O being/O independent/O of/O local/O governments/O -/O has/O to/O answer/O directly/O to/O the/O disciplinary/O commission/O ./O
Furthermore/O ,/O more/O lawyers/O are/O going/O to/O be/O trained/O and/O their/O education/O improved/O ./O
In/O addition/O ,/O there/O are/O plans/O to/O further/O separate/O local/O courts/O from/O their/O respective/O governments/O and/O put/O them/O under/O direct/O control/O of/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
Ideally/O ,/O this/O could/O lead/O to/O bribed/O cadres/O being/O exposed/O by/O the/O disciplinary/O committee/O ./O
They/O would/O then/O be/O turned/O over/O to/O the/O nascent/O Chinese/O state/O under/O rule/O of/O law/O ,/O which/O in/O turn/O is/O left/O with/O the/O task/O of/O enforcing/O fair/O and/O transparent/O lawsuits/O ./O
But/O this/O is/O not/O going/O to/O happen/O in/O the/O near/O future/O ./O
The/O fourth/O assembly/O has/O ,/O nevertheless/O ,/O achieved/O remarkable/O progress/O ./O
But/O this/O progress/O is/O not/O far-reaching/O enough/O to/O alleviate/O the/O feeling/O of/O anxiety/O ,/O even/O fear/O ,/O among/O the/O population/O ./O
It/O is/O the/O kind/O of/O fear/O that/O spreads/O in/O the/O face/O of/O non-transparency/O ./O
Even/O those/O cadres/O who/O have/O done/O nothing/O wrong/O have/O started/O to/O feel/O uncomfortable/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON has/O been/O living/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O the/O last/O 20/O years/O ./O
