Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O government/O said/O it/O hoped/O for/O more/O talks/O with/O pro-democracy/O protesters/O following/O the/O first/O formal/O negotiations/O ./O
But/O as/O China/LOCATION scholar/O Perry/PERSON Link/PERSON tells/O DW/ORGANIZATION ,/O no/O compromise/O on/O universal/O suffrage/O is/O expected/O ./O
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O government/O and/O student/O leaders/O met/O on/O October/O 21/O for/O their/O first/O talks/O after/O three/O weeks/O of/O pro-democracy/O protests/O ./O
But/O ,/O as/O widely/O expected/O ,/O there/O was/O no/O breakthrough/O in/O the/O negotiations/O ,/O with/O Chief/O Secretary/O Carrie/PERSON Lam/PERSON reiterating/O the/O government/O 's/O position/O that/O open/O nominations/O were/O not/O possible/O under/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION law/O ./O
``/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION is/O not/O an/O independent/O country/O ./O
It/O is/O only/O a/O special/O administrative/O region/O within/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O we/O need/O to/O work/O within/O the/O framework/O set/O by/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O said/O Lam/PERSON ./O
The/O student/O leaders/O ,/O in/O turn/O ,/O urged/O the/O government/O to/O stop/O treating/O the/O decision/O of/O the/O central/O government/O on/O the/O semi-autonomous/O region/O 's/O election/O rules/O as/O ``/O unshakeable/O ./O ''/O
Government/O negotiators/O said/O they/O hoped/O for/O further/O talks/O down/O the/O line/O ,/O but/O student/O leaders/O have/O yet/O to/O decide/O whether/O or/O not/O to/O hold/O a/O second/O round/O ./O
Many/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION are/O angry/O at/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O refusal/O to/O allow/O genuine/O universal/O suffrage/O in/O the/O city/O in/O 2017/O and/O have/O staged/O protests/O occupying/O major/O traffic/O arteries/O of/O the/O semi-autonomous/O region/O ./O
Link/PERSON :/O `/O Beijing/LOCATION views/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION protests/O as/O a/O genuine/O threat/O to/O its/O survival/O '/O In/O a/O DW/ORGANIZATION interview/O ,/O China/LOCATION scholar/O Perry/PERSON Link/PERSON says/O that/O while/O minor/O progress/O may/O be/O made/O in/O future/O talks/O which/O allow/O both/O the/O protesters/O to/O save/O face/O and/O the/O authorities/O to/O buy/O time/O ,/O there/O is/O simply/O no/O room/O for/O a/O compromise/O on/O the/O key/O issue/O of/O universal/O suffrage/O ,/O as/O Beijing/LOCATION views/O the/O ongoing/O protests/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION as/O a/O genuine/O threat/O to/O its/O survival/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION :/O If/O the/O student/O leaders/O decide/O to/O continue/O negotiations/O ,/O what/O do/O you/O expect/O to/O come/O out/O of/O future/O talks/O ?/O
Perry/PERSON Link/PERSON :/O I/O would/O expect/O a/O stalemate/O in/O the/O talks/O or/O ,/O at/O most/O ,/O some/O very/O minor/O progress/O or/O some/O promises/O from/O the/O government/O that/O postpone/O the/O substantive/O question/O to/O future/O talks/O ./O
This/O kind/O of/O postponement/O could/O be/O face-saving/O for/O the/O student/O negotiators/O ,/O who/O could/O say/O ``/O at/O least/O we/O got/O something/O ,/O ''/O and/O for/O the/O government/O it/O could/O buy/O time/O ./O
How/O far/O do/O you/O think/O both/O sides/O are/O willing/O to/O compromise/O ?/O
Compromise/O on/O secondary/O ,/O tactical/O issues/O is/O possible/O ./O
By/O ``/O secondary/O issues/O ''/O I/O mean/O ,/O for/O the/O students/O ,/O compromises/O as/O large/O as/O agreeing/O to/O a/O temporary/O withdrawal/O from/O the/O streets/O and/O ,/O for/O the/O government/O ,/O compromises/O as/O large/O as/O whether/O to/O replace/O -LSB-/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION Chief/O Executive/O -RSB-/O Mr./O C.Y./PERSON Leung/PERSON with/O some/O other/O Beijing-loyalist/O as/O chief/O administrator/O ./O
But/O on/O the/O essential/O issue/O of/O whether/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION people/O will/O be/O able/O to/O nominate/O their/O own/O candidates/O for/O chief/O administrator/O in/O the/O 2017/O elections/O ,/O I/O believe/O there/O is/O no/O room/O for/O compromise/O on/O either/O side/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION will/O not/O accept/O real/O democracy/O while/O the/O students/O will/O not/O accept/O pretend/O democracy/O ,/O says/O Link/PERSON
Beijing/ORGANIZATION will/O not/O accept/O real/O democracy/O ,/O while/O the/O students/O will/O not/O accept/O pretend/O democracy/O ./O
The/O reason/O for/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O to/O do/O so/O has/O little/O to/O do/O with/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION itself/O ,/O and/O everything/O to/O do/O with/O the/O example/O it/O would/O set/O for/O the/O rest/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O as/O this/O would/O show/O that/O democracy/O and/O Chinese/O culture/O do/O fit/O together/O well/O -/O despite/O what/O the/O government/O has/O been/O telling/O its/O people/O for/O many/O years/O -/O and/O if/O that/O idea/O were/O to/O spread/O in/O mainland/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION 's/O one-party/O rule/O would/O unravel/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION views/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION protests/O as/O a/O genuine/O threat/O to/O its/O survival/O ./O
Some/O analysts/O and/O government/O insiders/O recently/O quoted/O by/O the/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION argue/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O directing/O broad/O strokes/O of/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION strategy/O ./O
What/O is/O your/O view/O on/O this/O ?/O
There/O is/O no/O question/O at/O all/O that/O the/O broad/O strokes/O of/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION government/O policy/O are/O designed/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O and/O indeed/O at/O the/O very/O top/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
It/O would/O be/O naive/O in/O the/O extreme/O to/O assume/O otherwise/O ./O
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O embattled/O chief/O executive/O has/O said/O the/O city/O 's/O pro-democracy/O movement/O is/O ``/O out/O of/O hand/O ''/O and/O being/O influenced/O by/O ``/O external/O forces/O ''/O from/O outside/O the/O city/O ./O
What/O do/O you/O make/O of/O this/O ?/O
This/O language/O from/O C.Y./PERSON Leung/PERSON is/O a/O good/O example/O of/O the/O ``/O broad/O strokes/O of/O policy/O ''/O that/O are/O sent/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ./O
For/O decades/O ,/O the/O rulers/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION have/O used/O these/O same/O points/O -/O that/O protesters/O ``/O create/O turmoil/O ''/O and/O are/O ``/O backed/O by/O foreign/O forces/O ''/O -/O in/O order/O to/O try/O to/O discredit/O anyone/O who/O presents/O organized/O objection/O to/O their/O rule/O ./O
The/O pro-democracy/O demonstrators/O at/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION -/O but/O also/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O the/O Tibetans/O ,/O civil-rights/O lawyers/O ,/O environmental/O activists/O ,/O and/O many/O others/O -/O have/O all/O heard/O this/O language/O before/O ./O
What/O role/O is/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O police/O force/O playing/O in/O the/O dispute/O ?/O
The/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION police/O of/O course/O must/O obey/O the/O broad/O outlines/O of/O what/O Beijing/LOCATION dictates/O ./O
That/O said/O ,/O the/O ordinary/O police/O on/O the/O streets/O are/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION people/O ./O
It/O is/O natural/O that/O they/O have/O complex/O ,/O mixed/O feelings/O about/O the/O protestors/O ./O
What/O is/O ,/O in/O your/O view/O ,/O the/O most/O likely/O way/O out/O of/O the/O current/O crisis/O ?/O
In/O the/O short/O term/O ,/O I/O think/O the/O government/O will/O continue/O its/O strategy/O of/O waiting/O out/O the/O protesters/O by/O pretending/O to/O talk/O seriously/O while/O continuing/O with/O its/O publicity/O campaign/O to/O discredit/O the/O protesters/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O this/O strategy/O will/O work/O fairly/O well/O ./O
Pro-democracy/O protestors/O watched/O the/O talks/O on/O a/O video/O screen/O near/O the/O government/O headquarters/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION
I/O think/O it/O is/O likely/O that/O the/O government/O will/O try/O to/O find/O ,/O or/O perhaps/O manufacture/O ,/O some/O ``/O incident/O ''/O in/O which/O the/O protesters/O look/O bad/O ,/O or/O to/O identify/O a/O particular/O ``/O villain/O ''/O among/O them/O ,/O and/O then/O use/O that/O incident/O or/O that/O villain/O to/O distract/O attention/O from/O the/O main/O issue/O and/O to/O make/O themselves/O seem/O to/O be/O in/O the/O right/O ./O
I/O make/O this/O guess/O because/O it/O is/O a/O common/O pattern/O that/O the/O leaders/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION have/O used/O elsewhere/O ./O
In/O the/O long/O term/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O think/O that/O ``/O waiting/O out/O the/O opposition/O ''/O will/O work/O for/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
I/O think/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION people/O will/O get/O their/O democracy/O in/O the/O long/O term/O ./O
China/LOCATION scholar/O Perry/PERSON Link/PERSON is/O Chancellorial/O Chair/O Professor/O for/O Innovative/O Teaching/O Comparative/O Literature/O &/O Foreign/O Languages/O in/O College/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Humanities/ORGANIZATION ,/ORGANIZATION Arts/ORGANIZATION ,/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Social/ORGANIZATION Sciences/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION ,/O Riverside/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O Emeritus/O Professor/O of/O Asian/O Studies/O at/O Princeton/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ./O
