More/O than/O a/O dozen/O people/O have/O died/O in/O fresh/O violence/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O troubled/O western/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
The/O area/O has/O seen/O a/O spate/O of/O recent/O clashes/O between/O police/O and/O ethnic/O minority/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O ./O
Chinese/O state/O media/O say/O that/O a/O number/O of/O people/O died/O on/O Friday/O in/O separate/O incidents/O in/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O ./O
Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O reported/O on/O Saturday/O that/O one/O person/O was/O killed/O and/O two/O injured/O in/O two/O blasts/O at/O a/O market/O and/O hair/O salon/O in/O the/O Uighur/O town/O of/O Xinhe/U_LOCATION in/O the/O Aksu/U_LOCATION prefecture/O ,/O with/O two/O more/O dying/O inside/O a/O car/O that/O exploded/O when/O police/O were/O trying/O to/O apprehend/O it/O ./O
Officials/O in/O neighboring/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION said/O another/O 11/O ethnic/O Uighur/O men/O from/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION were/O shot/O dead/O crossing/O the/O border/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O
They/O said/O nine/O were/O killed/O by/O a/O Kyrgyz/O border/O guard/O unit/O ,/O while/O two/O others/O were/O shot/O by/O a/O local/O hunter/O ./O
The/O Munich-based/O World/U_ORGANIZATION Uighur/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION has/O called/O for/O a/O ``/O full/O ,/O transparent/O and/O independent/O ''/O investigation/O into/O the/O shootings/O ./O
In/O another/O incident/O ,/O assailants/O threw/O explosives/O at/O police/O in/O Xinhe/U_LOCATION county/O ,/O triggering/O a/O clash/O in/O which/O police/O shot/O dead/O six/O people/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O Tianshan/U_LOCATION news/O portal/O ,/O run/O by/O the/O regional/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O
Ethnic/O unrest/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION has/O experienced/O a/O number/O of/O clashes/O in/O recent/O months/O triggered/O by/O the/O resentment/O felt/O by/O minority/O Uighurs/O who/O claim/O they/O are/O discriminated/O against/O by/O Chinese/O majority/O Han/O people/O ./O
The/O government/O has/O responded/O by/O cracking/O down/O on/O what/O it/O says/O is/O terrorism/O caused/O by/O radical/O Islamic/O separatists/O ./O
In/O one/O high-profile/O incident/O ,/O a/O car/O ploughed/O into/O a/O crowd/O and/O burst/O into/O flames/O ,/O killing/O three/O Uighur/O occupants/O and/O two/O bystanders/O at/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION in/O November/O ./O
The/O government/O immediately/O linked/O the/O attack/O to/O a/O Uighur/O terrorist/O organization/O ,/O but/O Uighur/O exile/O groups/O said/O the/O driver/O ,/O his/O wife/O and/O mother/O may/O have/O had/O a/O personal/O grudge/O over/O the/O demolition/O of/O part/O of/O his/O local/O mosque/O ./O
Last/O year/O ,/O clashes/O between/O authorities/O and/O members/O of/O the/O minority/O group/O left/O scores/O dead/O ,/O including/O 40/O police/O officers/O ./O
Uighurs/O make/O up/O about/O 8/O million/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION 's/O 21.8/O million/O people/O ./O
tj/rc/O -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O dpa/O -RRB-/O
