Pakistani/O fighter/O jets/O have/O launched/O a/O bombing/O campaign/O aimed/O at/O flushing/O Islamist/O militants/O out/O of/O a/O tribal/O region/O near/O the/O country/O 's/O border/O with/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
Dozens/O are/O reported/O to/O have/O been/O killed/O in/O the/O offensive/O ./O
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O army/O said/O on/O Monday/O that/O at/O least/O 27/O militants/O had/O been/O killed/O in/O the/O airstrikes/O launched/O in/O the/O early/O hours/O of/O the/O morning/O ,/O targeting/O six/O hideouts/O in/O the/O Shawal/LOCATION area/O of/O North/LOCATION Waziristan/LOCATION ``/O In/O these/O precise/O strikes/O ,/O 27/O terrorists/O were/O killed/O ./O
There/O is/O no/O -LRB-/O civilian/O -RRB-/O population/O in/O the/O area/O ,/O ''/O a/O statement/O released/O by/O the/O army/O said/O ./O
It/O added/O that/O the/O operation/O was/O ``/O progressing/O as/O per/O plan/O ./O ''/O
The/O DPA/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O cited/O a/O military/O spokesman/O ,/O Major/O General/O Asim/PERSON Saleem/PERSON Bjawa/PERSON ,/O who/O said/O at/O least/O 140/O militants/O had/O been/O killed/O in/O the/O Degan-Boya/LOCATION area/O of/O North/LOCATION Waziristan/LOCATION on/O Sunday/O ./O
``/O Most/O of/O those/O killed/O are/O Uzbeks/O ./O
Many/O ETIM/U_ORGANIZATION East/U_ORGANIZATION Turkestan/U_ORGANIZATION Islamic/U_ORGANIZATION Movement/U_ORGANIZATION terrorists/O and/O their/O affiliates/O have/O also/O been/O killed/O in/O the/O strikes/O ./O
It/O was/O a/O massive/O blow/O to/O the/O terrorists/O and/O one/O of/O their/O main/O communication/O centers/O has/O been/O dismantled/O ,/O ''/O Bjawa/PERSON said/O ./O
The/O Pakistani/O army/O ,/O meanwhile/O ,/O has/O sustained/O its/O first/O casualties/O since/O the/O offensive/O started/O ,/O with/O six/O soldiers/O being/O killed/O and/O three/O others/O wounded/O in/O a/O roadside/O bombing/O in/O the/O district/O ./O
The/O military/O also/O said/O its/O soldiers/O had/O cordoned/O off/O all/O known/O militant/O bases/O and/O was/O providing/O extra/O security/O for/O urban/O areas/O and/O sensitive/O installations/O ./O
Thousands/O of/O civilians/O were/O also/O reported/O to/O be/O fleeing/O from/O the/O region/O ./O
Warning/O to/O international/O organizations/O
Shahidullah/PERSON Shahid/PERSON ,/O a/O spokesman/O for/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O called/O on/O all/O international/O organizations/O to/O leave/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O saying/O if/O they/O failed/O to/O do/O so/O ,/O they/O would/O be/O considered/O fair/O game/O ./O
``/O All/O international/O investors/O ,/O airlines/O and/O institutions/O should/O immediately/O suspend/O all/O relations/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O leave/O the/O country/O ,/O or/O they/O will/O be/O responsible/O for/O any/O loss/O or/O harm/O to/O them/O ,/O ''/O said/O Shahid/PERSON ,/O who/O also/O vowed/O to/O hit/O the/O cities/O of/O Islamabad/LOCATION and/O Lahore/LOCATION ,/O which/O until/O now/O have/O been/O largely/O free/O from/O the/O sort/O of/O bombings/O and/O shootings/O that/O plague/O Karachi/LOCATION and/O Peshawar/LOCATION ./O
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O northwest/O is/O a/O largely/O lawless/O region/O used/O by/O insurgents/O both/O as/O a/O training/O base/O and/O a/O staging/O area/O from/O which/O to/O attack/O NATO/ORGANIZATION and/O Afghan/O troops/O across/O the/O border/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
The/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION has/O for/O years/O complained/O that/O the/O Pakistani/O authorities/O were/O failing/O to/O tackle/O the/O militants/O in/O its/O northwest/O and/O has/O carried/O out/O hundreds/O of/O drone/O strikes/O in/O the/O region/O ./O
The/O offensive/O comes/O a/O week/O after/O an/O insurgent/O attack/O that/O killed/O dozens/O of/O people/O and/O shut/O down/O Karachi/LOCATION 's/O international/O airport/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O busiest/O ,/O for/O more/O than/O 12/O hours/O ./O
pfd/slk/O -LRB-/O dpa/O ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
