China/LOCATION has/O condemned/O eight/O to/O death/O for/O attacks/O in/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O ./O
Five/O others/O were/O given/O suspended/O death/O sentences/O -/O a/O penalty/O normally/O commuted/O to/O life/O in/O prison/O -/O with/O another/O four/O jailed/O ./O
On/O Monday/O ,/O the/O state/O broadcaster/O China/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION Television/ORGANIZATION reported/O that/O a/O court/O had/O sentenced/O eight/O people/O to/O death/O for/O involvement/O in/O two/O attacks/O that/O killed/O 46/O people/O earlier/O this/O year/O in/O the/O far/O western/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
The/O sentences/O ,/O handed/O down/O by/O the/O Intermediate/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION in/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ,/O represent/O the/O Chinese/O government/O 's/O latest/O move/O in/O a/O harsh/O crackdown/O on/O unrest/O in/O the/O vast/O resource-rich/O region/O ./O
In/O one/O incident/O -LRB-/O pictured/O -RRB-/O ,/O assailants/O armed/O with/O knives/O and/O explosives/O attacked/O a/O train/O station/O in/O the/O regional/O capital/O ,/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ,/O in/O April/O ,/O killing/O one/O person/O and/O wounding/O 79/O on/O the/O final/O day/O of/O a/O visit/O to/O the/O area/O by/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ./O
Two/O assailants/O also/O died/O ./O
China/LOCATION has/O sent/O paramilitary/O police/O into/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION in/O a/O ``/O show/O of/O force/O ''/O The/O following/O month/O ,/O attackers/O killed/O 39/O people/O and/O wounded/O 90/O when/O they/O threw/O explosives/O and/O plowed/O two/O vehicles/O through/O a/O market/O in/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ,/O state/O media/O reported/O ./O
Police/O killed/O four/O attackers/O on/O the/O scene/O ./O
In/O October/O ,/O China/LOCATION sentenced/O another/O dozen/O people/O to/O die/O for/O their/O roles/O in/O a/O July/O melee/O with/O police/O that/O left/O up/O to/O 100/O people/O dead/O ./O
At/O least/O 200/O people/O have/O died/O in/O a/O year/O of/O clashes/O and/O attacks/O in/O and/O around/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O including/O four/O people/O just/O last/O month/O inan/O attack/O on/O food/O stalls/O -/O and/O 11/O assailants/O killed/O by/O police/O immediately/O after/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION blames/O ``/O separatists/O ,/O ''/O but/O rights/O groups/O charge/O that/O China/LOCATION 's/O repression/O of/O cultural/O and/O religious/O minorities/O has/O fueled/O unrest/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O which/O borders/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O is/O home/O to/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O a/O largely/O Muslim/O group/O who/O speak/O a/O Turkic/O language/O ./O
Chinese/O authorities/O argue/O that/O the/O country/O 's/O policies/O have/O boosted/O economic/O development/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION and/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O upheld/O minority/O and/O religious/O rights/O in/O a/O country/O that/O has/O 56/O officially/O recognized/O ethnic/O groups/O ./O
In/O September/O ,/O China/LOCATION sentenced/O Uighur/O scholar/O and/O prominent/O dissident/O Ilhan/U_PERSON Tohti/U_PERSON to/O life/O in/O prison/O for/O ``/O separatism/O ./O ''/O
mkg/mg/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
