Sticking/O to/O its/O traditional/O policy/O of/O non-interference/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O adopted/O a/O cautious/O stance/O on/O the/O tug/O of/O war/O over/O Ukraine/LOCATION ./O
Faced/O with/O pressing/O separatist/O threats/O and/O energy/O needs/O ,/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION would/O be/O another/O matter/O ./O
The/O puzzling/O crisis/O that/O is/O gripping/O Ukraine/LOCATION ,/O with/O Russia/LOCATION annexing/O the/O Crimean/O peninsula/O after/O the/O shift/O of/O power/O in/O Kiev/LOCATION from/O the/O Moscow-leaning/O government/O of/O ousted/O president/O Victor/PERSON Yanukovych/PERSON to/O a/O Western-backed/O leadership/O ,/O could/O lead/O to/O a/O misalignment/O of/O interests/O between/O the/O Kremlin/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION -/O something/O new/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O geopolitical/O competition/O that/O sees/O the/O Russian/O President/O Vladimir/PERSON Putin/PERSON face/O off/O with/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O EU/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O
Over/O the/O past/O decade/O ,/O China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION have/O often/O joined/O hands/O in/O torpedoing/O Western/O initiatives/O regarding/O a/O wide/O range/O of/O armed/O conflicts/O and/O international/O crises/O ,/O not/O least/O vetoing/O several/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION resolutions/O against/O the/O Syrian/O regime/O of/O Bashar/PERSON al-Assad/PERSON and/O ``/O rogue/O ''/O states/O such/O as/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O Sudan/LOCATION ,/O Myanmar/LOCATION and/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION ./O
The/O Chinese/O leadership/O has/O repeatedly/O stated/O that/O it/O will/O not/O interfere/O in/O Ukraine/LOCATION 's/O domestic/O affairs/O and/O has/O called/O for/O dialogue/O to/O resolve/O the/O ongoing/O dispute/O ./O
In/O this/O regard/O ,/O it/O has/O put/O forward/O a/O proposal/O to/O create/O an/O international/O coordination/O mechanism/O committed/O to/O favoring/O a/O political/O way/O forward/O and/O has/O urged/O the/O international/O financial/O bodies/O to/O facilitate/O Kiev/LOCATION 's/O economic/O recovery/O ./O
``/O China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION have/O often/O joined/O hands/O in/O torpedoing/O Western/O initiatives/O regarding/O a/O wide/O range/O of/O armed/O conflicts/O and/O international/O crises/O ''/O Looking/O at/O the/O fresh/O redrawing/O of/O maps/O in/O the/O Black/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION region/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O wary/O of/O both/O defusing/O separatist/O appetites/O at/O home/O and/O protecting/O its/O business/O abroad/O -LRB-/O notably/O in/O its/O near/O abroad/O -RRB-/O ./O
Its/O abstention/O from/O the/O March/O 15/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION vote/O on/O a/O US-sponsored/O draft/O resolution/O condemning/O the/O breakaway/O referendum/O in/O Crimea/LOCATION ,/O which/O Russia/LOCATION promptly/O vetoed/O ,/O should/O be/O read/O in/O this/O perspective/O ./O
Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON needs/O to/O contain/O the/O domestic/O fallout/O from/O any/O possible/O Russian/O blitzkrieg/O threatening/O further/O Kiev/LOCATION 's/O independence/O and/O territorial/O integrity/O -/O after/O Crimea/LOCATION ,/O Putin/PERSON could/O target/O the/O mostly/O Russophone/O Eastern/LOCATION and/O Southern/LOCATION Ukraine/LOCATION ./O
Much/O as/O it/O did/O in/O Georgia/LOCATION in/O 2008/O and/O in/O Moldova/LOCATION earlier/O in/O the/O 1990s/O ,/O the/O separatist/O card/O that/O Russia/LOCATION has/O been/O playing/O in/O Crimea/LOCATION ,/O where/O roughly/O 60/O percent/O of/O population/O is/O ethnically/O Russian/O ,/O could/O trigger/O unease/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O whose/O rulers/O consider/O the/O breakaway/O feelings/O going/O through/O the/O Chinese/O autonomous/O regions/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION as/O the/O most/O dangerous/O challenge/O to/O the/O country/O 's/O internal/O stability/O and/O security/O ./O
Not/O to/O mention/O the/O prospect/O that/O Taiwan/LOCATION ,/O a/O rebel/O province/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O view/O ,/O holds/O a/O referendum/O on/O -LRB-/O de/O jure/O -RRB-/O independence/O from/O the/O mainland/O in/O the/O future/O ./O
Ukraine/LOCATION -/O China/LOCATION trade/O
Crimean/O separatism/O ,/O coupled/O with/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O mounting/O interventionism/O ,/O undermines/O the/O stability/O of/O Ukraine/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O also/O grappling/O with/O economic/O and/O financial/O hardships/O ./O
China/LOCATION is/O Ukraine/LOCATION 's/O third-largest/O commercial/O partner/O after/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION and/O Russia/LOCATION ./O
Total/O trade/O in/O goods/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O was/O worth/O more/O than/O 8/O billion/O USD/O in/O 2012/O ,/O according/O to/O data/O from/O Eurostat/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Monetary/ORGANIZATION Fund/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O IMF/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION recommends/O
China/LOCATION growth/O concerns/O ,/O Ukraine/LOCATION crisis/O put/O damper/O on/O German/O business/O climate/O
Confidence/O among/O German/O business/O leaders/O has/O taken/O a/O hit/O from/O the/O Ukraine/LOCATION crisis/O and/O concerns/O about/O slower/O growth/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
A/O crucial/O indicator/O compiled/O by/O the/O Ifo/ORGANIZATION institute/O has/O fallen/O for/O the/O first/O time/O in/O five/O months/O ./O
-LRB-/O 25.03.2014/O -RRB-/O
Putin/PERSON 's/O power/O play/O embraces/O Latin/LOCATION America/LOCATION
Russia/LOCATION is/O seeking/O to/O expand/O traditional/O ties/O with/O leftist/O Latin/O American/O states/O as/O part/O of/O renewed/O global-power/O ambitions/O ,/O but/O reactions/O in/O Nicaragua/LOCATION ,/O Cuba/LOCATION and/O Venezuela/LOCATION have/O been/O cautious/O ./O
-LRB-/O 24.03.2014/O -RRB-/O
Time/O for/O American/O leadership/O Drones/O and/O sanctions/O as/O opposed/O to/O expensive/O military/O interventions/O :/O Obama/PERSON 's/O foreign/O policy/O strategy/O is/O shifting/O ./O
Experts/O say/O he/O wants/O a/O light/O military/O footprint/O -/O however/O the/O Ukraine/LOCATION crisis/O may/O challenge/O that/O premise/O ./O
-LRB-/O 22.03.2014/O -RRB-/O
`/O This/O Cold/O War/O could/O last/O 10/O years/O '/O
Vladimir/PERSON Putin/PERSON felt/O humiliated/O by/O the/O West/LOCATION and/O frustrated/O by/O the/O outcome/O in/O Kyiv/LOCATION ./O
Now/O ,/O he/O wants/O to/O show/O the/O West/LOCATION he/O means/O business/O ,/O says/O Eberhard/PERSON Schneider/PERSON of/O the/O EU-Russia/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION in/O Brussels/LOCATION ./O
-LRB-/O 19.03.2014/O -RRB-/O
The/O Middle/LOCATION Kingdom/LOCATION is/O the/O biggest/O buyer/O of/O Ukrainian/O weapons/O ./O
Kiev/LOCATION exported/O 690/O million/O USD/O in/O arms/O and/O equipment/O to/O China/LOCATION only/O in/O 2012/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O Stockholm/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION Peace/ORGANIZATION Research/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SIPRI/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O worth/O noting/O that/O the/O first/O aircraft/O carrier/O of/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION Navy/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O PLAN/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O Liaoning/LOCATION ,/O is/O in/O reality/O a/O refurbished/O Ukrainian/O vessel/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION has/O bolstered/O an/O agricultural/O cooperation/O with/O Kiev/LOCATION over/O the/O past/O few/O years/O ./O
Last/O fall/O ,/O news/O that/O China/LOCATION 's/O Xinjiang/U_ORGANIZATION Production/U_ORGANIZATION and/U_ORGANIZATION Construction/U_ORGANIZATION Corps/U_ORGANIZATION had/O leased/O in/O June/O 2013/O three/O million/O hectares/O of/O Ukrainian/O farmland/O for/O Chinese/O consumers/O attracted/O great/O attention/O ./O
Later/O ,/O Ukrainian/O authorities/O downplayed/O the/O case/O ,/O denying/O any/O land/O grab/O and/O talking/O about/O a/O 2.8/O billion/O USD/O agreement/O concerning/O Chinese/O assistance/O in/O the/O realm/O of/O irrigation/O technology/O ./O
In/O another/O respect/O ,/O Wang/PERSON Jing/PERSON ,/O the/O Chinese/O billionaire/O planning/O to/O build/O up/O an/O inter-oceanic/O waterway/O through/O Nicaragua/LOCATION ,/O would/O be/O ready/O to/O spend/O 10/O billion/O USD/O in/O a/O deepwater/O harbor/O and/O an/O economic/O zone/O in/O Crimea/LOCATION ,/O Bloomberg/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION reported/O late/O in/O 2013/O ./O
In/O 2012/O ,/O the/O Export-Import/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION granted/O a/O 3-billion-dollar/O loan/O to/O Ukraine/LOCATION in/O return/O for/O supplies/O of/O grain/O ./O
Voices/O are/O growing/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O seeking/O compensation/O from/O Kiev/LOCATION for/O the/O breach/O of/O this/O deal/O ,/O but/O Chinese/O officials/O have/O denied/O that/O they/O are/O contemplating/O any/O such/O move/O ./O
On/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O never/O confirmed/O the/O signing/O of/O a/O new/O credit/O agreement/O worth/O 8/O billion/O dollars/O with/O the/O Ukrainian/O counterpart/O following/O a/O meeting/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION between/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON and/O Yanukovych/PERSON back/O in/O December/O 2013/O ./O
Keeping/O a/O low/O profile/O
As/O usual/O in/O disputes/O far/O away/O from/O its/O regional/O perimeter/O of/O projection/O ,/O China/LOCATION will/O maintain/O a/O low/O profile/O ./O
It/O recognizes/O that/O there/O is/O too/O much/O power/O at/O stake/O in/O Ukraine/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O Euro-Atlantic/O and/O Russian/O spheres/O of/O influence/O collide/O ,/O for/O it/O can/O go/O beyond/O nudging/O the/O Western/O bloc/O and/O Russia/LOCATION into/O accepting/O a/O compromise/O over/O the/O current/O spat/O ./O
Ukraine/LOCATION is/O quite/O different/O from/O Sudan/LOCATION and/O South/LOCATION Sudan/LOCATION ,/O where/O sizable/O Chinese/O oil/O interests/O are/O matched/O by/O a/O well-established/O political/O clout/O ,/O and/O this/O to/O such/O an/O extent/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O partly/O given/O up/O its/O long-standing/O policy/O of/O non-interference/O in/O other/O nations/O '/O internal/O affairs/O to/O resolve/O civil/O and/O border/O conflicts/O plaguing/O these/O two/O eastern/O African/O countries/O ./O
``/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O partly/O given/O up/O its/O long-standing/O policy/O of/O non-interference/O in/O other/O nations/O '/O internal/O affairs/O ''/O From/O China/LOCATION 's/O viewpoint/O ,/O Kiev/LOCATION is/O also/O nowhere/O near/O as/O strategic/O as/O the/O ``/O stans/O ''/O at/O its/O doorstep/O ./O
While/O it/O can/O be/O safely/O assumed/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION abhors/O any/O form/O of/O regime/O change/O ,/O not/O least/O if/O it/O is/O a/O Western-backed/O one/O ,/O it/O is/O equally/O true/O that/O it/O can/O not/O turn/O a/O blind/O eye/O to/O a/O Kremlin/LOCATION claiming/O a/O power/O of/O guardianship/O of/O sorts/O in/O the/O post-Soviet/O space/O ,/O regardless/O of/O their/O common/O membership/O in/O the/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Organization/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SCO/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O
Much/O as/O in/O Crimea/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION has/O military/O bases/O and/O troops/O dispatched/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O where/O former/O Soviet/LOCATION republics/O look/O to/O China/LOCATION for/O their/O economic/O development/O just/O like/O Ukraine/LOCATION turns/O to/O Europe/LOCATION for/O its/O political/O destiny/O ,/O and/O where/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O advancing/O energy/O projects/O to/O reduce/O its/O oil/O and/O gas/O dependence/O on/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION in/O perennial/O turmoil/O ./O
If/O mass/O uprisings/O were/O to/O break/O out/O in/O these/O turbulent/O Central/O Asian/O nations/O ,/O ruled/O by/O old/O autocrats/O and/O therefore/O structurally/O ill-suited/O to/O manage/O smooth/O political/O successions/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION could/O find/O itself/O in/O the/O same/O position/O as/O Europe/LOCATION is/O today/O in/O Ukraine/LOCATION ,/O faced/O with/O the/O Russian/O bear/O justifying/O an/O armed/O intervention/O to/O defend/O its/O interests/O and/O citizens/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O lives/O of/O ethnic/O Russians/O ,/O across/O this/O region/O ./O
Such/O a/O scenario/O ultimately/O amounts/O to/O a/O responsibility/O to/O protect/O in/O ``/O Russian/O guise/O ''/O that/O China/LOCATION would/O find/O indeed/O uncomfortable/O ,/O if/O for/O no/O other/O reason/O than/O it/O would/O entail/O Moscow/LOCATION 's/O enhanced/O leverage/O on/O countries/O providing/O Beijing/LOCATION with/O over/O half/O of/O its/O gas/O imports/O ./O
Emanuele/PERSON Scimia/PERSON is/O a/O journalist/O and/O geopolitical/O analyst/O based/O in/O Italy/LOCATION ./O
