China/LOCATION has/O announced/O the/O deaths/O of/O 28/O people/O during/O a/O police/O crackdown/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O home/O to/O many/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O ./O
In/O September/O ,/O the/O group/O allegedly/O launched/O a/O terror/O attack/O at/O a/O coal/O mine/O ,/O killing/O more/O than/O a/O dozen/O people/O ./O
The/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION regional/O government/O said/O on/O Friday/O police/O had/O killed/O 28/O members/O of/O a/O ``/O terrorist/O ''/O group/O accused/O of/O carrying/O out/O an/O attack/O a/O couple/O months/O ago/O in/O the/O largely/O Muslim/O region/O of/O western/O China/LOCATION ./O
State/O newspaper/O Xinjiang/U_ORGANIZATION Daily/U_ORGANIZATION reported/O that/O those/O killed/O had/O links/O to/O the/O violent/O assault/O on/O a/O coal/O mine/O in/O September/O that/O left/O 16/O people/O dead/O and/O 18/O injured/O ./O
Radio/ORGANIZATION Free/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O US/O government-funded/O broadcaster/O to/O the/O region/O ,/O first/O reported/O the/O incident/O ,/O claiming/O that/O at/O least/O 50/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O the/O attack/O ./O
Ongoing/O strife/O
According/O to/O the/O Xinjiang/U_ORGANIZATION Daily/U_ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O attackers/O fled/O into/O the/O mountains/O and/O were/O subsequently/O hunted/O down/O over/O the/O course/O of/O two/O months/O by/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O ./O
Xinjiang/U_LOCATION is/O home/O to/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O a/O restive/O Muslim/O minority/O that/O has/O long/O claimed/O to/O be/O the/O victim/O of/O Chinese/O oppression/O ./O
The/O country/O 's/O officials/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O claim/O the/O region/O is/O a/O hotbed/O of/O Islamist/O militants/O seeking/O to/O wrest/O control/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
Human/O rights/O activists/O have/O been/O highly/O critical/O of/O the/O tactics/O used/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O in/O combatting/O these/O alleged/O extremists/O ,/O accusing/O it/O of/O human/O rights/O abuses/O ./O
blc/msh/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
