Once/O again/O ,/O a/O human/O rights/O lawyer/O is/O being/O tried/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
The/O charge/O against/O 50-year-old/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON is/O that/O he/O disturbed/O peace/O and/O incited/O hatred/O ./O
He/O can/O face/O up/O to/O eight/O years/O in/O prison/O if/O convicted/O ./O
Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O awaiting/O trial/O ,/O has/O already/O been/O behind/O bars/O for/O 587/O days/O ./O
It/O is/O a/O case/O amongst/O peers/O ,/O as/O all/O parties/O involved/O are/O deeply/O familiar/O with/O every/O detail/O of/O the/O Chinese/O legal/O system/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O its/O recesses/O ./O
In/O the/O only/O three/O page/O criminal/O complaint/O against/O him/O ,/O the/O state/O prosecutor/O has/O accused/O the/O human/O rights/O lawyer/O of/O ``/O inciting/O hatred/O among/O ethnic/O groups/O ''/O within/O the/O country/O and/O being/O a/O ``/O public/O troublemaker/O ./O ''/O
On/O Monday/O ,/O December/O 14/O ,/O the/O case/O will/O be/O heard/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Second/ORGANIZATION Intermediate/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION ./O
Last/O year/O in/O March/O ,/O nine/O people/O clad/O in/O black/O indiscriminately/O attacked/O pedestrians/O with/O machetes/O at/O a/O railway/O station/O ./O
Twenty-nine/O people/O were/O killed/O and/O several/O hundred/O were/O wounded/O in/O the/O attacks/O ./O
The/O perpetrators/O belonged/O to/O the/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O group/O ,/O a/O Turkic-speaking/O minority/O based/O in/O western/O China/LOCATION ./O
Chinese/O authorities/O describe/O them/O as/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O and/O ``/O separatists/O ./O ''/O
Twenty-nine/O people/O died/O during/O a/O terrorist/O attack/O in/O Kunming/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION
After/O the/O assault/O ,/O Pu/PERSON allegedly/O published/O eight/O short/O messages/O on/O the/O Internet/O ,/O which/O ,/O the/O prosecutor/O says/O ,/O incited/O hatred/O and/O tensions/O between/O the/O ethnic/O communities/O ./O
The/O officials/O also/O claim/O that/O many/O Internet/O users/O said/O that/O Pu/PERSON 's/O messages/O were/O damaging/O for/O the/O solidarity/O between/O China/LOCATION 's/O ethnic/O groups/O ./O
Seven/O posts/O as/O proof/O ?/O
The/O three/O page/O indictment/O report/O does/O not/O explicitly/O state/O which/O of/O Pu/PERSON 's/O messages/O are/O being/O investigated/O ./O
Seven/O Weibo/ORGANIZATION messages/O -/O which/O Pu/PERSON allegedly/O posted/O between/O 2011/O and/O 2014/O -/O have/O been/O circulating/O online/O and/O may/O now/O prove/O to/O be/O his/O downfall/O ./O
Pu/PERSON protesting/O at/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION in/O 1989/O
Following/O the/O attacks/O in/O Kunming/LOCATION ,/O Pu/PERSON allegedly/O wrote/O :/O ``/O The/O act/O of/O terrorism/O is/O the/O result/O ,/O not/O the/O cause/O ./O ''/O
Pu/PERSON also/O supposedly/O wrote/O on/O the/O subject/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION :/O ``/O In/O the/O Tibetan/O areas/O ,/O all/O temples/O should/O demonstrate/O nine/O things/O ,/O namely/O ,/O portraits/O of/O the/O four/O major/O Chinese/O leaders/O -LRB-/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON ,/O Deng/PERSON Xiaoping/PERSON ,/O Jiang/PERSON Zemin/PERSON and/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON -RRB-/O ,/O the/O national/O flag/O ,/O a/O map/O ,/O tap/O water/O ,/O radio/O and/O TV/O ,/O cinema/O ,/O a/O library/O ,/O and/O newspapers/O ./O
And/O in/O the/O city/O of/O Yinging/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O in/O the/O predominantly/O Muslim/O Xinjian/U_LOCATION autonomous/O region/O -RRB-/O ,/O beards/O and/O face/O veils/O are/O forbidden/O ./O
These/O measures/O should/O weaken/O religious/O consciousness/O ./O
Are/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O crazy/O ?/O
Or/O is/O it/O ,/O rather/O ,/O their/O leadership/O ?/O ''/O
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O `/O Nemesis/O '/O
Pu/PERSON was/O always/O a/O problem/O for/O the/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
As/O a/O student/O ,/O he/O called/O for/O more/O democracy/O at/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION in/O 1989/O ./O
He/O went/O on/O a/O hunger/O strike/O and/O participated/O in/O a/O sit-in/O ,/O but/O he/O was/O not/O arrested/O ./O
After/O graduating/O with/O a/O degree/O in/O law/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O he/O passed/O the/O state/O examination/O and/O was/O licensed/O as/O a/O lawyer/O and/O university/O lecturer/O ./O
Among/O his/O clients/O were/O critical/O journalists/O ,/O farmers/O whose/O land/O was/O expropriated/O ,/O and/O victims/O of/O torture/O ./O
In/O 2011/O ,/O he/O represented/O the/O renowned/O artist/O Ai/PERSON Weiwei/PERSON who/O had/O come/O to/O the/O attention/O of/O the/O authorities/O for/O alleged/O tax/O evasion/O ./O
In/O 2013/O ,/O Pu/PERSON accused/O Zhou/PERSON Yongkang/PERSON ,/O a/O retired/O permanent/O member/O of/O the/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION ,/O of/O abuse/O of/O office/O on/O his/O social/O network/O account/O ./O
Something/O no/O one/O previously/O dared/O to/O do/O ./O
Two/O years/O later/O ,/O Zhou/PERSON was/O sentenced/O to/O life/O in/O prison/O for/O corruption/O and/O abuse/O of/O office/O ./O
Germany/LOCATION 's/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Commissioner/ORGANIZATION Straesser/PERSON praised/O Pu/PERSON for/O his/O `/O commitment/O to/O enhancing/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O '/O
International/O criticism/O
Christoph/PERSON Straesser/PERSON ,/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O Human/O Rights/O Commissioner/O ,/O criticized/O the/O lawsuit/O currently/O opened/O against/O Pu/PERSON ./O
According/O to/O Straesser/PERSON ,/O Pu/PERSON stood/O up/O for/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O ``/O within/O the/O context/O of/O his/O legal/O profession/O and/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O applicable/O laws/O ./O ''/O
The/O US/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION also/O called/O Pu/PERSON ``/O a/O courageous/O defense/O attorney/O recognized/O around/O the/O world/O for/O his/O tireless/O work/O in/O support/O of/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O
Many/O of/O Pu/PERSON 's/O fellow/O lawyers/O in/O China/LOCATION are/O carefully/O following/O his/O public/O trial/O ./O
But/O Courtroom/O Number/O 6/O ,/O where/O Pu/PERSON will/O stand/O trial/O on/O Monday/O ,/O is/O one/O of/O the/O smallest/O out/O of/O the/O 35/O courtrooms/O available/O ./O
