At/O least/O 2,000/O Central/O Asians/O are/O believed/O to/O have/O joined/O ``/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O a/O new/O report/O found/O ./O
Marked/O by/O poverty/O and/O radicalization/O ,/O the/O region/O has/O become/O a/O growing/O source/O of/O foreign/O fighters/O ,/O as/O Deirdre/PERSON Tynan/PERSON tells/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
The/O fallout/O from/O the/O conflicts/O in/O Syria/LOCATION and/O Iraq/LOCATION has/O become/O a/O major/O security/O concern/O for/O Central/O Asian/O governments/O ./O
Crippled/O by/O corruption/O ,/O the/O five/O former/O Soviet/LOCATION
In/O a/O recently/O released/O report/O ,/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Crisis/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O ICG/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O says/O that/O ``/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION ''/O -LRB-/O IS/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O is/O attracting/O Central/O Asians/O to/O Syria/LOCATION and/O fostering/O new/O links/O among/O radicals/O within/O the/O region/O ./O
Between/O 2,000/O and/O 4,000/O of/O their/O citizens/O have/O left/O for/O IS-held/O territory/O to/O fight/O or/O otherwise/O support/O the/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION cause/O ,/O the/O report/O notes/O ./O
The/O briefing/O titled/O ``/O Syria/LOCATION Calling/O :/O Radicalization/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ''/O examines/O the/O socio-political/O context/O behind/O growing/O radicalism/O in/O the/O region/O and/O argues/O that/O a/O comprehensive/O solution/O requires/O not/O only/O better/O coordination/O of/O security/O services/O ,/O but/O also/O a/O liberalization/O of/O religious/O laws/O and/O greater/O economic/O opportunities/O to/O and/O for/O young/O people/O ,/O including/O women/O ./O
In/O a/O DW/ORGANIZATION interview/O ,/O Deirdre/PERSON Tynan/PERSON ,/O the/O ICG/ORGANIZATION 's/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION Project/O Director/O ,/O says/O that/O it/O is/O easier/O for/O ``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ''/O to/O gain/O recruits/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION than/O in/O nearby/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O adding/O that/O the/O group/O 's/O appeal/O in/O the/O region/O is/O rooted/O in/O an/O unfulfilled/O desire/O for/O political/O and/O social/O change/O and/O will/O eventually/O pose/O a/O serious/O threat/O to/O the/O region/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION :/O Where/O do/O these/O ``/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION ''/O supporters/O come/O from/O ?/O
Deirdre/PERSON Tynan/PERSON :/O Official/O Central/O Asian/O governments/O '/O estimates/O of/O several/O hundred/O fighters/O are/O conservative/O ./O
Western/O officials/O suggest/O the/O number/O is/O 2,000/O ,/O and/O it/O may/O be/O as/O many/O as/O 4,000/O ./O
Tynan/PERSON :/O `/O Recruitment/O to/O the/O extremist/O cause/O is/O happening/O in/O mosques/O and/O prayer/O rooms/O across/O the/O region/O '/O
The/O largest/O single/O group/O is/O reportedly/O Uzbek/O ,/O both/O citizens/O of/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION and/O ethnic/O Uzbeks/O from/O the/O Ferghana/LOCATION Valley/LOCATION ,/O including/O Osh/LOCATION ,/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION 's/O southern/O city/O ./O
The/O number/O of/O the/O former/O in/O Syria/LOCATION is/O not/O the/O estimated/O 500/O or/O so/O cited/O by/O Tashkent/LOCATION and/O may/O exceed/O 2,500/O ./O
Perhaps/O 1,000/O men/O and/O women/O ,/O including/O 500/O ethnic/O Kyrgyz/O and/O others/O from/O Osh/LOCATION ,/O have/O left/O the/O Ferghana/LOCATION Valley/LOCATION to/O fight/O for/O or/O provide/O humanitarian/O assistance/O to/O IS/ORGANIZATION ./O
How/O would/O you/O describe/O a/O typical/O ``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ''/O supporter/O from/O this/O region/O ?/O
There/O is/O no/O single/O profile/O of/O an/O ``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ''/O supporter/O ./O
Central/O Asian/O governments/O often/O fail/O to/O recognise/O that/O ``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ''/O appeals/O to/O a/O cross-section/O of/O citizens/O ./O
There/O are/O seventeen-year-old/O hairdressers/O ,/O established/O businessmen/O ,/O women/O abandoned/O by/O their/O husbands/O ,/O families/O who/O believe/O their/O children/O will/O have/O better/O prospects/O in/O a/O caliphate/O ,/O young/O men/O ,/O school/O dropouts/O and/O university/O students/O ./O
All/O are/O inspired/O by/O the/O belief/O that/O an/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION state/ORGANIZATION is/O a/O meaningful/O alternative/O to/O post-Soviet/O life/O ./O
It/O is/O easier/O for/O ``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ''/O to/O gain/O recruits/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION than/O in/O nearby/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
What/O are/O their/O reasons/O for/O leaving/O their/O countries/O behind/O and/O supporting/O ``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ?/O ''/O
They/O are/O prompted/O in/O part/O by/O marginalization/O and/O bleak/O economic/O prospects/O ./O
``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ''/O appeals/O not/O only/O to/O those/O who/O seek/O combat/O experience/O ,/O but/O also/O to/O those/O who/O envision/O a/O more/O devout/O ,/O purposeful/O ,/O fundamentalist/O religious/O life/O ./O
The/O radicalization/O of/O women/O is/O often/O a/O response/O to/O the/O lack/O of/O social/O ,/O religious/O ,/O economic/O and/O political/O opportunities/O afforded/O to/O them/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O
Economic/O reward/O is/O not/O a/O motivation/O for/O those/O drawn/O to/O ``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ''/O -/O controlled/O territory/O ./O
For/O some/O ,/O it/O is/O a/O personal/O adventure/O ;/O for/O others/O it/O is/O a/O call/O to/O arms/O ./O
``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ''/O sympathizers/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION are/O motivated/O by/O an/O extremist/O religious/O ideology/O ./O
The/O growth/O of/O radical/O tendencies/O is/O exacerbated/O by/O poor/O religious/O education/O and/O grievances/O against/O the/O region/O 's/O secular/O governments/O ./O
Even/O though/O socio-economic/O factors/O play/O a/O role/O ,/O ideological/O commitment/O to/O jihad/O -/O the/O idea/O of/O holy/O struggle/O to/O advance/O Islam/ORGANIZATION -/O is/O for/O many/O the/O main/O reason/O Central/O Asians/O are/O drawn/O to/O ``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ./O ''/O
DW/ORGANIZATION recommends/O
Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION 's/O intensifying/O water/O dispute/O
A/O new/O report/O finds/O political/O rivalries/O ,/O economic/O competition/O and/O nationalism/O are/O hampering/O efforts/O to/O solve/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION 's/O growing/O water/O and/O energy/O needs/O ;/O a/O situation/O that/O may/O lead/O to/O conflict/O says/O analyst/O Deirdre/PERSON Tynan/PERSON ./O
-LRB-/O 12.09.2014/O -RRB-/O
Ethnic/O tensions/O escalating/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION 
The/O latest/O incidents/O of/O deadly/O violence/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION indicate/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policies/O towards/O ethnic/O minorities/O have/O reached/O a/O dead/O end/O ./O
-LRB-/O 05.07.2013/O -RRB-/O
Xinjiang/U_LOCATION :/O Restrictions/O on/O religion/O may/O lead/O to/O `/O Uighur/O radicalization/O '/O
A/O city/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION province/O has/O temporarily/O banned/O people/O with/O veils/O ,/O head/O scarves/O and/O long/O beards/O from/O boarding/O buses/O ./O
Experts/O say/O attempts/O at/O repressing/O their/O culture/O are/O fueling/O violence/O and/O extremism/O ./O
-LRB-/O 08.08.2014/O -RRB-/O
Are/O Pakistani/O militants/O moving/O closer/O to/O `/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION '/O ?/O
In/O a/O new/O video/O ,/O a/O group/O of/O Pakistani/O and/O Afghan/O militants/O could/O be/O seen/O beheading/O a/O Pakistani/O soldier/O after/O pledging/O allegiance/O to/O ``/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION ''/O and/O its/O leader/O Baghdadi/PERSON ./O
Is/O IS/ORGANIZATION gaining/O a/O foothold/O in/O the/O Islamic/O country/O ?/O
-LRB-/O 12.01.2015/O -RRB-/O
How/O are/O these/O supporters/O being/O recruited/O ?/O
Recruitment/O to/O the/O extremist/O cause/O is/O happening/O in/O mosques/O and/O namazkhana/O -LRB-/O prayer/O rooms/O -RRB-/O across/O the/O region/O ./O
The/O Internet/O and/O social/O media/O play/O a/O critical/O but/O not/O definitive/O role/O ./O
Some/O are/O recruited/O at/O home/O ;/O others/O are/O radicalized/O abroad/O ,/O often/O as/O migrant/O workers/O ./O
Recruitment/O happens/O mainly/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION and/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O but/O also/O from/O among/O young/O men/O who/O travel/O to/O religious/O schools/O in/O Egypt/LOCATION ,/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION or/O Bangladesh/LOCATION ./O
In/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O migrants/O who/O are/O marginalized/O -/O often/O doing/O illegal/O and/O badly/O paid/O jobs/O -/O seek/O solace/O ,/O a/O sense/O of/O identity/O and/O community/O in/O religion/O ./O
They/O may/O fall/O in/O with/O Caucasian/O networks/O ,/O Dagestani/O or/O Chechen/O ,/O that/O blur/O the/O lines/O between/O religion/O and/O organized/O crime/O ,/O while/O offering/O a/O degree/O of/O protection/O against/O other/O criminal/O groups/O and/O difficulties/O ./O
Word/O of/O mouth/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O powerful/O tools/O of/O recruitment/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ;/O one/O family/O member/O or/O friend/O leaves/O for/O ``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ''/O -/O controlled/O territory/O ,/O then/O several/O more/O follow/O ./O
Social/O media/O maintains/O communication/O between/O those/O in/O Syria/LOCATION and/O those/O at/O home/O thinking/O about/O joining/O ./O
Recruitment/O cells/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION are/O small/O ,/O secretive/O and/O sometimes/O extensions/O of/O prayer/O groups/O ./O
In/O which/O ways/O do/O these/O recruits/O support/O ``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ?/O ''/O
Some/O fight/O ,/O others/O provide/O support/O services/O to/O more/O experienced/O fighters/O from/O the/O Caucasus/LOCATION or/O Arab/O states/O ./O
``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ''/O says/O it/O wants/O teachers/O ,/O nurses/O and/O engineers/O ,/O not/O just/O fighters/O -/O this/O appeals/O to/O educated/O men/O and/O women/O ./O
What/O problems/O does/O this/O pose/O to/O Central/O Asian/O governments/O and/O the/O region/O as/O a/O whole/O ?/O
The/O number/O of/O Central/O Asians/O receiving/O combat/O training/O and/O progressing/O through/O ``/O IS/ORGANIZATION ''/O command/O structures/O is/O increasing/O ,/O as/O are/O the/O jihadi/O networks/O of/O which/O they/O are/O a/O part/O ./O
Although/O most/O Central/O Asians/O find/O themselves/O in/O jamaats/O -LRB-/O factions/O -RRB-/O organized/O loosely/O along/O ethnic/O and/O linguistic/O lines/O ,/O these/O form/O larger/O regional/O battalions/O of/O cooperating/O fighters/O from/O across/O the/O former/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION 's/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O ./O
The/O risk/O is/O rising/O that/O these/O connections/O will/O gather/O pace/O and/O purpose/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O and/O governments/O are/O ill-prepared/O to/O respond/O to/O a/O security/O threat/O of/O this/O type/O ./O
What/O are/O Central/O Asian/O governments/O doing/O about/O this/O ?/O
Tajikistan/LOCATION and/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION have/O introduced/O laws/O criminalizing/O fighting/O abroad/O ,/O the/O former/O coming/O into/O effect/O in/O July/O 2014/O ,/O the/O latter/O on/O January/O 2015/O ./O
Uzbekistan/LOCATION banned/O terrorism/O training/O without/O reference/O to/O location/O in/O January/O 2014/O ,/O but/O the/O law/O was/O widely/O interpreted/O as/O directed/O against/O foreign-trained/O fighters/O ./O
`/O The/O number/O of/O Central/O Asians/O receiving/O combat/O training/O and/O progressing/O through/O `/O IS/ORGANIZATION '/O command/O structures/O is/O increasing/O ,/O '/O says/O Tynan/PERSON
The/O Kyrgyz/O parliament/O approved/O criminal/O code/O amendments/O suggesting/O sentences/O of/O 8/O to/O 15/O years/O for/O taking/O part/O in/O conflicts/O ,/O military/O operations/O or/O terrorist/O -/O or/O extremist/O training/O in/O a/O foreign/O state/O in/O September/O 2014/O ,/O but/O these/O have/O yet/O to/O be/O signed/O into/O law/O ./O
Rehabilitation/O programs/O could/O have/O potential/O ,/O but/O Central/O Asian/O governments/O lack/O the/O resources/O and/O apparently/O the/O political/O will/O to/O implement/O them/O ./O
The/O governments/O ,/O though/O ,/O aware/O of/O the/O dangers/O fighters/O could/O pose/O upon/O return/O from/O Syria/LOCATION ,/O have/O done/O little/O to/O address/O the/O reasons/O why/O such/O a/O diverse/O cross-section/O of/O their/O citizens/O seek/O to/O participate/O in/O IS/ORGANIZATION ./O
Prevention/O of/O extremism/O and/O rehabilitation/O of/O jihadis/O are/O not/O yet/O high/O on/O the/O agenda/O ,/O and/O female/O radicalization/O is/O largely/O ignored/O by/O religious/O leaders/O ,/O while/O the/O lack/O of/O economic/O and/O political/O opportunities/O for/O young/O people/O compounds/O radicalism/O ./O
Poorly/O educated/O imams/O struggle/O to/O compete/O with/O the/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION 's/O glamorization/O of/O jihad/O ./O
Deirdre/PERSON Tynan/PERSON is/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION Project/O Director/O at/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Crisis/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION ./O
The/O interview/O was/O conducted/O by/O Gabriel/PERSON Domínguez/PERSON ./O
