Indonesian/O security/O forces/O have/O killed/O two/O ethnic-Uighur/O Chinese/O militants/O following/O a/O shootout/O ./O
The/O two/O men/O belonged/O to/O a/O militant/O network/O run/O by/O the/O country/O 's/O most/O wanted/O man/O ./O
The/O shootout/O happened/O while/O police/O were/O hunting/O for/O Abu/PERSON Wardah/PERSON Santoso/PERSON ,/O a/O militant/O ,/O in/O Poso/LOCATION ,/O in/O central/O Sulawesi/LOCATION ./O
The/O two/O men/O had/O reportedly/O joined/O Santoso/PERSON 's/O group/O after/O leaving/O the/O Muslim/O region/O of/O western/O China/LOCATION ./O
Indonesian/O security/O forces/O have/O been/O intensifying/O operations/O against/O the/O Mujahidin/ORGANIZATION Indonesia/ORGANIZATION Timur/ORGANIZATION network/O led/O by/O Santoso/PERSON ,/O Indonesia/LOCATION 's/O most/O high-profile/O supporter/O of/O ``/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION ''/O -LRB-/O IS/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O who/O has/O been/O on/O the/O run/O for/O over/O three/O years/O ./O
``/O We/O hope/O Santoso/PERSON will/O surrender/O ,/O but/O we/O are/O prepared/O for/O the/O worst-case/O scenario/O ,/O ''/O Security/O Minister/O Luhut/PERSON Panjaitan/PERSON said/O ./O
Tuesday/O 's/O shootout/O followed/O a/O standoff/O between/O security/O forces/O and/O a/O group/O of/O unknown/O men/O during/O an/O operation/O in/O a/O forested/O area/O of/O Poso/LOCATION ,/O over/O 1,600/O kilometers/O -LRB-/O 950/O miles/O -RRB-/O northeast/O of/O the/O capital/O ,/O Jakarta/LOCATION ./O
``/O Based/O on/O testimony/O from/O another/O suspect/O we/O had/O arrested/O ,/O those/O two/O were/O identified/O as/O Uighurs/O ,/O ''/O Central/LOCATION Sulawesi/LOCATION police/O spokesman/O Hari/PERSON Suprapto/PERSON said/O ./O
Hundreds/O of/O Uighurs/O escaping/O unrest/O in/O the/O western/O Chinese/O homeland/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION have/O also/O traveled/O secretly/O via/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION to/O Turkey/LOCATION and/O often/O end/O up/O crossing/O into/O Syria/LOCATION and/O Iraq/LOCATION to/O fight/O for/O IS/ORGANIZATION ./O
Four/O Uighur/O men/O were/O jailed/O in/O Indonesia/LOCATION last/O year/O for/O attempting/O to/O join/O the/O same/O militant/O network/O ./O
jh/rg/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION //O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
