Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION will/O hold/O their/O first-ever/O joint/O military/O exercises/O later/O this/O year/O ,/O say/O media/O reports/O ./O
Islamabad/LOCATION is/O looking/O for/O new/O alliances/O in/O the/O region/O as/O its/O ties/O with/O Washington/LOCATION are/O rapidly/O deteriorating/O ./O
Geo-strategic/O relations/O are/O rapidly/O changing/O in/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O
Former/O Cold/O War/O rivals/O India/LOCATION and/O the/O US/LOCATION are/O bolstering/O their/O defense/O and/O trade/O ties/O amid/O growing/O concerns/O about/O China/LOCATION 's/O assertiveness/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O particularly/O in/O the/O disputed/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ./O
On/O the/O other/O side/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION and/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O which/O were/O allies/O against/O the/O former/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION and/O collaborated/O in/O the/O 1980s/O Afghan/O War/O ,/O are/O drifting/O away/O ./O
Simultaneously/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION and/O Moscow/LOCATION are/O reviving/O their/O ties/O ,/O as/O the/O two/O Cold/O War-era/O foes/O are/O planning/O to/O hold/O their/O first-ever/O joint/O military/O drills/O later/O this/O year/O ./O
Around/O 200/O Russian/O and/O Pakistani/O troops/O will/O take/O part/O in/O the/O exercises/O ,/O The/ORGANIZATION Express/ORGANIZATION Tribune/ORGANIZATION newspaper/O quoted/O a/O senior/O Pakistani/O official/O as/O saying/O ./O
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Ambassador/O to/O Moscow/LOCATION Qazi/PERSON Khalilullah/PERSON told/O the/O newspaper/O that/O the/O joint/O drills/O would/O be/O called/O ``/O Friendship-2016/O ,/O ''/O however/O he/O did/O not/O divulge/O any/O further/O details/O ./O
Kerry/PERSON admitted/O that/O the/O deteriorating/O ties/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION were/O having/O a/O negative/O impact/O on/O South/O Asian/O security/O
``/O This/O obviously/O indicates/O a/O desire/O on/O both/O sides/O to/O broaden/O defense/O and/O military-technical/O cooperation/O ,/O ''/O Khalilullah/PERSON told/O a/O Russian/O news/O agency/O last/O week/O ./O
The/O move/O comes/O at/O a/O time/O when/O US/LOCATION lawmakers/O are/O pondering/O over/O imposing/O sanctions/O on/O Islamabad/LOCATION for/O its/O ``/O lack/O of/O cooperation/O ''/O in/O the/O war/O against/O Islamist/O extremists/O ./O
The/O US/ORGANIZATION Senate/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Relations/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION held/O a/O hearing/O on/O US-Pakistani/O relations/O on/O Sunday/O ,/O September/O 11/O ,/O in/O which/O the/O committee/O 's/O chairman/O Senator/O Bob/PERSON Corker/PERSON criticized/O Islamabad/LOCATION 's/O alleged/O support/O to/O the/O militants/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
Washington/LOCATION tilts/O towards/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION
While/O the/O US-Pakistani/O ties/O worsen/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION gets/O closer/O to/O Islamabad/LOCATION 's/O archrival/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION ./O
US/LOCATION Secretary/O of/O State/O John/PERSON Kerry/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O on/O a/O trip/O to/O India/LOCATION last/O month/O ,/O made/O it/O clear/O that/O the/O US/LOCATION wanted/O to/O see/O India/LOCATION in/O a/O more/O powerful/O role/O in/O the/O South/O Asian/O region/O ./O
Not/O only/O is/O the/O US/LOCATION moving/O ahead/O on/O a/O nuclear/O deal/O with/O India/LOCATION ,/O it/O is/O also/O aiming/O to/O increase/O the/O bilateral/O trade/O to/O around/O $/O 500/O billion/O -LRB-/O 448/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O annually/O ./O
``/O I/O 'm/O very/O ,/O very/O confident/O that/O we/O will/O continue/O to/O strengthen/O what/O President/O Obama/PERSON has/O called/O the/O defining/O partnership/O of/O the/O 21st/O century/O ,/O ''/O Kerry/PERSON said/O in/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION ,/O adding/O that/O cooperation/O on/O trade/O and/O security/O had/O ``/O room/O to/O be/O able/O to/O further/O grow/O ./O ''/O
The/O US/LOCATION is/O also/O actively/O supporting/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION 's/O bid/O for/O the/O Nuclear/ORGANIZATION Suppliers/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O NSG/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O which/O has/O been/O opposed/O by/O India/LOCATION 's/O archrivals/O China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
``/O The/O US-India/O security/O agreements/O will/O have/O an/O impact/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O
Islamabad/LOCATION is/O rightly/O worried/O ./O
Why/O should/O Pakistan/LOCATION then/O work/O for/O the/O US/LOCATION interests/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ?/O ''/O
Talat/PERSON A./PERSON Wazarat/PERSON ,/O an/O International/O Relations/O expert/O from/O Karachi/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION recommends/O
Examining/O Saudi-Pakistani/O ties/O in/O changing/O geopolitics/O Suffering/O setbacks/O in/O Yemen/LOCATION ,/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION seeks/O closer/O ties/O and/O increased/O military/O cooperation/O with/O East/O and/O South/O Asian/O countries/O ./O
Analysts/O say/O Pakistan/LOCATION provides/O a/O stepping/O stone/O for/O Riyadh/LOCATION 's/O ``/O look/O east/O ''/O policy/O ./O -LRB-/O 30.08.2016/O -RRB-/O
China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION start/O joint/O war/O games/O
In/O spite/O of/O tense/O regional/O debate/O over/O the/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ,/O the/O two/O countries/O are/O set/O to/O conduct/O joint/O drills/O ./O
Moscow/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION have/O enjoyed/O increasingly/O close/O military/O cooperation/O in/O recent/O years/O ./O -LRB-/O 12.09.2016/O -RRB-/O
Obama/PERSON vows/O longterm/O US/LOCATION engagement/O with/O Asia/LOCATION in/O Laos/LOCATION speech/O
US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON has/O pledged/O enduring/O cooperation/O between/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O Asia/LOCATION in/O a/O speech/O in/O Laos/LOCATION ./O
He/O also/O warned/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION 's/O government/O that/O its/O weapons/O tests/O would/O lead/O to/O increased/O isolation/O ./O -LRB-/O 06.09.2016/O -RRB-/O
``/O The/O new/O strategy/O is/O aimed/O at/O containing/O China/LOCATION 's/O influence/O ,/O but/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O also/O bearing/O the/O brunt/O ./O
China/LOCATION ,/O Iran/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION should/O also/O take/O the/O US-India/O deals/O very/O seriously/O and/O do/O something/O about/O it/O ,/O ''/O she/O added/O ./O
Pakistan/LOCATION concerned/O
The/O changing/O geopolitics/O in/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION has/O also/O prompted/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O forge/O closer/O ties/O with/O its/O long-time/O ally/O China/LOCATION ./O
Beijing/LOCATION is/O expanding/O trade/O and/O military/O cooperation/O with/O Islamabad/LOCATION keeping/O in/O view/O the/O New/O Delhi-Washington/O maneuvers/O ./O
Last/O year/O ,/O China/LOCATION announced/O an/O economic/O project/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION worth/O $/O 46/O billion/O -LRB-/O 41/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O ./O
With/O the/O China-Pakistan/U_LOCATION Economic/U_LOCATION Corridor/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O CPEC/U_LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION aims/O to/O expand/O its/O influence/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O across/O Central/O and/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION in/O order/O to/O counter/O US/LOCATION and/O Indian/O influences/O ./O
The/O CPEC/U_LOCATION would/O link/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O southern/O Gwadar/LOCATION port/O on/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION to/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O ./O
It/O also/O includes/O plans/O to/O create/O road/O ,/O rail/O and/O oil/O pipeline/O links/O to/O improve/O connectivity/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O
The/O ties/O between/O Russia/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION are/O still/O friendly/O ./O
Moscow/LOCATION has/O remained/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION 's/O largest/O arms/O supplier/O over/O the/O past/O three/O years/O ./O
The/O two/O countries/O '/O relations/O have/O blossomed/O since/O Narendra/PERSON Modi/PERSON became/O India/LOCATION 's/O prime/O minister/O two/O years/O ago/O ./O
But/O Russia/LOCATION is/O skeptical/O about/O India/LOCATION 's/O warming/O ties/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O seeks/O to/O put/O pressure/O on/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION by/O reaching/O out/O to/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O
Over/O the/O last/O 15/O months/O ,/O several/O high-ranking/O Pakistani/O military/O officials/O have/O travelled/O to/O Moscow/LOCATION to/O boost/O bilateral/O ties/O ,/O which/O has/O resulted/O in/O the/O signing/O of/O a/O deal/O for/O the/O sale/O of/O four/O Russian/O Mi-35/O attack/O helicopters/O to/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O
Both/O countries/O also/O agreed/O on/O a/O pipeline/O project/O intended/O to/O transfer/O liquefied/O natural/O gas/O -LRB-/O LNG/O -RRB-/O from/O Karachi/LOCATION to/O Lahore/LOCATION ./O
It/O could/O assist/O in/O resolving/O the/O Islamic/O country/O 's/O protracted/O energy/O crisis/O ./O
``/O Improved/O ties/O with/O Russia/LOCATION augurs/O well/O for/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Shuakat/PERSON Qadir/PERSON ,/O a/O retired/O Pakistani/O military/O official/O and/O defense/O analyst/O ,/O told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O The/O US/LOCATION policies/O have/O forced/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O look/O for/O alternatives/O ./O
Islamabad/LOCATION is/O unhappy/O with/O the/O US-India/O partnership/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O
The/O analyst/O says/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION has/O finally/O come/O out/O of/O the/O Cold/O War/O dynamics/O as/O it/O is/O not/O depending/O on/O one/O global/O power/O anymore/O ./O
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O Qadir/PERSON said/O ,/O the/O ``/O closer/O ties/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O Moscow/LOCATION do/O not/O mean/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION should/O turn/O its/O back/O on/O Washington/LOCATION ./O ''/O
``/O We/O should/O engage/O with/O all/O countries/O ,/O ''/O Qadir/PERSON underlined/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION is/O expanding/O trade/O and/O military/O cooperation/O with/O Islamabad/LOCATION keeping/O in/O view/O the/O New/O Delhi-Washington/O maneuvers/O
South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION bears/O the/O brunt/O
The/O conflicting/O interests/O of/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION in/O Asia/LOCATION and/O the/O new/O strategic/O formations/O are/O spiking/O tensions/O in/O the/O South/O Asian/O region/O ./O
The/O Indian-Pakistani/O ties/O are/O at/O their/O worst/O with/O both/O neighboring/O countries/O accusing/O each/O other/O of/O sponsoring/O terrorism/O ./O
Since/O July/O 8/O ,/O the/O Indian/O part/O of/O Kashmir/LOCATION has/O been/O in/O a/O grip/O of/O violence/O ./O
New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION has/O accused/O Islamabad/LOCATION of/O supporting/O separatist/O groups/O in/O the/O valley/O ./O
Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O in/O turn/O ,/O has/O alleged/O that/O Indian/O intelligence/O agencies/O have/O been/O backing/O an/O insurgent/O movement/O in/O its/O western/O Balochistan/LOCATION province/O ./O
Kerry/PERSON acknowledged/O that/O the/O deteriorating/O ties/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION were/O having/O a/O negative/O impact/O on/O the/O security/O situation/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O particularly/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O where/O American/O troops/O are/O stationed/O ./O
But/O instead/O of/O engaging/O with/O Pakistani/O authorities/O ,/O the/O top/O US/LOCATION diplomat/O chose/O to/O be/O tough/O with/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O
``/O It/O is/O clear/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION has/O work/O to/O do/O in/O order/O to/O push/O harder/O against/O its/O indigenous/O groups/O that/O are/O engaged/O in/O extremist/O terrorist/O activities/O ,/O ''/O Kerry/PERSON said/O in/O an/O address/O to/O students/O in/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION ./O
``/O They/O must/O work/O with/O us/O to/O help/O clear/O the/O sanctuaries/O of/O bad/O actors/O who/O are/O affecting/O not/O only/O relations/O between/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION but/O also/O our/O ability/O to/O achieve/O peace/O and/O stability/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O
Analyst/O Shuakat/PERSON Qadir/PERSON said/O that/O Islamabad/LOCATION would/O take/O action/O against/O the/O militants/O on/O its/O own/O volition/O ./O
``/O We/O are/O already/O fighting/O terrorists/O ./O
The/O US/LOCATION needs/O to/O review/O its/O policies/O also/O ,/O ''/O Qadir/PERSON said/O ./O
Ties/O between/O Kabul/LOCATION and/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION have/O improved/O a/O lot/O in/O recent/O years/O
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O military/O and/O civilian/O leaders/O ,/O analysts/O say/O ,/O still/O consider/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION an/O important/O strategic/O ally/O ,/O who/O they/O think/O should/O be/O part/O of/O the/O Afghan/O government/O after/O the/O NATO/ORGANIZATION pullout/O ./O
Observers/O say/O that/O the/O Pakistani/O military/O hopes/O to/O regain/O the/O influence/O in/O Kabul/LOCATION it/O once/O enjoyed/O before/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O its/O allies/O toppled/O the/O pro-Pakistan/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION government/O in/O 2001/O ./O
``/O Kabul/LOCATION is/O friendlier/O towards/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION now/O ,/O whereas/O Islamabad/LOCATION continues/O to/O back/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O
Pakistan/LOCATION wishes/O to/O change/O this/O scenario/O and/O turn/O Afghanistan/LOCATION into/O its/O political/O backyard/O once/O again/O ,/O ''/O London-based/O journalist/O and/O researcher/O Farooq/PERSON Sulehria/PERSON told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ./O
Nonetheless/O ,/O some/O experts/O blame/O the/O growing/O involvement/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION and/O the/O US/LOCATION in/O the/O South/O Asian/O affairs/O for/O the/O worsening/O state/O of/O security/O in/O the/O region/O ./O
They/O believe/O it/O could/O trigger/O new/O conflicts/O and/O plunge/O the/O region/O into/O a/O deeper/O turmoil/O ./O
Additional/O reporting/O by/O Sattar/PERSON Khan/PERSON ,/O DW/ORGANIZATION 's/O Islamabad/LOCATION correspondent/O ./O
