More/O than/O two/O decades/O after/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION withdrawal/O from/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Moscow/LOCATION is/O once/O again/O seeking/O to/O play/O a/O major/O role/O in/O the/O country/O by/O boosting/O military/O and/O economic/O cooperation/O with/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION examines/O ./O
Russia/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION have/O become/O friends/O again/O ,/O putting/O behind/O their/O past/O enmity/O and/O bitter/O memories/O from/O the/O decade-long/O Soviet/LOCATION occupation/O of/O the/O South/O Asian/O country/O ./O
The/O two/O countries/O today/O share/O good/O relations/O ,/O and/O they/O even/O signed/O a/O security/O agreement/O last/O year/O ./O
Just/O recently/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION gave/O 10,000/O Kalashnikov/O rifles/O and/O millions/O of/O rounds/O of/O ammunition/O to/O the/O Afghan/O government/O ./O
And/O further/O Russian/O military/O and/O economic/O aid/O is/O expected/O to/O flow/O to/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O
Although/O Russia/LOCATION has/O n't/O engaged/O militarily/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION since/O the/O start/O of/O the/O US-led/O invasion/O of/O the/O country/O in/O 2001/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION has/O provided/O logistical/O support/O for/O the/O reconstruction/O of/O the/O war-torn/O nation/O ./O
This/O cooperation/O was/O formally/O institutionalized/O by/O the/O NATO-Russia/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ./O
Increasing/O engagement/O However/O ,/O after/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O relations/O with/O the/O West/LOCATION soured/O following/O the/O Ukraine/LOCATION conflict/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION decided/O to/O become/O active/O and/O expand/O its/O role/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O said/O Omar/PERSON Nessar/PERSON ,/O the/O director/O of/O the/O Moscow-based/O Center/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Contemporary/ORGANIZATION Afghan/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CISA/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O
``/O Russia/LOCATION has/O sought/O closer/O ties/O with/O the/O Afghan/O government/O in/O a/O bid/O to/O help/O shape/O the/O events/O on/O the/O ground/O ,/O ''/O he/O told/O DW/ORGANIZATION ,/O pointing/O to/O Moscow/LOCATION 's/O military/O aid/O and/O economic/O investment/O in/O the/O country/O ./O
Watch/O video/O 01:51/O
Share/O Germany/LOCATION extends/O mission/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION
Send/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION Twitter/ORGANIZATION Google/ORGANIZATION +/O Whatsapp/ORGANIZATION Tumblr/ORGANIZATION linkedin/O stumble/O Digg/ORGANIZATION reddit/O Newsvine/ORGANIZATION Permalink/O http://dw.com/p/1HPHI/O
Germany/LOCATION extends/O mission/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION
Furthermore/O ,/O Russia/LOCATION plans/O to/O support/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O housing/O sector/O ,/O as/O indicated/O by/O Zamir/PERSON Kabulov/PERSON ,/O a/O department/O chief/O at/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION and/O President/O Vladimir/PERSON Putin/PERSON 's/O special/O envoy/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O during/O his/O meeting/O with/O Afghan/O President/O Ashraf/PERSON Ghani/PERSON on/O February/O 29/O ./O
Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O in/O turn/O ,/O has/O welcomed/O economic/O support/O not/O only/O from/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O but/O also/O China/LOCATION ,/O as/O Western/O nations/O continue/O their/O drawdown/O from/O the/O impoverished/O nation/O ./O
China/LOCATION is/O also/O playing/O a/O major/O role/O in/O the/O so/O far/O indirect/O peace/O talks/O held/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O
While/O Russia/LOCATION officially/O favors/O peace/O talks/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O it/O remains/O skeptical/O about/O whether/O the/O negotiations/O could/O begin/O soon/O ./O
Nevertheless/O ,/O Kabulov/PERSON called/O on/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION to/O take/O part/O in/O the/O talks/O ./O
During/O his/O recent/O visit/O to/O Kabul/LOCATION ,/O he/O insisted/O that/O only/O the/O Afghan/O government/O was/O empowered/O to/O lead/O the/O peace/O talks/O with/O the/O militants/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION recommends/O
Disillusionment/O driving/O Afghan/O asylum/O seekers/O back/O home/O
A/O special/O plane/O from/O Germany/LOCATION carrying/O rejected/O Afghan/O asylum/O seekers/O has/O landed/O in/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O
What/O prospects/O do/O these/O people/O now/O have/O in/O their/O home/O country/O ?/O
DW/ORGANIZATION examines/O ./O -LRB-/O 25.02.2016/O -RRB-/O
Afghan/O civilian/O casualties/O hit/O new/O high/O :/O UN/ORGANIZATION
The/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION says/O civilian/O casualties/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O conflict/O have/O hit/O a/O record/O high/O for/O the/O seventh/O year/O running/O ./O
Children/O made/O up/O a/O large/O proportion/O of/O the/O dead/O and/O wounded/O ./O -LRB-/O 14.02.2016/O -RRB-/O
Child/O soldiers/O -/O What/O 's/O their/O role/O in/O the/O Afghan/O conflict/O ?/O
The/O recent/O killing/O of/O a/O 10-year-old/O boy/O has/O highlighted/O the/O issue/O of/O child/O soldiers/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
Although/O it/O 's/O illegal/O ,/O government/O forces/O and/O insurgents/O have/O kept/O recruiting/O minors/O for/O years/O ./O
DW/ORGANIZATION examines/O ./O -LRB-/O 13.02.2016/O -RRB-/O
Are/O US/LOCATION troops/O getting/O drawn/O into/O combat/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ?/O
The/O US/LOCATION is/O planning/O to/O send/O extra/O troops/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O Helmand/LOCATION Province/LOCATION to/O assist/O the/O local/O security/O forces/O ./O
But/O analyst/O Jason/PERSON Campbell/PERSON says/O the/O line/O between/O advising/O and/O getting/O involved/O in/O combat/O is/O becoming/O blurred/O ./O -LRB-/O 10.02.2016/O -RRB-/O
``/O Russia/LOCATION shares/O friendly/O relations/O with/O the/O Afghan/O government/O ,/O but/O it/O has/O no/O confidence/O in/O the/O China/LOCATION and/O US-mediated/O peace/O talks/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O said/O Javid/PERSON Ahmad/PERSON ,/O a/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION expert/O at/O Yale/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O The/O Russians/O are/O more/O interested/O in/O a/O parallel/O diplomatic/O effort/O led/O by/O Moscow/LOCATION to/O promote/O their/O own/O interests/O ./O ''/O
But/O experts/O say/O Russia/LOCATION has/O found/O a/O rather/O unusual/O partner/O in/O this/O attempt/O ,/O in/O the/O form/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O
A/O double/O game/O ?/O
Russia/LOCATION 's/O interests/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ``/O objectively/O coincide/O ''/O with/O those/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O Kabulov/PERSON told/O journalists/O in/O Moscow/LOCATION in/O January/O ./O
He/O noted/O that/O the/O Russian/O government/O has/O been/O in/O contact/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION to/O exchange/O information/O about/O the/O so-called/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O IS/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O terrorist/O group/O ,/O which/O has/O been/O seeking/O to/O increase/O its/O presence/O in/O the/O country/O ./O
Yale/ORGANIZATION analyst/O Ahmad/PERSON says/O the/O Russians/O view/O IS/ORGANIZATION as/O a/O bigger/O threat/O to/O their/O interests/O ./O
``/O That/O 's/O why/O they/O have/O embraced/O their/O former/O nemesis/O :/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O a/O hedge/O against/O the/O growing/O influence/O of/O IS/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O neighborhood/O ,/O ''/O he/O pointed/O out/O ./O
A/O September/O 2015/O UN/ORGANIZATION report/O said/O IS/ORGANIZATION fighters/O were/O operating/O in/O 25/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O 34/O provinces/O ./O
Many/O of/O these/O militants/O are/O former/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION members/O ./O
It/O is/O estimated/O that/O there/O are/O currently/O some/O 3,000/O IS/ORGANIZATION fighters/O in/O the/O country/O ./O
``/O This/O is/O a/O calculated/O ,/O and/O at/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O dangerous/O approach/O ,/O which/O not/O only/O has/O far-reaching/O consequences/O for/O the/O security/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O but/O could/O also/O lead/O to/O a/O proxy/O war/O ,/O ''/O said/O Ahmad/PERSON ./O
However/O ,/O he/O cautioned/O ,/O any/O material/O support/O provided/O to/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION also/O means/O that/O UN/ORGANIZATION sanctions/O have/O been/O violated/O ./O
But/O CISA/ORGANIZATION analyst/O Nessar/PERSON views/O this/O as/O an/O exaggeration/O ./O
``/O All/O regional/O and/O world/O powers/O have/O established/O contact/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O said/O the/O expert/O ./O
``/O Whether/O it/O is/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION or/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O all/O countries/O have/O the/O right/O to/O contact/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O
Why/O should/O n't/O this/O also/O apply/O to/O Russia/LOCATION ?/O ''/O
According/O to/O Nessar/PERSON ,/O it/O is/O Western/O and/O Afghan/O media/O that/O often/O distort/O and/O misinterpret/O Kabulov/PERSON 's/O statements/O ./O
``/O The/O goal/O is/O to/O undermine/O the/O trust/O between/O these/O two/O countries/O and/O prevent/O renewed/O Russian/O engagement/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O Nessar/PERSON ,/O pointing/O out/O that/O Russia/LOCATION still/O faces/O strong/O enemies/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
Amu/LOCATION Darya/LOCATION instead/O of/O Wolga/LOCATION
Nonetheless/O ,/O Russia/LOCATION fears/O that/O terrorist/O groups/O could/O infiltrate/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O
According/O to/O Afghan/O security/O officials/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O terrorists/O from/O Arab/O nations/O ,/O along/O with/O Chechens/O ,/O Uighurs/O ,/O Uzbeks/O ,/O Tajiks/O and/O Pakistanis/O from/O the/O bordering/O area/O of/O North/LOCATION Waziristan/LOCATION have/O come/O through/O the/O bordering/O area/O of/O North/LOCATION Waziristan/LOCATION to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION to/O fight/O ./O
Watch/O video/O 02:32/O
Share/O How/O Afghans/O are/O fleeing/O their/O country/O
Send/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION Twitter/ORGANIZATION Google/ORGANIZATION +/O Whatsapp/ORGANIZATION Tumblr/ORGANIZATION linkedin/O stumble/O Digg/PERSON reddit/O Newsvine/ORGANIZATION Permalink/O http://dw.com/p/1HOuq/O
How/O Afghans/O are/O fleeing/O their/O country/O
As/O a/O result/O ,/O over/O the/O past/O year/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION has/O become/O the/O scene/O of/O bloody/O battles/O ./O
The/O provincial/O capital/O of/O Kunduz/LOCATION ,/O located/O some/O 70/O kilometers/O from/O the/O Tajik/O border/O ,/O fell/O into/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION hands/O for/O a/O few/O days/O ./O
Rumors/O have/O been/O circulating/O that/O it/O was/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O material/O support/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION which/O enabled/O the/O fall/O of/O city/O in/O the/O first/O place/O ./O
Russia/LOCATION is/O also/O concerned/O about/O having/O that/O many/O terrorist/O fighters/O so/O close/O to/O its/O borders/O ./O
To/O prevent/O them/O from/O entering/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION has/O decided/O to/O support/O and/O train/O the/O Tajik/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O We/O 'd/O rather/O fight/O the/O Islamists/O on/O the/O Amu/LOCATION Darya/LOCATION than/O on/O the/O Volga/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Kabulov/PERSON told/O Russian/O news/O agency/O Interfax/ORGANIZATION early/O this/O year/O ./O
Perhaps/O this/O could/O become/O the/O slogan/O of/O the/O renewed/O Russian-Afghan/O friendship/O ./O
