Beijing/LOCATION has/O detained/O several/O lawyers/O and/O legal/O staff/O on/O subversion/O charges/O ,/O according/O to/O family/O and/O colleagues/O ./O
The/O arrests/O are/O part/O of/O a/O crackdown/O on/O dissent/O and/O follow/O months/O of/O secret/O detention/O ./O
Among/O the/O detained/O is/O Zhou/PERSON Shifeng/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O law/O firm/O Fengrui/ORGANIZATION ,/O his/O family/O was/O told/O on/O Tuesday/O ./O
The/O families/O of/O Wang/PERSON Quanzhang/PERSON and/O Li/PERSON Shuyun/PERSON ,/O a/O lawyer/O and/O apprentice/O lawyer/O at/O the/O firm/O ,/O were/O also/O notified/O of/O their/O arrests/O by/O police/O in/O Tianjin/LOCATION ./O
According/O to/O the/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O ,/O as/O many/O as/O 38/O of/O its/O staff/O and/O associates/O -/O lawyers/O and/O activists/O -/O have/O been/O questioned/O or/O held/O since/O last/O July/O in/O a/O government/O effort/O to/O hold/O to/O account/O those/O it/O says/O aim/O to/O subvert/O state/O power/O ./O
State/O subversion/O carries/O a/O maximum/O sentence/O of/O life/O in/O jail/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
Fengrui/ORGANIZATION has/O represented/O several/O high-profile/O clients/O ,/O such/O as/O the/O ethnic/O Uighur/O dissident/O Ilham/U_PERSON Tohti/U_PERSON ./O
State/O media/O has/O accused/O the/O firm/O and/O its/O associates/O of/O orchestrating/O protests/O outside/O courts/O and/O politicizing/O ordinary/O legal/O cases/O to/O attract/O international/O attention/O ./O
The/O arrests/O are/O part/O of/O a/O clampdown/O on/O dissent/O that/O has/O seen/O up/O to/O 300/O human/O rights/O lawyers/O and/O activists/O detained/O and/or/O questioned/O since/O last/O July/O ,/O authorities/O ,/O according/O to/O rights/O groups/O ./O
Many/O had/O been/O held/O in/O undisclosed/O locations/O for/O months/O ./O
Swedish/O activist/O Peter/PERSON Dahlin/PERSON ,/O who/O works/O for/O a/O human/O rights/O group/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O has/O also/O been/O detained/O on/O suspicion/O of/O endangering/O state/O security/O ,/O his/O colleague/O said/O on/O Tuesday/O ./O
Campaigners/O consider/O it/O the/O fiercest/O attempt/O by/O China/LOCATION to/O silence/O activists/O in/O decades/O -/O despite/O its/O insistence/O that/O it/O is/O adhering/O to/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O ruling/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION does/O not/O tolerate/O organized/O dissent/O and/O has/O tightened/O controls/O on/O civil/O society/O under/O the/O leadership/O of/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ./O
ng/jil/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
