Having/O announced/O its/O intention/O to/O close/O the/O Guantánamo/LOCATION prison/O camp/O ,/O the/O Obama/PERSON administration/O has/O been/O trying/O to/O convince/O other/O countries/O to/O take/O in/O detainees/O who/O are/O up/O for/O release/O ./O 
In/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O particularly/O ,/O a/O debate/O had/O been/O going/O on/O about/O letting/O a/O group/O of/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/LOCATION</OTHER> settle/O here/O ./O 
They/O belong/O to/O a/O Muslim/O minority/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O fear/O persecution/O if/O they/O return/O home/O ./O 
But/O now/O ,/O another/O solution/O seems/O to/O be/O on/O the/O cards/O :/O The/O Pacific/LOCATION island/O nation/O of/O Palau/LOCATION says/O it/O has/O agreed/O to/O temporarily/O resettle/O up/O to/O 17/O Uyghur/O prisoners/O from/O Guantánamo/LOCATION ./O 
The/O news/O from/O Palau/LOCATION has/O come/O as/O a/O total/O surprise/O --/O also/O to/O <U_PERSON>Dolkun/PERSON Isa/PERSON</U_PERSON> in/O Munich/LOCATION ,/O the/O Secretary/O General/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> :/O ``/O It/O is/O of/O course/O very/O good/O news/O ,/O because/O all/O the/O countries/O always/O refused/O to/O accept/O Uyghurs/O ./O ''/O 
But/O <U_PERSON>Dolkun/PERSON Isa/PERSON</U_PERSON> is/O also/O disappointed/O ./O 
Munich/LOCATION 's/O more/O than/O 500/O Uyghurs/O and/O some/O local/O politicians/O had/O campaigned/O for/O the/O Guantánamo/LOCATION <OTHER>Uyghurs/LOCATION</OTHER> to/O come/O to/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
``/O The/O people/O living/O in/O Guantánamo/LOCATION for/O seven/O years/O have/O psychological/O problems/O because/O of/O seven/O years/O in/O jail/O ,/O ''/O he/O says/O ./O 
``/O Maybe/O they/O were/O tortured/O ./O 
If/O they/O come/O to/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O we/O are/O ready/O to/O give/O moral/O support/O to/O them/O ./O 
We/O have/O some/O small/O companies/O ,/O some/O small/O Uyghur/O businesses/O ,/O which/O are/O prepared/O to/O provide/O jobs/O to/O them/O ./O 
So/O they/O would/O very/O quickly/O be/O integrated/O in/O the/O German/O society/O ./O ''/O 
Objections/O in/O Germany/LOCATION 
But/O there/O was/O resistance/O in/O Germany/LOCATION as/O well/O ./O 
Interior/O minister/O Wolfgang/PERSON Schäuble/PERSON ,/O in/O particular/O ,/O insisted/O that/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION had/O set/O up/O the/O Guantánamo/LOCATION camp/O in/O the/O first/O place/O ,/O so/O the/O US/LOCATION should/O now/O also/O bear/O the/O consequences/O ./O 
Reed/PERSON Brody/PERSON from/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION in/O Brussels/LOCATION thinks/O another/O factor/O might/O have/O discouraged/O German/O politicians/O ./O 
``/O Apparently/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O considers/O these/O Uyghurs/O ,/O who/O come/O from/O a/O part/O of/O China/LOCATION that/O is/O chafing/O under/O Chinese/O rule/O ,/O to/O be/O potential/O terrorists/O ,/O and/O has/O threatened/O and/O put/O pressure/O on/O countries/O like/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O ''/O says/O Brody/PERSON ./O 
Palau/LOCATION feels/O honoured/O 
Palau/LOCATION does/O n't/O have/O these/O problems/O ,/O being/O one/O of/O a/O handful/O of/O countries/O worldwide/O which/O do/O n't/O recognize/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O but/O have/O diplomatic/O relations/O with/O Taiwan/LOCATION instead/O ./O 
Palau/LOCATION 's/O president/O Johnson/PERSON Toribiong/PERSON said/O in/O a/O statement/O he/O was/O ``/O honoured/O and/O proud/O that/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION had/O asked/O Palau/LOCATION to/O assist/O in/O such/O a/O critical/O task/O ''/O ./O 
Reed/PERSON Brody/PERSON from/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION puts/O it/O this/O way/O :/O ``/O Palau/LOCATION is/O a/O country/O that/O has/O very/O strong/O ties/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
It/O was/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION '/O possession/O for/O a/O long/O time/O and/O certainly/O is/O a/O country/O that/O is/O susceptible/O to/O American/O pressure/O if/O there/O is/O one/O ./O ''/O 
Brody/PERSON does/O n't/O think/O sending/O the/O Uyghurs/O to/O Palau/LOCATION is/O the/O best/O solution/O :/O ``/O The/O Uyghurs/O are/O probably/O the/O easiest/O of/O the/O <LOCATION>Guantánamo/O</LOCATION> detainees/O to/O resettle/O ./O 
They/O are/O people/O who/O almost/O certainly/O were/O just/O in/O the/O wrong/O place/O at/O the/O wrong/O time/O ./O 
Even/O the/O Bush/PERSON administration/O said/O they/O have/O no/O links/O to/O terrorist/O activities/O ./O 
One/O would/O think/O we/O could/O have/O done/O better/O and/O that/O Palau/LOCATION might/O be/O saved/O for/O the/O hard/O cases/O ./O ''/O 
The/O Albanian/O example/O In/O the/O past/O ,/O Albania/LOCATION has/O accepted/O a/O few/O Uyghurs/O released/O from/O Guantánamo/LOCATION ./O 
The/O exile/O community/O in/O Germany/LOCATION and/O other/O places/O has/O helped/O them/O settle/O down/O ,/O and/O now/O they/O are/O doing/O reasonably/O well/O ,/O says/O <U_PERSON>Dolkun/PERSON Isa/PERSON</U_PERSON> from/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> :/O ``/O They/O are/O very/O popular/O through/O the/O media/O ,/O so/O all/O the/O Albanian/O people/O know/O them/O ./O 
Those/O people/O also/O integrated/O very/O quickly/O into/O the/O Albanian/O society/O ./O 
Some/O of/O them/O go/O to/O the/O university/O now/O ,/O some/O of/O them/O work/O in/O Albania/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
But/O at/O least/O there/O are/O some/O cultural/O similarities/O in/O Albania/LOCATION :/O most/O people/O are/O Muslims/O ,/O as/O are/O the/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
The/O last/O census/O from/O Palau/LOCATION does/O n't/O mention/O Muslims/O among/O the/O 20,000/O inhabitants/O ./O 
The/O Uyghurs/O are/O from/O a/O desert/O area/O which/O is/O further/O away/O from/O the/O nearest/O ocean/O than/O any/O other/O place/O on/O earth/O ./O 
They/O are/O now/O likely/O to/O find/O themselves/O in/O a/O divers/O '/O paradise/O 800/O kilometres/O east/O of/O the/O Philippines/LOCATION ./O 
Author/O :/O Thomas/PERSON Bärthlein/PERSON 
Editor/O :/O Grahame/PERSON Lucas/PERSON
