The/O 2010/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O has/O been/O controversially/O awarded/O to/O jailed/O Chinese/O dissident/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON in/O a/O move/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION says/O could/O damage/O relations/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O Norway/LOCATION ./O 
The/O <ORGANIZATION>Norwegian/O</ORGANIZATION> Nobel/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION followed/O up/O last/O year/O 's/O surprising/O choice/O of/O US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON as/O the/O winner/O of/O the/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O by/O announcing/O an/O even/O more/O controversial/O choice/O for/O 2010/O :/O Chinese/O dissident/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON ,/O a/O political/O activist/O jailed/O by/O a/O Beijing/LOCATION court/O for/O 11/O years/O in/O December/O ./O 
World/O leaders/O welcomed/O the/O award/O with/O many/O using/O the/O opportunity/O to/O press/O home/O their/O belief/O in/O stronger/O efforts/O to/O secure/O human/O rights/O ,/O a/O belief/O championed/O by/O Lui/PERSON himself/O ./O 
Norway/LOCATION 's/O Prime/O Minister/O Jens/PERSON Stoltenberg/PERSON congratulated/O Liu/PERSON ,/O ignoring/O the/O possibility/O of/O exacerbating/O an/O already/O volatile/O situation/O with/O China/LOCATION over/O Lui/PERSON 's/O nomination/O and/O subsequent/O triumph/O ./O 
``/O I/O would/O like/O to/O congratulate/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O been/O awarded/O the/O 2010/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O for/O his/O work/O to/O promote/O democracy/O and/O human/O rights/O ,/O ''/O Stoltenberg/PERSON said/O in/O a/O statement/O ./O 
``/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON has/O been/O awarded/O the/O prize/O for/O defending/O freedom/O of/O expression/O and/O democracy/O in/O a/O way/O that/O deserves/O attention/O and/O respect/O ./O ''/O 
World/O leaders/O praised/O the/O decision/O to/O honour/O <PERSON>Liu/LOCATION Xiaobo/LOCATION</PERSON> 
Germany/LOCATION was/O quick/O to/O offer/O its/O own/O congratulations/O with/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON 's/O spokesman/O Steffen/PERSON Seibert/PERSON calling/O on/O Liu/PERSON to/O be/O allowed/O to/O collect/O the/O award/O himself/O in/O person/O ./O 
Liu/PERSON was/O ``/O a/O courageous/O man/O ,/O a/O man/O who/O wants/O to/O help/O bring/O about/O democracy/O in/O his/O home/O country/O ,/O ''/O Seibert/PERSON said/O ./O 
German/O Foreign/O Minister/O Guido/PERSON Westerwelle/PERSON added/O :/O ``/O I/O am/O very/O pleased/O that/O his/O courage/O and/O his/O untiring/O advocacy/O of/O freedom/O and/O human/O rights/O have/O been/O honored/O ./O 
I/O welcome/O this/O courageous/O decision/O ,/O which/O sends/O a/O signal/O to/O the/O world/O that/O human/O rights/O will/O be/O supported/O ./O 
It/O will/O encourage/O others/O to/O continue/O this/O work/O ./O ''/O 
The/O office/O of/O European/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION President/O Jose/PERSON Manuel/PERSON Barroso/PERSON issued/O a/O statement/O on/O behalf/O of/O the/O head/O of/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION 's/O executive/O which/O praised/O the/O Noble/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION 's/O decision/O as/O ``/O a/O strong/O message/O of/O support/O to/O all/O those/O around/O the/O world/O who/O ,/O sometimes/O with/O great/O personal/O sacrifice/O ,/O are/O struggling/O for/O freedom/O and/O human/O rights/O ./O ''/O 
Navi/PERSON Pillay/PERSON ,/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Commissioner/O for/O Human/O Rights/O also/O paid/O tribute/O :/O ``/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON is/O of/O course/O a/O very/O prominent/O human/O rights/O defender/O ./O 
We/O welcome/O this/O recognition/O of/O the/O very/O important/O role/O human/O rights/O defenders/O play/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O in/O many/O other/O countries/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O challenges/O they/O face/O ./O ''/O 
The/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> ,/O the/O 1989/O Nobel/O peace/O laureate/O ,/O praised/O the/O bravery/O of/O the/O Nobel/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION and/O said/O its/O choice/O reflected/O international/O recognition/O of/O ``/O the/O increasing/O voices/O among/O the/O Chinese/O people/O in/O pushing/O China/LOCATION towards/O political/O ,/O legal/O and/O constitutional/O reforms/O ./O ''/O 
Criticism/O from/O both/O Chinese/O government/O and/O fellow/O dissidents/O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O as/O expected/O ,/O China/LOCATION reacted/O with/O anger/O to/O the/O news/O ./O 
``/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON is/O a/O criminal/O sentenced/O by/O Chinese/O judicial/O organs/O due/O to/O his/O violation/O of/O Chinese/O law/O ,/O ''/O the/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION said/O in/O a/O statement/O ./O 
``/O His/O actions/O are/O against/O the/O purpose/O of/O the/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O ./O ''/O 
``/O The/O Nobel/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION 's/O award/O of/O the/O Peace/O Prize/O to/O such/O a/O person/O is/O totally/O contrary/O to/O the/O aim/O of/O this/O prize/O and/O also/O seriously/O disrespects/O the/O peace/O prize/O ,/O ''/O the/O statement/O said/O ./O 
Wei/PERSON ,/O who/O lives/O in/O exile/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O criticised/O Liu/PERSON 's/O award/O 
Criticism/O also/O came/O from/O Wei/PERSON Jingsheng/PERSON ,/O a/O senior/O figure/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O democracy/O movement/O ,/O who/O said/O that/O other/O dissidents/O were/O more/O deserving/O of/O Liu/PERSON who/O he/O accused/O of/O being/O a/O moderate/O willing/O to/O work/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Wei/PERSON ,/O who/O spent/O nearly/O two/O decades/O in/O prison/O for/O his/O own/O dissent/O ,/O claimed/O that/O Liu/PERSON had/O often/O been/O allowed/O to/O operate/O freely/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O and/O had/O criticized/O those/O who/O had/O pushed/O for/O even/O greater/O change/O ./O 
``/O In/O my/O observation/O ,/O the/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O is/O going/O to/O Liu/PERSON because/O he/O is/O different/O from/O the/O majority/O of/O people/O in/O opposition/O ./O 
He/O made/O more/O gestures/O of/O cooperation/O with/O the/O government/O and/O made/O more/O criticism/O of/O other/O resisters/O who/O suffered/O ,/O ''/O Wei/PERSON said/O ,/O adding/O that/O there/O were/O ``/O tens/O of/O thousands/O ''/O of/O Chinese/O who/O would/O deserve/O the/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O ./O 
China/LOCATION warns/O committee/O over/O Norway/LOCATION relations/O 
The/O Nobel/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION risked/O damaging/O relations/O between/O Norway/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION by/O picking/O Liu/PERSON ,/O a/O champion/O of/O political/O change/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O an/O outspoken/O campaigner/O for/O freedom/O of/O assembly/O ,/O freedom/O of/O expression/O ,/O and/O freedom/O of/O religion/O in/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION ./O 
Liu/PERSON 's/O campaign/O for/O reform/O in/O China/LOCATION has/O come/O at/O a/O high/O cost/O 
However/O ,/O Liu/PERSON is/O seen/O as/O a/O dangerous/O subversive/O by/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION government/O which/O warned/O the/O committee/O to/O steer/O clear/O of/O recognizing/O any/O pro-democracy/O advocates/O ,/O especially/O Liu/PERSON ./O 
Liu/PERSON ,/O who/O helped/O set/O up/O Charter/O 08/O ,/O a/O pro-democracy/O manifesto/O issued/O by/O Chinese/O intellectuals/O and/O activists/O which/O demanded/O political/O reform/O ,/O free/O speech/O and/O multi-party/O elections/O ,/O has/O had/O a/O number/O of/O prominent/O supporters/O backing/O his/O nomination/O since/O his/O name/O was/O included/O in/O the/O short/O list/O ,/O including/O ,/O among/O others/O ,/O Nobel/O peace/O laureates/O Desmond/PERSON Tutu/PERSON ,/O South/LOCATION Africa/LOCATION 's/O former/O Anglican/O archbishop/O ,/O and/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ,/O the/O spiritual/O leader/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
A/O former/O literature/O professor/O ,/O Liu/PERSON was/O among/O the/O leaders/O of/O a/O hunger/O strike/O during/O student/O protests/O on/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION in/O 1989/O ./O 
His/O involvement/O and/O his/O outspoken/O views/O earned/O him/O a/O 20/O month/O jail/O term/O ./O 
He/O was/O later/O sentenced/O to/O three/O years/O in/O a/O ``/O labor/O reeducation/O ''/O camp/O for/O his/O continuing/O opposition/O to/O the/O regime/O and/O has/O spent/O various/O periods/O over/O the/O last/O few/O years/O under/O house/O arrest/O ./O 
Liu/PERSON 's/O wife/O called/O on/O the/O international/O community/O to/O use/O her/O husband/O 's/O award/O to/O call/O on/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O press/O for/O his/O release/O ./O 
``/O As/O the/O committee/O recognized/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O new/O status/O in/O the/O world/O comes/O with/O increased/O responsibility/O ,/O ''/O Liu/PERSON Xia/PERSON said/O in/O a/O written/O statement/O released/O by/O the/O Freedom/ORGANIZATION Now/ORGANIZATION human/O rights/O group/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION should/O embrace/O this/O responsibility/O ,/O have/O pride/O in/O his/O selection/O ,/O and/O release/O him/O from/O prison/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
Lui/PERSON triumphs/O in/O face/O of/O strong/O competition/O 
Lui/PERSON triumphed/O over/O a/O list/O of/O distinguished/O nominees/O 
Lui/PERSON was/O chosen/O in/O the/O face/O of/O stiff/O competition/O from/O Zimbabwean/O Prime/O Minister/O Morgan/PERSON Tsvangirai/PERSON ,/O former/O Irish/O president/O Mary/PERSON Robinson/PERSON ,/O and/O Russian/O human/O rights/O activist/O Svetlana/PERSON Gannushkina/PERSON ./O 
Helmut/PERSON Kohl/PERSON ,/O the/O German/O chancellor/O who/O oversaw/O reunification/O and/O the/O fall/O of/O the/O Berlin/LOCATION Wall/LOCATION ,/O Afghan/O doctor/O and/O women/O 's/O rights/O activist/O Sima/PERSON Samar/PERSON and/O leader/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uighur/O minority/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> were/O also/O mentioned/O as/O possible/O winners/O along/O with/O Burma/LOCATION 's/O broadcaster-in-exile/O ,/O the/O Democratic/ORGANIZATION Voice/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Burma/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Author/O :/O Nick/PERSON Amies/PERSON 
<OTHER>Editor/PERSON</OTHER> :/O Rob/PERSON Mudge/PERSON
