Police/O say/O three/O men/O were/O arrested/O in/O Germany/LOCATION and/O Norway/LOCATION who/O are/O thought/O to/O be/O linked/O with/O the/O terrorist/O organization/O <ORGANIZATION>al/O Qaeda/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
The/O detainees/O are/O reported/O to/O have/O been/O planning/O a/O bomb/O attack/O in/O Oslo/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Three/O people/O suspected/O .../O of/O preparing/O a/O terrorist/O act/O and/O who/O have/O links/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>al-Qaeda/O</ORGANIZATION> have/O been/O arrested/O today/O ,/O ''/O Janne/PERSON Kristiansen/PERSON ,/O the/O head/O of/O the/O PST/ORGANIZATION ,/O confirmed/O reporters/O in/O Oslo/LOCATION ./O 
National/O prosecutor/O Jan/PERSON Glent/PERSON told/O the/O press/O conference/O that/O the/O three/O had/O been/O ``/O charged/O with/O having/O entered/O into/O a/O partnership/O to/O commit/O a/O terrorist/O act/O ./O ''/O 
``/O We/O also/O think/O they/O have/O links/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>al-Qaeda/O</ORGANIZATION> and/O to/O similar/O attempts/O -LSB-/O at/O terror/O attacks/O -RSB-/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O Manchester/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
Kristiansen/PERSON said/O that/O two/O of/O the/O men/O had/O been/O arrested/O in/O Oslo/LOCATION and/O one/O in/O Germany/LOCATION after/O an/O extensive/O investigation/O lasting/O over/O a/O year/O ./O 
The/O police/O force/O would/O not/O give/O details/O as/O to/O the/O men/O 's/O suspected/O plans/O ,/O but/O reports/O say/O they/O were/O preparing/O a/O bomb/O attack/O in/O the/O Norwegian/O capital/O using/O portable/O bombs/O similar/O in/O design/O to/O those/O used/O in/O recently-thwarted/O attacks/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION and/O Manchester/LOCATION ,/O England/LOCATION ./O 
Police/O refused/O to/O give/O the/O names/O of/O the/O suspects/O ,/O but/O Kristiansen/PERSON said/O one/O was/O a/O 39-year-old/O Norwegian/O citizen/O of/O Chinese/O Uighur/O origin/O ./O 
Both/O foreign/O nationals/O ,/O she/O said/O ,/O were/O legal/O residents/O of/O Norway/LOCATION ./O 
Kristiansen/PERSON said/O the/O international/O arrests/O were/O the/O result/O of/O cooperation/O between/O Norwegian/O and/O other/O European/O intelligence/O agencies/O ,/O although/O she/O would/O not/O say/O which/O ./O 
Europe/LOCATION 's/O war/O on/O terror/O Europe/LOCATION has/O n't/O experienced/O a/O major/O terrorist/O attack/O since/O London/LOCATION bombings/O in/O 2005/O 
Terrorism/O expert/O Rolf/PERSON Tophoven/PERSON of/O the/O Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Terrorism/ORGANIZATION Research/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Policy/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION that/O Thursday/O 's/O arrests/O were/O ``/O evidence/O ''/O that/O Europe/LOCATION 's/O intelligence/O agencies/O were/O on/O ``/O highest/O alert/O ./O ''/O 
Tophoven/PERSON likened/O the/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O to/O an/O Olympic/O marathon/O that/O never/O ended/O ,/O with/O both/O intelligence/O forces/O and/O terrorists/O constantly/O gaining/O speed/O ./O 
He/O added/O that/O ,/O because/O of/O interagency/O communication/O ,/O he/O believed/O the/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O was/O more/O effective/O in/O Europe/LOCATION than/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O where/O intelligence/O agencies/O like/O the/O FBI/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O CIA/ORGANIZATION notoriously/O compete/O with/O each/O other/O ./O 
Terrorism/O expert/O David/PERSON Schiller/PERSON agrees/O ./O 
``/O There/O 's/O much/O more/O sharing/O of/O information/O and/O intelligence/O than/O there/O was/O in/O the/O 1980s/O and/O 1990s/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
''/O -LSB-/O September/O 11/O -RSB-/O did/O bring/O home/O the/O lesson/O that/O one/O nation/O alone/O can/O not/O stand/O up/O against/O that/O type/O of/O threat/O ,/O so/O we/O have/O to/O cooperate/O and/O we/O have/O to/O share/O information/O ./O ''/O 
Europe/LOCATION needs/O united/O policies/O Norwegian/O authorities/O stressed/O that/O the/O threat/O of/O terrorism/O in/O Norway/LOCATION was/O normally/O low/O and/O remained/O low/O ./O 
Schiller/PERSON believes/O that/O to/O truly/O fight/O terrorism/O ,/O Europe/LOCATION must/O have/O stronger/O ,/O more/O united/O policies/O on/O its/O handling/O of/O the/O nations/O that/O support/O terrorists/O ./O 
These/O arrests/O ,/O he/O said/O ,/O are/O a/O ``/O tactical/O event/O ''/O but/O ``/O in/O the/O long/O run/O ,/O -LSB-/O arresting/O people/O alone/O -RSB-/O is/O not/O a/O strategy/O ./O ''/O 
Author/O :/O David/PERSON Levitz/PERSON 
Editor/O :/O Martin/PERSON Kuebler/PERSON
