Chinese/O authorities/O have/O raised/O the/O death/O toll/O to/O 18/O from/O a/O clash/O at/O a/O police/O station/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O saying/O that/O 14/O ``/O rioters/O ''/O died/O along/O with/O two/O policemen/O and/O two/O hostages/O in/O the/O worst/O violence/O there/O in/O a/O year/O ./O 
State/O news/O agency/O ,/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O reported/O on/O Tuesday/O that/O police/O in/O the/O city/O <U_LOCATION>Hotan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O had/O gunned/O down/O several/O rioters/O who/O had/O attacked/O a/O police/O station/O and/O apparently/O taken/O hostages/O in/O what/O is/O the/O region/O 's/O worst/O outbreak/O of/O violence/O in/O about/O a/O year/O ./O 
``/O Population/O flow/O spread/O in/O all/O directions/O ''/O -/O Uighurs/O now/O make/O up/O less/O than/O half/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O population/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O now/O raised/O the/O death/O toll/O from/O four/O to/O 18/O ,/O saying/O that/O 14/O ``/O rioters/O ''/O died/O along/O with/O two/O policemen/O and/O two/O hostages/O ./O 
The/O latest/O bout/O of/O violence/O in/O western/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O was/O ``/O an/O organised/O terrorist/O attack/O ,/O ''/O Hou/PERSON Hanmin/PERSON ,/O chief/O of/O the/O regional/O information/O office/O ,/O was/O quoted/O saying/O in/O the/O Global/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O popular/O tabloid/O owned/O by/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION 's/O mouthpiece/O ,/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Hou/PERSON told/O reporters/O ,/O ``/O the/O rioters/O carried/O explosive/O devices/O and/O grenades/O ./O 
They/O first/O broke/O into/O the/O offices/O of/O the/O local/O administration/O of/O industry/O and/O commerce/O and/O the/O taxation/O bureau/O that/O are/O close/O to/O the/O police/O station/O ,/O ''/O adding/O that/O people/O had/O been/O injured/O before/O the/O demonstrators/O started/O attacking/O the/O police/O station/O ,/O ``/O where/O they/O showed/O a/O flag/O with/O separatist/O messages/O ./O ''/O 
The/O attackers/O set/O the/O police/O station/O on/O fire/O before/O killing/O hostages/O during/O a/O stand-off/O with/O armed/O police/O ,/O Hou/PERSON added/O ./O 
`/O Systematic/O oppression/O '/O 
The/O Germany-based/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O citing/O sources/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O said/O security/O forces/O beat/O 14/O people/O to/O death/O and/O shot/O dead/O six/O others/O during/O the/O unrest/O ./O 
``/O The/O Chinese/O authorities/O should/O immediately/O cease/O their/O systematic/O oppression/O to/O prevent/O a/O further/O escalation/O of/O the/O situation/O ,/O ''/O said/O group/O spokesman/O <U_PERSON>Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON</U_PERSON> in/O a/O statement/O ./O 
Two/O hostages/O ,/O a/O paramilitary/O policeman/O and/O a/O guard/O ,/O died/O in/O the/O violence/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O several/O of/O the/O attackers/O ,/O the/O congress/O reported/O ,/O adding/O that/O six/O hostages/O were/O freed/O ./O 
The/O Global/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION said/O the/O national/O counter-terrorism/O office/O had/O dispatched/O a/O team/O to/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
The/O Uighurs/O belong/O to/O a/O Muslim/O minority/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O province/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 
A/O vast/O swathe/O of/O territory/O ,/O accounting/O for/O one-sixth/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O land/O mass/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> holds/O oil/O ,/O gas/O and/O coal/O deposits/O and/O borders/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O India/LOCATION and/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> has/O been/O plagued/O by/O violent/O unrest/O in/O recent/O years/O ,/O culminating/O in/O savage/O Uighur/O attacks/O on/O members/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O dominant/O Han/O group/O in/O the/O regional/O capital/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O July/O 2009/O ./O 
Uighur/O unrest/O 
The/O government/O says/O nearly/O 200/O people/O were/O killed/O and/O 1,700/O injured/O in/O the/O 2009/O riots/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -/O China/LOCATION 's/O worst/O ethnic/O violence/O in/O decades/O -/O which/O shattered/O the/O authoritarian/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION 's/O claims/O of/O harmony/O and/O unity/O among/O the/O country/O 's/O dozens/O of/O ethnic/O groups/O ./O 
China/LOCATION threw/O a/O huge/O security/O clampdown/O on/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> after/O the/O violence/O and/O many/O Uighurs/O are/O angry/O over/O the/O arrests/O or/O alleged/O disappearances/O of/O people/O rounded/O up/O across/O the/O region/O in/O the/O aftermath/O ./O 
After/O Monday/O 's/O attack/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Hotan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O Chinese/O censors/O blocked/O searches/O on/O <ORGANIZATION>Sina/PERSON Weibo/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O Twitter-like/O microblogging/O services/O ,/O on/O the/O attack/O ./O 
Search/O results/O for/O the/O Chinese/O renderings/O of/O ``/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> unrest/O ''/O and/O ``/O <U_LOCATION>Hotan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ''/O showed/O a/O page/O that/O said/O ,/O ``/O according/O to/O relevant/O laws/O ,/O regulations/O and/O policies/O ,/O search/O results/O are/O not/O displayed/O ./O ''/O 
Beijing/LOCATION often/O blames/O what/O it/O calls/O violent/O separatist/O groups/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> for/O attacks/O on/O police/O or/O other/O government/O targets/O ,/O saying/O they/O work/O with/O al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION or/O Central/O Asian/O militants/O to/O bring/O about/O an/O independent/O state/O called/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Many/O Uighurs/O ,/O a/O Muslim/O ,/O Turkic-speaking/O people/O native/O to/O the/O region/O ,/O chafe/O under/O rule/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O restrictions/O on/O their/O language/O ,/O culture/O and/O religion/O ./O 
They/O make/O up/O less/O than/O half/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O population/O after/O decades/O of/O immigration/O by/O the/O majority/O Han/O from/O other/O parts/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Author/O :/O Sarah/PERSON Berning/PERSON -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O <ORGANIZATION>AFP/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O 
Editor/O :/O Ziphora/PERSON Robina/PERSON
