The/O latest/O incidents/O of/O deadly/O violence/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> indicate/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policies/O towards/O ethnic/O minorities/O have/O reached/O a/O dead/O end/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>Autonomous/O Region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O more/O than/O four/O times/O larger/O than/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O yet/O it/O has/O only/O 22/O million/O inhabitants/O ./O 
Muslim/O Uighurs/O make/O up/O around/O 45/O percent/O of/O the/O region/O 's/O population/O ./O 
But/O they/O may/O soon/O lose/O their/O majority/O status/O as/O Han/O Chinese/O pour/O into/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O ever-increasing/O numbers/O ./O 
When/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION marched/O into/O the/O territory/O 64/O years/O ago/O ,/O Han/O Chinese/O accounted/O for/O just/O 6/O percent/O of/O its/O population/O ./O 
This/O development/O is/O tied/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O ongoing/O policy/O of/O promoting/O large-scale/O migration/O into/O the/O remote/O and/O under-developed/O Western/O regions/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
Officially/O ,/O the/O policy/O was/O designed/O ,/O among/O other/O things/O ,/O to/O support/O local/O inhabitants/O ./O 
But/O in/O reality/O this/O has/O only/O led/O to/O the/O locals/O feeling/O marginalized/O and/O suppressed/O ,/O especially/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O their/O religious/O practices/O ./O 
Events/O like/O the/O ``/O ethnic-harmony/O education/O month/O ''/O held/O last/O May/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Shanshan/LOCATION County/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> have/O done/O nothing/O to/O change/O this/O ./O 
Last/O June/O 35/O ,/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O clashes/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Shanshan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
A/O suppressed/O minority/O Chinese/O politics/O expert/O Willy/PERSON Lam/PERSON believes/O the/O situation/O wo/O n't/O change/O as/O long/O as/O Beijing/LOCATION does/O n't/O shift/O tack/O ./O 
``/O Police/O and/O plainclothes/O security/O personnel/O maintain/O tight/O surveillance/O over/O most/O monasteries/O and/O mosques/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
The/O personal/O movements/O of/O religious/O leaders/O suspected/O to/O have/O anti-Beijing/O inclinations/O are/O kept/O under/O even/O closer/O scrutiny/O ,/O ''/O Lam/PERSON told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION would/O like/O to/O see/O China/LOCATION 's/O ethnic/O minorities/O live/O in/O harmony/O ./O 
But/O at/O what/O price/O ?/O 
Lam/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O a/O professor/O at/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Hong/ORGANIZATION Kong/ORGANIZATION ,/O added/O that/O ``/O authorities/O in/O many/O Uighur-dominated/O towns/O have/O also/O forbidden/O Muslims/O to/O practice/O Ramadan/O and/O other/O religious/O rites/O ./O 
The/O teaching/O of/O Muslim/O religion/O and/O the/O Uighur/O language/O has/O consistently/O been/O cut/O in/O high/O schools/O and/O universities/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
According/O to/O a/O report/O by/O the/O UK-based/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Economist/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O magazine/O ,/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Turpan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -/O the/O prefecture/O where/O the/O latest/O deadly/O clashes/O took/O place/O -/O the/O authorities/O had/O been/O waging/O a/O campaign/O to/O persuade/O Uighur/O men/O not/O to/O grow/O long/O beards/O and/O women/O not/O to/O wear/O the/O veil/O or/O other/O Islamic/O clothing/O ./O 
Those/O living/O in/O neighborhoods/O where/O all/O residents/O complied/O were/O given/O preferential/O access/O to/O loans/O and/O government-sponsored/O job-training/O schemes/O ,/O the/O report/O stated/O ./O 
Links/O to/O Syrian/O rebels/O ?/O 
But/O the/O Chinese/O government/O does/O n't/O put/O the/O blame/O for/O the/O growing/O tensions/O on/O flawed/O decisions/O taken/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION or/O local/O leaders/O -/O they/O are/O instead/O accusing/O extremist/O separatists/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O state/O newspaper/O ``/O Global/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION ''/O reported/O that/O Uighurs/O had/O traveled/O to/O Syria/LOCATION ,/O where/O they/O were/O ``/O radicalized/O ''/O allegedly/O fighting/O alongside/O Syrian/O rebels/O ./O 
The/O paper/O cited/O a/O Chinese/O anti-terrorism/O official/O who/O said/O that/O around/O 100/O people/O had/O done/O the/O same/O over/O the/O past/O year/O ./O 
In/O a/O separate/O story/O ,/O the/O newspaper/O quoted/O Syria/LOCATION 's/O ambassador/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O Imad/PERSON Moustafa/PERSON ,/O as/O saying/O that/O at/O least/O 30/O members/O of/O the/O militant/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkistan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O which/O seeks/O independence/O for/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O had/O entered/O Syria/LOCATION to/O fight/O government/O forces/O in/O Aleppo/LOCATION ./O 
`/O Not/O purely/O a/O terrorism/O issue/O '/O 
Raffaello/PERSON Pantucci/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O on/O China/LOCATION and/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION at/O the/O Royal/ORGANIZATION United/ORGANIZATION Services/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION -/O a/O London-based/O think/O tank/O -/O told/O the/O Associated/ORGANIZATION Press/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O it/O was/O plausible/O that/O some/O Uighurs/O who/O identify/O with/O radical/O Islamist/O ideology/O might/O participate/O in/O the/O Syrian/O conflict/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O claims/O Uighurs/O have/O traveled/O to/O Syria/LOCATION to/O support/O the/O rebels/O 
``/O That/O there/O are/O Uighurs/O who/O are/O probably/O radicalized/O going/O into/O the/O battlefield/O in/O Syria/LOCATION is/O not/O entirely/O surprising/O ./O 
But/O whether/O this/O is/O an/O organized/O thing/O from/O the/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> movement/O or/O its/O elements/O ,/O it/O 's/O difficult/O to/O know/O ,/O ''/O Pantucci/PERSON said/O ./O 
Terrorism/O expert/O Rohan/PERSON Gunaratna/PERSON told/O the/O AP/ORGANIZATION he/O was/O also/O sceptical/O ,/O since/O the/O Pakistan-based/O movement/O is/O believed/O to/O have/O only/O about/O 100/O members/O and/O support/O from/O a/O few/O hundred/O other/O people/O ./O 
But/O rather/O than/O being/O driven/O purely/O by/O religious/O extremism/O ,/O unrest/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O largely/O fueled/O by/O tensions/O and/O anger/O over/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policies/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O said/O Gunaratna/PERSON ,/O who/O heads/O a/O terrorism/O research/O center/O in/O Singapore/LOCATION ./O 
He/O added/O that/O the/O government/O 's/O hard-line/O approach/O could/O be/O driving/O people/O to/O join/O separatist/O groups/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION has/O to/O address/O this/O not/O only/O as/O a/O pure/O terrorism/O issue/O ,/O but/O more/O as/O an/O inter-ethnic/O ,/O inter-religious/O issue/O ./O ''/O 
A/O new/O approach/O Some/O experts/O say/O there/O are/O signs/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION might/O change/O its/O approach/O towards/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
Lam/PERSON points/O to/O Yu/PERSON Zhengsheng/PERSON ,/O a/O politburo/O member/O in/O charge/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O who/O earlier/O this/O year/O dropped/O hints/O to/O representative/O Tibetan/O figures/O in/O and/O out/O of/O China/LOCATION that/O Beijing/LOCATION might/O consider/O resuming/O long-stalled/O talks/O with/O emissaries/O of/O the/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
`/O We/O will/O fight/O until/O they/O grant/O us/O self-determination/O '/O 
Riots/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O leave/O dozens/O dead/O 
More/O than/O two/O dozen/O people/O have/O died/O in/O clashes/O with/O police/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ./O 
The/O riots/O are/O the/O deadliest/O since/O the/O 2009/O clashes/O between/O Muslims/O and/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O population/O there/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 26.06.2013/O -RRB-/O 
Looking/O back/O at/O `/O China/LOCATION 's/O lost/O decade/O '/O 
But/O many/O are/O pointing/O to/O corruption/O ,/O stagnation/O and/O environmental/O devastation/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 13.03.2013/O -RRB-/O 
Opinion/O :/O `/O China/LOCATION 's/O minorities/O policies/O are/O at/O a/O dead/O end/O '/O 
As/O China/LOCATION gears/O up/O for/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O another/O explosion/O of/O violence/O in/O the/O country/O 's/O west/O shows/O that/O policies/O towards/O minorities/O are/O at/O a/O dead/O end/O ,/O says/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Matthias/PERSON von/PERSON Hein/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O 01.03.2012/O -RRB-/O 
More/O recently/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O allowed/O monks/O in/O several/O monasteries/O to/O openly/O display/O portraits/O of/O the/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> ,/O who/O is/O still/O the/O most/O revered/O leader/O in/O the/O greater/O Tibet/LOCATION region/O ./O 
Jin/PERSON Wei/PERSON ,/O a/O director/O of/O ethnic/O and/O religious/O affairs/O at/O the/O Central/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O seems/O to/O have/O publicly/O broken/O away/O from/O the/O party/O orthodoxy/O on/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
Referring/O to/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ,/O she/O said/O in/O a/O recent/O interview/O with/O the/O Hong/O Kong-based/O magazine/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Asia/O Weekly/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O :/O ``/O We/O can/O not/O just/O simply/O treat/O and/O regard/O him/O as/O an/O enemy/O ./O ''/O 
Doing/O this/O ,/O she/O added/O ,/O would/O trigger/O the/O ire/O of/O people/O who/O simply/O want/O to/O maintain/O their/O culture/O and/O traditions/O ./O 
Jin/PERSON believes/O there/O is/O a/O possibility/O that/O the/O ``/O political/O struggle/O ''/O between/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON might/O evolve/O into/O an/O ethnic/O conflict/O between/O Han/O Chinese/O and/O Tibetans/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION continues/O to/O rely/O on/O an/O intensified/O army/O presence/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Authorities/O also/O are/O offering/O rewards/O of/O up/O to/O $/O 16,300/O for/O information/O on/O terrorist/O activity/O that/O may/O help/O solve/O major/O terror/O crimes/O or/O lead/O to/O the/O arrest/O of/O terror/O suspects/O ./O 
It/O says/O those/O who/O knowingly/O shelter/O ,/O protect/O or/O help/O ``/O violent/O terrorist/O criminals/O ''/O will/O be/O prosecuted/O ./O
