A/O Chinese/O court/O has/O sentenced/O a/O prominent/O Uighur/O scholar/O to/O life/O imprisonment/O on/O charges/O of/O inciting/O ``/O separatism/O ./O ''/O 
His/O detention/O and/O conviction/O have/O sparked/O international/O protest/O ./O 
A/O Chinese/O court/O on/O Tuesday/O handed/O down/O a/O sentence/O of/O life/O imprisonment/O to/O a/O well-known/O scholar/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O Uighur/O minority/O after/O convicting/O him/O of/O inciting/O ``/O separatism/O ./O ''/O 
The/O court/O in/O the/O capital/O of/O the/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O announced/O the/O sentence/O against/O the/O 44-year-old/O scholar/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O after/O a/O two-day/O trial/O last/O week/O ./O 
One/O of/O his/O lawyers/O said/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> would/O appeal/O ,/O although/O such/O actions/O are/O rarely/O successful/O in/O the/O Communist-Party-controlled/O courts/O ./O 
The/O official/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O said/O the/O court/O heard/O that/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ``/O spread/O lessons/O containing/O separatist/O thoughts/O via/O the/O website/O Uygur/O Online/O ./O ''/O 
``/O He/O bewitched/O and/O coerced/O young/O ethnic/O students/O to/O work/O for/O the/O website/O and/O built/O a/O criminal/O syndicate/O according/O to/O the/O ruling/O ,/O ''/O the/O agency/O said/O ./O 
It/O also/O said/O he/O incited/O violence/O ./O 
Rights/O advocate/O 
<U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O former/O university/O professor/O and/O advocate/O for/O minority/O rights/O ,/O was/O arrested/O at/O his/O Beijing/LOCATION apartment/O in/O January/O along/O with/O some/O of/O his/O students/O after/O criticizing/O the/O official/O response/O to/O a/O suicide/O car/O attack/O last/O October/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O which/O authorities/O claimed/O was/O carried/O out/O by/O Uighur/O separatists/O ./O 
He/O himself/O had/O spoken/O out/O against/O independence/O for/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O interviews/O ,/O but/O his/O advocacy/O of/O more/O rights/O for/O Uighurs/O has/O in/O the/O past/O resulted/O in/O his/O frequently/O being/O put/O under/O house/O arrest/O and/O prevented/O from/O leaving/O the/O country/O ./O 
The/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ,/O home/O to/O about/O 10/O million/O members/O of/O the/O mostly/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O ,/O has/O seen/O a/O wave/O of/O deadly/O violence/O over/O the/O last/O year/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION blames/O on/O militant/O separatists/O ./O 
Rights/O groups/O say/O the/O unrest/O has/O been/O fueled/O by/O government/O discrimination/O and/O repression/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O '/O religion/O and/O language/O ./O 
International/O condemnation/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O detention/O in/O January/O provoked/O calls/O for/O his/O release/O from/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O several/O human/O rights/O groups/O ,/O who/O have/O also/O condemned/O Tuesday/O 's/O verdict/O ./O 
A/O researcher/O for/O US-based/O group/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION ,/O Maya/PERSON Wang/PERSON ,/O said/O the/O sentence/O was/O unprecedented/O in/O view/O of/O the/O moderate/O criticism/O expressed/O by/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O calling/O it/O ``/O extremely/O harsh/O ''/O ,/O ``/O unexpected/O ''/O and/O ``/O shocking/O ./O ''/O 
William/PERSON Nee/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION researcher/O at/O human/O rights/O group/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O the/O judgement/O against/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> had/O ``/O no/O basis/O in/O reality/O ./O ''/O 
``/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> worked/O to/O peacefully/O build/O bridges/O between/O ethnic/O communities/O and/O for/O that/O he/O has/O been/O punished/O through/O politically/O motivated/O charges/O ,/O ''/O Nee/PERSON said/O ./O 
Amnesty/ORGANIZATION said/O on/O its/O website/O that/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> had/O been/O tortured/O while/O in/O detention/O ,/O denied/O food/O for/O 10/O days/O and/O tied/O up/O for/O 20/O days/O ./O 
The/O organization/O also/O noted/O a/O number/O of/O legal/O shortcomings/O in/O his/O trial/O ,/O saying/O his/O lawyers/O had/O been/O refused/O access/O to/O evidence/O and/O not/O been/O allowed/O to/O meet/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> for/O six/O months/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O conviction/O comes/O amid/O a/O harsh/O crackdown/O on/O dissidents/O spearheaded/O by/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ./O 
Dozens/O of/O academics/O ,/O journalists/O and/O activists/O have/O been/O detained/O or/O jailed/O ,/O but/O the/O verdict/O against/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> is/O the/O most/O severe/O in/O years/O ./O 
tj/nm/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O dpa/O -RRB-/O
