Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON is/O innocent/O ./O 
His/O sentence/O may/O be/O mild/O by/O Chinese/O standards/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O still/O unjust/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Matthias/PERSON von/PERSON Hein/PERSON calls/O it/O a/O face-saving/O compromise/O to/O ward/O off/O a/O PR/O disaster/O ./O 
There/O is/O widespread/O relief/O following/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON 's/O sentencing/O ./O 
The/O prominent/O human/O rights/O lawyer/O will/O not/O have/O to/O spend/O any/O more/O nights/O in/O jail/O ;/O he/O had/O faced/O a/O possible/O sentence/O of/O eight/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O 
But/O there/O 's/O also/O widespread/O anger/O ./O 
Because/O if/O this/O case/O had/O anything/O to/O do/O with/O justice/O ,/O then/O <PERSON>Pu/O</PERSON> never/O would/O have/O been/O imprisoned/O in/O the/O first/O place/O ./O 
He/O should/O have/O been/O declared/O innocent/O and/O given/O compensation/O for/O the/O 19/O months/O he/O has/O spent/O in/O custody/O ./O 
A/O guilty/O verdict/O combined/O with/O a/O three-year/O suspended/O jail/O sentence/O is/O a/O clear/O attempt/O by/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O to/O save/O face/O while/O ending/O proceedings/O against/O Pu/PERSON ./O 
His/O case/O had/O turned/O into/O a/O veritable/O PR/O disaster/O -/O one/O that/O put/O the/O Chinese/O legal/O system/O in/O a/O very/O bad/O light/O indeed/O ./O 
And/O that/O ,/O in/O turn/O ,/O is/O not/O good/O for/O business/O ./O 
Lawyers/O lead/O a/O dangerous/O life/O 
Since/O the/O 1990s/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O rebuilding/O and/O expanding/O its/O legal/O institutions/O ,/O which/O were/O abolished/O under/O Mao/PERSON ./O 
It/O has/O laws/O ,/O state/O prosecutors/O ,/O judges/O and/O yes/O ,/O lawyers/O ,/O too/O ./O 
But/O lawyers/O live/O dangerously/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O at/O least/O in/O the/O China/LOCATION under/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ./O 
Since/O he/O took/O office/O three/O years/O ago/O ,/O he/O has/O ruthlessly/O cracked/O down/O on/O anything/O and/O anyone/O that/O could/O be/O perceived/O as/O a/O threat/O to/O himself/O ,/O and/O the/O leadership/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION :/O Corrupt/O officials/O and/O political/O opponents/O ,/O civil/O rights/O activists/O ,/O trade/O unionists/O ,/O and/O lawyers/O ,/O too/O ./O 
Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON 's/O arrest/O in/O May/O 2014/O was/O just/O the/O beginning/O of/O a/O massive/O intimidation/O campaign/O ./O 
This/O past/O summer/O alone/O ,/O more/O than/O 200/O lawyers/O were/O arrested/O ;/O around/O 20/O of/O them/O are/O still/O in/O jail/O ./O 
Intimidation/O campaign/O Pu/PERSON 's/O arrest/O was/O also/O meant/O to/O intimidate/O others/O ./O 
The/O message/O :/O If/O a/O national/O hero/O and/O internationally/O recognized/O lawyer/O like/O <PERSON>Pu/O</PERSON> -/O a/O man/O who/O ,/O in/O 2013/O was/O chosen/O by/O a/O Chinese/O weekly/O as/O the/O most/O influential/O person/O working/O in/O the/O area/O of/O civil/O rights/O -/O can/O be/O arrested/O ,/O then/O no/O one/O is/O safe/O from/O the/O whims/O of/O the/O Chinese/O state/O ./O 
The/O members/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION operate/O above/O the/O law/O ./O 
And/O when/O they/O want/O to/O ,/O they/O 'll/O bend/O ,/O shape/O and/O twist/O the/O law/O until/O it/O fits/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O authorities/O usually/O try/O to/O make/O it/O appear/O as/O though/O their/O actions/O are/O constitutional/O ,/O but/O in/O the/O case/O against/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON ,/O it/O did/O n't/O quite/O work/O ./O 
The/O accusations/O were/O absurd/O :/O ``/O Picking/O quarrels/O and/O provoking/O trouble/O ''/O and/O ``/O inciting/O ethnic/O hatred/O ./O ''/O 
The/O state/O prosecution/O tried/O for/O over/O a/O year/O to/O build/O a/O case/O ./O 
In/O the/O end/O ,/O they/O had/O just/O seven/O tweets/O in/O their/O hands/O ,/O chosen/O out/O of/O thousands/O of/O tweets/O posted/O over/O a/O period/O of/O three/O years/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O the/O tweets/O were/O impertinent/O ,/O and/O sometimes/O rather/O coarse/O in/O style/O ./O 
But/O illegal/O ?/O 
One/O of/O them/O poked/O fun/O at/O a/O member/O of/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION who/O ,/O over/O the/O course/O of/O 60/O years/O ,/O had/O not/O once/O voted/O ``/O No/O ''/O on/O anything/O ./O 
Another/O criticized/O China/LOCATION 's/O handling/O of/O a/O train/O accident/O in/O 2011/O ./O 
Another/O in/O part/O blamed/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policies/O on/O minorities/O for/O a/O deadly/O terror/O attack/O by/O extremists/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
But/O nothing/O in/O these/O short/O statements/O in/O any/O way/O justifies/O a/O guilty/O verdict/O for/O <PERSON>Pu/O</PERSON> ./O 
It/O 's/O good/O that/O diplomats/O from/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O Canada/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O US/LOCATION protested/O against/O the/O case/O last/O week/O in/O front/O of/O the/O court/O building/O ./O 
But/O we/O 'll/O never/O know/O what/O role/O that/O may/O have/O played/O in/O his/O relatively/O mild/O sentence/O ./O 
Have/O something/O to/O say/O ?/O 
Add/O your/O comments/O below/O ./O 
The/O thread/O is/O open/O for/O 24/O hours/O from/O posting/O ./O
