Even/O 40/O years/O after/O his/O death/O ,/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Communist/O Party/O of/O China/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> still/O feels/O the/O need/O for/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON to/O maintain/O its/O legitimacy/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> talks/O to/O sinologist/O Felix/PERSON Wemheuer/PERSON about/O the/O leader/O 's/O legacy/O and/O current/O significance/O ./O 
Born/O to/O a/O wealthy/O farmer/O in/O the/O Hunan/LOCATION province/O in/O 1893/O ,/O Mao/PERSON aimed/O to/O transform/O China/LOCATION into/O a/O communist/O state/O and/O succeeded/O in/O achieving/O his/O goal/O 1949/O ,/O when/O he/O declared/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O his/O reign/O of/O China/LOCATION was/O anything/O but/O smooth/O ,/O with/O the/O country/O experiencing/O convulsions/O as/O a/O consequence/O of/O the/O leader/O 's/O ill-conceived/O initiatives/O ,/O which/O have/O led/O to/O the/O deaths/O of/O millions/O of/O people/O ./O 
Still/O ,/O 40/O years/O after/O his/O death/O ,/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON 's/O presence/O remains/O impossible/O to/O escape/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O yet/O difficult/O to/O discuss/O ./O 
His/O corpse/O still/O lies/O in/O state/O in/O the/O center/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O watched/O over/O by/O a/O giant/O portrait/O hanging/O on/O the/O Forbidden/LOCATION City/LOCATION in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ./O 
While/O Mao/PERSON is/O still/O officially/O venerated/O by/O the/O ruling/O CPC/ORGANIZATION as/O the/O founder/O of/O modern/O China/LOCATION ,/O some/O fear/O the/O party/O ,/O in/O a/O bid/O to/O modernize/O its/O image/O ,/O wants/O to/O play/O down/O his/O legacy/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O Mao/PERSON has/O become/O a/O potent/O symbol/O for/O leftists/O within/O and/O without/O the/O ruling/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION who/O feel/O three/O decades/O of/O market-based/O reform/O have/O gone/O too/O far/O ,/O creating/O social/O inequalities/O like/O poverty/O and/O graft/O ./O 
In/O lauding/O Mao/PERSON ,/O they/O sometimes/O seek/O to/O put/O pressure/O on/O the/O current/O leadership/O and/O its/O market-oriented/O policies/O ./O 
In/O a/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> interview/O ,/O China/LOCATION expert/O Felix/PERSON Wemheuer/PERSON explains/O about/O Mao/PERSON 's/O record/O on/O both/O the/O domestic/O and/O foreign/O policy/O fronts/O and/O how/O his/O personality/O cult/O continues/O to/O play/O a/O role/O in/O present-day/O China/LOCATION ./O 
<PERSON>Wemheuer/O</PERSON> :/O The/O CPC/ORGANIZATION believes/O `/O it/O can/O not/O justify/O its/O legitimacy/O without/O Mao/PERSON '/O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> :/O Could/O you/O tell/O us/O about/O Mao/PERSON 's/O journey/O from/O being/O the/O son/O of/O a/O wealthy/O farmer/O to/O the/O head/O of/O communist/O China/LOCATION ?/O 
Felix/PERSON Wemheuer/PERSON :/O We/O have/O to/O go/O back/O to/O the/O period/O immediately/O after/O the/O end/O of/O World/O War/O I/O ./O 
A/O major/O theme/O of/O the/O so-called/O ``/O May/O 4th/O Movement/O ''/O of/O 1919/O was/O the/O question/O of/O how/O to/O make/O China/LOCATION a/O modern/O nation/O while/O fending/O off/O Western/O imperialism/O ./O 
In/O this/O context/O ,/O many/O intellectuals/O turned/O to/O communism/O and/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Treaty/O of/O Versailles/LOCATION and/O the/O disappointment/O caused/O by/O the/O pact/O ,/O which/O transferred/O the/O control/O of/O the/O Shandong/LOCATION region/O -LRB-/O currently/O Shandong/LOCATION Province/LOCATION -RRB-/O to/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O also/O contributed/O to/O the/O development/O ./O 
Mao/PERSON was/O also/O part/O of/O this/O movement/O and/O he/O founded/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O in/O 1921/O ./O 
Initially/O ,/O he/O was/O only/O one/O of/O several/O leaders/O ./O 
But/O his/O successful/O strategy/O ,/O of/O creating/O so-called/O liberated/O areas/O in/O the/O hinterland/O with/O guerilla/O bases/O and/O establishing/O a/O parallel/O state/O later/O propelled/O him/O to/O become/O the/O party/O 's/O sole/O leader/O and/O the/O figurehead/O of/O the/O Chinese/O Communist/O revolution/O ./O 
It/O also/O helped/O him/O establish/O his/O personality/O cult/O and/O image/O as/O a/O person/O who/O developed/O the/O right/O strategy/O to/O implement/O the/O Chinese/O revolution/O ,/O which/O ultimately/O brought/O the/O CPC/ORGANIZATION to/O power/O ./O 
The/O Cultural/O Revolution/O began/O in/O 1966/O when/O Mao/PERSON declared/O a/O class/O war/O 
The/O takeover/O of/O power/O by/O the/O CPC/ORGANIZATION under/O Mao/PERSON 's/O leadership/O was/O followed/O by/O two/O catastrophes/O resulting/O in/O the/O loss/O of/O millions/O of/O lives/O ./O 
How/O do/O you/O view/O these/O disasters/O and/O Mao/PERSON 's/O responsibility/O for/O causing/O them/O ?/O 
The/O two/O catastrophes/O are/O the/O Great/O Leap/O Forward/O -LRB-/O 1958-61/O -RRB-/O and/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O -LRB-/O 1966-76/O -RRB-/O ./O 
The/O Great/O Leap/O Forward/O was/O part/O of/O an/O ill-conceived/O industrialization/O program/O ,/O with/O the/O help/O of/O which/O China/LOCATION wanted/O to/O quickly/O modernize/O and/O catch/O up/O with/O the/O <LOCATION>West/O</LOCATION> ./O 
Mao/PERSON pursued/O this/O goal/O along/O with/O the/O establishment/O of/O a/O communist/O society/O ./O 
But/O it/O failed/O miserably/O and/O ended/O in/O a/O catastrophe/O ./O 
His/O aim/O certainly/O was/O not/O to/O have/O people/O starve/O to/O death/O ,/O although/O after/O the/O famine/O broke/O out/O he/O did/O little/O to/O save/O as/O many/O as/O possible/O ./O 
During/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O days/O ,/O however/O ,/O Mao/PERSON applied/O some/O of/O the/O lessons/O learned/O from/O the/O failure/O of/O the/O Great/O Leap/O Forward/O ,/O thus/O ensuring/O that/O the/O nation/O 's/O economy/O did/O not/O entirely/O collapse/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O small/O economic/O slump/O at/O the/O start/O of/O 1967/O ,/O but/O agriculture/O and/O industry/O remained/O relatively/O stable/O during/O that/O time/O ./O 
Despite/O party/O infighting/O and/O political/O chaos/O ,/O the/O economy/O did/O not/O once/O again/O collapse/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
China/LOCATION 's/O Cultural/O Revolution/O and/O Germany/LOCATION 
When/O Mao/PERSON launched/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O left-wing/O students/O in/O Berlin/LOCATION were/O paying/O attention/O ./O 
Gottfried/PERSON Schmitt/PERSON was/O one/O of/O them/O ./O 
Today/O ,/O he/O takes/O a/O more/O critical/O view/O but/O some/O of/O his/O convictions/O remain/O ./O -LRB-/O 13.05.2016/O -RRB-/O 
Q&A/O :/O What/O was/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O ?/O 
50/O years/O ago/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O leader/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON launched/O a/O socio-political/O movement/O that/O became/O known/O as/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> examines/O the/O movement/O and/O its/O impact/O on/O Chinese/O politics/O and/O society/O ./O -LRB-/O 13.05.2016/O -RRB-/O
China/LOCATION :/O `/O The/O Cultural/O Revolution/O is/O long/O over/O '/O 
State/O media/O has/O broken/O its/O silence/O on/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O following/O reports/O of/O a/O social/O media/O blackout/O ./O 
The/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION has/O rejected/O the/O values/O of/O the/O movement/O ,/O saying/O :/O ``/O There/O is/O no/O place/O for/O it/O in/O today/O 's/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O -LRB-/O 17.05.2016/O -RRB-/O 
Opinion/O :/O China/LOCATION 's/O Cultural/O Revolution/O and/O the/O injustices/O of/O the/O present/O 
Fifty/O years/O after/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON launched/O the/O ``/O Great/O Proletarian/O Cultural/O Revolution/O ,/O ''/O Chinese/O society/O has/O still/O not/O found/O a/O consensus/O on/O how/O to/O judge/O it/O ,/O writes/O Sinologist/O Felix/PERSON Wernheuer/PERSON ./O -LRB-/O 16.05.2016/O -RRB-/O 
The/O paradox/O in/O Mao/PERSON 's/O attitude/O towards/O violence/O is/O that/O at/O the/O start/O of/O each/O of/O his/O big/O campaigns/O ,/O he/O always/O incited/O violence/O against/O landowners/O and/O party/O cadres/O ./O 
But/O at/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O when/O things/O started/O to/O get/O out/O of/O hand/O ,/O he/O was/O the/O only/O one/O who/O could/O stop/O them/O ./O 
That/O led/O many/O victims/O to/O a/O paradoxical/O situation/O where/O they/O could/O only/O be/O saved/O by/O Mao/PERSON ./O 
Even/O Xi/PERSON Zhongxun/PERSON ,/O the/O father/O of/O the/O current/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O was/O one/O of/O the/O victims/O of/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O ./O 
Almost/O all/O members/O of/O the/O current/O leadership/O come/O from/O families/O that/O suffered/O during/O the/O revolution/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O these/O people/O have/O many/O reasons/O to/O say/O Mao/PERSON was/O bad/O ./O 
But/O they/O do/O n't/O do/O that/O because/O the/O party/O is/O still/O of/O the/O view/O that/O it/O can/O not/O justify/O its/O legitimacy/O without/O Mao/PERSON ./O 
How/O do/O you/O see/O Mao/PERSON 's/O record/O on/O the/O foreign/O policy/O front/O ?/O 
Mao/PERSON scored/O his/O most/O lasting/O successes/O in/O foreign/O policy/O ./O 
Although/O the/O nationalist/O Kuomintang/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O KMT/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O government/O was/O recognized/O as/O one/O of/O the/O victors/O of/O World/O War/O II/O and/O accorded/O a/O permanent/O seat/O in/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O KMT/ORGANIZATION remained/O very/O weak/O and/O was/O unable/O to/O control/O either/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> or/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
But/O after/O the/O Communist/O takeover/O in/O 1949/O ,/O China/LOCATION was/O able/O to/O re-establish/O its/O control/O over/O a/O territory/O that/O was/O in/O accordance/O with/O the/O borders/O of/O the/O Qing/O Dynasty/O ./O 
<LOCATION>The/O West/O</LOCATION> initially/O had/O to/O give/O up/O all/O its/O claims/O and/O then/O China/LOCATION was/O able/O to/O assert/O its/O independence/O from/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION 's/O policies/O ./O 
Following/O the/O escalation/O of/O the/O Sino-Soviet/O conflict/O ,/O Mao/PERSON made/O a/O strategic/O pivot/O ,/O normalizing/O relations/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION in/O 1972/O under/O President/O Richard/PERSON Nixon/PERSON ./O 
This/O put/O an/O end/O to/O the/O bipolarity/O of/O the/O Cold/O War/O in/O Asia/LOCATION ,/O where/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O US/LOCATION joined/O hands/O in/O their/O opposition/O against/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O early/O 1960s/O ,/O it/O was/O considered/O outrageous/O in/O the/O world/O communist/O movement/O to/O publicly/O challenge/O the/O Soviet/O leadership/O ./O 
And/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ,/O for/O its/O part/O ,/O tried/O to/O bring/O together/O all/O eastern/O European/O nations/O to/O oppose/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Moscow/LOCATION succeeded/O in/O its/O mission/O ,/O with/O the/O exception/O of/O Albania/LOCATION ,/O but/O China/LOCATION was/O able/O to/O gain/O new/O allies/O ,/O particularly/O in/O Africa/LOCATION ./O 
What/O role/O does/O Mao/PERSON play/O in/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON 's/O China/LOCATION ?/O 
Watch/O video/O 03:01/O 
Share/O The/O Cultural/O Revolution/O ,/O 50/O years/O on/O 
Send/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION Twitter/ORGANIZATION Google/ORGANIZATION +/O <ORGANIZATION>Whatsapp/O</ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION>Tumblr/O</ORGANIZATION> linkedin/O stumble/O <ORGANIZATION>Digg/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> reddit/O <ORGANIZATION>Newsvine/O</ORGANIZATION> Permalink/O http://dw.com/p/1IoQq/O 
The/O Cultural/O Revolution/O ,/O 50/O years/O on/O With/O his/O anti-corruption/O campaign/O ,/O President/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> -/O similar/O to/O Mao/PERSON -/O has/O positioned/O himself/O as/O someone/O who/O is/O above/O the/O party/O ./O 
<PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> presents/O himself/O as/O a/O leader/O who/O -/O in/O the/O interests/O of/O the/O Chinese/O people/O -/O is/O willing/O to/O take/O on/O the/O party/O ruthlessly/O to/O cleanse/O it/O of/O corruption/O ./O 
<PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O pledges/O like/O vowing/O to/O crack/O down/O on/O both/O ``/O tigers/O ''/O and/O ``/O flies/O ''/O were/O also/O a/O page/O taken/O from/O Mao/PERSON 's/O book/O ./O 
In/O general/O ,/O we/O are/O currently/O seeing/O a/O trend/O towards/O strong/O men/O like/O <PERSON>Recip/O</PERSON> Tayyip/PERSON Erdogan/PERSON ,/O Vladimir/PERSON Putin/PERSON and/O Donald/PERSON Trump/PERSON ./O 
And/O it/O is/O somehow/O fitting/O for/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> to/O be/O regarded/O as/O China/LOCATION 's/O strongman/O ./O 
In/O my/O view/O ,/O he/O wants/O to/O cultivate/O a/O Mao-like/O charisma/O without/O actually/O propagating/O Maoist/O content/O ./O 
So/O the/O idea/O of/O class/O struggle/O does/O not/O matter/O at/O all/O ./O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O maintaining/O stability/O and/O continuity/O is/O important/O for/O the/O party/O ./O 
And/O Mao/PERSON is/O viewed/O in/O a/O much/O more/O positive/O light/O now/O than/O ten/O years/O ago/O ./O 
But/O discourse/O over/O his/O legacy/O has/O been/O more/O or/O less/O limited/O ,/O portraying/O Mao/PERSON as/O the/O leader/O who/O built/O a/O strong/O and/O rich/O China/LOCATION that/O was/O able/O to/O assert/O its/O importance/O on/O the/O international/O arena/O ./O 
Felix/PERSON Wemheuer/PERSON is/O Professor/O of/O China-Studies/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Cologne/ORGANIZATION and/O author/O of/O a/O biography/O on/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON ,/O published/O in/O 2009/O ./O
