Ten/O years/O since/O the/O killing/O of/O Baloch/O separatist/O Akbar/PERSON Bugti/PERSON ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION continues/O its/O confrontational/O approach/O with/O the/O leaders/O of/O ethnic/O groups/O ,/O calling/O them/O ``/O traitors/O ./O ''/O 
Experts/O say/O it/O does/O n't/O bode/O well/O for/O the/O country/O ./O 
``/O Do/O n't/O push/O us/O ./O 
It/O is/O not/O the/O 1970s/O when/O you/O can/O hit/O and/O run/O and/O hide/O in/O the/O mountains/O ./O 
This/O time/O you/O wo/O n't/O even/O know/O what/O hit/O you/O ./O ''/O 
Former/O Pakistani/O president/O and/O military/O chief/O Pervez/PERSON Musharraf/PERSON made/O these/O remarks/O in/O 2006/O as/O a/O warning/O to/O Baloch/O separatists/O and/O their/O leader/O Nawab/PERSON Akbar/PERSON Bugti/PERSON ./O 
Soon/O after/O ,/O the/O general/O came/O down/O hard/O on/O the/O separatists/O and/O Bugti/PERSON was/O killed/O in/O a/O military/O operation/O ./O 
Baloch/O nationalists/O claim/O that/O Bugti/PERSON -/O who/O had/O been/O hiding/O in/O a/O mountain/O -/O was/O hit/O by/O a/O military/O rocket/O ,/O an/O accusation/O Musharraf/PERSON and/O the/O country/O 's/O army/O denies/O ./O 
Ten/O years/O after/O Bugti/PERSON 's/O assassination/O ,/O the/O Pakistani/O army/O continues/O to/O target/O rebels/O in/O the/O western/O Balochistan/LOCATION province/O ./O 
Musharraf/PERSON 's/O wish/O that/O the/O <OTHER>Baloch/PERSON</OTHER> separatist/O movement/O would/O die/O with/O Bugti/PERSON 's/O killing/O has/O n't/O come/O true/O yet/O ./O 
On/O the/O contrary/O ,/O the/O Balochistan/LOCATION conflict/O has/O received/O more/O international/O attention/O in/O the/O past/O few/O years/O ./O 
As/O <OTHER>Baloch/PERSON</OTHER> separatists/O commemorate/O Bugti/PERSON 's/O tenth/O death/O anniversary/O on/O Friday/O ,/O August/O 26/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION accuses/O the/O rebels/O of/O receiving/O support/O from/O India/LOCATION ./O 
Recently/O ,/O Indian/O Premier/O Narendra/PERSON Modi/PERSON referred/O to/O Pakistani/O oppression/O in/O the/O Balochistan/LOCATION province/O ./O 
Akbar/PERSON Bugti/PERSON remained/O close/O to/O Islamabd/LOCATION until/O the/O military/O operation/O in/O 2005/O Decades-long/O insurgency/O Balochistan/LOCATION ,/O which/O borders/O Iran/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O remains/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O poorest/O and/O least/O populous/O province/O despite/O a/O number/O of/O development/O projects/O Islamabad/LOCATION has/O initiated/O there/O in/O the/O past/O ./O 
Rebel/O groups/O have/O waged/O a/O separatist/O insurgency/O in/O the/O province/O for/O decades/O ,/O complaining/O that/O the/O central/O government/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION and/O the/O richer/O Punjab/LOCATION province/O unfairly/O exploit/O their/O resources/O ./O 
Islamabad/LOCATION reacted/O to/O the/O insurgency/O by/O launching/O a/O military/O operation/O in/O the/O province/O in/O 2005/O ./O 
The/O armed/O struggle/O for/O <OTHER>Baloch/PERSON</OTHER> independence/O intensified/O after/O Bugti/PERSON 's/O killing/O in/O 2006/O ./O 
Rebel/O <OTHER>Baloch/PERSON</OTHER> groups/O like/O the/O Balochistan/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION have/O repeatedly/O attacked/O security/O forces/O and/O state/O installations/O ./O 
Most/O of/O the/O rebel/O leadership/O is/O thought/O to/O be/O abroad/O in/O the/O UK/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Dubai/LOCATION ./O 
Local/O rights/O groups/O have/O the/O details/O of/O thousands/O of/O people/O who/O they/O say/O have/O disappeared/O over/O the/O past/O ten/O years/O and/O have/O not/O been/O seen/O since/O ./O 
Pakistani/O security/O agencies/O claim/O these/O people/O were/O arrested/O on/O terrorism/O charges/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O whereabouts/O of/O these/O people/O are/O kept/O secret/O from/O the/O public/O ;/O they/O have/O not/O been/O presented/O to/O local/O courts/O for/O a/O proper/O trial/O ./O 
Exploitation/O of/O economic/O resources/O ?/O 
Last/O year/O ,/O China/LOCATION announced/O an/O economic/O project/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION worth/O $/O 46/O billion/O -LRB-/O about/O 41/O billion/O euro/O -RRB-/O ./O 
With/O the/O <U_LOCATION>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION aims/O to/O expand/O its/O influence/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O across/O <LOCATION>Central/O</LOCATION> and/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION in/O order/O to/O counter/O US/LOCATION and/O Indian/O influence/O ./O 
The/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> would/O link/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O southern/O Gwadar/LOCATION port/O on/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION to/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ./O 
It/O also/O includes/O plans/O to/O create/O road/O ,/O rail/O and/O oil/O pipeline/O links/O to/O improve/O connectivity/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Why/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O army/O is/O targeting/O the/O MQM/ORGANIZATION party/O 
Expert/O Arif/PERSON Jamal/PERSON talks/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> about/O a/O paramilitary/O operation/O against/O the/O MQM/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O liberal/O political/O party/O in/O southern/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O how/O the/O army/O is/O allowing/O an/O Islamist/O takeover/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O economic/O hub/O ,/O Karachi/LOCATION ./O -LRB-/O 23.08.2016/O -RRB-/O 
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Balochistan/LOCATION violence/O as/O deplorable/O as/O Kashmir/LOCATION killings/O ?/O 
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O <OTHER>Baloch/PERSON</OTHER> activists/O accuse/O Islamabad/LOCATION of/O committing/O rights/O abuses/O in/O their/O province/O ./O 
In/O recently/O held/O rallies/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O they/O complained/O that/O while/O Kashmir/LOCATION continues/O to/O dominate/O news/O ,/O their/O plight/O is/O ignored/O ./O -LRB-/O 01.08.2016/O -RRB-/O 
Gwadar/LOCATION --/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O impoverished/O colony/O or/O an/O economic/O hub/O ?/O 
Despite/O much-vaunted/O Chinese-Pakistani/O development/O projects/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Gwadar/LOCATION city/O ,/O the/O locals/O still/O have/O no/O access/O to/O clean/O water/O ./O 
And/O separatists/O have/O vowed/O to/O resist/O what/O they/O say/O is/O Sino-Pakistani/O colonization/O ./O -LRB-/O 14.04.2016/O -RRB-/O 
Pakistan/LOCATION is/O grappling/O with/O an/O acute/O economic/O crisis/O ./O 
Experts/O say/O the/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> can/O certainly/O stir/O the/O much-needed/O economic/O activity/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
But/O the/O much-vaunted/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> has/O not/O impressed/O residents/O of/O Gwadar/LOCATION and/O Balochistan/LOCATION who/O believe/O they/O should/O be/O the/O main/O stakeholders/O of/O development/O projects/O in/O their/O port/O city/O ./O 
``/O Just/O look/O at/O the/O condition/O of/O our/O roads/O ,/O our/O homes/O and/O towns/O ;/O we/O still/O lack/O basic/O necessities/O of/O life/O ,/O ''/O Farhad/PERSON Baloch/PERSON ,/O a/O Gwadar/LOCATION resident/O ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
``/O Even/O drinking/O water/O is/O a/O rare/O commodity/O in/O the/O area/O ./O 
We/O are/O facing/O a/O drought-like/O situation/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
K./PERSON B./PERSON Firaq/PERSON ,/O president/O of/O the/O Gwadar/ORGANIZATION Educational/ORGANIZATION Welfare/ORGANIZATION Society/ORGANIZATION ,/O complains/O that/O the/O locals/O are/O being/O driven/O out/O of/O the/O city/O 's/O port/O area/O to/O make/O way/O for/O Chinese/O workers/O and/O engineers/O ./O 
``/O The/O Gwadar/LOCATION fishermen/O are/O not/O allowed/O near/O the/O port/O boundaries/O ./O 
Thousands/O of/O fishermen/O have/O been/O asked/O to/O leave/O the/O harbor/O ,/O ''/O Firaq/PERSON claimed/O ./O 
Senator/O Mushahid/PERSON Ullah/PERSON Khan/PERSON ,/O leader/O of/O the/O ruling/O Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Muslim/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION party/O ,/O admits/O that/O the/O people/O of/O Balochistan/LOCATION are/O unhappy/O with/O some/O of/O the/O government/O 's/O policies/O ,/O but/O he/O denies/O that/O Islamabad/LOCATION is/O usurping/O the/O province/O 's/O economic/O resources/O ./O 
``/O Prime/O Minister/O Nawaz/PERSON Sharif/PERSON 's/O government/O allowed/O a/O <OTHER>Baloch/PERSON</OTHER> nationalist/O to/O become/O the/O chief/O minister/O of/O the/O province/O ./O 
Our/O administration/O has/O also/O launched/O a/O number/O of/O development/O projects/O for/O the/O benefit/O of/O the/O locals/O ,/O ''/O Senator/O Khan/PERSON told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
But/O nationalist/O leader/O Abdul/PERSON Hai/PERSON Baloch/PERSON is/O skeptical/O about/O the/O government/O 's/O claims/O ,/O as/O he/O says/O the/O issue/O is/O more/O political/O than/O economic/O ./O 
He/O believes/O the/O Gwadar/LOCATION residents/O resent/O the/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> project/O because/O they/O fear/O that/O with/O the/O arrival/O of/O workers/O from/O China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O other/O provinces/O ,/O they/O will/O soon/O become/O a/O minority/O in/O their/O own/O town/O ./O 
Dr./O Abdul/PERSON Aziz/PERSON ,/O a/O Gwadar/LOCATION resident/O ,/O echoes/O Hai/PERSON Baloch/PERSON 's/O sentiments/O ./O 
``/O Our/O resources/O are/O being/O plundered/O ,/O and/O we/O are/O being/O deprived/O of/O our/O livelihood/O ./O 
Many/O people/O had/O to/O move/O to/O remote/O areas/O after/O the/O government/O started/O the/O construction/O work/O on/O Gwadar/LOCATION port/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O non-locals/O were/O already/O buying/O land/O in/O the/O city/O ./O 
``/O More/O dislocations/O are/O on/O the/O horizon/O ./O ''/O 
``/O We/O should/O be/O the/O masters/O of/O our/O resources/O ,/O but/O we/O are/O being/O treated/O like/O slaves/O ./O 
This/O will/O have/O catastrophic/O consequences/O ,/O ''/O he/O continued/O ./O 
Rights/O groups/O accuse/O the/O military/O of/O committing/O grave/O human/O rights/O abuses/O in/O Balochistan/LOCATION 
Last/O year/O ,/O in/O an/O interview/O with/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O Brahamdagh/PERSON Bugti/PERSON ,/O leader/O of/O the/O Baloch/ORGANIZATION Republican/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION living/O in/O exile/O in/O Switzerland/LOCATION ,/O and/O grandson/O of/O slain/O nationalist/O leader/O Nawab/PERSON Akbar/PERSON Bugti/PERSON ,/O criticized/O Islamabad/LOCATION 's/O development/O policies/O for/O Balochistan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O None/O of/O the/O previous/O development/O projects/O in/O Balochistan/LOCATION have/O ever/O been/O beneficial/O to/O the/O province/O or/O its/O people/O ,/O ''/O Bugti/PERSON told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
``/O We/O have/O been/O complaining/O for/O decades/O that/O Islamabad/LOCATION has/O never/O sought/O the/O consent/O of/O the/O Baloch/O people/O before/O initiating/O these/O projects/O ./O 
It/O is/O quite/O obvious/O that/O they/O are/O not/O launched/O to/O boost/O the/O province/O 's/O economy/O or/O to/O help/O people/O out/O of/O poverty/O ./O 
They/O are/O started/O for/O the/O benefit/O of/O the/O rulers/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
New/O `/O traitors/O '/O 
Ten/O years/O ago/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION declared/O Akbar/PERSON Bugti/PERSON a/O ``/O terrorist/O ''/O and/O a/O ``/O traitor/O ./O ''/O 
Experts/O say/O that/O a/O majority/O of/O Baloch/PERSON leaders/O are/O still/O not/O trusted/O by/O the/O army/O and/O the/O politicians/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O the/O central/O government/O and/O the/O military/O are/O bent/O on/O pushing/O more/O nationalist/O leaders/O against/O the/O wall/O ,/O analysts/O say/O ./O 
Recently/O ,/O the/O Muttahida/ORGANIZATION Qaumi/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O MQM/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O a/O southern/O Sindh/O province-based/O political/O party/O ,/O came/O under/O direct/O conflict/O with/O the/O Pakistani/O authorities/O when/O its/O exiled/O leader/O Altaf/PERSON Hussain/PERSON criticized/O the/O army/O and/O government/O officials/O of/O systematically/O targeting/O his/O workers/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O accuse/O MQM/ORGANIZATION and/O its/O leader/O Hussain/PERSON of/O racketeering/O ,/O abductions/O ,/O torture/O and/O murder/O Hussain/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O been/O living/O in/O self-imposed/O exile/O since/O the/O early/O 1990s/O ,/O also/O called/O Pakistan/LOCATION ``/O the/O epicenter/O of/O terrorism/O ./O ''/O 
The/O politician/O warned/O the/O authorities/O that/O his/O followers/O would/O choose/O not/O to/O be/O loyal/O to/O the/O country/O if/O the/O ``/O extrajudicial/O killings/O ''/O of/O his/O activists/O continued/O ./O 
Like/O Baloch/O leader/O Akbar/PERSON Bugti/PERSON ,/O Hussain/PERSON has/O so/O far/O chosen/O to/O remain/O close/O to/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O but/O the/O government/O 's/O actions/O against/O him/O are/O forcing/O him/O to/O turn/O against/O the/O state/O ./O 
Some/O analysts/O say/O that/O instead/O of/O resolving/O the/O conflicts/O and/O paying/O attention/O to/O the/O grievances/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O smaller/O provinces/O and/O ethnic/O groups/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION continues/O to/O use/O force/O against/O them/O ,/O which/O shows/O that/O the/O military/O and/O the/O civilian/O establishment/O have/O n't/O learnt/O much/O from/O their/O past/O mistakes/O ./O 
It/O is/O the/O same/O ``/O you/O wo/O n't/O even/O know/O what/O hit/O you/O ''/O paradigm/O all/O over/O again/O ./O 
Additional/O reporting/O by/O Sattar/PERSON Khan/PERSON ,/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Islamabad/LOCATION correspondent/O ./O
