Closer/O economic/O ties/O will/O top/O the/O agenda/O during/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON 's/O visits/O to/O Egypt/LOCATION ,/O Iran/LOCATION and/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION this/O week/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Chinese/O mediation/O in/O the/O feud/O between/O Tehran/LOCATION and/O Riyadh/LOCATION is/O unlikely/O ,/O say/O experts/O ./O 
President/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> is/O visiting/O the/O three/O Middle/O Eastern/O countries/O from/O January/O 19/O to/O 24/O ,/O said/O China/LOCATION 's/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O trip/O -/O the/O first/O by/O a/O Chinese/O head/O of/O state/O to/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION since/O 2009/O ,/O to/O Egypt/LOCATION since/O 2004/O ,/O and/O to/O Iran/LOCATION since/O 2002/O -/O comes/O just/O days/O after/O international/O sanctions/O on/O Iran/LOCATION were/O lifted/O following/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION nuclear/O agency/O 's/O announcement/O that/O Tehran/LOCATION had/O scaled/O back/O its/O nuclear/O program/O ./O 
But/O the/O three-nation/O tour/O also/O comes/O amid/O an/O intensifying/O rivalry/O between/O Tehran/LOCATION and/O Riyadh/LOCATION following/O Sunni-majority/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION 's/O execution/O in/O early/O January/O of/O Shiite/O cleric/O Nimr/PERSON al-Nimr/PERSON ,/O which/O prompted/O outrage/O among/O Shiites/O ./O 
After/O Iranian/O protesters/O responded/O by/O storming/O Saudi/O diplomatic/O facilities/O in/O the/O country/O ,/O Riyadh/LOCATION severed/O relations/O with/O Tehran/LOCATION ,/O which/O ,/O in/O turn/O ,/O cut/O all/O commercial/O ties/O with/O Riyadh/LOCATION ./O 
In/O light/O of/O the/O growing/O regional/O tensions/O ,/O Chinese/O Vice/O Foreign/O Minister/O Zhang/PERSON Ming/PERSON recently/O told/O reporters/O China/LOCATION would/O not/O be/O taking/O sides/O ./O 
``/O Regarding/O some/O of/O the/O region/O 's/O problems/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O always/O taken/O a/O balanced/O and/O just/O position/O ,/O ''/O Zhang/PERSON was/O quoted/O as/O saying/O ./O 
A/O few/O days/O later/O ,/O Zhang/PERSON added/O the/O Chinese/O have/O maintained/O thorough/O communication/O with/O countries/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION through/O various/O channels/O ``/O in/O a/O bid/O to/O ease/O regional/O tensions/O ./O ''/O 
A/O diplomatic/O push/O ?/O 
The/O overlap/O of/O President/O Xi/PERSON 's/O visit/O with/O the/O deterioration/O of/O Iranian-Saudi/O relations/O has/O prompted/O speculation/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O trying/O to/O promote/O itself/O as/O a/O potential/O mediator/O ./O 
But/O analysts/O such/O as/O Flynt/PERSON Leverett/PERSON ,/O a/O professor/O of/O international/O affairs/O at/O Penn/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O believes/O such/O speculation/O is/O ``/O overblown/O ''/O given/O that/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O trip/O has/O been/O in/O the/O works/O for/O well/O over/O a/O year/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O
China/LOCATION seeking/O to/O link/O Iran/LOCATION to/O its/O <U_LOCATION>New/LOCATION Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 
Iran/LOCATION is/O arguably/O one/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O closest/O partners/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
And/O with/O economic/O sanctions/O on/O Tehran/LOCATION set/O to/O be/O eased/O ,/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> examines/O China/LOCATION 's/O latest/O proposal/O to/O integrate/O Iran/LOCATION into/O its/O <U_LOCATION>New/O Silk/O Road/O</U_LOCATION> Initiative/O ./O -LRB-/O 15.12.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Diplomatic/O tensions/O worsen/O over/O Saudi-Iran/O row/O 
The/O UAE/LOCATION ,/O Bahrain/LOCATION and/O Sudan/LOCATION have/O joined/O Riyadh/LOCATION in/O cutting/O ties/O with/O Iran/LOCATION over/O the/O ransacking/O of/O the/O Saudi/O embassy/O in/O Tehran/LOCATION ./O 
Violence/O flared/O after/O the/O execution/O in/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION of/O Shiite/O cleric/O Nimr/PERSON al-Nimr/PERSON ./O -LRB-/O 04.01.2016/O -RRB-/O 
Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON defends/O national/O sovereignty/O online/O 
According/O to/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O every/O country/O should/O have/O independent/O control/O over/O its/O own/O Internet/O ./O 
But/O rights/O groups/O have/O said/O China/LOCATION is/O only/O trying/O to/O justify/O its/O own/O efforts/O to/O enforce/O authority/O online/O ./O -LRB-/O 16.12.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Is/O an/O oil/O policy/O change/O in/O the/O pipeline/O ?/O 
Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION could/O suggest/O a/O coordinated/O cut/O in/O oil/O production/O as/O delegates/O of/O oil-exporting/O countries/O meet/O in/O Vienna/LOCATION ./O 
The/O move/O would/O be/O a/O departure/O from/O current/O OPEC/ORGANIZATION policy/O amid/O a/O global/O supply/O glut/O ./O -LRB-/O 03.12.2015/O -RRB-/O 
``/O Once/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> will/O undoubtedly/O affirm/O ,/O at/O the/O highest/O levels/O ,/O the/O message/O that/O both/O sides/O should/O show/O restraint/O and/O work/O to/O deescalate/O bilateral/O tensions/O ./O 
Beyond/O this/O ,/O though/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O unlikely/O to/O seek/O an/O ongoing/O diplomatic/O role/O for/O itself/O ,/O ''/O Leverett/PERSON told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Zhiqun/PERSON Zhu/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>The/O</ORGANIZATION> China/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION at/O Bucknell/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O agrees/O ./O 
The/O expert/O points/O out/O that/O China/LOCATION 's/O primary/O interests/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION are/O economic/O and/O strategic/O ,/O and/O that/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O visit/O is/O therefore/O not/O intended/O to/O resolve/O the/O regional/O dispute/O ./O 
``/O President/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> is/O likely/O to/O emphasize/O China/LOCATION 's/O policy/O that/O disputes/O need/O to/O be/O resolved/O peacefully/O through/O dialogue/O ./O 
However/O ,/O anyone/O hoping/O that/O China/LOCATION will/O serve/O as/O an/O honest/O broker/O to/O bring/O the/O disputants/O together/O will/O be/O disappointed/O ,/O ''/O he/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
This/O view/O is/O shared/O by/O Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON ,/O a/O fellow/O with/O the/O Asia/LOCATION program/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>German/O</ORGANIZATION> Marshall/ORGANIZATION Fund/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
The/O expert/O in/O Chinese/O foreign/O policy/O argues/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION would/O have/O preferred/O not/O to/O be/O visiting/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION and/O Iran/LOCATION on/O the/O same/O itinerary/O ./O 
``/O But/O it/O would/O have/O been/O even/O more/O problematic/O in/O the/O present/O circumstances/O to/O visit/O one/O country/O without/O the/O other/O ,/O so/O the/O Chinese/O have/O bitten/O the/O bullet/O and/O gone/O ahead/O with/O this/O `/O paired/O '/O trip/O ,/O ''/O the/O expert/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Nonetheless/O ,/O <PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> added/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O still/O cautious/O about/O taking/O on/O a/O serious/O political/O role/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O and/O this/O is/O ``/O neither/O a/O situation/O where/O the/O two/O parties/O involved/O in/O the/O feud/O are/O soliciting/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O help/O as/O a/O broker/O ,/O nor/O one/O where/O it/O has/O much/O leverage/O to/O do/O so/O either/O ./O ''/O 
The/O regional/O rivalry/O is/O also/O believed/O to/O be/O one/O of/O the/O main/O reasons/O why/O it/O has/O taken/O so/O long/O for/O a/O Chinese/O president/O to/O visit/O these/O three/O countries/O -/O all/O of/O which/O are/O founding/O members/O of/O the/O China-led/O Asian/ORGANIZATION Infrastructure/ORGANIZATION Investment/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AIIB/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION has/O thus/O far/O been/O the/O missing/O region/O from/O President/O Xi/PERSON 's/O global/O diplomacy/O push/O ,/O with/O visits/O to/O all/O three/O countries/O having/O been/O postponed/O since/O last/O year/O ./O 
A/O window/O of/O opportunity/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> was/O expected/O to/O visit/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION and/O Egypt/LOCATION last/O spring/O ,/O with/O Iran/LOCATION to/O follow/O on/O a/O subsequent/O trip/O ,/O but/O the/O timing/O coincided/O with/O the/O Saudis/O launching/O their/O military/O campaign/O in/O Yemen/LOCATION ,/O so/O the/O trip/O was/O postponed/O ./O 
China/LOCATION imports/O on/O average/O one/O million/O barrels/O of/O crude/O per/O day/O from/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION 
``/O The/O delays/O have/O become/O a/O political/O point/O of/O sensitivity/O ,/O particularly/O with/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O which/O has/O been/O actively/O soliciting/O a/O visit/O for/O some/O time/O ./O 
But/O there/O were/O additional/O reasons/O for/O holding/O off/O ,/O as/O China/LOCATION waited/O for/O the/O nuclear/O deal/O to/O come/O into/O effect/O ,/O ''/O said/O <PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> ,/O adding/O that/O the/O fact/O that/O it/O has/O taken/O so/O long/O into/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O term/O to/O embark/O on/O such/O a/O trip/O is/O indicative/O of/O how/O ``/O politically/O challenging/O ''/O the/O region/O is/O for/O the/O Chinese/O leadership/O ./O 
It/O therefore/O seems/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O still/O treading/O carefully/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O at/O five/O days/O ,/O the/O tour/O will/O be/O a/O relatively/O short/O one/O -/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> spent/O almost/O as/O much/O time/O in/O the/O UK/LOCATION alone/O as/O he/O 's/O spending/O in/O these/O three/O countries/O combined/O ./O 
``/O President/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> is/O more/O about/O conflict/O avoidance/O than/O outright/O mediation/O ,/O and/O he/O 's/O is/O traveling/O to/O both/O Iran/LOCATION and/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION to/O maintain/O a/O balance/O ./O 
So/O the/O decision/O to/O go/O now/O is/O probably/O because/O this/O is/O a/O window/O of/O opportunity/O before/O things/O get/O worse/O ,/O ''/O Michal/PERSON Meidan/PERSON ,/O a/O China/LOCATION expert/O at/O UK-based/O think/O tank/O Chatham/ORGANIZATION House/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Not/O just/O oil/O 
And/O with/O Iran/LOCATION poised/O to/O open/O to/O the/O world/O again/O ,/O many/O argue/O there/O is/O also/O an/O imperative/O for/O the/O Chinese/O to/O take/O steps/O to/O consolidate/O their/O ties/O with/O the/O region/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O some/O of/O the/O areas/O where/O China/LOCATION wants/O to/O boost/O cooperation/O with/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION range/O from/O satellite/O technology/O to/O renewable/O energy/O and/O nuclear/O technology/O ./O 
Since/O the/O 1990s/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O cultivated/O both/O Iran/LOCATION and/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION as/O two/O of/O its/O most/O important/O oil/O suppliers/O ./O 
The/O growth/O of/O those/O links/O has/O also/O spurred/O broader/O expansion/O of/O economic/O ties/O ,/O with/O China/LOCATION becoming/O a/O leading/O source/O of/O exports/O and/O investment/O for/O both/O Iran/LOCATION and/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O as/O Professor/O Leverett/PERSON points/O out/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O come/O to/O appreciate/O the/O need/O for/O an/O at/O least/O minimally/O balanced/O distribution/O of/O power/O in/O the/O Persian/LOCATION Gulf/LOCATION in/O order/O to/O ``/O forestall/O open-ended/O American/O hegemony/O ''/O and/O prevent/O Washington/LOCATION from/O using/O the/O region/O 's/O hydrocarbons/O as/O leverage/O against/O China/LOCATION ./O 
``/O This/O makes/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O in/O particular/O ,/O increasingly/O critical/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O strategic/O calculations/O ,/O ''/O said/O Leverett/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O also/O author/O of/O ``/O Going/O to/O Tehran/LOCATION :/O Why/O <LOCATION>America/O</LOCATION> Must/O Accept/O the/O Islamic/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION Iran/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O analysts/O such/O as/O <PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> believe/O Beijing/LOCATION will/O try/O to/O move/O quickly/O to/O become/O one/O of/O the/O first/O nations/O to/O take/O full/O advantage/O of/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O opening/O -/O a/O development/O China/LOCATION 's/O state-run/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION already/O hinted/O at/O ./O 
Iran/LOCATION is/O one/O of/O the/O main/O locations/O where/O the/O continental/O transit/O routes/O for/O China/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>One/O Belt/O ,/O One/LOCATION Road/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> initiative/O converge/O ``/O <LOCATION>China/O</LOCATION> -/O <LOCATION>Iran/O</LOCATION> relations/O are/O facing/O important/O opportunities/O as/O interactions/O between/O Iran/LOCATION and/O the/O international/O community/O have/O grown/O markedly/O since/O the/O sealing/O of/O a/O comprehensive/O deal/O on/O the/O Iranian/O nuclear/O issue/O in/O 2015/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O side/O will/O work/O with/O Iran/LOCATION to/O turn/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O visit/O into/O a/O milestone/O in/O the/O development/O of/O bilateral/O ties/O ./O ''/O 
China/LOCATION expert/O Meidan/PERSON explains/O that/O the/O timing/O of/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O visit/O -/O following/O the/O lifting/O of/O international/O sanctions/O -/O is/O indeed/O fortunate/O ,/O and/O that/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> will/O come/O with/O a/O big/O business/O delegation/O as/O companies/O hope/O to/O gain/O or/O expand/O market/O share/O in/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
In/O this/O context/O ,/O Rajiv/PERSON Biswas/PERSON ,/O Asia-Pacific/O Chief/O Economist/O at/O the/O analytics/O firm/O IHS/ORGANIZATION ,/O points/O out/O that/O ``/O if/O there/O is/O a/O strong/O Iranian/O economic/O recovery/O now/O that/O sanctions/O have/O been/O lifted/O ,/O this/O could/O create/O a/O fast-growing/O market/O for/O Chinese/O manufactures/O in/O a/O wide/O range/O of/O sectors/O ,/O such/O as/O automobiles/O ,/O power/O infrastructure/O as/O well/O as/O consumer/O goods/O ./O ''/O 
Iran/LOCATION and/O <U_LOCATION>OBOR/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> 
Iran/ORGANIZATION 's/O importance/O also/O stems/O from/O its/O key/O position/O on/O China/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>One/LOCATION Belt/LOCATION ,/O One/LOCATION Road/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>OBOR/O</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O initiative/O ,/O given/O that/O it/O is/O one/O of/O the/O main/O locations/O where/O the/O continental/O transit/O routes/O and/O the/O maritime/O routes/O converge/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O Iran/LOCATION is/O among/O a/O handful/O of/O countries/O in/O the/O <U_LOCATION>OBOR/O</U_LOCATION> scheme/O -/O a/O major/O avenue/O through/O which/O China/LOCATION is/O seeking/O to/O diversify/O its/O energy/O supplies/O -/O and/O one/O of/O the/O few/O countries/O in/O the/O region/O where/O ,/O according/O to/O analyst/O <PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> ,/O Chinese/O military/O and/O intelligence/O services/O have/O a/O relationship/O that/O is/O n't/O ``/O overshadowed/O by/O their/O counterparts/O '/O ties/O with/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O infrastructure/O projects/O and/O Chinese/O investment/O will/O be/O a/O major/O focus/O during/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O visit/O ./O 
And/O one/O of/O the/O things/O to/O watch/O will/O be/O how/O big/O a/O package/O Beijing/LOCATION will/O be/O able/O to/O announce/O with/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O which/O should/O ,/O in/O theory/O ,/O be/O one/O of/O the/O countries/O where/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O able/O to/O step/O in/O on/O a/O very/O large/O scale/O with/O new/O investments/O ./O 
This/O is/O why/O analysts/O reckon/O there/O will/O probably/O be/O more/O concrete/O ``/O deliverables/O ''/O from/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O visit/O to/O Tehran/LOCATION than/O from/O his/O stop/O in/O Riyadh/LOCATION ./O 
Many/O are/O keen/O to/O see/O whether/O an/O agreement/O is/O reached/O on/O the/O development/O of/O a/O high-speed/O rail/O link/O between/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O China/LOCATION and/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O capital/O city/O of/O Tehran/LOCATION ./O 
But/O as/O analyst/O<PERSON> Small/O</PERSON> points/O out/O ,/O Iran/LOCATION also/O knows/O that/O it/O will/O have/O other/O suitors/O in/O the/O coming/O period/O and/O does/O n't/O want/O to/O cast/O its/O lot/O in/O too/O far/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Many/O are/O keen/O to/O see/O whether/O a/O deal/O is/O reached/O on/O the/O development/O of/O a/O high-speed/O rail/O link/O between/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O Tehran/LOCATION In/O this/O context/O ,/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O balancing/O act/O will/O involve/O not/O upsetting/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION while/O he/O seeks/O to/O deepen/O ties/O with/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
During/O his/O visit/O to/O Riyadh/LOCATION ,/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> is/O set/O to/O hold/O talks/O with/O the/O <OTHER>Saudi/LOCATION King/LOCATION</OTHER> to/O discuss/O lifting/O bilateral/O ties/O to/O a/O comprehensive/O strategic/O partnership/O ./O 
<PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> will/O also/O hold/O separate/O meetings/O with/O the/O Gulf/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O GCC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O and/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Organization/O of/O the/O Islamic/O Cooperation/O</ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O OIC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O 
The/O two/O sides/O will/O exchange/O views/O on/O promoting/O China/LOCATION 's/O cooperation/O with/O the/O GCC/ORGANIZATION and/O Islamic/O nations/O ,/O according/O to/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Riyadh/LOCATION plays/O a/O key/O role/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O energy/O security/O strategy/O as/O a/O source/O of/O oil/O supply/O ,/O with/O Chinese/O imports/O of/O Saudi/O crude/O averaging/O around/O one/O million/O barrels/O per/O day/O during/O the/O first/O 11/O months/O of/O 2015/O ./O 
``/O With/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION being/O the/O largest/O global/O supplier/O of/O oil/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O long-term/O bilateral/O relationship/O remains/O very/O important/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O long-term/O energy/O security/O ,/O ''/O said/O economist/O Biswas/PERSON ./O 
As/O for/O Egypt/LOCATION ,/O the/O country/O is/O one/O of/O the/O crucial/O focal/O points/O of/O Chinese/O diplomacy/O in/O the/O Arab/O world/O ./O 
With/O the/O 60th/O anniversary/O of/O diplomatic/O relations/O ,/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O visit/O to/O Cairo/LOCATION will/O also/O be/O a/O celebratory/O one/O ./O 
And/O given/O that/O Cairo/LOCATION is/O also/O notably/O enthusiastic/O about/O <U_LOCATION>OBOR/O</U_LOCATION> ,/O experts/O believe/O some/O announcements/O will/O be/O made/O in/O this/O regard/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O worried/O about/O radicalization/O of/O the/O Muslim/O Uighur/O people/O who/O live/O in/O the/O far/O western/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 
It/O is/O therefore/O economic/O gains/O which/O will/O be/O the/O chief/O outcome/O of/O the/O trip/O ,/O as/O analyst/O Zhiqun/PERSON Zhu/PERSON stressed/O ./O 
``/O Having/O friendly/O relations/O with/O countries/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION is/O crucial/O for/O the/O success/O of/O <U_LOCATION>OBOR/O</U_LOCATION> ./O 
So/O cooperation/O will/O be/O the/O main/O theme/O of/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O visit/O ./O ''/O 
Security/O concerns/O Last/O but/O not/O least/O ,/O the/O ongoing/O crisis/O in/O Syria/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION 's/O counter-terrorism/O efforts/O are/O two/O issues/O which/O are/O also/O likely/O to/O feature/O high/O on/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> 's/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION agenda/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O worried/O about/O radicalization/O of/O the/O Muslim/O Uighur/O people/O who/O live/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O far/O western/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O and/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O looking/O to/O work/O more/O closely/O with/O the/O countries/O that/O have/O influence/O over/O the/O situation/O on/O the/O ground/O ./O 
``/O While/O tacitly/O supporting/O the/O military/O strikes/O on/O `/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION ,/O '/O China/LOCATION believes/O that/O progress/O there/O will/O require/O a/O political/O settlement/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ,/O and/O will/O be/O encouraging/O the/O Saudis/O and/O Iranians/O to/O help/O facilitate/O that/O ,/O ''/O said/O <PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> ./O
