Millions/O of/O Falun/ORGANIZATION Gong/ORGANIZATION members/O are/O victims/O of/O relentless/O persecution/O in/O this/O province/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/SCMP/O -RRB-/O --/O UN/ORGANIZATION special/O rapporteur/O on/O torture/O yesterday/O said/O he/O was/O unable/O to/O visit/O Shandong/LOCATION province/O to/O investigate/O claims/O of/O torture/O mostly/O against/O Falun/PERSON Gong/PERSON practitioners/O during/O his/O China/LOCATION tour/O because/O of/O time/O constraints/O ./O 
Manfred/PERSON Nowak/PERSON ,/O the/O first/O UN/ORGANIZATION official/O invited/O to/O visit/O Chinese/O prisons/O ,/O said/O he/O cancelled/O yesterday/O 's/O trip/O to/O Jinan/LOCATION ,/O the/O capital/O of/O Shandong/LOCATION ,/O because/O he/O needed/O to/O spend/O more/O time/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
``/O I/O had/O to/O take/O this/O decision/O because/O there/O are/O so/O many/O people/O who/O want/O to/O see/O me/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O I/O really/O wanted/O to/O go/O to/O Shandong/LOCATION ,/O but/O I/O think/O this/O was/O a/O good/O decision/O ./O ''/O 
Falun/ORGANIZATION Gong/ORGANIZATION is/O a/O spiritual/O movement/O that/O involves/O meditation/O and/O practices/O inspired/O by/O Buddhism/O and/O Taoism/LOCATION such/O as/O callisthenics/O and/O breathing/O exercises/O to/O improve/O health/O and/O seek/O immortality/O ,/O peace/O and/O harmony/O ./O 
On/O April/O 15/O ,/O 19999/O ,/O more/O than/O 10,000/O adepts/O demonstrate/O peacefully/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION against/O the/O violation/O of/O their/O rights/O ./O 
But/O beginning/O in/O July/O of/O that/O year/O on/O the/O urging/O of/O the/O President/O Jiang/PERSON Zemin/PERSON a/O vicious/O persecution/O was/O launched/O against/O the/O group/O ,/O which/O at/O the/O time/O had/O about/O 100/O million/O followers/O ,/O on/O the/O grounds/O that/O it/O was/O an/O ``/O evil/O cult/O ''/O that/O ``/O threatened/O social/O and/O political/O stability/O ''/O ./O 
Since/O then/O Falun/ORGANIZATION Gong/ORGANIZATION members/O have/O been/O defamed/O ,/O imprisoned/O and/O tortured/O -LRB-/O more/O than/O 38,000/O documented/O cases/O according/O to/O the/O Falun/ORGANIZATION Gong/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ;/O some/O have/O even/O been/O killed/O ./O 
Between/O July/O 1999/O and/O April/O 2005/O Falun/ORGANIZATION Gong/ORGANIZATION collected/O the/O names/O of/O 1,880/O victims/O ,/O including/O details/O about/O the/O circumstances/O of/O their/O death/O ,/O often/O a/O result/O of/O physical/O and/O psychological/O torture/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O total/O number/O is/O probably/O higher/O since/O such/O deaths/O are/O deemed/O state/O secrets/O and/O releasing/O any/O information/O about/O them/O constitutes/O a/O crime/O punishable/O by/O incarceration/O ./O 
Hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O followers/O ,/O including/O whole/O families/O ,/O are/O in/O fact/O in/O prison/O ,/O and/O more/O than/O 200,000/O have/O been/O sent/O without/O trial/O to/O labour/O camps/O for/O re-education/O ./O 
Many/O have/O been/O sent/O to/O mental/O hospitals/O and/O subjected/O to/O virtual/O ``/O brainwashing/O ''/O and/O medication/O dangerous/O to/O the/O nervous/O system/O in/O order/O to/O get/O them/O to/O forsake/O the/O movement/O ./O 
After/O deciding/O against/O finding/O the/O truth/O in/O Shandong/LOCATION ,/O Mr/O Nowak/PERSON arrived/O today/O in/O Lhasa/LOCATION ,/O Tibet/LOCATION 's/O capital/O ,/O where/O he/O is/O scheduled/O to/O visit/O prisons/O ,/O government/O staff/O and/O civilians/O ./O 
He/O will/O then/O travel/O from/O Lhasa/LOCATION to/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
The/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION insisted/O on/O visiting/O these/O two/O autonomous/O regions/O known/O for/O the/O violence/O security/O forces/O visit/O upon/O local/O prisoners/O accused/O of/O separatism/O ./O 
The/O UN/ORGANIZATION envoy/O announced/O that/O he/O was/O going/O to/O stay/O on/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION because/O of/O statements/O received/O from/O different/O sources/O according/O to/O which/O people/O who/O were/O willing/O to/O testify/O were/O placed/O under/O house/O arrest/O or/O taken/O away/O ./O 
``/O Such/O statements/O are/O hard/O to/O prove/O and/O I/O am/O trying/O to/O solve/O the/O problem/O with/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O Nowak/PERSON said/O ./O 
But/O the/O ministry/O itself/O has/O been/O co-operating/O with/O him/O since/O his/O arrival/O on/O November/O 21/O ./O 
The/O two-week/O trip/O is/O scheduled/O to/O end/O on/O December/O 2/O when/O he/O will/O hold/O a/O press/O conference/O to/O take/O stock/O of/O the/O situation/O ./O 
A/O written/O report/O should/O be/O ready/O next/O year/O for/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION on/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION ./O 
