Fukang/O -LRB-/O AsiaNews/SCMP/O -RRB-/O --/O A/O gas/O blast/O in/O a/O coal/O mine/O in/O Shenlong/LOCATION ,/O 38/O km/O east/O of/O the/O city/O of/O Fukang/LOCATION -LRB-/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O -RRB-/O has/O killed/O 65/O people/O with/O an/O additional/O 18/O listed/O as/O missing/O ,/O said/O officials/O with/O the/O State/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Work/ORGANIZATION Safety/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Only/O four/O people/O were/O found/O alive/O after/O the/O blast/O ,/O they/O added/O ./O 
Local/O and/O Work/O Safety/O authorities/O are/O still/O investigating/O possible/O causes/O for/O the/O disaster/O ,/O but/O rescuers/O at/O the/O scene/O said/O the/O blast/O destroyed/O the/O mine/O 's/O ventilation/O system/O and/O the/O density/O of/O gas/O at/O the/O site/O was/O six/O times/O higher/O than/O normal/O ./O 
It/O took/O rescue/O crews/O five/O hours/O to/O get/O the/O ventilation/O system/O working/O again/O ./O 
A/O Fukang/ORGANIZATION Work/ORGANIZATION Safety/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION official/O said/O that/O ''/O -LSB-/O t/O -RSB-/O his/O region/O has/O not/O seen/O such/O a/O serious/O disaster/O for/O years/O ./O ''/O 
The/O mine/O is/O privately/O run/O by/O the/O Fukang/ORGANIZATION Shenlong/ORGANIZATION Coal/ORGANIZATION Mine/ORGANIZATION Co/ORGANIZATION and/O has/O an/O annual/O capacity/O of/O 600,000/O tonnes/O ./O 
Under/O national/O safety/O standards/O ,/O it/O is/O rated/O as/O a/O Class/O B/O coal/O mine/O ,/O meaning/O that/O it/O had/O good/O safety/O conditions/O ./O 
Coal/O provides/O for/O 70/O per/O cent/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O energy/O needs/O ,/O but/O the/O country/O 's/O mines/O are/O among/O the/O most/O dangerous/O in/O the/O world/O ./O 
Official/O statistics/O released/O yesterday/O indicate/O that/O coal/O mine/O disasters/O have/O contributed/O more/O to/O mass/O deaths/O on/O the/O mainland/O than/O fires/O and/O traffic/O accidents/O ./O 
According/O to/O government/O figures/O ,/O work-related/O deaths/O reached/O 6,000/O last/O year/O ,/O but/O unofficial/O sources/O put/O the/O number/O at/O at/O least/O 20,000/O ./O 
In/O the/O first/O four/O months/O of/O this/O year/O ,/O the/O official/O death/O toll/O for/O mining/O accidents/O stood/O at/O 1,113/O ,/O a/O 20/O per/O cent/O increase/O over/O last/O year/O ./O 
Incidents/O leading/O to/O structural/O mine/O damage/O rose/O 44/O per/O cent/O this/O year/O over/O last/O ./O 
