Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O Vaccinating/O all/O poultry/O raised/O in/O China/LOCATION against/O bird/O flu/O ``/O is/O impossible/O ''/O ,/O experts/O say/O ./O 
The/O government/O announced/O on/O 15/O November/O that/O it/O will/O vaccinate/O all/O poultry/O and/O ,/O at/O the/O beginning/O of/O this/O week/O ,/O it/O said/O 60/O %/O have/O already/O been/O vaccinated/O ./O 
At/O the/O moment/O ,/O there/O are/O 5.2/O billion/O chickens/O in/O breeding/O farms/O and/O 14/O billion/O will/O be/O bred/O over/O one/O year/O ./O 
Experts/O have/O highlighted/O considerable/O technical/O problems/O ./O 
Above/O all/O ,/O ``/O the/O problem/O is/O it/O takes/O so/O many/O people/O to/O implement/O the/O programme/O across/O such/O immense/O territory/O ,/O ''/O said/O Leon/PERSON Russell/PERSON ,/O president/O of/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Veterinary/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O It/O is/O not/O possible/O to/O provide/O medicine/O with/O the/O feed/O as/O this/O does/O not/O work/O on/O birds/O ./O 
And/O even/O if/O it/O did/O ,/O the/O residue/O would/O contaminate/O the/O poultry/O meat/O and/O make/O it/O dangerous/O to/O consume/O ./O ''/O 
Chinese/O television/O has/O shown/O workers/O spraying/O whole/O coops/O at/O a/O time/O ,/O but/O the/O Food/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Agriculture/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O FAO/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O said/O it/O had/O not/O heard/O of/O cases/O where/O this/O method/O had/O proven/O effective/O ./O 
Each/O and/O every/O bird/O must/O be/O injected/O with/O the/O vaccine/O ./O 
Using/O an/O automatic/O injector/O ,/O ``/O each/O person/O can/O vaccinate/O about/O 600/O an/O hour/O ''/O ,/O said/O J.J./PERSON Giambrone/PERSON ,/O professor/O of/O poultry/O health/O at/O Auburn/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION in/O Alabama/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O he/O added/O ,/O even/O if/O China/LOCATION has/O plenty/O of/O cheap/O labour/O available/O ,/O ``/O vaccinating/O 14/O billion/O birds/O in/O the/O field/O by/O hand/O would/O be/O almost/O impossible/O ./O ''/O 
Another/O difficulty/O is/O that/O 70/O %/O of/O Chinese/O poultry/O is/O raised/O in/O backyard/O farms/O spread/O across/O the/O territory/O ./O 
In/O Vietnam/LOCATION too/O ,/O the/O government/O started/O to/O vaccinate/O poultry/O in/O September/O ./O 
There/O are/O around/O 220/O million/O birds/O and/O the/O authorities/O said/O that/O within/O a/O short/O time/O ,/O vaccination/O would/O be/O completed/O in/O 58/O out/O of/O 64/O provinces/O ./O 
Hoang/PERSON Dang/PERSON Huyen/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O Animal/ORGANIZATION Health/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION in/O Bac/LOCATION Giang/LOCATION province/O ,/O said/O veterinarians/O visit/O households/O with/O more/O than/O 200/O poultry/O for/O vaccination/O ,/O while/O people/O with/O fewer/O fowl/O have/O to/O travel/O to/O an/O agreed/O location/O ./O 
Another/O obstacle/O is/O the/O timing/O and/O costs/O involved/O in/O producing/O the/O necessary/O vaccines/O ./O 
China/LOCATION said/O it/O could/O produce/O 100/O million/O doses/O of/O the/O vaccine/O per/O day/O ,/O a/O claim/O which/O Giambrone/PERSON dismissed/O as/O ``/O nearly/O impossible/O ''/O ./O 
He/O said/O the/O vaccines/O are/O made/O in/O specific/O pathogen/O free/O -LRB-/O SPF/O -RRB-/O eggs/O ,/O but/O there/O are/O not/O enough/O SPF/O eggs/O in/O the/O world/O to/O produce/O that/O much/O vaccine/O ./O 
If/O China/LOCATION is/O using/O regular/O hatching/O eggs/O ,/O they/O ``/O may/O be/O contaminated/O with/O bacteria/O and/O viruses/O ,/O ''/O and/O this/O means/O they/O run/O the/O ``/O risk/O -LSB-/O of/O -RSB-/O contaminating/O all/O their/O poultry/O flocks/O ''/O ./O 
The/O use/O of/O fake/O vaccines/O is/O a/O widespread/O problem/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Du/PERSON Qingling/PERSON ,/O Agriculture/O Minister/O ,/O warned/O this/O month/O that/O ``/O the/O use/O of/O fake/O and/O shoddy/O vaccines/O will/O result/O in/O a/O disaster/O ''/O and/O that/O only/O the/O use/O of/O certified/O vaccines/O can/O provide/O immunity/O to/O the/O virus/O ./O 
It/O has/O been/O observed/O that/O in/O the/O case/O of/O outbreaks/O of/O infection/O ,/O China/LOCATION prefers/O to/O cull/O birds/O at/O risk/O rather/O than/O to/O vaccinate/O them/O ./O 
So/O far/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O government/O ,/O more/O than/O 21.1/O million/O birds/O have/O been/O culled/O ./O 
This/O leads/O one/O to/O believe/O that/O vaccinations/O are/O either/O still/O incomplete/O or/O else/O not/O easily/O applicable/O ./O 
Said/O Russell/PERSON :/O ``/O The/O best/O thing/O is/O to/O stop/O the/O spread/O by/O destroying/O the/O flocks/O that/O have/O bird/O flu/O ./O ''/O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O despite/O the/O vaccination/O campaign/O ,/O new/O outbreaks/O of/O infection/O are/O practically/O a/O daily/O occurrence/O now/O ./O 
Today/O ,/O the/O Agriculture/O Minister/O reported/O another/O three/O in/O the/O northern/O regions/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O Ningxia/PERSON and/O in/O the/O southern/O province/O of/O Yunnan/LOCATION ./O 
Poulty/O within/O a/O 3km/O radius/O were/O culled/O ,/O more/O than/O 8,000/O birds/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O 99,400/O in/O Yunnan/LOCATION and/O 66,800/O in/O Ningxia/PERSON ./O 
Live/O poultry/O markets/O in/O Guangzhou/LOCATION and/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION have/O been/O shut/O down/O ,/O and/O Shanghai/LOCATION is/O expected/O to/O follow/O suit/O within/O days/O ./O 
The/O municipal/O government/O of/O Shanghai/LOCATION has/O ordered/O all/O hospitals/O to/O pinpoint/O and/O to/O monitor/O all/O patients/O with/O high/O fever/O ./O 
In/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O all/O those/O with/O temperature/O higher/O than/O 37,5/O degrees/O Centrigrade/O are/O placed/O under/O observation/O ./O 
