Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O The/O Chinese/O are/O coming/O .../O to/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
Economic/O -LRB-/O growing/O energy/O demands/O -RRB-/O and/O political/O factors/O -LRB-/O regional/O stability/O -RRB-/O are/O pushing/O China/LOCATION to/O establish/O closer/O relations/O with/O the/O former/O Soviet/O Central/LOCATION Asian/LOCATION Republics/LOCATION of/LOCATION Kazakhstan/LOCATION ,/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ,/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION ./O 
Internal/O security/O reasons/O are/O also/O playing/O a/O prominent/O role/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Central/O Asian/O policy/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O want/O to/O avoid/O anything/O that/O might/O encourage/O Uigur/O Muslim/O separatism/O in/O oil-rich/O border/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Hence/O ,/O the/O central/O government/O has/O pursued/O for/O decades/O a/O persecutory/O policy/O towards/O the/O Uigurs/O that/O includes/O prison/O ,/O suppression/O of/O the/O their/O language/O an/O culture/O and/O mass/O immigration/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O encouraged/O to/O settle/O through/O financial/O and/O professional/O incentives/O ./O 
Uigur/O communities/O --/O in/O some/O areas/O they/O are/O the/O majority/O --/O also/O live/O in/O neighbouring/O states/O ./O 
The/O region/O situation/O was/O such/O that/O several/O countries/O ,/O including/O China/LOCATION ,/O set/O up/O in/O 1996/O the/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SCO/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O also/O known/O as/O the/O Shanghai/LOCATION group/O ,/O to/O promote/O regional/O trade/O and/O fight/O the/O three/O evils/O --/O extremism/O ,/O terrorism/O and/O fundamentalism/O --/O that/O were/O emerging/O in/O the/O wake/O of/O the/O civil/O war/O in/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ,/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION takeover/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Islamic/O terrorist/O attacks/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O the/O rise/O of/O Islamic/O fundamentalist/O groups/O in/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION Four/O of/O the/O five/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION Republics/LOCATION -LRB-/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION is/O not/O a/O member/O -RRB-/O and/O Russia/LOCATION are/O also/O in/O the/O SCO/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O is/O increasingly/O become/O an/O important/O diplomatic/O forum/O ./O 
India/LOCATION has/O for/O instance/O asked/O to/O join/O ./O 
For/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O region/O is/O increasingly/O important/O to/O satisfy/O its/O energy/O needs/O ./O 
It/O is/O actively/O involved/O in/O establishing/O a/O new/O `/O Silk/O Road/O '/O ,/O a/O network/O of/O railway/O lines/O and/O pipelines/O that/O would/O deliver/O oil/O and/O gas/O to/O from/O the/O mountains/O of/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O the/O Caspian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION to/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Additionally/O ,/O such/O a/O network/O would/O be/O useful/O to/O develop/O closer/O ties/O to/O Iran/LOCATION and/O Arab/O countries/O as/O well/O as/O faraway/O Europe/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Caspian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION region/O is/O rich/O in/O oil/O ,/O gas/O ,/O and/O mineral/O ores/O but/O the/O countries/O of/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION lack/O the/O financial/O wherewithal/O and/O technical/O expertise/O as/O well/O infrastructure/O necessary/O free/O them/O from/O heavy/O reliance/O on/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O transportation/O networks/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O also/O view/O with/O alarm/O the/O military/O presence/O of/O extra-regional/O powers/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
In/O addition/O to/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O the/O US/LOCATION has/O in/O fact/O set/O up/O military/O bases/O in/O some/O Central/LOCATION Asian/LOCATION countries/O and/O has/O been/O involved/O in/O the/O Afghan/O war/O since/O 9/11/O ./O 
Finally/O ,/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION represents/O growing/O markets/O for/O Chinese/O goods/O ,/O from/O technology/O and/O technical/O services/O to/O food/O ,/O raw/O materials/O and/O finished/O products/O ./O 
In/O addition/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O the/O region/O has/O attracted/O India/LOCATION and/O many/O European/O countries/O ,/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION -LRB-/O for/O shared/O religious/O ties/O -RRB-/O ,/O Turkey/LOCATION and/O Iran/LOCATION -LRB-/O for/O shared/O cultural/O ties/O -RRB-/O as/O well/O as/O Japan/LOCATION and/O South/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O especially/O good/O relations/O with/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ./O 
According/O to/O figures/O released/O by/O the/O Kazakh/ORGANIZATION Embassy/ORGANIZATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Sino-Kazakh/O trade/O was/O US$/O 3.29/O billion/O in/O 2003/O ,/O up/O 68.1/O per/O cent/O over/O the/O previous/O years/O and/O is/O expected/O to/O reach/O US$/O 5/O billion/O in/O 2010/O ./O 
For/O the/O Kazakh/O government/O ,/O the/O economic/O and/O diplomatic/O benefits/O generated/O by/O the/O Chinese/O presence/O are/O welcome/O ,/O especially/O after/O it/O had/O a/O falling/O out/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION in/O the/O wake/O of/O ``/O Kazakhgate/O ''/O scandal/O --/O Kazakh/O President/O Nursultan/PERSON Nazarbayev/PERSON and/O other/O members/O of/O his/O government/O are/O said/O to/O have/O stashed/O away/O some/O US$/O 78/O million/O in/O Swiss/O bank/O accounts/O ./O 
After/O Chinese/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON visited/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION in/O June/O 2003/O ,/O top/O levels/O government/O visits/O have/O become/O frequent/O ./O 
Currently/O ,/O a/O 3,000/O km/O oil/O pipeline/O is/O being/O constructed/O that/O will/O eventually/O link/O the/O Kazakh/O city/O of/O Atasu/LOCATION to/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
-LRB-/O PB/O -RRB-/O 
