On/O the/O basis/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O one-child/O policy/O she/O was/O not/O entitled/O to/O another/O child/O ./O 
Now/O authorities/O say/O given/O her/O health/O conditions/O she/O can/O not/O have/O an/O abortion/O more/O six/O months/O into/O her/O pregnancy/O ./O 
Others/O suggest/O that/O their/O change/O of/O heart/O is/O closely/O related/O to/O an/O international/O protest/O campaign/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O Arzigul/PERSON Tursun/PERSON ,/O a/O young/O Uyghur/O woman/O ,/O is/O back/O home/O in/O Bulaq/LOCATION -LRB-/O Gulja/LOCATION -RRB-/O still/O pregnant/O after/O Chinese/O authorities/O had/O forced/O into/O a/O hospital/O for/O an/O abortion/O ./O 
``/O I/O am/O all/O right/O and/O I/O am/O at/O home/O now/O ,/O ''/O was/O the/O first/O thing/O she/O told/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Free/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION 's/O Uyghur/O service/O ./O 
``/O I/O brought/O her/O home/O ,/O ''/O the/O local/O population-control/O committee/O chief/O Rashide/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O She/O was/O n't/O in/O good/O enough/O health/O to/O have/O an/O abortion/O ./O ''/O 
The/O authorities/O '/O change/O of/O heart/O came/O after/O her/O case/O was/O picked/O up/O by/O overseas/O Uyghur/O groups/O as/O well/O as/O two/O members/O of/O the/O US/LOCATION Congress/ORGANIZATION who/O made/O personal/O appeals/O to/O the/O Chinese/O ambassador/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ./O 
Earlier/O in/O the/O affair/O Chinese/O authorities/O were/O not/O so/O ``/O reasonable/O ''/O ./O 
First/O they/O took/O her/O against/O her/O will/O and/O brought/O her/O to/O a/O hospital/O for/O an/O abortion/O despite/O the/O fact/O that/O she/O was/O already/O 26/O weeks/O into/O her/O pregnancy/O ./O 
After/O she/O fled/O ,/O police/O mounted/O a/O hunt/O for/O her/O ,/O sending/O tens/O of/O police/O officers/O after/O her/O ,/O confiscating/O her/O family/O 's/O cellphones/O to/O prevent/O them/O from/O going/O public/O with/O the/O story/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O one-child/O policy/O applies/O mainly/O to/O majority/O Han/O Chinese/O and/O allows/O ethnic/O minorities/O ,/O including/O Uyghurs/O ,/O to/O have/O additional/O children/O ,/O with/O peasants/O permitted/O to/O have/O three/O children/O and/O city-dwellers/O two/O ./O 
But/O whilst/O Tursun/PERSON ,/O who/O already/O has/O two/O children/O ,/O is/O a/O peasant/O ,/O her/O husband/O is/O from/O a/O city/O ,/O so/O their/O status/O is/O unclear/O ./O 
