The/O Uyghur/O woman/O is/O expecting/O her/O third/O child/O ,/O but/O the/O authorities/O say/O she/O can/O have/O only/O two/O ,/O and/O have/O taken/O her/O to/O a/O hospital/O for/O an/O abortion/O ./O 
Her/O husband/O has/O denounced/O the/O case/O ,/O and/O protests/O have/O erupted/O in/O the/O country/O and/O abroad/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O In/O bed/O number/O 3/O of/O the/O Water/O Gate/O Hospital/O in/O Gulja/LOCATION -LRB-/O Xinjiang/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O Arzigul/PERSON Tursun/PERSON ,/O an/O Uyghur/O woman/O six/O and/O a/O half/O months/O pregnant/O ,/O is/O under/O guard/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O want/O to/O make/O her/O have/O an/O abortion/O ,/O because/O this/O is/O her/O third/O child/O ,/O while/O she/O is/O permitted/O to/O have/O only/O two/O ./O 
A/O nurse/O explains/O ``/O the/O procedure/O ''/O :/O ``/O We/O will/O give/O an/O injection/O first/O ./O 
Then/O she/O will/O experience/O abdominal/O pain/O ,/O and/O the/O baby/O will/O come/O out/O by/O itself/O ./O 
But/O we/O have/O n't/O given/O her/O any/O injection/O yet/O -/O we/O are/O waiting/O for/O instructions/O from/O the/O doctors/O ./O ''/O 
There/O have/O been/O many/O protests/O over/O the/O health/O of/O the/O woman/O ,/O who/O is/O 26/O weeks/O pregnant/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O an/O official/O one-child/O policy/O ,/O with/O severe/O fines/O and/O other/O sanctions/O for/O those/O who/O violate/O it/O ./O 
The/O Uyghurs/O ,/O as/O an/O ethnic/O minority/O ,/O can/O have/O two/O children/O if/O they/O live/O in/O a/O city/O ,/O and/O three/O if/O they/O live/O in/O rural/O areas/O ./O 
Tursun/O is/O from/O the/O countryside/O ,/O but/O her/O husband/O ,/O Nurmemet/PERSON Tohtisin/PERSON ,/O is/O from/O the/O city/O of/O Gulja/LOCATION -LRB-/O Yining/LOCATION in/O Chinese/O -RRB-/O ./O 
They/O live/O in/O the/O village/O of/O Bulaq/LOCATION -LRB-/O near/O Dadamtu/LOCATION -RRB-/O ./O 
All/O of/O this/O leaves/O their/O status/O unclear/O ./O 
Tohtisin/PERSON explained/O -/O before/O the/O authorities/O confiscated/O his/O cell/O phone/O -/O that/O when/O his/O wife/O ``/O fled/O the/O village/O to/O avoid/O abortion/O ,/O police/O and/O party/O officials/O and/O the/O family/O planning/O committee/O officials/O all/O came/O and/O interrogated/O us/O ./O 
The/O deputy/O chief/O of/O the/O village/O ,/O a/O Chinese/O woman/O named/O Wei/PERSON Yenhua/PERSON ,/O threatened/O that/O if/O we/O did/O n't/O find/O Arzigul/PERSON and/O bring/O her/O to/O the/O village/O ,/O she/O would/O confiscate/O our/O land/O and/O all/O our/O property/O ./O ''/O 
She/O came/O back/O ./O 
On/O November/O 11/O ,/O Rashide/PERSON ,/O an/O official/O on/O the/O family/O planning/O committee/O ,/O brought/O her/O by/O force/O to/O the/O hospital/O in/O Gulja/LOCATION ./O 
The/O abortion/O ,/O scheduled/O for/O November/O 13/O ,/O has/O been/O delayed/O until/O the/O 17th/O because/O of/O the/O many/O phone/O calls/O of/O protest/O from/O local/O Uyghurs/O and/O those/O in/O exile/O ./O 
U.S./LOCATION members/O of/O congress/O have/O even/O intervened/O with/O Chinese/O ambassador/O Zhou/PERSON Wenzhong/PERSON ./O 
Now/O the/O authorities/O are/O insisting/O that/O the/O couple/O sign/O an/O ``/O authorization/O ./O ''/O 
Rashide/PERSON explains/O that/O if/O the/O abortion/O were/O not/O possible/O ,/O for/O example/O because/O of/O reasons/O of/O the/O mother/O 's/O health/O ,/O the/O couple/O would/O ``/O have/O to/O pay/O a/O fine/O in/O the/O amount/O of/O 45,000/O yuan/O -LRB-/O about/O 4,500/O euros/O -RRB-/O -/O that/O 's/O a/O lot/O of/O money/O ,/O and/O they/O wo/O n't/O have/O it/O ./O ''/O 
