Accused/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O masterminding/O the/O violence/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Uyghur/O leader/O calls/O for/O an/O international/O inquiry/O to/O see/O who/O was/O behind/O the/O clashes/O and/O deaths/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION says/O US/LOCATION agrees/O the/O matter/O is/O an/O internal/O Chinese/O matter/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION criticises/O Japan/LOCATION and/O Australia/LOCATION for/O hosting/O Kadeer/PERSON ./O 
Tokyo/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O Exiled/O Uyghur/O dissident/O Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON accused/O China/LOCATION today/O of/O trying/O to/O lay/O a/O veil/O of/O silence/O over/O the/O disappearance/O of/O ``/O about/O 10,000/O people/O ''/O during/O the/O unrest/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
The/O head/O of/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION has/O also/O reproached/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION for/O its/O silence/O over/O the/O matter/O as/O well/O ./O 
Ms/O Kadeer/PERSON arrived/O yesterday/O in/O the/O Japanese/O capital/O to/O urge/O the/O international/O community/O to/O provide/O support/O to/O her/O people/O ,/O ``/O massacred/O ''/O by/O the/O Chinese/O ./O 
``/O About/O 10,000/O people/O disappeared/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION in/O one/O night/O ./O 
Where/O have/O they/O gone/O ?/O 
If/O they/O are/O dead/O ,/O where/O are/O they/O ''/O now/O ,/O she/O said/O during/O a/O press/O conference/O through/O an/O interpreter/O ./O 
In/O early/O July/O protests/O by/O Uyghurs/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION turned/O into/O clashes/O with/O police/O and/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Chinese/O government/O 197/O people/O died/O as/O a/O result/O of/O the/O violence/O ,/O mostly/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
Uyghur/O dissidents/O claim/O instead/O that/O thousands/O of/O people/O have/O probably/O died/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O accused/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O masterminding/O the/O unrest/O and/O has/O labelled/O Ms/O Kadeer/PERSON the/O ``/O black/O hand/O ''/O that/O seeks/O the/O independence/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION with/O the/O help/O of/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O ./O 
The/O Uyghur/O leader/O has/O dismissed/O these/O charges/O and/O always/O rejected/O appeals/O from/O al-Qaeda/O to/O resort/O to/O violence/O ./O 
Instead/O she/O believes/O Chinese/O police/O and/O government/O are/O responsible/O for/O the/O clashes/O ./O 
``/O The/O responsibility/O lies/O with/O the/O authorities/O who/O transformed/O what/O had/O been/O a/O peaceful/O demonstration/O into/O violent/O unrest/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
The/O dissident/O leader/O also/O called/O for/O an/O international/O inquiry/O into/O the/O demonstrations/O and/O clashes/O ./O 
Ms/O Kadeer/PERSON said/O she/O was/O ``/O perplexed/O and/O disappointed/O ''/O by/O the/O ``/O cool/O response/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ''/O towards/O the/O Xinjiang/LOCATION problem/O ./O 
``/O I/O would/O like/O to/O believe/O that/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION will/O not/O remain/O impassive/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
She/O also/O urged/O the/O US/LOCATION administration/O to/O open/O a/O consulate/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ./O 
Yesterday/O after/O two/O days/O of/O Sino-American/O economic/O talks/O ,/O Wang/PERSON Guangya/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O vice/O foreign/O minister/O ,/O thanked/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION for/O taking/O a/O ``/O moderate/O ''/O line/O on/O recent/O ethnic/O violence/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
``/O The/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION unequivocally/O said/O that/O this/O incident/O is/O entirely/O a/O domestic/O affair/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
By/O contrast/O ,/O China/LOCATION criticised/O Japan/LOCATION for/O granting/O Ms/O Kadeer/PERSON a/O visa/O ./O 
Some/O news/O agencies/O have/O reported/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O blocked/O Japanese/O TV/O programmes/O reporting/O the/O arrival/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O leader/O ./O 
After/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O Kadeer/PERSON is/O expected/O to/O travel/O to/O Australia/LOCATION for/O the/O premiere/O of/O a/O film/O on/O her/O life/O ./O 
Even/O on/O this/O occasion/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O tried/O everything/O in/O the/O power/O to/O have/O the/O movie/O pulled/O from/O theMelbourne/O International/O Film/O Festival/O which/O will/O be/O held/O next/O month/O ./O 
