Hundreds/O of/O police/O officers/O keep/O squares/O under/O surveillance/O ,/O the/O Internet/O has/O been/O disconnected/O ,/O young/O people/O are/O confined/O to/O their/O campuses/O ./O 
The/O Mongols/ORGANIZATION criticize/O mining/O investments/O in/O the/O region/O -LRB-/O coal/O and/O rare/O minerals/O -RRB-/O ,/O which/O pollute/O their/O land/O and/O destroy/O the/O pastures/O and/O their/O daily/O lives/O ./O 
Party/O newspaper/O :/O These/O events/O are/O not/O similar/O to/O those/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //ORGANIZATION Agencies/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O tightened/O security/O after/O a/O series/O of/O demonstrations/O seeking/O justice/O for/O the/O deaths/O of/O two/O ethnic/O Mongols/O ./O 
Hundreds/O of/O policemen/O were/O deployed/O at/O various/O points/O of/O Hohhot/LOCATION ,/O the/O capital/O of/O the/O province/O ,/O schools/O and/O universities/O are/O under/O under/O surveillance/O and/O many/O young/O people/O can/O not/O leave/O the/O campus/O ./O 
The/O internet/O has/O been/O blocked/O and/O news/O searches/O on/O Mongolia/LOCATION are/O obscured/O ./O 
Tensions/O escalated/O after/O the/O death/O of/O two/O people/O in/O two/O separate/O incidents/O ./O 
The/O first/O occurred/O on/O May/O 10/O ,/O a/O Mongolian/O shepherd/O was/O hit/O by/O a/O truck/O ,/O driven/O by/O a/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O carrying/O minerals/O through/O the/O pastures/O ,/O ruining/O the/O grass/O and/O the/O work/O of/O shepherds/O ./O 
On/O May/O 15/O ,/O another/O ethnic/O Mongolian/O ,/O was/O killed/O during/O a/O protest/O in/O front/O of/O a/O mine.The/O Mongols/O ,/O a/O minority/O in/O their/O homeland/O ,/O accuse/O the/O government/O and/O its/O mining/O policy/O of/O destroying/O the/O pastures/O ,/O polluting/O the/O land/O and/O destroying/O the/O peace/O ./O 
The/O ethnic/O Mongolians/O are/O only/O 20/O %/O out/O of/O a/O population/O of/O 24/O million/O ./O 
In/O recent/O years/O ,/O the/O exploitation/O of/O coal/O and/O rare/O mineral/O mines/O has/O increased/O in/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION ,/O which/O are/O highly/O polluting/O ./O 
The/O boom/O has/O brought/O workers/O from/O other/O parts/O of/O China/LOCATION and/O Mongolia/LOCATION ,/O mainly/O devoted/O to/O sheep/O farming/O ,/O is/O now/O a/O threatened/O minority/O ,/O their/O work/O is/O also/O likely/O to/O be/O destroyed/O due/O to/O mining/O and/O pollution/O ./O 
In/O recent/O days/O there/O have/O been/O demonstrations/O that/O have/O gathered/O thousands/O of/O ethnic/O Mongolians/O in/O the/O capital/O and/O several/O other/O cities/O ./O 
Analysts/O say/O they/O are/O more/O numerous/O than/O demonstrations/O over/O the/O past/O 20/O years/O ./O 
To/O calm/O the/O public/O ,/O the/O government/O has/O promised/O to/O prosecute/O the/O two/O Chinese/O responsible/O for/O the/O deaths/O of/O two/O Mongols/O ./O 
Yesterday/O ,/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION reported/O that/O a/O Chinese/O man/O was/O tried/O for/O the/O death/O of/O Yan/PERSON Wenlong/PERSON ,/O an/O ethnic/O Mongolian/O man/O killed/O during/O protests/O at/O the/O mine/O ./O 
According/O to/O analysts/O ,/O the/O riots/O in/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION are/O similar/O to/O those/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O Tibetan/O and/O Uighur/O minorities/O are/O fighting/O for/O their/O survival/O ./O 
TheGlobal/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION today/O -LRB-/O linked/O to/O the/O tabloid/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O has/O now/O put/O on/O guard/O by/O the/O attempt/O to/O give/O meaning/O to/O political/O events/O in/O Mongolia/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
The/O Mongolian/O protests/O -/O says/O the/O newspaper/O -/O are/O not/O a/O politically-driven/O demonstration/O ./O 
Some/O of/O their/O requests/O are/O reasonable/O ,/O and/O should/O be/O responded/O to/O by/O the/O local/O government/O ''/O ./O 
But/O it/O rejected/O as/O ``/O improper/O ''/O any/O link/O between/O the/O situation/O in/O the/O region/O bordering/O Mongolia/LOCATION and/O outbursts/O of/O ethnic/O turmoil/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION in/O 2008/O and/O in/O the/O remote/O northwestern/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION in/O 2009/O ./O 
``/O Social/O conflicts/O are/O on/O the/O rise/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O ethnic/O minority/O areas/O are/O no/O exception/O ./O 
But/O the/O incidents/O there/O should/O not/O be/O exaggerated/O or/O over-interpreted/O ,/O ''/O it/O said/O ./O 
