The/O Chinese/O authorities/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION post/O pictures/O of/O the/O last/O two/O Uyghurs/O killed/O in/O cold/O blood/O a/O few/O days/O ago/O on/O its/O website/O and/O warns/O :/O ``/O They/O could/O be/O taken/O alive/O ./O ''/O 
Analysts/O explained/O :/O ``/O A/O clear/O message/O :/O those/O who/O rebel/O will/O be/O shot/O ./O ''/O 
Urumqi/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O -/O Chinese/O authorities/O ``/O are/O sending/O a/O clear/O message/O to/O the/O Uyghur/O minority/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION :/O those/O who/O rebel/O against/O the/O domination/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION will/O be/O unceremoniously/O killed/O ''/O ,/O say/O a/O number/O of/O analysts/O the/O day/O after/O the/O disturbing/O announcement/O on/O the/O website/O of/O the/O government/O of/O the/O autonomous/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O authorities/O have/O posted/O a/O photograph/O of/O two/O Uyghurs/O -LRB-/O pictured/O -RRB-/O murdered/O in/O cold/O blood/O after/O a/O being/O pursued/O by/O police/O and/O who/O ``/O could/O have/O been/O taken/O alive/O ./O ''/O 
On/O August/O 1/O ,/O Chinese/O police/O gunned/O down/O the/O two/O Uyghurs/O ,/O suspected/O of/O being/O involved/O in/O the/O July/O 31/O attack/O that/O caused/O the/O death/O of/O six/O people/O in/O a/O bar/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION ,/O in/O cold/O blood/O ./O 
The/O two/O -/O Memtieli/PERSON Tiliwaldi/PERSON -LRB-/O 29/O -RRB-/O and/O Turson/PERSON Hasan/PERSON -LRB-/O 34/O -RRB-/O -/O were/O killed/O in/O a/O cornfield/O and/O left/O there/O ./O 
Kashgar/LOCATION 's/O government/O had/O put/O a/O bounty/O of/O 100/O thousand/O yuan/O -LRB-/O about/O 10/O thousand/O euros/O -RRB-/O for/O their/O capture/O ./O 
Before/O this/O latest/O bloody/O episode/O there/O were/O other/O violent/O events/O in/O the/O city/O of/O Hotan/LOCATION and/O in/O the/O provincial/O capital/O ,/O Urumqi/LOCATION ./O 
Since/O 1949/O ,/O the/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O --/O Turkic/O speaking/O Muslims/O -/O have/O been/O under/O the/O heel/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O which/O has/O imposed/O a/O series/O of/O extreme/O religious/O and/O cultural/O restrictions/O on/O them/O ./O 
Several/O groups/O claim/O independence/O and/O call/O for/O the/O restoration/O of/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION ,/O but/O the/O majority/O of/O Uyghurs/O are/O simply/O seeking/O greater/O autonomy/O ./O 
In/O 2009/O ,/O the/O region/O was/O the/O scene/O of/O violent/O clashes/O between/O Uyghurs/LOCATION and/O Han/O Chinese/O immigrants/O ./O 
Clashes/O in/O the/O capital/O Urumqi/LOCATION at/O the/O time/O claimed/O the/O lives/O of/O more/O than/O 200/O people/O ./O 
Today/O ,/O two/O years/O later/O ,/O tensions/O are/O soaring/O once/O again/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O ,/O the/O Uyghurs/O carried/O out/O a/O ``/O coordinated/O terrorist/O attack/O ''/O against/O a/O police/O station/O and/O officers/O were/O forced/O to/O respond/O with/O force/O ./O 
Instead/O ,/O for/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O police/O have/O ``/O beaten/O to/O death/O ''/O 14/O people/O who/O were/O demonstrating/O peacefully/O ,/O and/O then/O shot/O 6/O other/O people/O ./O 
Ilyar/PERSON Shemseddin/PERSON ,/O a/O Uyghur/O analyst/O with/O who/O live/O in/O the/O U.S./LOCATION ,/O explains/O :/O ``/O China/LOCATION ,/O do/O not/O view/O Uyghurs/PERSON as/O Chinese/O citizens/O and/O ,/O instead/O ,/O treat/O them/O like/O ``/O foreign/O forces/O to/O be/O destroyed/O ./O 
If/O China/LOCATION really/O accepted/O these/O Uyghurs/PERSON as/O Chinese/O citizens/O ,/O they/O would/O not/O be/O killed/O like/O dogs/O in/O the/O streets/O ,/O partly/O because/O even/O the/O most/O violent/O demonstrators/O were/O armed/O at/O most/O with/O knives/O ,/O while/O the/O police/O have/O guns/O and/O are/O not/O afraid/O to/O use/O them/O ./O ''/O 
