Communist/O authorities/O in/O the/O province/O that/O is/O home/O to/O ethnic/O Uygur/O claim/O the/O children/O were/O being/O held/O against/O their/O will/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uygur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O is/O fighting/O for/O religious/O freedom/O ,/O police/O raided/O the/O religious/O school/O ``/O to/O eradicate/O religious/O belief/O ''/O ./O 
Urumqi/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O -/O Police/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O far/O western/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION have/O raided/O a/O Qur/O `/O anic/O school/O that/O taught/O the/O basics/O of/O Islam/O to/O 54/O children/O ./O 
During/O the/O intervention/O ,/O 12/O children/O received/O burns/O that/O police/O blame/O on/O suspects/O who/O ``/O ignited/O a/O flammable/O device/O to/O resist/O capture/O ''/O ./O 
``/O Acting/O on/O tips/O from/O local/O residents/O ,/O police/O .../O raided/O an/O illegal/O religious/O preaching/O venue/O in/O the/O city/O ,/O where/O 54/O children/O were/O being/O held/O ,/O ``/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O reported/O ./O 
``/O Three/O suspects/O were/O seized/O during/O the/O operation/O ,/O and/O three/O police/O officers/O were/O wounded/O ''/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uygur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O WUC/O -RRB-/O ,/O a/O German-based/O group/O defending/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O predominantly/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uygur/ORGANIZATION group/O ,/O which/O is/O the/O largest/O ethnic/O group/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O police/O used/O tear/O gas/O to/O attack/O the/O Islamic/O school/O ./O 
``/O There/O was/O a/O fight/O ,/O and/O the/O authorities/O used/O tear/O gas/O on/O the/O young/O students/O ,/O causing/O injuries/O on/O both/O sides/O ,/O ''/O a/O WUC/O spokesman/O said/O ./O 
``/O The/O aim/O was/O to/O eradicate/O religious/O belief/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
Police/O arrested/O 47/O people/O ,/O including/O 11/O women/O ./O 
The/O province/O remains/O a/O hotspot/O of/O opposition/O against/O China/LOCATION 's/O Communist/O government/O ./O 
After/O a/O brief/O period/O of/O independence/O ,/O the/O country/O was/O invaded/O by/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Since/O then/O ,/O Uygur/O leaders/O have/O called/O on/O the/O central/O government/O to/O grant/O their/O people/O cultural/O autonomy/O and/O religious/O freedom/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION claims/O that/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION extremist/O groups/O are/O active/O in/O the/O area/O trying/O to/O destabilise/O the/O situation/O ./O 
