Beijing/LOCATION uses/O an/O iron/O fist/O in/O the/O northwestern/O province/O ,/O homeland/O of/O minority/O Turkic/O Muslims/O ./O 
Courts/O convict/O ``/O activists/O ''/O for/O preparing/O ``/O Holy/O war/O ''/O ./O 
For/O exiled/O Uighurs/O ,/O they/O are/O only/O guilty/O of/O talking/O about/O ``/O freedom/O ''/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O -/O China/LOCATION 's/O relentless/O crackdown/O on/O ethnic/O minorities/O continues/O unabated/O ./O 
Despite/O its/O ongoing/O slaughter/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O opted/O for/O the/O iron/O fist/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O the/O homeland/O of/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O in/O northwestern/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Courts/O handed/O down/O heavy/O sentences/O ,/O including/O life/O in/O prison/O ,/O against/O 20/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O ``/O poisoned/O by/O religious/O extremism/O ''/O ./O 
Judges/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION and/O Bayingol/PERSON ruled/O that/O the/O offenders/O had/O their/O ``/O thoughts/O poisoned/O by/O religious/O extremism/O ''/O ,/O and/O that/O they/O were/O getting/O ready/O for/O a/O holy/O war/O ,/O a/O Xinjiang/LOCATION government/O press/O release/O said/O ./O 
Uighurs/O are/O a/O Turkic/O Muslim/O group/O ./O 
From/O the/O end/O of/O World/O War/O II/O until/O the/O 1990s/O ,/O they/O sought/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Today/O ,/O they/O want/O religious/O and/O cultural/O autonomy/O ./O 
According/O to/O exiled/O Uighurs/O ,/O centred/O mostly/O in/O Germany/LOCATION under/O the/O leadership/O of/O Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O magnified/O the/O threat/O of/O religious/O extremism/O to/O justify/O its/O repression/O against/O the/O minority/O ./O 
For/O Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON ,/O a/O spokesman/O for/O the/O exiled/O World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O those/O convicted/O were/O guilty/O of/O no/O more/O than/O listening/O to/O the/O US-fundedRadio/O Free/O Asia/O and/O using/O the/O Internet/O to/O discuss/O the/O importance/O of/O religious/O and/O cultural/O freedom/O ./O 
Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O rich/O in/O raw/O materials/O and/O is/O located/O in/O a/O strategic/O position/O on/O the/O border/O with/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
