Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON ,/O 45/O ,/O is/O a/O professor/O of/O economics/O at/O Beijing/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ./O 
About/O 30/O public/O security/O officials/O entered/O his/O house/O ,/O dragged/O him/O away/O and/O seized/O his/O computers/O and/O telephones/O ./O 
His/O wife/O :/O ``/O Arrested/O in/O other/O circumstances/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O different/O this/O time/O ''/O ./O 
The/O professor/O is/O known/O for/O his/O articles/O in/O defense/O of/O ethnicity/O ,/O accused/O by/O the/O government/O of/O covering/O Islamic/O terrorism/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //ORGANIZATION Agencies/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O A/O group/O of/O Chinese/O police/O have/O arrested/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON ,/O an/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O professor/O of/O economics/O at/O Beijing/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ./O 
They/O dragged/O him/O away/O after/O raiding/O his/O house/O without/O making/O public/O the/O charges/O brought/O against/O him/O ./O 
During/O the/O raid/O ,/O officials/O also/O seized/O computers/O ,/O cell/O phones/O and/O even/O some/O papers/O written/O by/O his/O students/O ./O 
His/O wife/O ,/O Guzaili/PERSON Nu'er/PERSON ,/O reports/O that/O the/O police/O told/O her/O nothing/O ./O 
``/O This/O time/O it/O 's/O different/O ;/O they/O sent/O so/O many/O security/O officers/O ,/O including/O police/O from/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O the/O nearby/O police/O station/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
``/O This/O time/O it/O is/O more/O serious/O ''/O ./O 
Tohti/PERSON ,/O 45/O ,/O was/O arrested/O on/O 15/O January/O ./O 
The/O academic/O is/O famous/O for/O his/O public/O speeches/O in/O favor/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O cause/O ./O 
This/O ethnic/O group/O lives/O in/O the/O northern/O autonomous/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O is/O of/O the/O Turkish/O language/O and/O the/O Muslim/O faith/O ,/O and/O denounces/O a/O strong/O linguistic/O ,/O cultural/O and/O religious/O repression/O by/O the/O Chinese/O central/O government/O ./O 
Over/O the/O years/O there/O have/O been/O numerous/O violent/O clashes/O between/O the/O two/O sides/O :/O Beijing/LOCATION argues/O the/O region/O is/O home/O to/O Islamic/O extremists/O and/O separatists/O ,/O while/O local/O activists/O pointing/O the/O finger/O at/O ethnic/O tensions/O caused/O by/O the/O Chinese/O control/O and/O ``/O racist/O ''/O policies/O in/O implemented/O by/O the/O central/O government/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Hong/PERSON Lei/PERSON argues/O that/O the/O academic/O was/O arrested/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O ``/O violations/O of/O the/O Criminal/O Code/O ''/O :/O he/O is/O currently/O suspected/O of/O having/O carried/O out/O unidentified/O crimes/O and/O of/O having/O ''/O violated/O the/O law/O ./O ''/O 
The/O Tohti/PERSON house/O is/O guarded/O around/O the/O clock/O by/O two/O plain/O clothes/O officers/O ,/O who/O block/O anyone/O trying/O to/O enter/O ./O 
His/O wife/O recalls/O that/O the/O Professer/O had/O already/O been/O stopped/O several/O times/O ,/O but/O always/O returned/O home/O for/O the/O night/O :/O ``/O This/O time/O I/O do/O not/O even/O know/O where/O he/O is/O ./O ''/O 
Several/O human/O rights/O activists/O argue/O that/O an/O article/O written/O by/O Tohti/PERSON to/O contest/O the/O charges/O against/O the/O Uyghur/ORGANIZATION minority/O after/O the/O attack/O onTiananmen/O Square/O in/O October/O 2013/O is/O behind/O the/O arrest/O :/O ``/O Even/O on/O other/O occasions/O we/O have/O been/O referred/O to/O as/O perpetrators/O of/O serious/O acts/O ,/O only/O to/O discover/O that/O we/O had/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O them/O ''/O ./O 
The/O day/O before/O his/O arrest/O ,/O he/O posted/O on/O his/O mobile/O social/O media/O account/O :/O ``/O The/O Uygur/O people/O have/O become/O outsiders/O in/O the/O development/O of/O their/O own/O homeland/O and/O survival/O ,/O ''/O It/O is/O here/O that/O the/O people/O 's/O anger/O begins/O to/O grow/O ./O 
Uygur/O people/O need/O an/O avenue/O to/O express/O their/O aspirations/O and/O protect/O their/O rights/O ''/O ./O 
