The/O catalyst/O that/O sparked/O the/O violence/O in/O the/O province/O ,/O which/O killed/O dozens/O of/O people/O ,/O is/O still/O unknown/O ./O 
Military/O patrol/O streets/O and/O authorities/O shut/O down/O communications/O with/O the/O outside/O world/O ./O 
Formal/O charges/O of/O ``/O separatism/O ''/O against/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON ,/O a/O scholar/O who/O defends/O the/O Uyghur/O minority/O ./O 
Urumqi/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O China/LOCATION 's/O central/O government/O has/O ordered/O the/O authorities/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ``/O to/O secure/O ''/O the/O province/O afterthe/O violence/O on/O July/O 28/O ,/O which/O resulted/O in/O dozens/O of/O deaths/O and/O injuries/O ./O 
The/O streets/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION and/O Yarkand/LOCATION County/LOCATION ,/O say/O local/O sources/O ,/O are/O ``/O full/O of/O soldiers/O ,/O policemen/O and/O armed/O checkpoints/O ''/O ./O 
The/O internet/O has/O been/O cut/O off/O and/O the/O phones/O are/O tapped/O to/O prevent/O contact/O with/O the/O outside/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O the/O government/O formally/O charged/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON ,/O a/O Uyghur/O academic/O who/O campaigns/O for/O respect/O for/O minority/O rights/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Its/O Uyghur/O Muslim/O minority/O ,/O who/O number/O about/O nine/O million/O ,/O have/O long/O sought/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O central/O government/O ,/O for/O its/O part/O ,/O has/O brought/O in/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O settlers/O to/O make/O Han/O Chinese/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O it/O has/O severely/O curtailed/O Muslim/O religious/O worship/O as/O well/O as/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O local/O language/O and/O culture/O ./O 
The/O dynamics/O of/O the/O attack/O against/O the/O government/O structures/O that/O took/O place/O on/O Monday/O and/O were/O termed/O ``/O terrorist/O ''/O by/O the/O authorities/O are/O still/O unclear/O :/O mainstream/O media/O reported/O the/O violence/O days/O later/O and/O local/O officials/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O questions/O of/O the/O few/O foreign/O journalists/O in/O the/O area/O ./O 
What/O is/O certain/O is/O that/O both/O Chinese/O Han/O and/O Uyghurs/PERSON died/O in/O the/O clashes/O ./O 
According/O to/O some/O sources/O quoted/O by/O newspapers/O close/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O it/O all/O started/O after/O the/O discovery/O of/O a/O ``/O large/O quantity/O of/O explosives/O ''/O in/O the/O house/O of/O a/O separatist/O Uyghur/O ./O 
Members/O of/O the/O minority/O deny/O this/O and/O talk/O of/O clashes/O provoked/O by/O Chinese/O repression/O during/O the/O month/O of/O Ramadan/O ./O 
Despite/O the/O high/O tension/O ,/O the/O central/O government/O has/O ,/O however/O ,/O decided/O to/O announce/O formal/O charges/O against/O Ilham/PERSON Tothi/PERSON ,/O an/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O economics/O professor/O and/O famous/O activist/O for/O the/O rights/O of/O minorities/O living/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O academichas/O been/O in/O jail/O since/O last/O January/O :/O Beijing/LOCATION accuse/O him/O of/O ``/O separatism/O ''/O a/O crime/O that/O carries/O the/O death/O penalty/O ,/O and/O added/O that/O his/O trial/O will/O begin/O ``/O very/O soon/O ''/O ./O 
