The/O Muslim/O holy/O month/O ,/O which/O began/O yesterday/O ,/O requires/O fasting/O from/O dawn/O to/O dusk/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION tightens/O its/O grip/O over/O the/O province/O ,/O home/O to/O nearly/O nine/O million/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O ./O 
Civil/O servants/O ,/O students/O and/O teachers/O must/O follow/O the/O guidelines/O ./O 
Uighur/O leader/O slams/O ban/O as/O ``/O a/O provocation/O ''/O that/O ``/O will/O only/O lead/O to/O instability/O and/O conflict/O ./O ''/O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O China/LOCATION has/O banned/O civil/O servants/O ,/O students/O and/O teachers/O in/O its/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O --/O home/O to/O a/O large/O Muslim/O community/O --/O from/O fasting/O during/O the/O Muslim/O holy/O month/O of/O Ramadan/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O have/O ordered/O restaurants/O to/O stay/O open/O ./O 
In/O some/O counties/O ,/O religious/O vigils/O and/O activities/O associated/O with/O the/O month/O have/O been/O banned/O ./O 
Out/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION 's/O 22/O million/O people/O ,/O almost/O nine/O million/O are/O indigenous/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O ./O 
Deemed/O a/O hotbed/O of/O terrorism/O ,/O the/O region/O has/O seen/O rising/O tensions/O due/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O restrictive/O ethnic/O and/O religious/O policies/O ./O 
Over/O the/O years/O ,/O clashes/O and/O violent/O incidents/O have/O broken/O out/O between/O native/O Uighurs/O and/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O settlers/O brought/O in/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O swamp/O the/O indigenous/O population/O ./O 
Going/O one/O step/O beyond/O simply/O discouraging/O government/O employees/O to/O forgo/O fasting/O ,/O police/O and/O court/O officials/O in/O Awat/LOCATION County/LOCATION were/O ordered/O to/O ``/O take/O the/O lead/O in/O teaching/O family/O members/O not/O to/O fast/O and/O not/O to/O participate/O in/O Ramadan-related/O religious/O activities/O ''/O ./O 
As/O in/O previous/O years/O ,/O teachers/O and/O schoolchildren/O were/O included/O in/O directives/O limiting/O Ramadan/O fasting/O and/O other/O religious/O observances/O ./O 
However/O ,/O for/O Dilxat/PERSON Rexit/PERSON ,/O a/O spokesman/O for/O the/O exiled/O World/ORGANIZATION Uygur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O ``/O Policies/O that/O prohibit/O religious/O fasting/O are/O a/O provocation/O and/O will/O only/O lead/O to/O instability/O and/O conflict/O ./O ''/O 
