Taking/O advantage/O of/O the/O Paris/LOCATION tragedy/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O wants/O to/O add/O Xinjiang/LOCATION Muslims/O on/O the/O terror/O lists/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O national/O media/O try/O to/O link/O the/O attacks/O in/O the/O French/O capital/O with/O the/O country/O 's/O own/O ``/O war/O on/O terror/O ''/O ./O 
International/O analysts/O are/O sceptical/O about/O any/O link/O between/O Islamist/O groups/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O --/O The/O struggle/O against/O Islamist/O militants/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O far/O western/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION should/O become/O an/O ``/O important/O part/O ''/O of/O the/O world/O 's/O war/O on/O terror/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O minister/O Wang/PERSON Yi/PERSON said/O following/O the/O attacks/O in/O Paris/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O blamed/O the/O violence/O on/O Islamist/O militants/O ,/O led/O by/O the/O East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O ETIM/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ;/O a/O group/O it/O said/O had/O ties/O to/O al-Qaeda/O ./O 
More/O recently/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O reported/O that/O some/O Uyghurs/O have/O travelled/O to/O Syria/LOCATION and/O Iraq/LOCATION to/O fight/O with/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION and/O other/O groups/O ./O 
Uyghurs/O are/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION ,/O Turkic-speaking/O ,/O and/O the/O largest/O ethnic/O group/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
They/O have/O given/O up/O on/O independence/O decades/O ago/O ,/O but/O want/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O grant/O them/O greater/O cultural/O and/O religious/O autonomy/O ./O 
In/O recent/O years/O ,/O violent/O attacks/O have/O targeted/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O who/O are/O China/LOCATION 's/O largest/O ethnic/O group/O ,/O mostly/O by/O lone/O attackers/O unconnected/O to/O extremist/O movements/O active/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O responded/O to/O rising/O violence/O with/O more/O repression/O ,/O and/O has/O effectively/O militarised/O the/O province/O ./O 
In/O recent/O days/O ,/O Chinese/O state/O media/O has/O already/O sought/O to/O link/O China/LOCATION 's/O own/O ``/O war/O on/O terror/O ''/O with/O the/O Paris/LOCATION attacks/O ./O 
Over/O the/O weekend/O ,/O pictures/O appeared/O on/O the/O microblogs/O of/O state-run/O newspapers/O showing/O Chinese/O armed/O police/O supposedly/O on/O a/O mission/O to/O root/O out/O militants/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION --/O pictures/O put/O out/O after/O what/O happened/O in/O France/LOCATION on/O Friday/O ./O 
For/O some/O experts/O ,/O this/O is/O an/O attempt/O to/O justify/O future/O human/O rights/O violations/O at/O the/O expense/O of/O the/O indigenous/O Uyghur/O population/O ./O 
Conversely/O ,/O for/O Foreign/O Minister/O Wang/PERSON ,/O ``/O The/O UN/ORGANIZATION 's/O leading/O role/O should/O be/O brought/O into/O full/O play/O to/O combat/O terrorism/O ,/O and/O a/O united/O front/O in/O this/O regard/O should/O be/O formed/O ''/O ./O 
In/O his/O view/O ,/O ``/O China/LOCATION is/O also/O a/O victim/O of/O terrorism/O ,/O and/O cracking/O down/O on/O ETIM/O should/O become/O an/O important/O part/O of/O the/O international/O fight/O against/O terrorism/O ''/O ./O 
