China/LOCATION '/O ethnic/O minorities/O number/O 120/O million/O ./O 
In/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O the/O central/O government/O appears/O to/O have/O lost/O control/O ./O 
The/O underlying/O cause/O is/O a/O power/O struggle/O between/O those/O ,/O like/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O who/O want/O to/O abandon/O ethnic/O policies/O in/O favour/O of/O forced/O integration/O ,/O and/O those/O ,/O like/O the/O president/O 's/O late/O father/O Xi/PERSON Zhongxun/PERSON ,/O who/O favour/O the/O maintenance/O of/O ethnic/O differences/O ./O 
Against/O this/O backdrop/O ,/O former/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON and/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Front/ORGANIZATION Work/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O plays/O an/O active/O role/O in/O managing/O ethnic/O and/O religious/O minorities/O ,/O still/O cast/O their/O long/O shadow/O ./O 
Courtesy/O of/O the/O Jamestown/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Washington/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O --/O Since/O assuming/O power/O in/O November/O 2012/O ,/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CCP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O Secretary/O General/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON has/O sought/O to/O put/O his/O imprimatur/O on/O the/O contentious/O realm/O of/O ethnic/O policy/O ./O 
As/O with/O other/O agenda/O items/O ,/O Xi/O has/O sought/O to/O concentrate/O power/O around/O his/O own/O person/O ,/O believing/O this/O to/O be/O the/O only/O way/O to/O push/O forward/O reform/O against/O vested/O interest/O groups/O ,/O including/O in/O the/O realm/O of/O inter-ethnic/O relations/O ./O 
Yet/O the/O minzu/O or/O ``/O ethnic/O ''/O lobby/O is/O a/O powerful/O and/O deeply/O entrenched/O part/O of/O the/O political/O machine/O in/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION -LRB-/O PRC/LOCATION -RRB-/O ./O 
State-run/O media/O frequently/O lauds/O Xi/O for/O his/O intimate/O knowledge/O and/O personal/O interest/O in/O the/O nearly/O 120/O million/O Chinese/O citizens/O who/O belong/O to/O an/O ethnic/O minority/O ,/O and/O especially/O the/O troubled/O regions/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
His/O inspection/O tours/O of/O minority/O regions/O are/O front-page/O news/O ,/O as/O are/O his/O important/O speeches/O on/O ethnic/O work/O ./O 
Most/O recently/O ,/O his/O image/O and/O words/O featured/O prominently/O at/O the/O official/O celebrations/O of/O the/O 50th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O Tibetan/O Autonomous/O Region/O and/O the/O 60th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O Xinjiang/LOCATION Uyghur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION -LRB-/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O September/O 8/O ;/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O October/O 1/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Yet/O ,/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON 's/O intervention/O has/O failed/O to/O end/O the/O long-running/O and/O deeply/O acrimonious/O debate/O over/O the/O future/O direction/O of/O ethnic/O policies/O in/O the/O PRC/LOCATION ./O 
Xi/O lacks/O both/O the/O authority/O and/O the/O political/O capital/O to/O push/O ethnic/O policy/O in/O the/O more/O assimilationist/O direction/O he/O desires/O ./O 
Rather/O ,/O he/O is/O hamstrung/O by/O the/O liberal/O legacy/O of/O his/O father/O Xi/PERSON Zhongxun/PERSON and/O the/O continued/O influence/O of/O former/O Secretary/O General/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ,/O two/O powerful/O sources/O of/O support/O for/O the/O ethnic/O lobby/O and/O its/O defense/O of/O ethnic/O pluralism/O ./O 
The/O end/O result/O is/O policy/O paralysis/O ,/O leaving/O local/O officials/O to/O interpret/O the/O contradictory/O messages/O emanating/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION while/O increasing/O the/O importance/O of/O stability/O maintenance/O work/O as/O the/O only/O agreed/O method/O for/O dealing/O with/O a/O complex/O set/O of/O ethnic/O contradictions/O ./O 
The/O Ethnic/O Policy/O Debate/O Since/O the/O establishment/O of/O the/O PRC/LOCATION in/O 1949/O ,/O ethnic/O policy/O has/O been/O in/O a/O state/O of/O constant/O flux/O ,/O swinging/O -LRB-/O often/O dramatically/O -RRB-/O between/O the/O accommodation/O and/O protection/O of/O ethnic/O differences/O and/O centralizing/O ,/O integrationist/O tendencies/O ./O 
The/O sudden/O collapse/O of/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION in/O 1991/O provided/O yet/O another/O jolt/O ./O 
Nationalists/O warned/O the/O liberal/O policies/O ushered/O in/O by/O former/O party/O secretary/O Hu/PERSON Yaobang/PERSON during/O the/O 1980s/O placed/O China/LOCATION in/O a/O precarious/O position/O not/O that/O dissimilar/O to/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION under/O Mikhail/PERSON Gorbachev/PERSON ./O 
Peking/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION Professor/O Ma/PERSON Rong/PERSON has/O long/O argued/O that/O China/LOCATION shares/O the/O same/O preconditions/O for/O national/O fracturing/O as/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ,/O while/O the/O influential/O policy/O scholar/O and/O Tsinghua/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION Professor/O Hu/PERSON Angang/PERSON has/O called/O for/O a/O ``/O second/O generation/O of/O ethnic/O policies/O ''/O on/O the/O eve/O of/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON 's/O elevation/O as/O party/O secretary/O -LRB-/O seeChina/O Brief/O ,/O July/O 6/O ,/O 2012/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Current/O policies/O ,/O these/O would-be/O reformers/O argue/O ,/O place/O too/O much/O emphasis/O on/O ethnic/O identities/O while/O creating/O institutional/O barriers/O -LRB-/O administrative/O autonomy/O ,/O ethnic/O classification/O ,/O ethnic-based/O preferences/O -RRB-/O that/O hinder/O the/O natural/O fusion/O of/O different/O groups/O and/O the/O forging/O of/O a/O strong/O ,/O shared/O national/O identity/O ./O 
In/O short/O ,/O Ma/PERSON ,/O Hu/PERSON and/O other/O reformers/O advocate/O a/O minzu-blind/O politic/O ,/O one/O that/O would/O naturalize/O and/O eventually/O eliminate/O policymaking/O based/O on/O ethnic/O differences/O ./O 
Opponents/O like/O Minzu/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION Professor/O Yang/PERSON Shengmin/PERSON argue/O any/O rethink/O of/O ethnic/O theory/O and/O policy/O would/O lead/O to/O ``/O ideological/O chaos/O ''/O and/O political/O and/O social/O upheaval/O -LRB-/O CUAES/O ,/O February/O 23/O ,/O 2012/O ;/O Phoenix/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION ,/O March/O 30/O ,/O 2014/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Open/O the/O minzu/O box/O ,/O they/O assert/O ,/O and/O you/O will/O unleash/O a/O Pandora-like/O set/O of/O contradictions/O that/O will/O undermine/O the/O cooperation/O ,/O solidarity/O ,/O and/O trust/O central/O to/O solving/O social/O problems/O in/O a/O multi-ethnic/O country/O such/O as/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O sheer/O size/O of/O the/O minzu/O establishment/O ensures/O vocal/O opposition/O to/O any/O shift/O in/O the/O status/O quo/O ,/O with/O a/O complex/O network/O of/O ``/O ethnic/O and/O religious/O affairs/O committees/O ''/O employing/O millions/O of/O officials/O at/O every/O level/O of/O the/O bureaucracy/O ,/O while/O overseeing/O the/O distribution/O of/O billions/O of/O dollars/O in/O state/O revenue/O each/O year/O ./O 
There/O are/O reasons/O to/O believe/O that/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON is/O highly/O sympathetic/O to/O the/O integrationist/O agenda/O ./O 
He/O has/O consistently/O stressed/O the/O importance/O of/O national/O unity/O in/O the/O context/O of/O his/O ``/O China/LOCATION dream/O ,/O ''/O while/O remaining/O largely/O silent/O on/O the/O place/O of/O ethnic/O autonomy/O ,/O languages/O and/O cultures/O ./O 
He/O has/O resurrected/O and/O promoted/O the/O ``/O four/O identifications/O ''/O ,/O which/O stresses/O the/O affinity/O of/O minorities/O with/O the/O motherland/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O nation/race/O ,/O Chinese/O culture/O and/O the/O socialist/O road/O with/O Chinese/O characteristics/O ,/O while/O promoting/O a/O sense/O of/O collective/O belonging/O through/O Mandarin/O --/O language/O instruction/O and/O patriotic/O education/O in/O frontier/O regions/O ./O 
-LSB-/O 1/O -RSB-/O Xi/O has/O also/O stressed/O the/O ``/O equality/O of/O everyone/O before/O the/O law/O ''/O ,/O rather/O than/O the/O group-differentiated/O rights/O enshrined/O in/O the/O Chinese/O Constitution/O -LRB-/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION ,/O November/O 21/O ,/O 2014/O ;/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O August/O 28/O -RRB-/O ./O 
The/O controversial/O theme/O of/O ``/O ethnic/O mingling/O ''/O is/O now/O one/O of/O the/O ``/O guiding/O principles/O ''/O of/O ethnic/O work/O under/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON 's/O government/O ./O 
Rather/O than/O promoting/O ethnic/O diversity/O ,/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION stresses/O residential/O integration/O ,/O joint/O schooling/O ,/O and/O increased/O interethnic/O migration/O and/O mobility/O ./O 
The/O concept/O of/O ethnic/O mingling/O is/O closely/O associated/O with/O another/O leading/O ethnic/O policy/O reformer/O ,/O the/O former/O Executive/O Director/O of/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Front/ORGANIZATION Work/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O UFWD/O -RRB-/O ,/O Zhu/PERSON Weiqun/PERSON ,/O who/O believes/O mingling/O is/O an/O inevitable/O social/O and/O historical/O trend/O that/O can/O not/O be/O resisted/O -LRB-/O China/LOCATION Brief/O ,/O June/O 19/O ,/O 2014/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Xi/O 's/O Failed/O Intervention/O At/O the/O Central/ORGANIZATION Ethnic/ORGANIZATION Work/ORGANIZATION Forum/ORGANIZATION in/O September/O 2014/O ,/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON sought/O to/O ``/O consolidate/O thinking/O ''/O and/O draw/O the/O ethnic/O policy/O debate/O to/O a/O close/O -LRB-/O seeChina/O Brief/O ,/O November/O 7/O ,/O 2014/O -RRB-/O ./O 
In/O his/O speech/O ,/O he/O called/O for/O confidence/O in/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION 's/O current/O approach/O and/O the/O need/O to/O ``/O unflinchingly/O walk/O the/O correct/O road/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O unique/O solution/O to/O the/O ethnic/O question/O ./O ''/O 
Xi/O was/O critical/O of/O those/O ,/O like/O Ma/PERSON Rong/PERSON and/O Hu/PERSON Angang/PERSON ,/O who/O praise/O foreign/O models/O ,/O such/O as/O an/O idealized/O version/O of/O the/O American/O ``/O melting/O pot/O ,/O ''/O and/O rather/O dramatically/O pleaded/O :/O ``/O There/O are/O people/O who/O say/O that/O we/O do/O not/O need/O the/O system/O of/O regional/O ethnic/O autonomy/O ,/O and/O we/O should/O implement/O the/O same/O system/O as/O we/O have/O in/O other/O provinces/O ./O 
This/O view/O is/O incorrect/O ,/O and/O politically/O pernicious/O ./O 
I/O want/O to/O again/O state/O clearly/O to/O everyone/O ,/O we/O must/O stop/O suggesting/O that/O the/O system/O of/O ethnic/O autonomy/O should/O be/O abolished/O !/O ''/O 
-LRB-/O China/LOCATION Ethnic/O Daily/O ,/O November/O 15/O ,/O 2014/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Yet/O ,/O in/O his/O speech/O ,/O Xi/O also/O made/O reference/O to/O the/O four/O identifications/O and/O the/O centrality/O of/O ethnic/O mingling/O ,/O leaving/O some/O to/O believe/O that/O he/O still/O desires/O to/O move/O ethnic/O policy/O in/O a/O new/O direction/O ./O 
Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON 's/O mediation/O did/O little/O to/O end/O the/O debate/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O under/O his/O leadership/O ,/O the/O divisions/O within/O the/O ethnic/O policy/O community/O have/O sharpened/O ,/O becoming/O more/O public/O and/O personal/O ./O 
Both/O sides/O have/O declared/O victory/O in/O the/O media/O ,/O highlighting/O those/O parts/O of/O Xi/O 's/O undisclosed/O speech/O that/O support/O their/O viewpoint/O ./O 
Ma/PERSON Rong/PERSON ,/O for/O example/O ,/O wrote/O a/O long/O essay/O arguing/O the/O meeting/O signaled/O ``/O an/O important/O readjustment/O ''/O in/O thinking/O ,/O shattering/O the/O ``/O dual/O structure/O ''/O that/O divides/O Chinese/O society/O into/O two/O unequal/O halves/O :/O the/O Han/O majority/O and/O the/O ethnic/O minorities/O ./O 
-LSB-/O 2/O -RSB-/O In/O reply/O ,/O his/O academic/O rival/O Hao/PERSON Shiyuan/PERSON countered/O with/O his/O own/O article/O ,/O asserting/O that/O Xi/O 's/O speech/O reaffirmed/O the/O centrality/O of/O ethnic/O autonomy/O and/O current/O policies/O ,/O and/O must/O put/O an/O end/O to/O the/O confused/O and/O erroneous/O viewpoints/O that/O have/O reigned/O in/O recent/O years/O ./O 
-LSB-/O 3/O -RSB-/O Wang/PERSON Zhengwei/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O the/O powerful/O State/ORGANIZATION Ethnic/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SEAC/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O and/O himself/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Hui/O minority/O -RRB-/O ,/O issued/O his/O own/O summary/O of/O the/O meeting/O ,/O claiming/O Xi/PERSON 's/O speech/O amounted/O to/O ``/O the/O final/O word/O ''/O on/O the/O ethnic/O policy/O debate/O -LRB-/O Qiushi/O ,/O October/O 16/O ,/O 2014/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Yet/O ,/O a/O month/O later/O ,/O one/O of/O his/O deputies/O at/O the/O SEAC/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O Tibetan/O official/O Danzhu'angben/O ,/O provided/O far/O more/O extensive/O excerpts/O from/O Xi/O 's/O speech/O ,/O making/O it/O clear/O that/O the/O new/O Party/O boss/O favors/O some/O gradual/O adjustments/O to/O concrete/O policies/O like/O family/O planning/O and/O educational/O preferences/O for/O minorities/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O an/O end/O to/O the/O creation/O of/O new/O ethnic/O groups/O and/O autonomous/O regions/O ./O 
``/O Fifty-six/O minzu/O is/O fifty-six/O minzu/O ,/O ''/O Danzhu'angben/O quotes/O Xi/O ,/O ``/O we/O do/O not/O want/O to/O divide/O any/O further/O ''/O -LRB-/O China/LOCATION Ethnic/O Daily/O ,/O November/O 15/O ,/O 2014/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON 's/O Continued/O Influence/O Despite/O the/O growing/O clamor/O for/O ethnic/O policy/O reform/O ,/O the/O minzu/O establishment/O remains/O a/O powerful/O interest/O group/O ,/O and/O it/O has/O a/O formidable/O ally/O in/O the/O former/O Secretary/O General/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ./O 
Many/O of/O Hu/PERSON 's/O people/O remain/O in/O key/O positions/O of/O authority/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O ethnic/O policy/O ,/O and/O according/O to/O Willy/PERSON Lam/PERSON ,/O Hu/PERSON 's/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Youth/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CYL/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O Faction/O -LRB-/O tuanpai/O -RRB-/O ``/O is/O the/O only/O party/O clique/O that/O can/O pose/O some/O kind/O of/O challenge/O to/O Xi/O and/O his/O powerful/O allies/O ./O ''/O 
-LSB-/O 4/O -RSB-/O Despite/O persistent/O rumors/O that/O an/O ally/O of/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON would/O replace/O Xinjiang/LOCATION party/O secretary/O Zhang/PERSON Chunxian/PERSON ,/O he/O remains/O in/O his/O post/O in/O spite/O of/O recent/O violence/O and/O reputed/O ties/O to/O the/O purged/O former/O security/O chief/O Zhou/PERSON Yongkang/PERSON -LRB-/O Duowei/LOCATION ,/O September/O 27/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Tibet/LOCATION has/O long/O been/O a/O stronghold/O of/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ,/O where/O he/O served/O as/O party/O secretary/O between/O 1988/O and/O 1992/O ./O 
Following/O his/O promotion/O to/O the/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O succession/O of/O Hu/PERSON allies/O has/O ruled/O over/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O frontier/O regions/O like/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Qinghai/LOCATION and/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION have/O served/O as/O important/O proving/O grounds/O for/O tuanpai/O officials/O ,/O including/O the/O leading/O candidate/O to/O replace/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON at/O the/O 20th/O Party/O Congress/O in/O 2022/O ,/O Hu/PERSON Chunhua/PERSON ,/O who/O spent/O nearly/O twenty/O years/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O eventually/O served/O as/O deputy/O party/O secretary/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION from/O 2003/O to/O 2006/O ,/O before/O becoming/O the/O party/O secretary/O of/O the/O Inner/O Mongolian/O Autonomous/O Region/O in/O 2009/O ./O 
The/O stocks/O of/O another/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ally/O ,/O SEAC/ORGANIZATION director/O Wang/PERSON Zhengwei/PERSON are/O also/O on/O the/O rise/O ./O 
In/O April/O of/O this/O year/O ,/O he/O was/O appointed/O Deputy/O Head/O of/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Front/ORGANIZATION Work/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Wang/PERSON now/O holds/O three/O key/O national/O leadership/O positions/O with/O the/O Chinese/O People/O 's/O Political/O Consultative/O Conference/O -LRB-/O CPPCC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O State/ORGANIZATION Ethnic/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Front/ORGANIZATION Work/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION ./O 
He/O is/O widely/O tipped/O to/O enter/O the/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O 19th/O Party/O Congress/O and/O might/O even/O take/O over/O the/O leadership/O of/O the/O UFWD/O -LRB-/O Dagongbao/LOCATION ,/O April/O 15/O -RRB-/O ./O 
If/O this/O occurs/O ,/O he/O will/O be/O the/O first/O leader/O since/O Li/PERSON Weihan/PERSON -LRB-/O 1949/O --/O 1954/O -RRB-/O to/O simultaneously/O hold/O the/O top/O Party/ORGANIZATION and/O State/ORGANIZATION posts/O related/O to/O ethnic/O policy/O ,/O and/O the/O first/O ethnic/O minority/O to/O do/O so/O ./O 
The/O new/O institutional/O powerbase/O of/O the/O ethnic/O policy/O reformers/O is/O the/O far/O less/O powerful/O Ethnic/O and/O Religious/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O CPPCC/ORGANIZATION ,/O where/O Zhu/PERSON Weiqun/PERSON is/O the/O director/O after/O retiring/O from/O the/O UFWD/O ./O 
Far/O from/O receding/O into/O the/O background/O ,/O Zhu/PERSON has/O become/O increasing/O strident/O on/O the/O need/O for/O ethnic/O reform/O ./O 
In/O May/O 2015/O ,/O for/O example/O ,/O a/O dialogue/O between/O himself/O and/O the/O Tibetan/O writer/O Alai/PERSON went/O viral/O due/O to/O its/O unusually/O frank/O criticism/O of/O the/O current/O approach/O to/O ethnic/O issues/O -LRB-/O Phoenix/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION ,/O May/O 31/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Yet/O ,/O he/O will/O be/O forced/O to/O retire/O at/O the/O 19th/O Party/O Congress/O ,/O and/O at/O present/O ,/O there/O does/O not/O seem/O to/O be/O anyone/O with/O sufficient/O political/O clout/O to/O take/O up/O his/O cause/O on/O retirement/O ./O 
The/O Father/O 's/O Long/O Shadow/O Xi/O Jinping/PERSON 's/O desire/O to/O break/O down/O the/O ethnic/O policy/O establishment/O is/O not/O only/O stymied/O by/O his/O political/O predecessor/O but/O also/O by/O his/O father/O 's/O extensive/O legacy/O of/O ethnic/O policy/O work/O ./O 
The/O elder/O Xi/PERSON was/O known/O as/O a/O leading/O expert/O on/O minority/O issues/O ,/O serving/O first/O in/O the/O Northwest/LOCATION during/O the/O 1940s/O and/O 1950s/O and/O then/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION as/O Vice-Premier/O in/O charge/O of/O ethnic/O ,/O religious/O and/O united/O front/O work/O during/O the/O 1980s/O ./O 
Xi/PERSON Zhongxun/PERSON consistently/O warned/O against/O ``/O leftist/O deviation/O ''/O in/O ethnic/O work/O ,/O and/O stressed/O the/O need/O for/O careful/O consideration/O of/O minority/O cultures/O ,/O languages/O and/O identities/O when/O implementing/O national/O policies/O ./O 
During/O the/O 1980s/O ,/O he/O worked/O closely/O with/O Hu/PERSON Yaobang/PERSON to/O readjust/O ethnic/O policies/O after/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O ,/O resulting/O in/O the/O passage/O of/O the/O 1984/O Law/O on/O Regional/O Ethnic/O Autonomy/O and/O a/O raft/O of/O new/O minority/O preferences/O that/O the/O ethnic/O policy/O reformers/O rail/O against/O today/O -LRB-/O Phoenix/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION ,/O October/O 21/O ,/O 2014/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Xi/O senior/O was/O particularly/O close/O to/O the/O 10th/O Panchen/O Lama/O ,/O and/O was/O also/O said/O to/O have/O kept/O a/O watch/O that/O the/O 14th/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON gave/O him/O ,/O in/O 1954/O ./O 
On/O the/O sudden/O death/O of/O the/O Panchen/O Lama/O in/O 1989/O ,/O Xi/PERSON Zhongxun/PERSON published/O a/O long/O memorial/O essay/O in/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION praising/O the/O patriotism/O and/O devotion/O of/O his/O ``/O close/O friend/O ,/O ''/O while/O lamenting/O leftist/O errors/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION policy/O in/O the/O past/O ./O 
After/O the/O death/O of/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON ,/O Xi/PERSON Zhongxun/PERSON worked/O closely/O with/O the/O Panchen/O Lama/O to/O implement/O a/O series/O of/O significant/O policy/O reforms/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O other/O ethnic/O regions/O ,/O creating/O today/O 's/O ethnic/O establishment/O ./O 
Unlike/O his/O father/O ,/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON has/O had/O little/O direct/O experience/O with/O ethnic/O issues/O ,/O spending/O his/O entire/O career/O in/O coastal/O provinces/O like/O Hebei/LOCATION ,/O Fujian/LOCATION and/O Zhejiang/LOCATION ./O 
A/O 5,000-character/O section/O of/O his/O 1992/O bookCasting/O Off/O Poverty/O is/O held/O up/O as/O his/O primary/O contribution/O to/O ethnic/O work/O -LRB-/O CPC/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION ,/O November/O 2/O ,/O 2014/O -RRB-/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O there/O is/O not/O a/O single/O essay/O on/O ethnic/O policy/O in/O Xi/LOCATION Jinping/LOCATION 's/O most/O recent/O book/O ,/O On/O Governance/O ,/O with/O only/O two/O fleeting/O references/O in/O the/O entire/O book/O ./O 
In/O sharp/O contrast/O ,/O Xi/PERSON Zhongxun/PERSON 's/O contribution/O to/O ethnic/O and/O religious/O work/O was/O highlighted/O in/O the/O essays/O ,/O books/O and/O even/O TV/O series/O commemorating/O the/O centenary/O of/O his/O birth/O in/O 2013/O ./O 
``/O Ethnic/O work/O was/O an/O indissoluble/O thread/O throughout/O Comrade/O Xi/PERSON Zhongxun/PERSON 's/O life/O ,/O ''/O Wang/PERSON Zhengwei/PERSON wrote/O ,/O ``/O where/O he/O made/O a/O major/O contribution/O to/O solving/O our/O country/O 's/O ethnic/O problems/O ''/O -LRB-/O China/LOCATION Ethnic/O Daily/O ,/O October/O 15/O ,/O 2013/O -RRB-/O ./O 
In/O short/O ,/O any/O move/O by/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON to/O scale/O back/O ethnic/O minority/O rights/O and/O autonomy/O would/O be/O viewed/O as/O a/O direct/O repudiation/O of/O his/O father/O 's/O legacy/O ,/O something/O he/O is/O frequently/O reminded/O of/O through/O the/O citation/O of/O his/O father/O 's/O speeches/O by/O those/O who/O seek/O to/O defend/O the/O status/O quo/O ./O 
Conclusion/O :/O Security/O Reigns/O Supreme/O With/O the/O lack/O of/O consensus/O at/O the/O top/O ,/O local/O officials/O are/O left/O without/O clear/O guidance/O as/O how/O to/O balance/O ethnic/O autonomy/O with/O interethnic/O mingling/O ./O 
Unsure/O how/O to/O proceed/O ,/O most/O stress/O the/O importance/O of/O stability/O above/O all/O else/O ,/O employing/O their/O considerable/O security/O and/O social/O welfare/O funds/O to/O inhibit/O ethnic/O contradictions/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O policy/O paralysis/O and/O continued/O ethnic/O unrest/O actually/O lends/O a/O freer/O hand/O to/O security/O officials/O while/O the/O underlying/O sources/O of/O interethnic/O tension/O go/O unaddressed/O ./O 
As/O chairman/O of/O the/O newly/O created/O National/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION ,/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON has/O considerable/O influence/O over/O the/O security/O agenda/O ,/O with/O its/O forces/O emerging/O as/O one/O of/O his/O most/O important/O power/O bases/O ./O 
In/O his/O speeches/O thus/O far/O ,/O Xi/O has/O consistently/O stressed/O the/O importance/O of/O stability/O maintenance/O --/O a/O common/O theme/O over/O the/O last/O two/O decades/O but/O one/O that/O has/O come/O to/O define/O Xi/PERSON 's/O approach/O to/O ethnic/O problems/O ./O 
In/O the/O name/O of/O combatting/O the/O ``/O three/O evils/O ''/O -LRB-/O separatism/O ,/O extremism/O and/O terrorism/O -RRB-/O ,/O security/O officials/O have/O not/O only/O garrisoned/O frontier/O regions/O like/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O Tibet/LOCATION but/O are/O increasingly/O adopting/O similar/O methods/O of/O militarized/O policing/O across/O the/O country/O ./O 
Yet/O ,/O the/O securitization/O of/O Chinese/O society/O fails/O to/O address/O any/O of/O the/O core/O issues/O at/O stake/O in/O the/O ethnic/O policy/O debate/O ./O 
In/O sum/O ,/O while/O the/O security/O apparatuses/O have/O proven/O themselves/O largely/O effective/O in/O snuffing/O out/O the/O spate/O of/O Tibetan/O self-immolations/O and/O Uyghur-linked/O terror/O attacks/O ,/O ethnic/O antagonism/O has/O sharpened/O in/O parts/O of/O Chinese/O society/O as/O they/O are/O pushed/O deeper/O underground/O by/O the/O now/O ubiquitous/O social/O monitoring/O ./O 
Without/O efforts/O to/O deal/O with/O these/O underlining/O tensions/O ,/O any/O stable/O and/O harmonious/O pluralism/O will/O continue/O to/O elude/O Chinese/O policymakers/O ./O 
***/O James/PERSON Leibold/PERSON is/O Senior/O Lecturer/O in/O Politics/O and/O Asian/O Studies/O at/O La/ORGANIZATION Trobe/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION in/O Melbourne/LOCATION Australia/LOCATION ./O 
He/O is/O the/O author/O ofEthnic/O Policy/O in/O China/LOCATION :/O Is/O Reform/O Inevitable/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O Honolulu/LOCATION :/O East/LOCATION West/LOCATION Center/LOCATION ,/O 2013/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Notes/O 1/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O at/O the/O 6th/O Tibetan/O Work/O Forum/O ,/O Xi/O added/O a/O fifth/O identification/O ,/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O thereby/O making/O the/O term/O his/O own/O -LRB-/O seePeople/O 's/O Daily/O ,/O August/O 26/O -RRB-/O ./O 
2/O ./O 
Ma/PERSON Rong/PERSON ,/O ``/O 旗帜不变/O ，/O 稳住阵脚/O ，/O 调整思想/O ,/O 务实改革/O ：/O 对中央民族工作会议的解读/O ''/O -LRB-/O Fixing/O the/O flag/O ,/O holding/O one/O 's/O ground/O ,/O readjusting/O one/O 's/O thinking/O ,/O and/O pragmatically/O reforming/O :/O Deciphering/O the/O Central/O Ethnic/O Work/O Conference/O -RRB-/O ,/O 民族社会学研究通讯/O ,/O 172/O -LRB-/O 2014/O -RRB-/O :/O pp./O 1/O --/O 10/O ./O 
3/O ./O 
Hao/PERSON Shiyuan/PERSON ,/O ``/O 民族区域自治/O ：/O 中央民族工作会议讲了什么/O ?/O ''/O 
-LRB-/O Regional/O ethnic/O autonomy/O :/O What/O was/O said/O at/O the/O Central/O Ethnic/O Work/O Conference/O ?/O -RRB-/O 
,/O 中央民族大学学报/O ,/O 219/O -LRB-/O 2015/O -RRB-/O :/O pp./O 5/O --/O 12/O ./O 
4/O ./O 
Willy/PERSON Wo-Lap/PERSON Lam/PERSON ,/O Chinese/O Politics/O in/O the/O Era/O of/O Xi/O Jinping/O :/O Renaissance/O ,/O Reform/O ,/O or/O Retrogression/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O London/LOCATION :/O Routledge/PERSON ,/O 2015/O -RRB-/O :/O p./O 5/O ./O 
