Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O --/O It/O is/O the/O end/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ./O 
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O as/O we/O have/O known/O it/O ,/O the/O one/O where/O we/O have/O lived/O ,/O is/O no/O more/O ./O 
The/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION of/O ``/O one/O country/O -/O two/O systems/O ''/O was/O to/O last/O at/O least/O 50/O years/O ;/O instead/O ,/O it/O has/O only/O lasted/O 18/O ./O 
The/O end/O came/O 32/O years/O ahead/O of/O time/O ./O 
The/O date/O of/O its/O death/O is/O 30/O December/O 2015/O ,/O just/O after/O 6/O pm/O ./O 
On/O that/O day/O ,/O witnesses/O saw/O some/O men/O forcing/O publisher/O Lee/PERSON Bo/PERSON -LRB-/O pictured/O -RRB-/O into/O a/O van/O ./O 
Since/O then/O ,/O nothing/O has/O been/O heard/O from/O him/O ,/O except/O his/O desperate/O wife/O who/O received/O a/O phone/O call/O from/O him/O in/O which/O ,/O uncharacteristically/O ,/O he/O spoke/O in/O Mandarin/O ,/O and/O said/O that/O he/O was/O in/O China/LOCATION to/O help/O the/O authorities/O in/O an/O investigation/O ./O 
In/O October/O ,/O three/O other/O people/O ,/O from/O a/O small/O publishing/O house/O ,/O disappeared/O whilst/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
A/O fourth/O person/O ,/O also/O from/O a/O small/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION publishing/O house/O ,/O disappeared/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O 
Five/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION publishers/O disappear/O into/O thin/O air/O ,/O like/O under/O the/O worst/O fascist/O ,/O communist/O or/O military/O regimes/O ./O 
The/O one/O thing/O they/O had/O in/O common/O was/O that/O they/O published/O and/O sold/O books/O that/O criticised/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O books/O that/O mainland/O Chinese/O tourists/O snapped/O up/O when/O they/O visited/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ./O 
Another/O was/O that/O they/O were/O preparing/O a/O new/O critical/O book/O on/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON with/O some/O titillating/O titbits/O about/O his/O private/O life/O ./O 
In/O the/O past/O ,/O I/O wrote/O many/O times/O that/O there/O is/O no/O democracy/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O but/O that/O at/O least/O there/O was/O freedom/O ./O 
Now/O I/O can/O not/O say/O that/O anymore/O ./O 
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION residents/O have/O already/O been/O imprisoned/O for/O political/O reasons/O as/O they/O travelled/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O Chinese/O security/O operations/O never/O reached/O into/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ./O 
As/O pro-democracy/O leader/O Lee/PERSON Cheuk-yan/PERSON rightly/O pointed/O out/O ,/O the/O abduction/O of/O Lee/PERSON Bo/PERSON is/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION people/O 's/O worse/O nightmare/O :/O disappearing/O into/O thin/O air/O ,/O i.e./O into/O the/O hands/O of/O Chinese/O officials/O ./O 
People/O always/O felt/O safe/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ./O 
No/O more/O !/O 
According/O to/O police/O sources/O ,/O there/O is/O no/O record/O showing/O of/O Lee/PERSON Bo/PERSON crossing/O the/O border/O ./O 
The/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION government/O says/O it/O knows/O nothing/O about/O it/O ./O 
I/O am/O inclined/O to/O believe/O that/O since/O it/O counts/O for/O nothing/O ./O 
Secret/O agents/O do/O not/O ask/O permission/O to/O act/O against/O dissidents/O ,/O or/O use/O legal/O procedures/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O are/O silent/O ./O 
Or/O rather/O ,/O they/O have/O admitted/O something/O ,/O namely/O that/O Lee/PERSON Bo/PERSON ,/O despite/O his/O British/O passport/O ,/O is/O still/O Chinese/O ./O 
This/O is/O an/O unusual/O way/O of/O interpreting/O international/O law/O ./O 
The/O consequences/O of/O the/O mysterious/O kidnappings/O have/O been/O devastating/O ./O 
Books/O that/O criticise/O the/O Chinese/O regime/O have/O been/O removed/O from/O the/O city/O 's/O bookstores/O ./O 
Yu/PERSON Jie/PERSON ,/O a/O Chinese/O dissident/O who/O lives/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION said/O thatOpen/O ,/O a/O Hong/LOCATION Kong-based/LOCATION publishing/O house/O ,/O has/O decided/O not/O to/O publish/O his/O book/O on/O Xi/O Jinping/O ,/O which/O is/O already/O finished/O ./O 
The/O chief/O editor/O ofOpen/O Magazine/O ,/O the/O foremost/O China-watcher/O publication/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O announced/O that/O he/O plans/O to/O immigrate/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION in/O the/O coming/O weeks/O ./O 
Anyone/O who/O has/O been/O outspoken/O is/O now/O afraid/O ./O 
In/O mainland/O China/LOCATION ,/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION was/O disparagingly/O described/O as/O a/O `/O cultural/O desert/O '/O ./O 
That/O was/O unfair/O ./O 
But/O now/O it/O is/O truly/O turning/O into/O a/O culturally/O conformist/O desert/O ./O 
Through/O self-censorship/O ,/O and/O with/O minimal/O efforts/O ,/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION regime/O is/O having/O resounding/O success/O ./O 
This/O is/O not/O the/O beginning/O of/O the/O end/O ;/O it/O is/O the/O end/O ./O 
The/O beginning/O came/O when/O ,/O a/O few/O years/O ago/O ,/O nothing/O was/O done/O to/O pursue/O the/O city/O 's/O process/O of/O democratic/O development/O as/O desired/O by/O the/O people/O and/O as/O required/O under/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O Basic/O Law/O ,/O which/O regulates/O its/O constitutional/O life/O ./O 
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O agony/O will/O last/O a/O few/O more/O years/O ./O 
Most/O publications/O are/O already/O in/O the/O hands/O of/O friends/O of/O those/O in/O power/O ,/O including/O ,/O unfortunately/O ,/O the/O daily/O South/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Morning/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Those/O journalists/O who/O had/O a/O critical/O voice/O have/O been/O elbowed/O out/O one/O by/O one/O ,/O without/O too/O much/O fuss/O ./O 
Softly/O but/O surely/O ,/O the/O purge/O will/O be/O completed/O ./O 
Eventually/O ,/O this/O will/O happen/O in/O education/O ./O 
Then/O religions/O will/O be/O asked/O to/O follow/O the/O party/O line/O ./O 
It/O is/O a/O matter/O of/O time/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION some/O socially/O active/O residents/O ,/O including/O some/O foreign/O missionaries/O ,/O have/O been/O received/O unsolicited/O visits/O from/O kind/O Chinese/O ``/O scholars/O ''/O who/O ask/O them/O many/O questions/O ,/O about/O their/O views/O and/O what/O they/O know/O ./O 
They/O are/O always/O courteous/O and/O kind/O ,/O but/O what/O lies/O behind/O such/O visits/O is/O very/O clear/O ./O 
Things/O in/O general/O are/O no/O more/O complicated/O than/O they/O appear/O ./O 
All/O it/O takes/O is/O having/O a/O pair/O of/O eyes/O to/O see/O ./O 
Under/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O respect/O for/O human/O rights/O and/O religious/O freedom/O has/O taken/O a/O backseat/O ./O 
In/O China/LOCATION ,/O journalists/O continue/O to/O be/O arrested/O ,/O disappear/O or/O endure/O otherwise/O restrictive/O measures/O ./O 
So/O far/O ,/O 49/O journalists/O have/O been/O detained/O ./O 
Nosy/O foreign/O journalists/O have/O been/O expelled/O ,/O the/O latest/O case/O involving/O French/O journalist/O Ursula/PERSON Gauthier/PERSON ,/O who/O wrote/O an/O article/O about/O the/O repression/O suffered/O by/O the/O Uighur/O population/O in/O western/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Unfortunately/O ,/O human/O rights/O lawyers/O ,/O who/O represented/O real/O hope/O ,/O have/O been/O targeted/O as/O well/O ./O 
More/O than/O 700/O ,/O law/O professionals/O and/O associates/O ,/O have/O been/O detained/O ,/O arrested/O ,/O or/O prevented/O from/O working/O ./O 
Since/O 2009/O ,/O 145/O Tibetan/O Buddhists/O set/O themselves/O on/O fire/O in/O protest/O against/O China/LOCATION 's/O oppressive/O policy/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
By/O and/O large/O ,/O this/O tragedy/O has/O been/O ignored/O ./O 
Christians/O too/O suffer/O ./O 
More/O than/O a/O thousand/O crosses/O have/O been/O taken/O down/O ,/O and/O many/O churches/O have/O been/O demolished/O ./O 
Above/O all/O ,/O there/O is/O the/O sad/O and/O disturbing/O case/O of/O Wei/PERSON Heping/PERSON ,/O a/O young/O and/O brave/O priest/O serving/O an/O underground/O Catholic/O community/O ,/O who/O was/O found/O dead/O in/O the/O Fen/LOCATION River/LOCATION in/O Shanxi/LOCATION under/O suspicious/O circumstances/O ./O 
The/O tragedy/O took/O place/O on/O 7/O November/O 2015/O ./O 
At/O first/O ,/O the/O police/O hurriedly/O ruled/O the/O case/O a/O suicide/O ./O 
Nothing/O suggests/O this/O conclusion/O ./O 
Many/O believe/O he/O met/O a/O violent/O death/O because/O of/O his/O influence/O with/O young/O people/O and/O online/O ./O 
For/O many/O Catholics/O he/O is/O a/O martyr/O ./O 
If/O that/O were/O the/O case/O ,/O he/O would/O be/O the/O first/O priest/O killed/O in/O China/LOCATION in/O 25/O years/O ./O 
His/O fate/O is/O like/O that/O of/O Fr/O Jerzy/PERSON Popieluszko/PERSON ,/O a/O Polish/O priest/O who/O was/O killed/O by/O government/O agents/O in/O 1984/O ,/O and/O is/O now/O a/O blessed/O ./O 
In/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O Wei/PERSON Heping/PERSON was/O remembered/O by/O hundreds/O of/O faithful/O on/O 30/O December/O ,/O at/O the/O same/O time/O as/O Lee/PERSON Bo/PERSON was/O being/O deported/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
A/O journalist/O friend/O does/O not/O share/O my/O pessimism/O about/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O fate/O ./O 
He/O says/O that/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION will/O make/O it/O ./O 
I/O sincerely/O hope/O he/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mine/O is/O not/O a/O forlorn/O pessimism/O ,/O but/O a/O simple/O reading/O of/O the/O facts/O ./O 
Things/O are/O almost/O always/O as/O they/O appear/O ,/O and/O they/O almost/O always/O end/O as/O expected/O ./O 
The/O latest/O events/O show/O us/O that/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O fate/O and/O that/O of/O China/LOCATION are/O now/O the/O same/O ./O 
There/O will/O be/O no/O more/O freedom/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O unless/O the/O same/O freedom/O also/O comes/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
