Since/O taking/O office/O President/O Obama/PERSON has/O worked/O hard/O to/O improve/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O relationship/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
While/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION grow/O closer/O together/O ,/O Europe/LOCATION could/O find/O itself/O relegated/O to/O the/O sidelines/O ./O 
In/O a/O move/O that/O was/O n't/O widely/O reported/O ,/O but/O probably/O did/O n't/O go/O unnoticed/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON last/O month/O turned/O the/O authority/O to/O monitor/O and/O approve/O missile/O and/O technology/O sales/O to/O China/LOCATION from/O the/O <LOCATION>White/ORGANIZATION House/ORGANIZATION</LOCATION> to/O the/O Commerce/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION ./O 
While/O the/O administration/O says/O the/O change/O wo/O n't/O loosen/O the/O strict/O rules/O on/O military/O technology/O exports/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O non-proliferation/O experts/O noted/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O enforcement/O of/O export/O rules/O was/O turned/O over/O to/O the/O Commerce/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION to/O promote/O US/LOCATION business/O interests/O instead/O of/O the/O Pentagon/ORGANIZATION or/O the/O State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Earlier/O ,/O Obama/PERSON 's/O decision/O not/O to/O meet/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON before/O the/O president/O 's/O upcoming/O trip/O to/O China/LOCATION -/O the/O first/O presidential/O snub/O for/O Tibet/LOCATION 's/O spiritual/O leader/O since/O 1991/O -/O had/O made/O international/O news/O and/O triggered/O a/O debate/O about/O a/O possible/O shift/O of/O <LOCATION>US/O</LOCATION> -/O <LOCATION>China/O</LOCATION> policy/O ./O 
Another/O indicator/O of/O a/O new/O US/LOCATION approach/O was/O a/O statement/O by/O Secretary/O of/O <OTHER>State/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Hillary/PERSON Clinton/PERSON that/O human/O rights/O issues/O were/O still/O part/O of/O <LOCATION>US/O</LOCATION> -/O <LOCATION>China/O</LOCATION> policy/O ,/O but/O could/O n't/O ultimately/O damage/O the/O relationship/O ./O 
A/O third/O aspect/O of/O a/O change/O in/O the/O <LOCATION>White/ORGANIZATION House/ORGANIZATION</LOCATION> 's/O human/O rights/O policy/O toward/O China/LOCATION are/O its/O dealings/O with/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> and/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ./O 
``/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> in/O previous/O administrations/O was/O having/O meetings/O with/O the/O president/O ./O 
She/O has/O found/O it/O very/O difficult/O to/O get/O a/O similiar/O level/O of/O access/O ,/O even/O to/O meet/O with/O a/O number/O of/O officials/O on/O lower/O levels/O in/O the/O administration/O and/O the/O Chinese/O are/O aware/O of/O this/O too/O ,/O ''/O said/O Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON ,/O a/O China/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>German/O</ORGANIZATION> Marshall/ORGANIZATION Fund/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
All/O these/O instances/O ,/O adds/O <PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> ,/O constitute/O a/O clear/O change/O in/O human/O rights/O policy/O from/O earlier/O administrations/O ./O 
That/O shift/O in/O focus/O by/O the/O new/O administration/O -/O less/O emphasis/O on/O human/O rights/O issues/O ,/O more/O emphasis/O on/O trade/O and/O security/O issues/O -/O is/O reminiscent/O of/O a/O China/LOCATION approach/O favored/O by/O German/O Chancellor/O Gerhard/PERSON Schroeder/PERSON ./O 
During/O his/O tenure/O from/O 1998/O to/O 2005/O he/O repeatedly/O argued/O for/O overturning/O a/O EU/ORGANIZATION weapons/O embargo/O against/O China/LOCATION ,/O but/O his/O move/O was/O rejected/O at/O home/O by/O the/O Green/ORGANIZATION <OTHER>party/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ,/O his/O coalition/O partner/O ,/O and/O abroad/O by/O other/O EU/ORGANIZATION member/O states/O ./O 
President/O Obama/PERSON may/O prove/O to/O be/O more/O successful/O in/O altering/O US/LOCATION human/O rights/O policy/O toward/O China/LOCATION than/O Chancellor/O Schroeder/PERSON was/O in/O his/O efforts/O to/O reframe/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION 's/O China/LOCATION policy/O ./O 
Still/O ,/O argue/O experts/O ,/O aside/O from/O human/O rights/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O approach/O toward/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O very/O much/O a/O continuation/O of/O long-standing/O US/LOCATION foreign/O policy/O ./O 
``/O There/O are/O significant/O elements/O of/O continuity/O with/O the/O Bush/PERSON policy/O on/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O <PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> ./O 
Good/O grades/O 
Josef/PERSON Braml/PERSON ,/O a/O US/LOCATION expert/O with/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>German/O Council/O on/O Foreign/O Relations/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O agreed/O :/O ``/O I/O think/O there/O is/O a/O continuity/O of/O American/O foreign/O policy/O toward/O China/LOCATION which/O can/O be/O labeled/O `/O congagement/O ,/O '/O a/O convergence/O of/O two/O diverting/O strategies/O -/O containment/O and/O engagement/O ./O ''/O 
The/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> has/O to/O wait/O until/O he/O can/O meet/O President/O Bush/PERSON 's/O successor/O ./O 
Relations/O between/O Washington/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION have/O improved/O under/O Obama/PERSON to/O an/O extent/O that/O even/O when/O the/O US/LOCATION slapped/O tariffs/O on/O Chinese/O tires/O ,/O the/O reaction/O from/O China/LOCATION was/O rather/O restrained/O ./O 
``/O I/O think/O the/O Chinese/O have/O treated/O some/O of/O these/O trade/O and/O economic/O issues/O with/O some/O degree/O of/O equanimity/O ,/O partly/O because/O of/O the/O policy/O on/O issues/O such/O as/O the/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> and/O contacts/O with/O <U_PERSON>Rabiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> as/O well/O have/O been/O placatory/O to/O the/O Chinese/O ,/O ''/O said/O <PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> ,/O adding/O that/O Obama/PERSON 's/O first/O year/O gets/O very/O good/O grades/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION :/O ``/O The/O Chinese/O expect/O a/O lot/O tensions/O usually/O in/O the/O first/O year/O of/O a/O new/O administration/O and/O the/O fact/O that/O it/O has/O been/O restricted/O largely/O to/O some/O of/O these/O trade/O issues/O in/O what/O is/O in/O any/O case/O a/O difficult/O time/O for/O all/O sides/O on/O the/O trade/O issues/O -/O and/O the/O Chinese/O themselves/O are/O not/O averse/O to/O some/O of/O these/O protectionist/O measures/O too/O -/O they/O see/O the/O overall/O tenor/O of/O this/O first/O year/O as/O very/O positive/O ./O ''/O 
What/O 's/O more/O ,/O noted/O Braml/PERSON ,/O both/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION are/O basically/O forced/O to/O get/O along/O ,/O because/O they/O simply/O are/O dependent/O on/O each/O other/O ./O 
``/O If/O one/O wanted/O to/O describe/O it/O with/O a/O strategic/O metaphor/O ,/O there/O is/O a/O new/O MAD/O system/O -/O mutually/O assured/O destruction/O ./O 
China/LOCATION could/O destroy/O America/LOCATION if/O it/O pulled/O the/O trigger/O in/O terms/O of/O financing/O US/LOCATION debt/O ,/O but/O it/O would/O also/O hurt/O itself/O ./O ''/O 
With/O Beijing/LOCATION holding/O approximately/O two/O billion/O dollars/O ,/O mostly/O in/O government/O bonds/O ,/O it/O is/O a/O major/O financier/O of/O US/LOCATION debt/O ./O 
However/O ,/O a/O quick/O disposal/O of/O those/O funds/O would/O seriously/O undermine/O the/O value/O of/O the/O US/LOCATION dollar/O and/O by/O extension/O the/O ability/O of/O American/O consumers/O to/O buy/O Chinese/O products/O ./O 
Therefore/O both/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O US/LOCATION have/O an/O avid/O interest/O in/O good/O economic/O and/O political/O relations/O ./O 
While/O Obama/PERSON 's/O so/O called/O concept/O of/O ``/O strategic/O reassurance/O ''/O has/O been/O successful/O on/O the/O political/O and/O economic/O front/O at/O least/O for/O now/O and/O Washington/LOCATION still/O hopes/O it/O will/O lead/O to/O improved/O Chinese/O cooperation/O on/O Iran/LOCATION and/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION ,/O progress/O is/O more/O difficult/O on/O military/O issues/O ./O 
``/O This/O is/O an/O area/O where/O the/O blame/O that/O relations/O have/O not/O been/O improving/O on/O the/O military/O side/O lies/O very/O much/O with/O the/O Chinese/O ,/O ''/O said/O <PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> ./O 
``/O There/O have/O been/O a/O number/O of/O efforts/O on/O the/O US/LOCATION side/O to/O improve/O crisis/O management/O mechanisms/O ,/O to/O upgrade/O relations/O between/O the/O two/O militaries/O and/O the/O pushback/O comes/O from/O the/O Chinese/O side/O ./O ''/O 
Beijing/LOCATION still/O perceives/O Washington/LOCATION to/O be/O militarily/O superior/O and/O thinks/O the/O US/LOCATION will/O gain/O more/O from/O better/O cooperation/O than/O China/LOCATION ,/O he/O said/O ./O 
He/O predicts/O future/O tensions/O between/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION in/O the/O Asia-Pacific/LOCATION region/O until/O the/O Chinese/O military/O changes/O its/O stance/O toward/O cooperation/O ./O 
Euro-skeptic/O China/LOCATION 
Despite/O the/O slow/O pace/O of/O improving/O military/O ties/O -/O something/O that/O the/O Bush/PERSON administration/O had/O also/O worked/O on/O -/O relations/O between/O two/O of/O the/O world/O 's/O major/O players/O have/O improved/O so/O much/O under/O Obama/PERSON that/O there/O have/O been/O concerns/O about/O the/O so-called/O <ORGANIZATION>G2/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION ,/O determining/O international/O policy/O with/O others/O left/O to/O follow/O ./O 
``/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O so/O ,/O ''/O said/O Braml/PERSON ,/O adding/O that/O there/O remain/O many/O issues/O were/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION do/O n't/O see/O eye/O to/O eye/O and/O that/O Europe/LOCATION is/O still/O a/O more/O reliable/O partner/O and/O known/O quantity/O for/O Washington/LOCATION than/O China/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O policy/O is/O increasingly/O focused/O on/O the/O US/LOCATION instead/O of/O Europe/LOCATION 
<PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> also/O does/O n't/O believe/O that/O the/O US/LOCATION or/O China/LOCATION can/O actually/O decide/O alone/O ,/O but/O that/O unless/O there/O is/O an/O agreement/O between/O them/O ,/O it/O is/O very/O hard/O to/O achieve/O a/O global/O deal/O on/O an/O issue/O ./O 
``/O And/O if/O you/O look/O on/O the/O Chinese/O side/O ,/O there/O is/O a/O lot/O of/O what/O they/O would/O describe/O as/O Euro-skepticism/O where/O the/O China-European/O relationship/O has/O got/O to/O and/O a/O sense/O that/O <LOCATION>US/O</LOCATION> -/O <LOCATION>China/O</LOCATION> relations/O are/O continuing/O to/O move/O in/O a/O very/O good/O direction/O and/O if/O anything/O are/O being/O upgraded/O with/O the/O new/O administration/O which/O has/O led/O them/O to/O become/O even/O more/O US-centric/O than/O they/O were/O before/O ./O ''/O 
The/O Obama/PERSON administration/O 's/O more/O pragmatic/O and/O multilateral/O approach/O to/O foreign/O policy/O places/O less/O of/O an/O emphasis/O on/O the/O traditional/O transatlantic/O relations/O than/O previous/O US/LOCATION governments/O ./O 
``/O And/O that/O 's/O meant/O that/O countries/O like/O China/LOCATION in/O particular/O and/O Russia/LOCATION are/O seeing/O quite/O a/O different/O environment/O and/O in/O some/O cases/O that/O is/O taking/O place/O at/O the/O expense/O of/O ties/O with/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O <PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> ./O 
``/O The/O standing/O of/O Europe/LOCATION for/O the/O new/O administration/O you/O would/O have/O to/O say/O in/O the/O grand/O scheme/O of/O things/O is/O probably/O not/O as/O high/O as/O it/O was/O under/O Bush/PERSON ./O ''/O 
Author/O :/O Michael/PERSON Knigge/PERSON 
Editor/O :/O Rob/PERSON Mudge/PERSON
