Portugal/LOCATION has/O agreed/O to/O take/O in/O a/O number/O of/O Guantanamo/LOCATION detainees/O as/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O drive/O to/O convince/O European/O states/O to/O accept/O former/O prisoners/O gathers/O pace/O ./O 
After/O EU/ORGANIZATION foreign/O ministers/O endorsed/O a/O deal/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION last/O week/O on/O transferring/O Guantanamo/LOCATION inmates/O to/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O while/O stressing/O that/O the/O decision/O to/O accept/O any/O inmate/O was/O up/O to/O individual/O European/O governments/O ,/O Portugal/LOCATION followed/O Spain/LOCATION and/O Italy/LOCATION 's/O lead/O by/O announcing/O Saturday/O that/O it/O was/O ready/O to/O take/O in/O ``/O two/O or/O three/O ''/O detainees/O ./O 
``/O We/O will/O accept/O two/O or/O three/O prisoners/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O it/O 's/O up/O to/O us/O ,/O internally/O ,/O to/O carry/O out/O the/O necessary/O procedures/O to/O welcome/O them/O ,/O ''/O Foreign/O Minister/O Luis/PERSON Amado/PERSON said/O after/O a/O visit/O to/O Lisbon/LOCATION by/O US/LOCATION Special/O Envoy/O Daniel/PERSON Fried/PERSON ,/O the/O man/O charge/O with/O finding/O host/O countries/O for/O more/O than/O 200/O detainees/O Washington/LOCATION has/O chosen/O not/O to/O prosecute/O ./O 
Amado/PERSON said/O that/O the/O question/O of/O the/O ex-prisoners/O '/O status/O was/O currently/O being/O studied/O by/O the/O <OTHER>interior/ORGANIZATION ministry/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ./O 
Seven/O countries/O have/O agreed/O to/O take/O inmates/O 
Italy/LOCATION announced/O Monday/O that/O it/O would/O accept/O three/O Guantanamo/LOCATION inmates/O ,/O while/O Spain/LOCATION agreed/O in/O principle/O to/O take/O four/O ,/O dependent/O on/O their/O cases/O being/O reviewed/O by/O the/O foreign/O ministry/O ./O 
Last/O week/O nine/O former/O detainees/O were/O transferred/O to/O Chad/LOCATION ,/O Iraq/LOCATION and/O Bermuda/LOCATION ,/O while/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION island/O nation/O of/O Palau/LOCATION also/O agreed/O to/O take/O in/O a/O group/O of/O 13/O Chinese/O Uighurs/O ./O 
Portugal/LOCATION was/O the/O first/O country/O to/O press/O publicly/O for/O a/O coordinated/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION resettlement/O plan/O for/O Guantanamo/LOCATION prisoners/O back/O in/O December/O and/O is/O now/O the/O seventh/O country/O to/O take/O them/O ./O 
The/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION prison/O camp/O was/O opened/O under/O former/O US/LOCATION President/O George/PERSON W./PERSON Bush/PERSON to/O house/O ``/O enemy/O combatants/O ''/O in/O the/O government/O 's/O war/O on/O terror/O after/O the/O September/O 11/O ,/O 2001/O attacks/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Gitmo/O ''/O ,/O as/O it/O became/O known/O ,/O attracted/O widespread/O international/O criticism/O for/O holding/O prisoners/O indefinitely/O ,/O many/O without/O charge/O ./O 
US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON ordered/O the/O Guantanamo/LOCATION facility/O closed/O by/O January/O of/O next/O year/O and/O the/O inmates/O either/O face/O trial/O or/O release/O ./O 
Washington/LOCATION has/O since/O been/O pushing/O for/O other/O countries/O to/O accept/O inmates/O who/O have/O not/O been/O charged/O and/O are/O ready/O to/O be/O released/O ./O 
nda/O //O <ORGANIZATION>AFP/O</ORGANIZATION> //O <ORGANIZATION>Reuters/O</ORGANIZATION> 
Editor/O :/O Greg/PERSON Benzow/PERSON
