As/O politically/O and/O ethnically-charged/O violence/O continues/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O three/O powerful/O nations/O who/O have/O hugely/O important/O strategic/O and/O geopolitical/O interests/O in/O the/O region/O are/O becoming/O particularly/O concerned/O ./O 
The/O Central/O Asian/O nation/O 's/O worst/O ethnic/O violence/O in/O decades/O ,/O which/O has/O reportedly/O left/O at/O least/O 179/O people/O dead/O ,/O many/O more/O injured/O and/O has/O forced/O tens/O of/O thousands/O to/O flee/O their/O homes/O ,/O has/O wider/O implications/O in/O a/O region/O full/O of/O strategic/O and/O geopolitical/O importance/O for/O the/O world/O 's/O biggest/O powers/O ./O 
The/O violence/O that/O erupted/O on/O Friday/O between/O Kyrgyz/O and/O Uzbek/O clans/O may/O have/O been/O ignited/O by/O the/O escalating/O tensions/O between/O the/O country/O 's/O two/O dominant/O ethnic/O groups/O but/O the/O conditions/O for/O the/O fighting/O have/O been/O created/O by/O the/O on-going/O unstable/O political/O situation/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ;/O a/O situation/O that/O has/O the/O fingerprints/O of/O the/O world/O 's/O most/O influential/O nations/O all/O over/O it/O ./O 
Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION 's/O wider/O role/O in/O international/O affairs/O is/O such/O that/O Russia/LOCATION and/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION continue/O to/O jostle/O for/O military/O influence/O there/O while/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O shares/O a/O 530-mile/O border/O with/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O pursues/O significant/O strategic/O and/O economic/O interests/O in/O the/O country/O and/O its/O surrounding/O region/O ./O 
This/O most/O recent/O uprising/O stems/O from/O the/O ousting/O of/O the/O Washington-friendly/O regime/O of/O President/O Kurmanbek/PERSON Bakiyev/PERSON in/O April/O which/O left/O the/O country/O in/O turmoil/O ./O 
Bakiyev/PERSON 's/O removal/O from/O power/O and/O the/O rise/O to/O power/O of/O the/O current/O provisional/O government/O has/O not/O only/O allowed/O ethnic/O tensions/O to/O reach/O boiling/O point/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION but/O could/O trigger/O a/O new/O struggle/O for/O proxy/O control/O of/O the/O country/O and/O the/O regional/O benefits/O which/O come/O with/O it/O ./O 
Bakiyev/PERSON 's/O installation/O as/O president/O in/O 2005/O with/O US/LOCATION backing/O may/O have/O provided/O Washington/LOCATION with/O a/O friendly/O government/O with/O whom/O to/O do/O business/O with/O but/O it/O also/O gave/O the/O US/LOCATION a/O significant/O foothold/O in/O a/O country/O that/O some/O strategists/O believe/O is/O paramount/O to/O its/O plans/O for/O regional/O dominance/O ./O 
Regional/O unrest/O could/O put/O US/LOCATION objectives/O under/O threat/O 
Unrest/O may/O put/O the/O US/LOCATION base/O at/O Manas/LOCATION under/O threat/O 
Experts/O say/O that/O it/O has/O been/O a/O prime/O US/LOCATION strategic/O objective/O to/O increase/O its/O influence/O in/O the/O former/O <LOCATION>Soviet/O</LOCATION> states/O of/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION since/O the/O collapse/O of/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION in/O 1991/O ./O 
The/O inclusion/O of/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION and/O three/O other/O central/O Asian/O states/O in/O NATO/ORGANIZATION 's/O Partnership/O for/O Peace/O program/O in/O 1994/O ,/O was/O seen/O as/O a/O major/O step/O toward/O increasing/O US/LOCATION military/O presence/O in/O the/O region/O which/O eventually/O led/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION base/O at/O Manas/LOCATION ,/O outside/O Bishkek/LOCATION in/O the/O north/O ,/O being/O established/O ./O 
``/O During/O the/O April/O unrest/O ,/O the/O <LOCATION>US/LOCATION Manas/ORGANIZATION Airbase/ORGANIZATION</LOCATION> was/O closed/O and/O the/O vital/O supply/O route/O for/O sending/O military/O hardware/O and/O troops/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION was/O not/O being/O used/O ,/O ''/O Asher/PERSON Pirt/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O on/O Central/O Asian/O affairs/O and/O military/O issues/O ,/O told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O The/O US/LOCATION needs/O a/O stable/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION in/O order/O to/O keep/O the/O supply/O route/O working/O ./O ''/O 
``/O There/O is/O also/O the/O possibility/O of/O Uzbek/O intervention/O in/O the/O restive/O Osh/LOCATION region/O due/O to/O the/O fact/O that/O Uzbeks/O are/O being/O killed/O and/O hurt/O in/O the/O violence/O and/O any/O such/O intervention/O is/O likely/O to/O lead/O to/O further/O instability/O and/O will/O continue/O cause/O problems/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION principle/O supply/O route/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O its/O troops/O deployed/O there/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
``/O Another/O issue/O is/O if/O the/O instability/O spreads/O throughout/O the/O rest/O of/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O there/O is/O a/O rise/O of/O Islamic/O extremism/O this/O could/O significantly/O affect/O US/LOCATION interests/O in/O the/O region/O ./O ''/O 
US/LOCATION presence/O increases/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O concern/O over/O NATO/ORGANIZATION plans/O 
While/O <LOCATION>Manas/PERSON</LOCATION> remains/O a/O key/O hub/O for/O US/LOCATION operations/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O it/O is/O also/O used/O as/O a/O NATO/ORGANIZATION base/O -/O a/O situation/O which/O angers/O and/O concerns/O Russia/LOCATION which/O fears/O the/O eastern/O enlargement/O of/O its/O former/O Cold/O War/O opponent/O ,/O putting/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION at/O the/O center/O of/O a/O power/O struggle/O for/O regional/O influence/O ./O 
Medvedev/PERSON wants/O a/O friendly/O government/O in/O Bishkek/LOCATION 
``/O The/O current/O unrest/O is/O a/O major/O threat/O to/O the/O authority/O of/O the/O Kyrgyz/O government/O ,/O ''/O <PERSON>Dex/ORGANIZATION Torrike-Barton/ORGANIZATION</PERSON> ,/O an/O international/O security/O analyst/O ,/O told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION from/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O The/O provisional/O government/O is/O still/O very/O weak/O ./O 
If/O violence/O spreads/O beyond/O the/O cities/O currently/O affected/O ,/O then/O we/O could/O see/O major/O political/O instability/O ./O 
In/O that/O context/O ,/O all/O bets/O are/O off/O the/O table/O on/O whether/O the/O US/LOCATION can/O retain/O its/O airbase/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
There/O are/O plenty/O of/O political/O factions/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION who/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O see/O the/O Americans/O keep/O any/O sort/O of/O foothold/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
If/O Russia/LOCATION or/O the/O Collective/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Treaty/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION -/O the/O regional/O defence/O alliance/O -/O ultimately/O ends/O up/O intervening/O ,/O the/O same/O result/O is/O likely/O ./O ''/O 
Russia/LOCATION ,/O which/O itself/O has/O its/O own/O military/O base/O at/O the/O <LOCATION>Kant/O</LOCATION> airbase/O near/O Bishkek/LOCATION and/O a/O strategic/O naval/O base/O on/O Lake/LOCATION Issyk-Kul/LOCATION ,/O is/O highly/O suspicious/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION '/O interest/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION and/O the/O wider/O Eurasian/O region/O ./O 
Since/O the/O US-backed/O Bakiyev/PERSON regime/O was/O ousted/O in/O April/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION has/O unsurprisingly/O been/O the/O biggest/O supporter/O of/O the/O new/O provisional/O government/O ,/O presumably/O in/O the/O hope/O that/O if/O order/O is/O restored/O the/O swing/O of/O influence/O will/O return/O to/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
Washington/LOCATION 's/O plans/O for/O the/O regions/O sit/O very/O uncomfortably/O with/O the/O Kremlin/LOCATION ./O 
While/O the/O US/LOCATION may/O justify/O that/O its/O increased/O influence/O is/O mutually/O beneficial/O by/O claiming/O its/O presence/O will/O help/O stop/O the/O spread/O of/O Islamic/O fundamentalism/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O solve/O the/O hugely/O destabilizing/O problem/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION believes/O the/O US/LOCATION has/O another/O agenda/O ./O 
The/O <LOCATION>Kremlin/ORGANIZATION</LOCATION> says/O that/O Washington/LOCATION is/O aiming/O to/O prevent/O Russian/O and/or/O Chinese/O hegemony/O while/O securing/O energy/O resources/O and/O pipelines/O ./O 
Read/O more/O about/O the/O volatile/O situation/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION 
Moscow/LOCATION fears/O ethnic/O instability/O on/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O borders/O 
Russia/LOCATION has/O its/O own/O interests/O of/O course/O ./O 
As/O well/O as/O the/O obvious/O future/O of/O regional/O energy/O security/O ,/O Russian/O domestic/O security/O is/O heavily/O linked/O to/O the/O stability/O of/O the/O countries/O on/O its/O borders/O ./O 
Regardless/O of/O whether/O there/O is/O a/O Kremlin-friendly/O regime/O in/O place/O or/O not/O ,/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION is/O of/O huge/O importance/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O the/O stability/O or/O instability/O of/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O neighbours/O ./O 
With/O states/O throughout/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O Central/O Asian/O periphery/O simmering/O with/O ethnic/O tensions/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION does/O n't/O need/O a/O civil/O war/O sparking/O a/O wider/O conflict/O on/O its/O doorstep/O ,/O one/O which/O could/O spread/O to/O within/O its/O borders/O and/O explode/O in/O its/O cities/O ./O 
Russia/LOCATION wants/O to/O avoid/O a/O spread/O of/O unrest/O around/O its/O borders/O 
``/O Russia/LOCATION wants/O a/O stable/O international/O neighbourhood/O ,/O ''/O Torrike-Barton/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O Violence/O ,/O especially/O with/O an/O ethnic/O or/O religious/O dimension/O ,/O could/O potentially/O become/O contagious/O throughout/O the/O region/O ./O 
The/O brutalization/O of/O the/O Uzbek/O community/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION could/O fuel/O Islamic/O extremism/O -/O and/O there/O is/O no/O greater/O nightmare/O for/O a/O Russian/O state/O still/O dealing/O with/O insurgent/O forces/O in/O the/O Caucasus/O ./O ''/O 
``/O It/O is/O not/O in/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O interests/O to/O have/O an/O unstable/O Kyrgyz/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION as/O it/O will/O affect/O their/O interests/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Asher/PERSON Pirt/PERSON added/O ./O 
``/O The/O main/O interest/O is/O the/O fact/O that/O Moscow/LOCATION is/O concerned/O about/O instability/O spreading/O from/O the/O region/O to/O its/O own/O country/O ./O 
A/O stable/O region/O without/O ethnic/O unrest/O or/O religious/O extremism/O is/O a/O strategic/O goal/O for/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
Furthermore/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION cares/O about/O the/O status/O and/O the/O wellbeing/O of/O its/O ethnic/O Russians/O or/O compatriots/O ./O ''/O 
``/O Russia/LOCATION is/O unlikely/O to/O intervene/O unless/O it/O felt/O that/O the/O situation/O was/O going/O to/O make/O the/O region/O unstable/O or/O ethnic/O Russians/O or/O compatriots/O were/O in/O danger/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O Kyrgyz/ORGANIZATION Provisional/ORGANIZATION Government/ORGANIZATION would/O very/O much/O like/O the/O Russians/O to/O intervene/O ./O 
At/O present/O it/O is/O unlikely/O that/O this/O will/O happen/O but/O if/O the/O violence/O escalates/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION might/O decide/O that/O it/O has/O to/O ./O ''/O 
Russia/LOCATION is/O also/O concerned/O about/O the/O possibility/O of/O being/O encircled/O by/O NATO/ORGANIZATION member/O states/O should/O the/O alliance/O go/O ahead/O with/O its/O provocative/O eastern/O enlargement/O ./O 
Having/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION onside/O ,/O especially/O as/O a/O partner/O in/O the/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Organization/ORGANIZATION -/O the/O emerging/O Eurasian/O economic/O and/O military/O cooperation/O organization/O -/O would/O mean/O that/O Russia/LOCATION would/O continue/O to/O have/O a/O significant/O obstacle/O in/O its/O plan/O to/O block/O NATO/ORGANIZATION expansion/O ./O 
China/LOCATION wants/O to/O protect/O economic/O interests/O ,/O secrets/O from/O US/LOCATION 
China/LOCATION 's/O border/O with/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION presents/O its/O own/O problems/O 
China/LOCATION also/O has/O much/O to/O be/O concerned/O about/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O clear/O strategic/O interests/O in/O a/O stable/O and/O friendly/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION but/O also/O in/O keeping/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION from/O dominating/O the/O region/O ./O 
China/LOCATION was/O the/O main/O financial/O benefactor/O of/O President/O Askar/PERSON Akayev/PERSON ,/O a/O former/O US-backed/O leader/O who/O was/O dropped/O by/O Washington/LOCATION as/O soon/O as/O he/O took/O China/LOCATION 's/O cash/O ,/O and/O its/O huge/O economic/O clout/O remains/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O strongest/O weapon/O in/O retaining/O a/O foothold/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ./O 
While/O this/O is/O seen/O as/O crucial/O for/O China/LOCATION 's/O own/O plan/O of/O spreading/O its/O influence/O throughout/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O it/O is/O also/O an/O important/O factor/O in/O reducing/O the/O chances/O of/O the/O US/LOCATION doing/O the/O same/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O see/O increasing/O US/LOCATION influence/O as/O not/O only/O a/O threat/O to/O its/O plans/O for/O <LOCATION>Eurasia/ORGANIZATION</LOCATION> ,/O which/O along/O with/O promoting/O its/O emerging/O market/O policy/O also/O includes/O energy/O security/O and/O supply/O ,/O but/O also/O a/O threat/O to/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION itself/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O border/O with/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION runs/O along/O the/O outer/O reaches/O of/O the/O politically/O sensitive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Province/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> where/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O rioted/O in/O July/O 2009/O ./O 
``/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION is/O the/O number/O one/O export/O market/O for/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O ''/O said/O Torrike-Barton/PERSON ./O 
``/O It/O 's/O a/O profitable/O destination/O for/O Chinese/O goods/O and/O labourers/O ,/O so/O there/O 's/O an/O important/O economic/O dimension/O driving/O Chinese/O policy/O toward/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ./O 
But/O like/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O the/O key/O priority/O is/O security/O ./O 
An/O unstable/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION with/O a/O restive/O Muslim/O population/O does/O not/O help/O Chinese/O efforts/O to/O preserve/O stability/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O the/O Uighur/O community/O ./O ''/O 
While/O Beijing/LOCATION would/O be/O concerned/O by/O the/O possibility/O of/O an/O upsurge/O in/O ethnic/O violence/O stirring/O up/O further/O unrest/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O it/O is/O more/O concerned/O that/O the/O porous/O nature/O of/O the/O border/O is/O allowing/O US/LOCATION intelligence/O agencies/O to/O run/O covert/O destabilizing/O operations/O into/O the/O strategically/O vital/O and/O politically/O fragile/O province/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION believes/O the/O flow/O of/O people/O across/O the/O border/O gives/O US/LOCATION operations/O a/O perfect/O cover/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION is/O unlikely/O to/O intervene/O in/O the/O crisis/O ,/O and/O despite/O its/O economic/O influence/O and/O status/O as/O a/O patron/O for/O many/O Kyrgyz/O politicians/O ,/O has/O limited/O capacity/O to/O affect/O the/O current/O situation/O ,/O ''/O Torrike-Barton/PERSON added/O ./O 
``/O Without/O greater/O Chinese/O involvement/O in/O settling/O the/O violence/O ,/O I/O doubt/O we/O 'll/O see/O many/O repercussions/O for/O US-China/O relations/O ./O ''/O 
With/O so/O much/O suspicion/O ,/O distrust/O and/O power/O games/O at/O play/O bteween/O the/O world/O 's/O most/O powerful/O nations/O ,/O the/O future/O of/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION may/O not/O only/O shape/O the/O region/O but/O have/O an/O equally/O important/O influence/O on/O global/O politics/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Nick/PERSON Amies/PERSON 
<OTHER>Editor/PERSON</OTHER> :/O Rob/PERSON Mudge/PERSON
