The/O plight/O of/O Afghan/O refugees/O is/O known/O ,/O but/O less/O familiar/O are/O the/O dissidents/O and/O victims/O of/O civil/O war/O who/O have/O sought/O refuge/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION although/O the/O war-torn/O country/O has/O no/O asylum/O law/O as/O yet/O ./O 
Amir/PERSON Hamza/PERSON Halimov/PERSON fled/O to/O Kabul/LOCATION in/O the/O early/O 1990s/O ./O 
He/O was/O one/O of/O tens/O of/O thousands/O of/O Tajiks/O who/O crossed/O the/O border/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION when/O Emomali/PERSON Rahmon/PERSON became/O president/O and/O civil/O war/O broke/O out/O in/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ./O 
Most/O returned/O after/O the/O end/O of/O the/O war/O but/O Halimov/PERSON ,/O a/O dissident/O who/O feared/O repercussions/O because/O of/O his/O anti-regime/O activity/O if/O he/O returned/O ,/O stayed/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
He/O and/O his/O two/O sons/O live/O in/O a/O guesthouse/O provided/O by/O the/O Afghan/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Refugees/ORGANIZATION <ORGANIZATION>and/O Repatriations/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
The/O ministry/O has/O provided/O accommodation/O to/O about/O 150/O asylum/O seekers/O from/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Bangladesh/LOCATION and/O Iraq/LOCATION ./O 
Although/O there/O is/O no/O asylum/O law/O ,/O it/O acts/O according/O to/O the/O tradition/O of/O nanawatai/O that/O allows/O a/O beleaguered/O person/O ,/O even/O an/O enemy/O ,/O to/O enter/O the/O house/O of/O any/O other/O person/O and/O make/O a/O request/O of/O him/O which/O can/O not/O be/O refused/O ,/O even/O at/O the/O cost/O of/O the/O host/O 's/O own/O life/O or/O fortune/O ./O 
Amir/PERSON Hamza/PERSON Halimov/PERSON and/O his/O sons/O live/O precariously/O 
There/O are/O also/O countless/O numbers/O of/O separatists/O from/O Indian-administered/O Kashmir/LOCATION who/O have/O taken/O refuge/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION as/O well/O as/O Muslims/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O ./O 
Confused/O status/O 
Until/O now/O ,/O Halimov/PERSON 's/O food/O and/O living/O expenses/O had/O been/O covered/O by/O the/O ministry/O but/O he/O says/O this/O support/O stopped/O three/O months/O ago/O ./O 
Now/O he/O has/O to/O buy/O food/O on/O credit/O ./O 
He/O can/O not/O work/O because/O his/O status/O is/O unclear/O ./O 
He/O has/O spent/O six/O years/O going/O from/O one/O authority/O to/O the/O next/O to/O clear/O his/O case/O but/O in/O vain/O ./O 
He/O is/O still/O not/O officially/O recognized/O as/O an/O asylum/O seeker/O nor/O does/O he/O have/O Afghan/O nationality/O ./O 
The/O Afghan/O president/O has/O the/O right/O to/O grant/O Afghan/O nationality/O if/O he/O wants/O to/O ./O 
Earlier/O this/O month/O ,/O four/O Iranians/O who/O fled/O their/O country/O after/O taking/O part/O in/O post-election/O protests/O in/O 2009/O were/O granted/O Afghan/O nationality/O by/O President/O Hamid/PERSON Karzai/PERSON ./O 
Amir/PERSON Hamza/PERSON Halimov/PERSON is/O still/O struggling/O to/O overcome/O all/O the/O red/O tape/O 
The/O government/O is/O currently/O drafting/O asylum/O and/O nationality/O legislation/O ./O 
Finally/O Afghanistan/LOCATION will/O be/O ``/O a/O country/O that/O can/O provide/O refuge/O in/O the/O classical/O sense/O ''/O says/O Karl/PERSON Kopp/PERSON from/O German/O rights/O organization/O <ORGANIZATION>Pro/LOCATION Asyl/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
People/O persecuted/O for/O political/O reasons/O or/O fleeing/O civil/O war/O will/O be/O able/O to/O apply/O for/O asylum/O ./O 
The/O country/O can/O be/O a/O ``/O corridor/O of/O protection/O ''/O in/O a/O region/O where/O there/O is/O no/O traditional/O system/O of/O protection/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Kopp/PERSON points/O out/O that/O the/O main/O problem/O is/O still/O how/O to/O create/O stable/O ,/O secure/O conditions/O in/O the/O devastated/O country/O ./O
