The/O leader/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION 's/O exiled/O government/O ,/O Lobsang/PERSON Sangay/PERSON ,/O spoke/O with/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> about/O his/O new/O campaign/O aimed/O at/O resuming/O long-stalled/O talks/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O softening/O China/LOCATION 's/O handling/O of/O his/O homeland/O ./O 
The/O prime/O minister/O of/O the/O Central/ORGANIZATION Tibetan/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CTA/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O has/O reaffirmed/O his/O commitment/O to/O the/O ``/O Middle/O Way/O ''/O approach/O of/O engaging/O the/O Chinese/O government/O through/O dialogue/O to/O achieve/O what/O his/O government/O calls/O ``/O genuine/O autonomy/O ''/O for/O Tibetans/O within/O the/O country/O ./O 
Sangay/PERSON 's/O announcement/O comes/O as/O the/O CTA/ORGANIZATION launches/O a/O global/O publicity/O campaign/O to/O persuade/O world/O governments/O to/O put/O pressure/O on/O China/LOCATION to/O restart/O dialogue/O with/O exiled/O Tibetans/O ./O 
Formal/O talks/O between/O the/O Chinese/O government/O and/O the/O CTA/ORGANIZATION reached/O a/O stalemate/O in/O 2010/O following/O leadership/O changes/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O a/O crackdown/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O ruled/O Tibet/LOCATION since/O 1950/O ,/O and/O many/O Tibetans/O feel/O their/O intensely/O Buddhist/O culture/O is/O at/O risk/O of/O erosion/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O political/O and/O economic/O domination/O ./O 
In/O a/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> interview/O ,/O Sangay/PERSON says/O he/O hopes/O the/O Xi/O Jinping-led/O Chinese/O government/O will/O review/O its/O hard-line/O approach/O and/O accept/O dialogue/O as/O the/O only/O way/O to/O peacefully/O resolve/O the/O Tibet/LOCATION issue/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> :/O Given/O that/O the/O mother/O of/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON was/O a/O Buddhist/ORGANIZATION and/O his/O father/O was/O on/O friendly/O terms/O with/O the/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> ,/O have/O you/O seen/O any/O changes/O in/O the/O attitude/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O leaders/O toward/O national/O minorities/O in/O general/O and/O the/O Tibetans/O in/O particular/O ?/O 
Lobsang/PERSON Sangay/PERSON :/O We/O have/O heard/O reports/O that/O discussions/O on/O minorities/O have/O been/O going/O on/O for/O some/O time/O ./O 
Recently/O ,/O scholars/O have/O contributed/O with/O their/O views/O on/O minorities/O and/O Tibetans/O in/O general/O ./O 
But/O we/O have/O yet/O to/O see/O any/O changes/O in/O the/O attitude/O of/O the/O Chinese/O leaders/O and/O the/O ground/O reality/O of/O repressive/O policies/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O is/O putting/O pressure/O on/O different/O governments/O not/O to/O meet/O with/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ,/O said/O Sangay/PERSON 
China/LOCATION 's/O growing/O clout/O in/O the/O international/O arena/O is/O very/O much/O felt/O by/O the/O Tibetans/O in/O exile/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O fewer/O and/O fewer/O governments/O are/O willing/O to/O meet/O with/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ./O 
Is/O time/O playing/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O favor/O ?/O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O is/O putting/O pressure/O on/O different/O governments/O not/O to/O meet/O with/O His/O Holiness/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ,/O misinforming/O about/O the/O Central/ORGANIZATION Tibetan/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION and/O its/O ``/O Middle/O Way/O ''/O approach/O ./O 
Yet/O on/O the/O people/O 's/O level/O ,/O interest/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION remains/O and/O it/O is/O important/O on/O our/O part/O to/O create/O more/O awareness/O and/O strengthen/O support/O from/O the/O international/O community/O ./O 
Time/O is/O not/O playing/O in/O support/O of/O China/LOCATION because/O even/O after/O 60/O years/O of/O occupation/O ,/O the/O third/O generation/O of/O Tibetans/O is/O in/O the/O streets/O protesting/O against/O the/O hard-line/O policies/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ,/O even/O though/O they/O are/O the/O beneficiaries/O of/O whatever/O Beijing/LOCATION claims/O to/O provide/O to/O Tibetans/O ./O 
Resentment/O and/O protests/O persist/O ./O 
The/O sense/O of/O unity/O and/O solidarity/O among/O Tibetans/O inside/O and/O outside/O has/O never/O been/O stronger/O in/O recent/O years/O ./O 
Given/O this/O foundation/O ,/O the/O Tibetan/O struggle/O is/O here/O to/O stay/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
<U_ORGANIZATION>WUC/O</U_ORGANIZATION> :/O China/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> policy/O `/O backfiring/O '/O 
A/O day/O after/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O suffered/O a/O major/O attack/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON Seytoff/PERSON</U_PERSON> of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Uighur/ORGANIZATION World/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> tells/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> the/O area/O is/O witnessing/O a/O violent/O response/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O 65-year-long/O ``/O brutal/O repression/O ''/O of/O Uighurs/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 23.05.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Opinion/O :/O China/LOCATION 's/O iron/O fist/O comes/O down/O where/O it/O should/O n't/O 
Over/O 30/O people/O have/O died/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O in/O a/O pointless/O attack/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O ``/O iron/O fist/O ''/O politics/O have/O failed/O to/O put/O an/O end/O to/O such/O violence/O for/O a/O reason/O ,/O says/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Matthias/PERSON von/PERSON Hein/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O 22.05.2014/O -RRB-/O 
China/LOCATION angry/O after/O Obama/PERSON 's/O meeting/O with/O <PERSON>Dalai/O Lama/O</PERSON> 
United/LOCATION States/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON has/O invoked/O the/O ire/O of/O China/LOCATION after/O meeting/O with/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON at/O the/O White/LOCATION House/LOCATION ./O 
Having/O warned/O the/O meeting/O would/O strain/O ties/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O now/O summoned/O a/O US/LOCATION diplomat/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 21.02.2014/O -RRB-/O 
India/LOCATION 's/O Tibetan/O women/O assuming/O bigger/O roles/O 
Tibetan/O women/O in/O exile/O are/O taking/O up/O leadership/O roles/O within/O their/O community/O ,/O challenging/O patriarchal/O stereotypes/O ./O 
In/O India/LOCATION ,/O many/O of/O these/O women/O are/O participating/O in/O workshops/O and/O trainings/O to/O hone/O their/O skills/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 01.01.2014/O -RRB-/O 
On/O Sunday/O -LRB-/O 08.06.2014/O -RRB-/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O Foreign/O Minister/O Wang/PERSON Yi/PERSON will/O meet/O with/O India/LOCATION 's/O new/O prime/O minister/O ,/O Narendra/PERSON Modi/PERSON ./O 
Could/O a/O thaw/O in/O Indo-Chinese/O ties/O potentially/O threaten/O the/O status/O of/O the/O Central/ORGANIZATION Tibetan/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION ,/O based/O in/O the/O Indian/O city/O of/O Dharamsala/LOCATION ?/O 
No/O ./O 
India/LOCATION 's/O policies/O over/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O its/O treatment/O of/O Tibetans/O have/O remained/O the/O same/O ,/O regardless/O of/O who/O is/O in/O power/O ./O 
We/O believe/O and/O hope/O the/O government/O of/O the/O recently/O elected/O Prime/O Minister/O Narendra/PERSON Modi/PERSON will/O continue/O the/O same/O policies/O ./O 
I/O hope/O China/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O minister/O will/O appreciate/O India/LOCATION 's/O unity/O in/O diversity/O and/O democracy/O as/O the/O foundation/O that/O keeps/O multilingual/O ,/O multiethnic/O India/LOCATION united/O as/O one/O country/O ./O 
We/O regard/O similar/O policies/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O towards/O Tibetan/O people/O as/O a/O win-win/O proposition/O ./O 
What/O exactly/O do/O you/O expect/O from/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ?/O 
We/O hope/O the/O Xi/O Jinping-led/O government/O will/O review/O its/O hard-line/O approach/O and/O introduce/O liberal/O policies/O towards/O Tibetans/O ./O 
I/O hope/O that/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON will/O accept/O dialogue/O as/O the/O only/O way/O to/O resolve/O the/O Tibet/LOCATION issue/O peacefully/O ./O 
To/O what/O extent/O are/O you/O willing/O to/O compromise/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION ?/O 
That/O is/O exactly/O what/O the/O ``/O Middle/O Way/O ''/O approach/O is/O all/O about/O ./O 
We/O would/O like/O to/O see/O an/O end/O to/O the/O present/O repression/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
If/O granted/O genuine/O autonomy/O within/O the/O framework/O of/O the/O Chinese/O constitution/O ,/O we/O will/O not/O seek/O separation/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
How/O has/O Chinese/O rule/O affected/O Tibet/LOCATION over/O the/O past/O decades/O ?/O 
Over/O the/O past/O decades/O there/O has/O been/O ongoing/O political/O repression/O ,/O social/O discrimination/O ,/O economic/O marginalization/O ,/O environmental/O destruction/O and/O cultural/O assimilation/O ,/O particularly/O due/O to/O Chinese/O migration/O to/O Tibet/LOCATION which/O is/O fueling/O intense/O resentment/O among/O the/O Tibetan/O people/O ./O 
How/O hopeful/O are/O you/O that/O China/LOCATION will/O begin/O a/O review/O of/O its/O Tibet/LOCATION policy/O ?/O 
Sangay/PERSON :/O ``/O The/O sense/O of/O unity/O and/O solidarity/O among/O Tibetans/O inside/O and/O outside/O has/O never/O been/O stronger/O ''/O 
Sooner/O or/O later/O ,/O China/LOCATION should/O realize/O that/O the/O hard-line/O policies/O are/O not/O working/O ./O 
Some/O 130/O self-immolations/O by/O Tibetans/O -/O which/O we/O discourage/O -/O should/O send/O a/O clear/O message/O to/O the/O Chinese/O government/O that/O it/O is/O time/O to/O enter/O into/O a/O dialogue/O between/O the/O envoys/O of/O His/O Holiness/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON and/O the/O representatives/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O 
Are/O Chinese/O authorities/O following/O a/O similar/O hard/O line/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION as/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ?/O 
Yes/O ./O 
From/O occupation/O until/O the/O present/O day/O ,/O the/O treatment/O of/O the/O Tibetan/O and/O Uighur/O people/O has/O been/O very/O similar/O ./O 
Sixty/O years/O of/O repression/O have/O not/O been/O working/O ./O 
It/O is/O time/O to/O give/O the/O ``/O Middle/O Way/O ''/O approach/O a/O chance/O ,/O for/O the/O dignity/O of/O the/O Tibetan/O people/O ,/O harmony/O within/O China/LOCATION and/O peace/O ./O 
Lobsang/PERSON Sangay/PERSON is/O the/O elected/O prime/O minister/O of/O the/O India-based/O Central/ORGANIZATION Tibetan/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION ,/O also/O referred/O to/O as/O the/O Tibetan/O government-in-exile/O ./O
