In/O case/O of/O a/O showdown/O over/O Ukraine/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION aims/O at/O replacing/O Europe/LOCATION with/O China/LOCATION to/O sell/O its/O huge/O reserves/O of/O oil/O and/O gas/O ,/O but/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O open/O to/O energy/O collaboration/O with/O the/O Kremlin/ORGANIZATION only/O on/O its/O own/O terms/O ./O 
Western/O powers/O and/O Russia/LOCATION keep/O on/O skirmishing/O over/O Ukraine/LOCATION ,/O and/O China/LOCATION is/O weighing/O its/O options/O in/O case/O of/O this/O war/O of/O attrition/O results/O in/O an/O energy/O dispute/O between/O the/O Kremlin/LOCATION and/O Europe/LOCATION ./O 
After/O Moscow/LOCATION 's/O annexation/O of/O Crimea/LOCATION ,/O a/O narrative/O that/O Russia/LOCATION could/O offset/O reduced/O demand/O of/O oil/O and/O gas/O from/O the/O <LOCATION>Old/O Continent/O</LOCATION> with/O export/O to/O Asia/LOCATION is/O brewing/O ,/O accompanied/O by/O concurrent/O remarks/O that/O the/O Chinese/O leadership/O might/O take/O advantage/O of/O the/O Russian/O need/O to/O reorient/O its/O energy/O sales/O should/O the/O European/O countries/O try/O to/O curb/O their/O reliance/O on/O commodities/O flowing/O from/O the/O former/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ./O 
The/O question/O is/O whether/O Russian/O President/O Vladimir/PERSON Putin/PERSON will/O succeed/O in/O diverting/O from/O Europe/LOCATION to/O China/LOCATION 130/O billion/O cubic/O meters/O -LRB-/O bcm/O -RRB-/O of/O gas/O annually/O ./O 
Russia/LOCATION covered/O 1.2/O percent/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O gas/O import/O in/O 2012/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O BP/ORGANIZATION <OTHER>Statistical/ORGANIZATION Review/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ./O 
In/O a/O memorandum/O of/O agreement/O signed/O in/O Moscow/LOCATION last/O year/O ,/O China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION estimate/O that/O annual/O deliveries/O of/O Russian/O gas/O will/O touch/O upon/O 38/O bcm/O from/O 2018/O on/O ./O 
It/O is/O since/O 2006/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O Moscow/LOCATION have/O been/O negotiating/O a/O gas/O deal/O in/O vain/O ./O 
China/ORGANIZATION National/ORGANIZATION Petroleum/ORGANIZATION Corporation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O and/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O Gazprom/ORGANIZATION still/O have/O not/O agreed/O on/O tariffs/O and/O supply/O routes/O ./O 
The/O last/O deadline/O missed/O was/O on/O January/O 31/O ,/O after/O China/LOCATION reiterated/O that/O it/O had/O no/O intention/O to/O pay/O the/O rates/O that/O Moscow/LOCATION was/O applying/O to/O European/O buyers/O ./O 
With/O regard/O to/O oil/O trade/O ,/O in/O 2013/O the/O two/O countries/O reached/O an/O arrangement/O whereby/O China/LOCATION would/O buy/O more/O than/O 355/O billion/O USD/O of/O Russian/O crude/O in/O the/O foreseeable/O future/O ./O 
Russia/LOCATION 's/O oil/O giant/O Rosneft/ORGANIZATION would/O let/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION explore/O three/O offshore/O Arctic/O blocks/O in/O exchange/O -/O Russia/LOCATION accounted/O for/O nine/O percent/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O crude/O imports/O in/O 2013/O ,/O US/ORGANIZATION Energy/ORGANIZATION Information/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION shows/O ./O 
It/O is/O probable/O that/O Moscow/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION are/O going/O to/O speed/O up/O negotiations/O on/O the/O long-delayed/O gas/O deal/O ,/O with/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ready/O to/O capitalize/O on/O the/O Kremlin/LOCATION 's/O present/O weak/O bargaining/O power/O to/O gain/O discounted/O prices/O ,/O but/O the/O Middle/LOCATION Kingdom/LOCATION will/O make/O every/O effort/O to/O avert/O a/O lethal/O embrace/O with/O its/O energy-rich/O neighbor/O ./O 
Europe/LOCATION 's/O dependence/O on/O Russian/O gas/O -/O not/O least/O via/O Ukraine/LOCATION 's/O territory/O -/O is/O a/O stark/O reminder/O that/O exposure/O to/O potential/O cuts/O of/O supplies/O by/O Moscow/LOCATION is/O a/O tangible/O danger/O for/O China/LOCATION ./O 
To/O minimize/O its/O energy/O security/O risk/O ,/O closer/O relations/O with/O Russia/LOCATION should/O be/O counterbalanced/O by/O both/O a/O more/O diversified/O energy/O basket/O and/O a/O variety/O of/O suppliers/O and/O relative/O transit/O routes/O ./O 
Coal/O and/O renewable/O energy/O 
``/O Energy/O independence/O means/O political/O independence/O ,/O ''/O Paolo/PERSON Scaroni/PERSON ,/O the/O outgoing/O chief/O executive/O of/O Italy/LOCATION 's/O ENI/ORGANIZATION ,/O was/O quoted/O as/O saying/O by/O the/O Italian/O daily/O Corriere/ORGANIZATION della/ORGANIZATION Sera/ORGANIZATION on/O March/O 25/O ./O 
By/O applying/O this/O concept/O to/O the/O case/O of/O Sino-Russian/O ties/O ,/O Scaroni/PERSON pointed/O out/O that/O China/LOCATION preferred/O to/O burn/O domestic/O coal/O -/O with/O a/O high/O level/O of/O pollution/O -/O rather/O than/O buying/O more/O oil/O and/O gas/O from/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O so/O as/O to/O protect/O its/O geopolitical/O autonomy/O ./O 
At/O most/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O turning/O to/O renewable/O energy/O to/O tackle/O pollution/O from/O coal/O combustion/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O indeed/O aims/O at/O adding/O 49/O gigawatts/O of/O renewable-energy/O capacity/O in/O 2014/O ,/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION National/ORGANIZATION Energy/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION stated/O on/O January/O 8/O ./O 
In/O addition/O to/O developing/O a/O more/O efficient/O use/O of/O coal/O and/O its/O shale/O gas/O resources/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O set/O to/O become/O the/O world/O 's/O biggest/O solar/O market/O ahead/O of/O Germany/LOCATION by/O installing/O roughly/O 5.40/O gigawatts/O of/O photovoltaic/O panels/O by/O the/O end/O of/O 2014/O ,/O Bloomberg/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION Energy/ORGANIZATION Finance/ORGANIZATION reported/O late/O last/O year/O ./O 
Geopolitics/O of/O transit/O routes/O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O engagement/O to/O open/O oil/O and/O gas/O links/O across/O Asia/LOCATION is/O a/O cornerstone/O of/O its/O foreign/O policy/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O search/O for/O new/O energy/O sources/O and/O transit/O passages/O is/O relevant/O for/O the/O government/O of/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON to/O such/O an/O extent/O that/O it/O is/O planning/O massive/O investments/O even/O in/O troubled/O regions/O ,/O where/O transport/O and/O trade/O are/O constantly/O at/O risk/O ./O 
The/O first/O target/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O geopolitics/O of/O pipelines/O is/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
In/O spite/O of/O persistent/O regional/O instability/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O poised/O to/O build/O the/O fourth/O branch/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION Gas/O Pipeline/O</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>CAGP/O</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O ./O 
Ushered/O in/O late/O 2009/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>CAGP/O</U_LOCATION> delivers/O Turkmen/O gas/O to/O China/LOCATION via/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION and/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O new/O strand/O of/O this/O Central/O Asian/O gas/O pipeline/O will/O run/O through/O Tajikistan/LOCATION and/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O outflanking/O the/O Kazakh/O territory/O ,/O cross-border/O tensions/O between/O these/O two/O former/O Soviet/O republics/O notwithstanding/O ./O 
The/O enhanced/O version/O of/O <U_LOCATION>CAGP/O</U_LOCATION> is/O expected/O to/O carry/O 80/O bcm/O of/O gas/O per/O year/O by/O 2020/O ,/O representing/O over/O 40/O percent/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O imports/O in/O this/O sector/O ,/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Free/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION wrote/O on/O March/O 24/O ,/O citing/O data/O from/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Shifting/O from/O north/O to/O south/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O also/O looking/O to/O the/O Indian/LOCATION Ocean/LOCATION to/O diversify/O its/O energy/O partners/O ./O 
In/O October/O 2013/O ,/O a/O conduit/O capable/O of/O piping/O 12/O bcm/O of/O gas/O each/O year/O from/O Myanmar/LOCATION 's/O west/O coast/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O southwest/O region/O went/O online/O ./O 
A/O parallel/O oil/O link/O that/O is/O purported/O to/O pump/O 440,000/O barrels/O of/O oil/O a/O day/O to/O China/LOCATION should/O go/O into/O operation/O by/O next/O June/O ./O 
While/O Beijing/LOCATION decreases/O its/O energy/O vulnerability/O with/O these/O new/O transit/O routes/O ,/O as/O vessels/O transporting/O oil/O and/O gas/O from/O Africa/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION can/O circumvent/O the/O Malacca/LOCATION Strait/LOCATION chokepoint/O ,/O it/O will/O concurrently/O struggle/O to/O protect/O its/O investments/O in/O the/O country/O once/O known/O as/O Burma/LOCATION ,/O where/O ethnic/O conflicts/O are/O common/O and/O sweep/O through/O areas/O crossed/O by/O the/O two/O pipelines/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Gwadar/LOCATION 
<OTHER>The/LOCATION</OTHER> Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION is/O yet/O another/O pivot/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O complex/O energy/O framework/O ./O 
During/O a/O meeting/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION with/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O officials/O on/O February/O 19/O ,/O China/LOCATION agreed/O to/O finance/O infrastructure/O projects/O worth/O 900/O million/O USD/O in/O the/O Pakistani/O port/O of/O Gwadar/LOCATION ./O 
These/O funds/O are/O part/O of/O a/O Chinese/O plan/O to/O channel/O 12/O billion/O USD/O into/O an/O economic/O corridor/O ,/O comprising/O a/O 2,000/O kilometer-long/O road/O link/O and/O a/O parallel/O railway/O ,/O which/O would/O connect/O the/O unstable/O southwestern/O Pakistani/O province/O of/O Balochistan/LOCATION with/O China/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O through/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Karakoram/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> mountain/O range/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O 's/O energy/O investments/O in/O volatile/O nations/O are/O risky/O but/O they/O contribute/O to/O alleviate/O its/O dependence/O on/O commodities/O imports/O from/O Russia/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION while/O allowing/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O expand/O its/O clout/O in/O the/O regions/O involved/O ./O 
Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION is/O paradigmatic/O in/O this/O sense/O ,/O given/O that/O its/O geography/O could/O provide/O China/LOCATION with/O strategic/O depth/O if/O it/O were/O to/O face/O a/O maritime/O encirclement/O in/O the/O future/O ./O 
Emanuele/PERSON Scimia/PERSON is/O a/O journalist/O and/O geopolitical/O analyst/O based/O in/O Italy/LOCATION ./O
