Cambodia/LOCATION 's/O Deputy/O Prime/O Minister/O Sar/PERSON Kheng/PERSON and/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O Immigration/O Minister/O Scott/PERSON <PERSON>Morrison/O</PERSON> <OTHER>signed/PERSON</OTHER> the/O agreement/O in/O Phnom/LOCATION Penh/LOCATION on/O Friday/O ,/O September/O 26/O ,/O in/O a/O four-minute-long/O ceremony/O that/O saw/O a/O tray/O of/O champagne/O flutes/O crash/O to/O the/O ground/O as/O they/O put/O pen/O to/O paper/O ./O 
The/O secretive/O agreement/O ,/O which/O has/O been/O under/O negotiation/O since/O February/O ,/O has/O been/O widely/O condemned/O by/O rights/O groups/O and/O others/O ./O 
The/O UN/ORGANIZATION High/O Commissioner/O for/O Refugees/O António/PERSON Guterres/PERSON condemned/O the/O deal/O to/O resettle/O refugees/O from/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION island/O of/O Nauru/LOCATION to/O Cambodia/LOCATION ,/O adding/O that/O he/O was/O ``/O deeply/O concerned/O ''/O at/O the/O precedent/O it/O set/O ./O 
``/O This/O is/O a/O worrying/O departure/O from/O international/O norms/O ./O 
We/O are/O seeing/O record/O forced/O displacement/O globally/O ,/O with/O 87/O percent/O of/O refugees/O now/O being/O hosted/O in/O developing/O countries/O ./O 
It/O is/O crucial/O that/O countries/O do/O not/O shift/O their/O refugee/O responsibilities/O elsewhere/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O International/O responsibility/O sharing/O is/O the/O basis/O on/O which/O the/O whole/O global/O refugee/O system/O works/O ./O 
I/O hope/O that/O the/O Australian/O government/O will/O reconsider/O its/O approach/O ,/O ''/O Guterres/PERSON added/O ./O 
UNHCR/ORGANIZATION :/O `/O This/O is/O a/O worrying/O departure/O from/O international/O norms/O '/O 
A/O joint/O statement/O handed/O to/O the/O media/O after/O Friday/O 's/O signing/O ceremony/O shed/O little/O new/O light/O on/O the/O issue/O beyond/O noting/O that/O Cambodia/LOCATION would/O decide/O when/O and/O how/O many/O refugees/O it/O would/O take/O ,/O and/O stating/O that/O there/O would/O be/O an/O ``/O initial/O trial/O arrangement/O with/O a/O small/O group/O of/O refugees/O ,/O which/O will/O be/O followed/O by/O further/O resettlement/O in/O accordance/O with/O Cambodia/LOCATION 's/O capacity/O ./O ''/O 
It/O reiterated/O that/O settlement/O would/O be/O ``/O on/O a/O voluntary/O basis/O ,/O ''/O a/O condition/O Phnom/O Penh/O has/O insisted/O upon/O ./O 
Earlier/O Morrison/PERSON told/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O ABC/ORGANIZATION network/O that/O the/O deal/O provided/O a/O regional/O solution/O to/O a/O regional/O problem/O ,/O and/O met/O the/O Abbott/PERSON government/O 's/O pledge/O that/O ``/O no-one/O will/O be/O resettled/O in/O Australia/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
He/O also/O said/O there/O was/O no/O upper/O limit/O on/O the/O number/O of/O refugees/O who/O might/O be/O sent/O ,/O adding/O that/O it/O currently/O applies/O to/O people/O at/O the/O detention/O centre/O on/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION island/O of/O Nauru/LOCATION ./O 
Around/O 200/O of/O the/O more/O than/O 1,200/O asylum/O seekers/O there/O have/O been/O classified/O as/O refugees/O ./O 
Australia/LOCATION has/O agreed/O to/O pay/O an/O additional/O 40/O million/O AUD/O -LRB-/O 35/O million/O USD/O -RRB-/O in/O development/O aid/O over/O the/O next/O four/O years/O to/O Cambodia/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O considered/O one/O of/O the/O world/O 's/O most/O corrupt/O countries/O ,/O with/O the/O money/O purportedly/O earmarked/O for/O projects/O such/O as/O electoral/O reform/O ,/O rice/O milling/O and/O land-mine/O clearance/O ./O 
But/O many/O aspects/O remain/O unknown/O ,/O including/O how/O many/O refugees/O will/O come/O ,/O where/O they/O will/O be/O housed/O ,/O whether/O they/O will/O be/O allowed/O to/O work/O ,/O and/O how/O they/O will/O access/O services/O in/O a/O country/O where/O provision/O of/O services/O is/O poor/O and/O government-sanctioned/O corruption/O is/O rife/O ./O 
Controversial/O 
The/O deal/O has/O proved/O highly/O controversial/O in/O Cambodia/LOCATION and/O abroad/O ./O 
In/O Phnom/LOCATION Penh/LOCATION on/O Friday/O morning/O ,/O around/O 100/O protestors/O petitioned/O the/O Australian/O embassy/O to/O scrap/O the/O agreement/O ,/O saying/O Cambodia/LOCATION is/O too/O poor/O to/O help/O others/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Australia/LOCATION and/O Cambodia/LOCATION sign/O refugee/O resettlement/O deal/O 
As/O part/O of/O a/O controversial/O deal/O Australia/LOCATION will/O start/O sending/O refugees/O to/O Cambodia/LOCATION by/O the/O end/O of/O the/O year/O ./O 
Rights/O groups/O have/O voiced/O great/O concern/O for/O the/O well-being/O of/O asylum/O seekers/O and/O have/O condemned/O Canberra/LOCATION ./O 
-LRB-/O 26.09.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Refugee/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION calls/O on/O Canberra/LOCATION to/O release/O `/O all/O children/O from/O detention/O '/O 
The/O Australian/O government/O has/O defended/O its/O continued/O detention/O of/O asylum/O seeker/O children/O in/O camps/O ,/O a/O policy/O which/O Refugee/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION CEO/O Paul/PERSON Power/PERSON says/O in/O a/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> interview/O `/O unquestionably/O '/O breaches/O children/O 's/O rights/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 22.08.2014/O -RRB-/O 
<ORGANIZATION>AI/O</ORGANIZATION> accuses/O Australia/LOCATION of/O `/O refouling/O asylum/O seekers/O '/O 
After/O returning/O a/O boat/O full/O of/O asylum/O seekers/O to/O Sri/LOCATION Lanka/LOCATION ,/O where/O they/O face/O imprisonment/O ,/O Canberra/LOCATION has/O come/O under/O growing/O criticism/O for/O a/O practice/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION 's/O Graeme/PERSON McGregor/PERSON describes/O as/O act/O of/O refoulement/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 15.07.2014/O -RRB-/O 
No/O place/O to/O go/O for/O asylum/O seekers/O in/O Australia/LOCATION 
Long/O before/O Sri/O Lankan/O asylum/O seekers/O reach/O their/O destination/O ,/O Australian/O navy/O boats/O stop/O them/O ,/O refuse/O their/O asylum/O requests/O ,/O and/O send/O them/O back/O home/O ./O 
But/O there/O is/O growing/O resistance/O against/O this/O policy/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 12.07.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Speaking/O to/O reporters/O at/O the/O demonstration/O ,/O opposition/O chief/O whip/O Son/PERSON Chhay/PERSON condemned/O the/O secrecy/O that/O surrounded/O the/O drafting/O process/O ,/O and/O warned/O against/O using/O Cambodia/LOCATION ``/O as/O a/O dumping/O ground/O for/O unwanted/O refugees/O ''/O by/O using/O money/O to/O buy/O off/O ``/O a/O corrupt/O government/O ./O ''/O 
``/O And/O -LSB-/O that/O -RSB-/O could/O create/O a/O bad/O habit/O for/O many/O countries/O to/O follow/O ./O ''/O 
<OTHER>Protester/PERSON</OTHER> Son/PERSON Chum/PERSON Chuon/PERSON said/O he/O was/O against/O the/O agreement/O because/O Cambodia/LOCATION lacks/O the/O capacity/O to/O handle/O the/O refugees/O and/O needs/O to/O sort/O out/O the/O entrenched/O problems/O facing/O its/O own/O people/O before/O it/O can/O assist/O others/O ./O 
``/O The/O human/O rights/O system/O -LSB-/O and/O -RSB-/O the/O democracy/O system/O in/O Cambodia/LOCATION -LSB-/O are/O -RSB-/O still/O poor/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O reason/O that/O some/O demonstrators/O want/O to/O gather/O in/O front/O of/O the/O Australian/O embassy/O today/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O In/O future/O ,/O if/O Cambodia/LOCATION -LSB-/O is/O -RSB-/O stable/O in/O democracy/O ,/O stable/O in/O human/O rights/O ,/O I/O am/O happy/O to/O see/O all/O those/O refugees/O ./O 
But/O now/O -LSB-/O I/O 'm/O -RSB-/O not/O ./O ''/O 
Top/O secret/O 
The/O deal/O has/O been/O on/O the/O cards/O since/O February/O when/O the/O visiting/O Australian/O Foreign/O Minister/O Julie/PERSON Bishop/PERSON asked/O Cambodia/LOCATION to/O take/O in/O refugees/O ./O 
Both/O countries/O subsequently/O maintained/O a/O near-uniform/O silence/O on/O the/O proposal/O until/O Wednesday/O when/O Cambodia/LOCATION 's/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION announced/O that/O Morrison/PERSON would/O visit/O Phnom/LOCATION Penh/LOCATION to/O sign/O ./O 
News/O of/O the/O signing/O has/O caused/O a/O storm/O of/O protest/O over/O the/O past/O two/O days/O ./O 
Opposition/O politicians/O in/O both/O countries/O have/O joined/O rights/O organizations/O ,/O church/O groups/O and/O legal/O experts/O in/O condemnation/O ./O 
Alastair/PERSON Nicholson/PERSON ,/O the/O former/O chief/O justice/O of/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O <ORGANIZATION>Family/O Court/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O described/O the/O deal/O as/O ``/O inappropriate/O ,/O immoral/O and/O likely/O illegal/O ,/O ''/O and/O said/O it/O raised/O serious/O concerns/O for/O the/O welfare/O of/O refugees/O and/O their/O children/O ./O 
Asylum/O seekers/O face/O threats/O in/O their/O home/O country/O 
Nicholson/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O speaking/O on/O behalf/O of/O an/O alliance/O of/O organizations/O including/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O Refugee/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Australia/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O <ORGANIZATION>Save/O the/O Children/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O said/O Cambodia/LOCATION 's/O welfare/O sector/O was/O already/O struggling/O ./O 
``/O It/O is/O inappropriate/O because/O Cambodia/LOCATION has/O no/O capacity/O within/O its/O social/O sector/O to/O take/O an/O influx/O of/O refugees/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O Immoral/O ,/O because/O these/O vulnerable/O people/O are/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O responsibility/O and/O ,/O while/O we/O await/O the/O detail/O ,/O it/O appears/O illegal/O in/O contravening/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O humanitarian/O and/O refugee/O obligations/O to/O vulnerable/O children/O and/O families/O ./O ''/O 
Cambodia/LOCATION ,/O one/O of/O the/O poorest/O countries/O in/O the/O world/O ,/O already/O relies/O significantly/O on/O international/O donors/O to/O fund/O its/O social/O and/O welfare/O programmes/O ./O 
``/O When/O you/O choose/O to/O place/O refugee/O children/O in/O the/O care/O of/O a/O country/O already/O dependent/O on/O the/O international/O donor/O community/O for/O supporting/O its/O own/O children/O ,/O you/O make/O a/O clear/O choice/O to/O put/O refugee/O children/O and/O their/O families/O at/O serious/O risk/O ,/O ''/O Nicholson/PERSON warned/O ./O 
`/O Unsafe/O and/O ill-equipped/O '/O 
On/O Thursday/O ,/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION warned/O that/O Cambodia/LOCATION 's/O poor/O record/O on/O refugees/O and/O on/O human/O rights/O meant/O Australia/LOCATION was/O failing/O to/O meet/O its/O commitment/O that/O it/O would/O send/O people/O to/O a/O ``/O safe/O third/O country/O ./O ''/O 
``/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O deal/O with/O Cambodia/LOCATION will/O send/O people/O to/O a/O country/O that/O has/O a/O terrible/O record/O for/O protecting/O refugees/O and/O is/O mired/O in/O serious/O human/O rights/O abuses/O ,/O ''/O said/O <ORGANIZATION>HRW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Australia/LOCATION director/O Elaine/PERSON Pearson/PERSON ./O 
``/O Despite/O Canberra/LOCATION 's/O claims/O ,/O the/O reality/O is/O Cambodia/LOCATION is/O both/O unsafe/O and/O ill-equipped/O to/O handle/O large/O numbers/O of/O refugees/O who/O will/O be/O given/O one-way/O tickets/O to/O Phnom/LOCATION Penh/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Cambodia/LOCATION has/O a/O poor/O record/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O asylum/O seekers/O ./O 
In/O 2009/O ,/O for/O example/O ,/O the/O country/O sent/O a/O group/O of/O 20/O Uighur/O asylum/O seekers/O back/O to/O China/LOCATION -LRB-/O where/O <ORGANIZATION>HRW/O</ORGANIZATION> said/O they/O were/O jailed/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Within/O days/O it/O had/O received/O a/O billion-dollar/O package/O of/O grants/O and/O loans/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
According/O to/O UNHCR/ORGANIZATION spokesperson/O Vivian/PERSON Tan/PERSON ,/O Friday/O 's/O deal/O meant/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O international/O responsibilities/O towards/O refugees/O ``/O are/O in/O question/O ,/O ''/O adding/O that/O people/O ``/O fleeing/O conflict/O and/O persecution/O deserve/O compassion/O and/O help/O ./O ''/O 
Since/O coming/O to/O power/O last/O year/O ,/O PM/O Abbott/PERSON has/O tightened/O Australia/LOCATION 's/O asylum/O policy/O ``/O UNHCR/ORGANIZATION has/O always/O advocated/O that/O asylum-seekers/O should/O be/O processed/O and/O benefit/O from/O protection/O in/O the/O territory/O of/O the/O country/O where/O they/O arrive/O or/O which/O otherwise/O has/O jurisdiction/O over/O them/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
``/O They/O should/O not/O be/O transferred/O to/O another/O country/O for/O asylum/O processing/O ,/O and/O if/O recognized/O as/O refugees/O ,/O relocated/O to/O yet/O another/O country/O for/O permanent/O settlement/O ./O ''/O 
Services/O lacking/O 
Much/O of/O Cambodia/LOCATION 's/O infrastructure/O and/O social/O services/O remain/O in/O disarray/O after/O the/O destruction/O of/O the/O Khmer/ORGANIZATION Rouge/ORGANIZATION 's/O 1975-79/O rule/O ,/O civil/O war/O ,/O and/O underinvestment/O by/O the/O government/O ./O 
Mental/O health/O services/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O are/O practically/O non-existent/O outside/O Phnom/LOCATION Penh/LOCATION ./O 
In/O addition/O ,/O there/O are/O few/O jobs/O ,/O and/O education/O and/O healthcare/O are/O poor/O ./O 
Sister/O Denise/PERSON Coghlan/PERSON heads/O the/O Cambodian/O office/O of/O the/O Jesuit/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Service/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O has/O operated/O here/O since/O 1990/O ./O 
Although/O Cambodia/LOCATION 's/O willingness/O to/O take/O in/O refugees/O was/O ``/O a/O good/O thing/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O the/O lack/O of/O mental/O health/O services/O is/O only/O one/O issue/O they/O will/O face/O ./O 
``/O -LSB-/O Cambodia/LOCATION 's/O -RSB-/O capacity/O to/O accept/O people/O who/O have/O been/O severely/O traumatized/O both/O by/O the/O situation/O in/O their/O own/O country/O and/O by/O their/O treatment/O by/O the/O Australian/O government/O --/O first/O on/O places/O like/O <LOCATION>Christmas/O Island/O</LOCATION> and/O then/O Nauru/LOCATION --/O these/O people/O have/O now/O been/O left/O in/O a/O very/O traumatized/O and/O psychologically/O weak/O situation/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
``/O The/O capacity/O of/O the/O mental/O health/O facilities/O in/O Cambodia/LOCATION to/O really/O cope/O with/O this/O kind/O of/O situation/O is/O pretty/O weak/O ./O ''/O
