China/LOCATION has/O offered/O to/O support/O the/O Afghan/O government/O in/O reconciling/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
But/O while/O Beijing/LOCATION brings/O major/O diplomatic/O and/O economic/O weight/O to/O the/O table/O ,/O the/O prospects/O of/O success/O are/O slim/O ,/O as/O Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON tells/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O said/O it/O is/O ready/O to/O support/O Kabul/LOCATION in/O facilitating/O reconciliation/O discussions/O with/O militant/O Islamic/O groups/O ,/O including/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Chinese/O Foreign/O Minister/O Wang/PERSON Yi/PERSON said/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION on/O February/O 12/O that/O ``/O broad-based/O and/O inclusive/O national/O reconciliation/O ''/O was/O vital/O to/O sustained/O stability/O in/O the/O South/O Asian/O country/O ./O 
The/O statements/O come/O just/O weeks/O afte/O members/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION visited/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O and/O a/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION last/O October/O by/O Afghan/O President/O Ashraf/PERSON Ghani/PERSON ./O 
Chinese/O officials/O claim/O that/O their/O country/O is/O the/O only/O state/O other/O than/O Pakistan/LOCATION which/O has/O been/O able/O to/O maintain/O contact/O with/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION leadership/O ./O 
Analysts/O agree/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION holds/O an/O important/O position/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O brokering/O reconciliation/O talks/O as/O China/LOCATION is/O a/O country/O trusted/O by/O both/O the/O Pakistani/O and/O Afghan/O governments/O ,/O and/O is/O also/O accepted/O by/O the/O Afghan/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION as/O mediator/O ./O 
In/O a/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> interview/O ,/O Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON ,/O a/O fellow/O with/O the/O Asia/LOCATION program/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>German/O Marshall/O Fund/O</ORGANIZATION> of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O says/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O top/O priority/O is/O to/O ensure/O that/O Islamic/O extremists/O do/O not/O target/O China/LOCATION and/O do/O not/O back/O Uighur/O militants/O ./O 
However/O ,/O he/O adds/O that/O the/O prospects/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O success/O are/O slim/O and/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O now/O far/O more/O exposed/O to/O political/O risks/O ./O 
<PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> :/O `/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O become/O increasingly/O worried/O about/O the/O implications/O of/O the/O <LOCATION>West/O</LOCATION> 's/O drawdown/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION '/O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> :/O Why/O is/O China/LOCATION offering/O support/O with/O reconciliation/O negotiations/O just/O now/O ?/O 
<PERSON>Andrew/O Small/O</PERSON> :/O In/O the/O past/O few/O years/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O become/O increasingly/O worried/O about/O the/O implications/O of/O the/O <LOCATION>West/O</LOCATION> 's/O drawdown/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
It/O fears/O that/O a/O deteriorating/O situation/O there/O could/O have/O destabilizing/O implications/O for/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O northwestern/O province/O ,/O and/O for/O the/O wider/O region/O ,/O impacting/O on/O China/LOCATION 's/O ambitions/O for/O a/O ``/O <U_LOCATION>Silk/O Road/O</U_LOCATION> economic/O belt/O ''/O and/O risking/O a/O proxy/O war/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O 1990s/O ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION was/O a/O safe/O haven/O for/O Uighur/O militants/O ,/O and/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O concerned/O that/O the/O situation/O will/O repeat/O itself/O ./O 
It/O sees/O the/O only/O solution/O to/O this/O is/O a/O political/O settlement/O between/O different/O factions/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
Given/O the/O failure/O of/O previous/O reconciliation/O efforts/O and/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O unique/O relationship/O with/O some/O of/O the/O key/O external/O parties/O to/O the/O conflict/O ,/O especially/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O it/O has/O felt/O obliged/O to/O take/O on/O a/O larger/O political/O role/O in/O helping/O to/O forge/O a/O solution/O ./O 
How/O has/O Kabul/LOCATION reacted/O to/O this/O ``/O offer/O of/O support/O ?/O ''/O 
Kabul/LOCATION is/O positively/O disposed/O towards/O the/O offer/O ./O 
China/LOCATION first/O formally/O proposed/O this/O at/O the/O ``/O Heart/O of/O Asia/LOCATION ''/O ministerial/O conference/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION last/O year/O ,/O and/O had/O been/O sounding/O various/O parties/O out/O informally/O for/O some/O time/O before/O that/O ./O 
From/O the/O Afghan/O government/O 's/O perspective/O ,/O Chinese/O involvement/O offers/O the/O best/O prospect/O of/O ensuring/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION does/O n't/O play/O a/O spoiler/O role/O in/O any/O reconciliation/O process/O ./O 
Kabul/LOCATION hopes/O that/O Islamabad/LOCATION will/O be/O more/O cautious/O about/O undermining/O the/O talks/O if/O its/O closest/O friend/O and/O sponsor/O is/O their/O leading/O broker/O ,/O as/O opposed/O to/O a/O purely/O Afghan/O process/O or/O a/O US-backed/O initiative/O ./O 
Some/O in/O the/O Afghan/O government/O remain/O skeptical/O about/O reconciliation/O talks/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION in/O general/O but/O drawing/O China/LOCATION into/O a/O greater/O political/O and/O economic/O role/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION is/O a/O principal/O objective/O for/O Ghani/PERSON 's/O new/O government/O ./O 
What/O can/O China/LOCATION bring/O to/O the/O negotiation/O table/O to/O facilitate/O the/O reconciliation/O process/O ?/O 
China/LOCATION has/O several/O assets/O ./O 
It/O is/O the/O only/O external/O power/O to/O have/O a/O good/O working/O relationship/O with/O all/O internal/O and/O external/O parties/O to/O the/O conflict/O --/O the/O Afghan/O government/O ,/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O former/O Northern/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION forces/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O Central/O Asian/O states/O ,/O and/O the/O West/LOCATION -/O making/O it/O a/O rare/O neutral/O broker/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Signs/O of/O change/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O policy/O The/O new/O Afghan/O President/O Ashraf/PERSON Ghani/PERSON seems/O to/O have/O taken/O a/O different/O approach/O to/O his/O country/O 's/O foreign/O policy/O ./O 
Experts/O say/O the/O challenge/O is/O to/O maintain/O a/O balance/O in/O ties/O with/O all/O regional/O and/O international/O players/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 28.11.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Afghan/O President/O Ghani/PERSON seeks/O stronger/O ties/O with/O China/LOCATION 
China/LOCATION has/O been/O a/O mere/O spectator/O during/O the/O decades-long/O conflict/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O been/O playing/O a/O more/O active/O role/O recently/O ;/O an/O approach/O welcomed/O by/O the/O recently/O elected/O Afghan/O President/O Ashraf/PERSON Ghani/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O 28.10.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Pakistanis/O tired/O of/O `/O hide/O and/O seek/O '/O over/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION talks/O
Not/O many/O people/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION expect/O much/O from/O the/O peace/O talks/O between/O the/O government/O and/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O but/O after/O months/O of/O futile/O negotiations/O ,/O they/O are/O getting/O increasingly/O frustrated/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 17.04.2014/O -RRB-/O 
Can/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION make/O a/O comeback/O ?/O 
Experts/O believe/O only/O a/O very/O small/O number/O of/O Afghans/O support/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ideology/O ./O 
If/O the/O insurgent/O group/O wants/O to/O truly/O integrate/O into/O Afghan/O society/O ,/O it/O should/O change/O its/O politics/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 16.04.2014/O -RRB-/O 
The/O partial/O exception/O to/O that/O is/O India/LOCATION ,/O but/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O working/O closely/O with/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION to/O reassure/O it/O that/O the/O two/O sides/O share/O concerns/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
It/O also/O claims/O to/O be/O the/O only/O country/O to/O have/O maintained/O continuous/O ties/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION leadership/O since/O 9/11/O other/O than/O Pakistan/LOCATION itself/O ,/O giving/O it/O an/O unusual/O level/O of/O political/O familiarity/O with/O the/O insurgents/O ./O 
And/O Beijing/LOCATION can/O bring/O its/O substantial/O diplomatic/O and/O economic/O weight/O to/O bear/O to/O support/O the/O process/O ./O 
The/O potential/O for/O China/LOCATION to/O make/O serious/O economic/O commitments/O in/O specific/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O means/O that/O it/O can/O effectively/O offer/O a/O peace/O dividend/O to/O the/O different/O parties/O ./O 
If/O need/O be/O ,/O it/O can/O also/O exert/O pressure/O on/O countries/O that/O have/O been/O historically/O unsupportive/O of/O a/O reconciliation/O process/O ./O 
Still/O ,/O this/O is/O not/O a/O region/O where/O China/LOCATION has/O taken/O on/O this/O sort/O of/O political/O role/O in/O the/O past/O ,/O so/O it/O will/O proceed/O cautiously/O --/O it/O is/O well/O outside/O its/O comfort/O zone/O here/O ./O 
What/O does/O Beijing/LOCATION expect/O to/O gain/O from/O facilitating/O these/O discussions/O ?/O 
China/LOCATION would/O have/O preferred/O to/O see/O others/O take/O on/O this/O task/O ,/O but/O there/O was/O n't/O much/O sign/O of/O a/O process/O that/O was/O likely/O to/O work/O without/O their/O involvement/O ./O 
The/O prospects/O of/O success/O are/O slim/O ,/O especially/O in/O the/O short/O term/O ,/O and/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O far/O more/O exposed/O to/O political/O risks/O by/O doing/O this/O than/O if/O it/O had/O been/O able/O to/O sit/O things/O out/O ./O 
There/O is/O some/O advantage/O to/O being/O in/O a/O position/O to/O steer/O and/O influence/O discussions/O but/O really/O the/O only/O benefit/O will/O come/O if/O the/O reconciliation/O process/O is/O actually/O successful/O ,/O helping/O to/O stabilize/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O periphery/O and/O heading/O off/O the/O risks/O of/O a/O wider/O deterioration/O of/O security/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
This/O is/O more/O of/O a/O burden/O than/O an/O opportunity/O for/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
How/O would/O you/O describe/O China/LOCATION 's/O relationship/O with/O Islamic/O extremists/O and/O specifically/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
China/LOCATION 's/O dealing/O with/O Islamic/O extremists/O vary/O ,/O group/O by/O group/O ./O 
With/O some/O ,/O such/O as/O the/O <OTHER>Pakistani/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Taliban/ORGANIZATION or/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O ''/O the/O relationship/O is/O clearly/O hostile/O ./O 
Others/O ,/O such/O as/O al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION ,/O have/O seen/O political/O advantage/O in/O avoiding/O a/O too/O conflictual/O relationship/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O 
With/O a/O number/O of/O groups/O though/O ,/O including/O the/O <OTHER>Afghan/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O China/LOCATION has/O maintained/O a/O direct/O relationship/O and/O figured/O out/O some/O working/O arrangements/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O top/O priority/O is/O to/O ensure/O that/O Islamic/O extremists/O do/O not/O target/O China/LOCATION and/O do/O not/O provide/O backing/O to/O Uighur/O militants/O ./O 
In/O return/O ,/O it/O offers/O some/O degree/O of/O political/O legitimacy/O ,/O some/O money/O ,/O and/O even/O some/O arms/O ./O 
<PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> :/O `/O Pakistan/LOCATION will/O be/O crucial/O to/O these/O negotiations/O '/O 
China/LOCATION reached/O an/O agreement/O along/O these/O lines/O directly/O with/O Mullah/PERSON Omar/PERSON during/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O period/O of/O rule/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O which/O it/O has/O largely/O maintained/O since/O then/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O continued/O to/O hold/O secret/O meetings/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION during/O their/O period/O of/O exile/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O which/O have/O intensified/O in/O recent/O years/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O China/LOCATION does/O not/O want/O to/O see/O a/O return/O to/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION rule/O and/O was/O somewhat/O relieved/O when/O the/O last/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION government/O fell/O ./O 
Whatever/O deals/O Beijing/LOCATION reaches/O with/O them/O ,/O Islamic/O extremist/O forces/O in/O the/O region/O inevitably/O act/O as/O a/O source/O of/O inspiration/O and/O practical/O support/O for/O militancy/O in/O China/LOCATION itself/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION is/O particularly/O concerned/O about/O the/O new/O generation/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION which/O it/O fears/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Quetta/LOCATION Shura/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> may/O not/O ultimately/O be/O able/O to/O control/O ./O 
What/O role/O is/O Pakistan/LOCATION expected/O to/O play/O during/O these/O negotiations/O ?/O 
Pakistan/LOCATION will/O be/O crucial/O to/O these/O negotiations/O ,/O and/O for/O all/O the/O language/O around/O an/O ``/O Afghan-owned/O ,/O Afghan-led/O ''/O process/O ,/O it/O is/O partly/O owned/O by/O Pakistan/LOCATION too/O ./O 
With/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION leadership/O based/O out/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O backed/O by/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O this/O is/O inevitably/O the/O case/O ./O 
Pakistani/O officials/O accompanied/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION delegation/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O have/O brokered/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O meetings/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O China/LOCATION 's/O involvement/O means/O that/O they/O are/O effectively/O guaranteed/O a/O seat/O at/O the/O table/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O expanded/O role/O puts/O them/O under/O some/O pressure/O ./O 
Previously/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION was/O able/O to/O derail/O talks/O with/O no/O real/O repercussions/O ,/O and/O China/LOCATION virtually/O outsourced/O its/O policy/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION to/O them/O ./O 
Now/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O making/O clear/O that/O ,/O although/O it/O appreciates/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O interests/O ,/O it/O wants/O to/O see/O its/O leadership/O help/O stabilize/O the/O country/O to/O support/O China/LOCATION 's/O interests/O ,/O too/O ./O 
How/O will/O neighboring/O countries/O and/O the/O US/LOCATION likely/O react/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O potential/O future/O role/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ?/O 
The/O US/LOCATION has/O been/O urging/O China/LOCATION to/O take/O on/O a/O greater/O role/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION for/O some/O time/O ./O 
The/O two/O sides/O share/O interests/O there/O to/O an/O unusual/O degree/O and/O this/O is/O one/O part/O of/O the/O world/O where/O Chinese/O assertiveness/O looks/O like/O a/O good/O thing/O from/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O perspective/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O dealing/O with/O Islamic/O extremists/O vary/O ,/O group/O by/O group/O ,/O says/O <PERSON>Small/O</PERSON> Afghanistan/LOCATION is/O perhaps/O the/O single/O foreign/O policy/O area/O on/O which/O the/O two/O sides/O are/O cooperating/O most/O closely/O ./O 
India/LOCATION retains/O its/O suspicions/O about/O China/LOCATION but/O would/O clearly/O welcome/O Beijing/LOCATION taking/O its/O concerns/O about/O militancy/O there/O more/O seriously/O and/O potentially/O restraining/O aspects/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O behavior/O ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O in/O the/O longer-term/O ,/O as/O in/O East/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O the/O wider/O region/O could/O turn/O into/O another/O zone/O of/O strategic/O competition/O with/O China/LOCATION if/O everything/O stabilizes/O ./O 
But/O in/O the/O short-to-mid/O term/O almost/O all/O parties/O are/O keen/O to/O see/O Beijing/LOCATION take/O on/O this/O burden/O ./O 
No-one/O has/O any/O illusions/O about/O the/O likelihood/O of/O China/LOCATION succeeding/O where/O others/O have/O struggled/O but/O greater/O Chinese/O involvement/O is/O genuinely/O something/O that/O offers/O potential/O benefits/O to/O every/O party/O ./O 
Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON is/O a/O transatlantic/O fellow/O with/O the/O Asia/LOCATION program/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>German/O</ORGANIZATION> Marshall/ORGANIZATION Fund/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O author/O of/O the/O book/O ``/O The/O <LOCATION>China/O</LOCATION> -/O <LOCATION>Pakistan/O</LOCATION> Axis/O -/O Asia/LOCATION 's/O New/O Geopolitics/O ./O ''/O 
You/O can/O follow/O him/O on/O <ORGANIZATION>Twitter/O</ORGANIZATION> @ajwsmall/O ./O 
The/O interview/O was/O conducted/O by/O Gabriel/PERSON Domínguez/PERSON ./O
