Malaysian/O police/O have/O arrested/O eight/O people/O on/O suspicion/O of/O being/O involved/O in/O the/O deadly/O bombing/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION last/O month/O ./O 
The/O worst/O attack/O in/O the/O city/O 's/O history/O has/O already/O impacted/O the/O country/O 's/O tourism/O industry/O ./O 
Malaysian/O national/O deputy/O police/O chief/O Noor/PERSON Rashid/PERSON Ibrahim/PERSON told/O reporters/O on/O Wednesday/O that/O four/O Malaysians/O and/O four/O foreigners/O had/O been/O detained/O in/O connection/O with/O last/O month/O 's/O bombing/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ./O 
The/O suspects/O were/O arrested/O in/O Kuala/LOCATION Lumpur/LOCATION as/O well/O as/O in/O the/O northeastern/O state/O of/O Kelantan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O four/O foreigners/O are/O believed/O to/O be/O Uighurs/O who/O entered/O the/O country/O illegally/O ,/O the/O official/O stated/O ./O 
The/O detained/O Malaysian/O nationals/O were/O also/O suspected/O of/O trafficking/O foreigners/O into/O the/O country/O ,/O the/O senior/O police/O official/O added/O ,/O without/O commenting/O on/O whether/O these/O included/O the/O four/O foreign/O suspects/O ./O 
The/O blast/O at/O the/O <LOCATION>Erawan/O Hindu/O Shrine/O</LOCATION> in/O the/O center/O of/O the/O Thai/O capital/O Bangkok/LOCATION on/O August/O 17/O killed/O 20/O people/O and/O injured/O more/O than/O 120/O ./O 
Since/O the/O shrine/O is/O a/O popular/O tourist/O destination/O ,/O many/O of/O the/O victims/O were/O foreigners/O ./O 
It/O was/O the/O deadliest/O attack/O the/O city/O 's/O history/O ./O 
Tourism/O accounts/O for/O about/O 10/O percent/O of/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O economy/O ,/O although/O this/O sector/O was/O affected/O by/O the/O months/O of/O street/O protests/O and/O violence/O in/O 2014/O ,/O followed/O by/O a/O military/O coup/O ./O 
Earlier/O this/O month/O ,/O three/O other/O people/O were/O arrested/O in/O connection/O with/O the/O bombing/O at/O the/O Erawan/LOCATION Shrine/LOCATION in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O national/O deputy/O police/O chief/O Noor/PERSON Rashid/PERSON Ibrahim/PERSON said/O the/O investigators/O did/O not/O establish/O any/O link/O between/O these/O suspects/O and/O the/O deadly/O attack/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O 
Tourism/O contributes/O more/O than/O 10/O per/O cent/O to/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O gross/O domestic/O product/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Tourism/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION there/O has/O been/O a/O noticeable/O drop/O since/O the/O Bangkok/LOCATION attack/O ./O 
das/rg/O -LRB-/O dpa/O ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
