Asia-Pacific/LOCATION nations/O ,/O excluding/O China/LOCATION ,/O executed/O fewer/O people/O and/O issued/O fewer/O death/O sentences/O last/O year/O than/O in/O 2013/O ,/O a/O new/O <ORGANIZATION>AI/O</ORGANIZATION> report/O shows/O ./O 
But/O the/O study/O also/O points/O to/O some/O worrisome/O trends/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> examines/O ./O 
The/O number/O of/O recorded/O executions/O in/O the/O region/O dropped/O from/O 37/O in/O 2013/O to/O 32/O last/O year/O ,/O whereas/O the/O number/O of/O recorded/O death/O sentences/O dropped/O by/O 335/O compared/O to/O 2013/O ,/O a/O new/O report/O by/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AI/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O on/O the/O use/O of/O the/O death/O penalty/O worldwide/O said/O ./O 
The/O human/O rights/O group/O views/O the/O development/O in/O the/O Asia-Pacific/LOCATION as/O part/O of/O a/O global/O trend/O of/O states/O moving/O away/O from/O the/O death/O penalty/O ./O 
At/O least/O 607/O executions/O were/O known/O to/O have/O been/O carried/O out/O worldwide/O in/O 2014/O ,/O compared/O to/O 778/O in/O 2013/O ,/O a/O drop/O of/O more/O than/O 20/O percent/O ./O 
``/O The/O numbers/O speak/O for/O themselves/O -/O the/O death/O penalty/O is/O becoming/O a/O thing/O of/O the/O past/O ./O 
The/O few/O countries/O that/O still/O execute/O need/O to/O take/O a/O serious/O look/O in/O the/O mirror/O and/O ask/O themselves/O if/O they/O want/O to/O continue/O to/O violate/O the/O right/O to/O life/O ,/O or/O join/O the/O vast/O majority/O of/O countries/O that/O have/O abandoned/O this/O ultimate/O cruel/O and/O inhuman/O punishment/O ,/O ''/O said/O Salil/PERSON Shetty/PERSON ,/O <ORGANIZATION>AI/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Secretary/O General/O ./O 
People/O faced/O the/O death/O penalty/O for/O a/O range/O of/O non-lethal/O crimes/O ,/O said/O the/O report/O 
Among/O the/O top/O executioners/O worldwide/O were/O Iran/LOCATION -LRB-/O 289/O officially/O announced/O -RRB-/O ,/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION -LRB-/O at/O least/O 90/O -RRB-/O ,/O Iraq/LOCATION -LRB-/O at/O least/O 61/O -RRB-/O and/O the/O USA/LOCATION -LRB-/O 35/O -RRB-/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O report/O ./O 
These/O figures/O ,/O however/O ,/O exclude/O China/LOCATION and/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O actual/O number/O of/O executions/O is/O a/O state/O secret/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O <ORGANIZATION>AI/O</ORGANIZATION> estimates/O that/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O carry/O out/O thousands/O of/O executions/O a/O year/O ,/O more/O than/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O world/O combined/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O <OTHER>US-based/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Dui/ORGANIZATION Hua/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION ,/O some/O 2,400/O people/O were/O executed/O in/O China/LOCATION alone/O last/O year/O ./O 
Nine/O countries/O 
As/O for/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O Asia-Pacific/LOCATION region/O ,/O at/O total/O of/O nine/O countries/O implemented/O capital/O punishment/O ,/O one/O fewer/O than/O the/O year/O before/O :/O Afghanistan/LOCATION -LRB-/O 6/O -RRB-/O ,/O China/LOCATION ,/O Japan/LOCATION -LRB-/O 3/O -RRB-/O ,/O Malaysia/LOCATION -LRB-/O at/O least/O 2/O -RRB-/O ,/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION -LRB-/O 7/O -RRB-/O ,/O Singapore/LOCATION -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O ,/O Taiwan/LOCATION -LRB-/O 5/O -RRB-/O and/O Vietnam/LOCATION -LRB-/O at/O least/O 3/O -RRB-/O ./O 
The/O most/O widely/O used/O methods/O of/O executions/O included/O hanging/O ,/O lethal/O injection/O and/O shooting/O ./O 
Released/O on/O April/O 1/O ,/O the/O 61-page/O report/O also/O reveals/O that/O at/O least/O 695/O new/O death/O sentences/O were/O imposed/O in/O 17/O countries/O across/O the/O region/O -/O excluding/O China/LOCATION and/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION -/O most/O of/O which/O were/O passed/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION -LRB-/O 231/O -RRB-/O Bangladesh/LOCATION -LRB-/O 142/O -RRB-/O ,/O Vietnam/LOCATION -LRB-/O 72/O -RRB-/O and/O India/LOCATION -LRB-/O 64/O -RRB-/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O rights/O group/O ,/O the/O decrease/O is/O partly/O attributable/O to/O developments/O in/O Bangladesh/LOCATION ,/O which/O in/O 2013/O recorded/O the/O exceptionally/O high/O figure/O of/O 220/O new/O death/O sentences/O because/O of/O the/O mass/O sentencing/O of/O 152/O people/O for/O mutiny/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O selective/O hangings/O :/O A/O means/O to/O harass/O opponents/O ?/O 
Pakistan/LOCATION has/O hanged/O 21/O people/O in/O the/O past/O two/O days/O ,/O taking/O the/O toll/O to/O 48/O since/O a/O moratorium/O on/O the/O death/O penalty/O was/O lifted/O in/O December/O ./O 
Experts/O say/O the/O government/O is/O executing/O opponents/O in/O the/O garb/O of/O fighting/O terror/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 19.03.2015/O -RRB-/O 
<ORGANIZATION>Bali/PERSON Nine/PERSON duo/PERSON</ORGANIZATION> <OTHER>-/PERSON</OTHER> Jokowi/PERSON 's/O growing/O predicament/O Indonesian/O President/O Joko/PERSON Widodo/PERSON has/O so/O far/O refused/O to/O pardon/O drug/O convicts/O on/O death/O row/O ,/O saying/O he/O intends/O to/O show/O no/O mercy/O in/O his/O war/O on/O drugs/O ./O 
But/O his/O strong/O stance/O also/O risks/O further/O straining/O ties/O with/O key/O partners/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 24.02.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Opinion/O :/O Bangladesh/LOCATION makes/O a/O difficult/O decision/O on/O war/O crimes/O 
The/ORGANIZATION Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION in/O Bangladesh/LOCATION has/O upheld/O another/O death/O sentence/O by/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION War/ORGANIZATION Crimes/ORGANIZATION Tribunal/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Democracy/O in/O the/O country/O would/O 've/O been/O better/O served/O had/O it/O chosen/O a/O different/O path/O ,/O writes/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Grahame/PERSON Lucas/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O 03.11.2014/O -RRB-/O 
But/O why/O did/O these/O countries/O resort/O to/O capital/O punishment/O ?/O 
``/O People/O faced/O the/O death/O penalty/O for/O a/O range/O of/O non-lethal/O crimes/O including/O robbery/O ,/O drug-related/O crimes/O and/O economic/O offences/O ,/O ''/O said/O Shetty/PERSON ./O 
In/O addition/O ,/O some/O countries/O used/O vaguely/O worded/O political/O ``/O crimes/O ''/O to/O put/O real/O or/O perceived/O dissidents/O to/O death/O ,/O added/O the/O human/O rights/O expert/O ./O 
The/O 61-page/O report/O also/O blames/O ``/O unfair/O trials/O ''/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Bangladesh/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION ,/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Sri/LOCATION Lanka/LOCATION for/O this/O development/O ,/O adding/O that/O both/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O Pyongyang/LOCATION admitted/O ``/O confessions/O ''/O at/O trials/O extracted/O through/O torture/O or/O other/O ill-treatment/O ./O 
In/O other/O cases/O ,/O courts/O imposed/O capital/O punishment/O for/O crimes/O such/O as/O blasphemy/O -LRB-/O Pakistan/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O economic/O crimes/O -LRB-/O China/LOCATION ,/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION ,/O Vietnam/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O and/O rape/O that/O resulted/O in/O deaths/O -LRB-/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O India/LOCATION -RRB-/O ./O 
A/O worrisome/O trend/O 
The/O <ORGANIZATION>AI/O</ORGANIZATION> report/O also/O indicates/O that/O more/O governments/O are/O resorting/O to/O capital/O punishment/O as/O a/O means/O to/O fight/O crime/O ,/O threats/O against/O the/O state/O and/O terrorism/O -/O a/O trend/O described/O by/O rights/O activists/O as/O increasingly/O disturbing/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>AI/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Secretary/O General/O Shetty/PERSON said/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O that/O in/O China/LOCATION authorities/O made/O use/O of/O the/O death/O penalty/O as/O a/O punitive/O tool/O in/O the/O ``/O Strike/O Hard/O ''/O campaign/O against/O unrest/O in/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Uighur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
``/O Authorities/O executed/O at/O least/O 21/O people/O during/O the/O year/O related/O to/O separate/O attacks/O ,/O while/O three/O people/O were/O condemned/O to/O death/O in/O a/O mass/O sentencing/O rally/O conducted/O in/O a/O stadium/O in/O front/O of/O thousands/O of/O spectators/O ,/O ''/O said/O the/O human/O rights/O expert/O ./O 
Increased/O use/O of/O capital/O punishment/O can/O also/O be/O found/O in/O Singapore/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Indonesia/LOCATION which/O recently/O resumed/O executions/O ./O 
In/O the/O aftermath/O of/O a/O brutal/O terror/O attack/O on/O a/O school/O in/O Peshawar/LOCATION ,/O the/O Pakistani/O government/O recently/O reinstated/O the/O death/O penalty/O in/O all/O capital/O cases/O ,/O thus/O putting/O thousands/O of/O prisoners/O '/O lives/O at/O risk/O ./O 
It/O is/O estimated/O that/O the/O South/O Asian/O nation/O currently/O has/O more/O than/O 8,000/O people/O on/O death/O row/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O highest/O in/O the/O world/O ./O 
Pakistani/O authorities/O have/O already/O executed/O more/O than/O 60/O people/O since/O capital/O punishment/O was/O resumed/O in/O December/O ./O 
The/O <ORGANIZATION>AI/O</ORGANIZATION> paper/O also/O indicates/O that/O more/O governments/O are/O resorting/O to/O capital/O punishment/O as/O a/O means/O to/O fight/O crime/O ,/O threats/O against/O the/O state/O and/O terrorism/O In/O Indonesia/LOCATION ,/O President/O Joko/PERSON Widodo/PERSON has/O defended/O the/O implementation/O of/O the/O death/O penalty/O for/O drug/O offenses/O ,/O saying/O those/O convicted/O of/O drug/O trafficking/O will/O not/O receive/O a/O presidential/O pardon/O given/O the/O country/O 's/O ``/O emergency/O ''/O over/O drug/O use/O ./O 
Six/O men/O have/O already/O been/O executed/O by/O firing/O squad/O this/O year/O ./O 
A/O glimmer/O of/O hope/O ?/O 
The/O president/O 's/O tough/O stance/O has/O also/O flared/O tensions/O between/O Indonesia/LOCATION and/O countries/O like/O Australia/LOCATION and/O Brazil/LOCATION ,/O whose/O citizens/O are/O among/O a/O group/O of/O up/O to/O 11/O drug/O offenders/O ,/O mostly/O foreigners/O ,/O due/O to/O be/O executed/O soon/O on/O the/O prison/O island/O of/O Nusakambangan/LOCATION ./O 
Executions/O for/O drug/O trafficking/O were/O also/O recorded/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O Malaysia/LOCATION ,/O Singapore/LOCATION and/O Vietnam/LOCATION last/O year/O ./O 
But/O there/O is/O a/O positive/O note/O for/O the/O region/O ./O 
Although/O the/O governments/O of/O both/O Papua/LOCATION New/LOCATION Guinea/LOCATION and/O Kiribati/LOCATION took/O steps/O to/O resume/O executions/O or/O introduce/O the/O death/O penalty/O ,/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION continues/O to/O be/O the/O world/O 's/O only/O virtually/O death/O penalty-free/O zone/O ,/O said/O <ORGANIZATION>AI/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O
