With/O its/O new/O security/O law/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O is/O opening/O the/O floodgates/O to/O arbitrariness/O ,/O says/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON ./O 
Such/O a/O law/O was/O not/O necessary/O ./O 
What/O is/O now/O allowed/O was/O already/O possible/O -/O the/O arrest/O of/O people/O that/O the/O state/O believes/O could/O disturb/O public/O order/O ./O 
Nobel/O Peace/O Laureate/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON was/O imprisoned/O for/O 11/O years/O on/O charges/O of/O ``/O inciting/O state/O subversion/O ,/O ''/O while/O the/O Uighur/O professor/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> was/O given/O life/O imprisonment/O for/O ``/O separatism/O ''/O and/O the/O journalist/O Gao/PERSON Yu/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O worked/O for/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ,/O was/O sentenced/O to/O seven/O years/O in/O jail/O for/O ``/O disclosing/O state/O secrets/O ./O ''/O 
Clearly/O the/O hardliners/O in/O the/O government/O are/O strong/O enough/O to/O insist/O upon/O a/O formal/O change/O and/O to/O make/O their/O success/O as/O visible/O as/O possible/O ./O 
Before/O ,/O they/O would/O simply/O do/O it/O ,/O whereas/O now/O they/O are/O allowed/O to/O do/O it/O officially/O ./O 
They/O can/O ``/O resort/O to/O all/O necessary/O measures/O to/O ensure/O state/O sovereignty/O and/O harmony/O ./O ''/O 
They/O struck/O immediately/O :/O At/O the/O end/O of/O last/O week/O -/O barely/O a/O week/O after/O the/O security/O law/O was/O published/O -/O over/O 50/O human/O rights/O activists/O and/O lawyers/O were/O arrested/O or/O summoned/O or/O disappeared/O in/O a/O nationwide/O raid/O ./O 
Without/O any/O official/O explanation/O ./O 
They/O included/O the/O lawyer/O of/O the/O Uighur/O professor/O and/O Zhang/PERSON Miao/PERSON ,/O a/O journalist/O who/O has/O worked/O with/O German/O weekly/O ``/O Die/ORGANIZATION Zeit/ORGANIZATION ./O ''/O 
She/O was/O released/O almost/O immediately/O without/O charge/O ./O 
Why/O now/O ?/O 
Who/O is/O behind/O this/O ?/O 
Does/O it/O indicate/O a/O change/O in/O the/O power/O relations/O within/O the/O leadership/O ?/O 
Is/O this/O a/O concession/O allowing/O more/O space/O for/O maneuver/O with/O regard/O to/O economic/O reforms/O ?/O 
Is/O the/O law/O a/O compromise/O that/O the/O hardliners/O are/O using/O to/O arrest/O lawyers/O on/O their/O own/O authority/O ?/O 
Or/O are/O the/O arrests/O in/O the/O interest/O of/O the/O leadership/O ,/O even/O that/O of/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O the/O head/O of/O the/O state/O and/O the/O party/O ,/O who/O in/O view/O of/O the/O big/O reforms/O and/O the/O economic/O situation/O wants/O to/O have/O stability/O at/O all/O costs/O ?/O 
We/O do/O not/O know/O ./O 
What/O we/O do/O know/O ,/O however/O ,/O is/O that/O the/O party/O leadership/O is/O much/O more/O plural/O and/O divided/O than/O widely/O assumed/O in/O the/O West/LOCATION ./O 
We/O also/O know/O that/O if/O the/O arrests/O are/O met/O with/O indifference/O or/O even/O with/O acceptance/O by/O the/O majority/O of/O the/O population/O ,/O it/O is/O because/O dissent/O does/O not/O have/O as/O long/O a/O tradition/O in/O China/LOCATION as/O in/O the/O West/LOCATION ,/O meaning/O that/O most/O can/O put/O themselves/O in/O the/O shoes/O of/O dissidents/O only/O with/O difficulty/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O government/O and/O party/O 's/O arbitrariness/O and/O lack/O of/O transparency/O are/O getting/O on/O the/O nerves/O of/O more/O and/O more/O people/O -/O because/O every/O day/O they/O themselves/O are/O becoming/O the/O victims/O of/O arbitrariness/O and/O lack/O of/O transparency/O ./O 
That/O is/O making/O them/O angry/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> correspondent/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON 
With/O the/O new/O security/O law/O ,/O the/O government/O is/O ensuring/O that/O power/O relations/O remain/O in/O its/O favor/O by/O declaring/O almost/O all/O areas/O affairs/O of/O ``/O national/O security/O ./O ''/O 
These/O range/O from/O territorial/O disputes/O in/O the/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ,/O the/O <OTHER>Antarctic/LOCATION</OTHER> and/O even/O space/O ,/O to/O environmental/O issues/O ,/O food/O security/O and/O religion/O ./O 
The/O intensified/O monitoring/O of/O the/O internet/O is/O not/O barred/O and/O nor/O is/O the/O stricter/O regulation/O of/O foreign/O firms/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION is/O tightening/O the/O reins/O China/LOCATION is/O not/O the/O only/O country/O that/O has/O wrapped/O itself/O up/O in/O a/O legal/O gray/O zone/O to/O nip/O potential/O dangers/O in/O the/O bud/O ./O 
The/O detention/O camp/O of/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION is/O a/O similar/O example/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O an/O exception/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O 
Lawyers/O there/O can/O at/O least/O fight/O against/O it/O without/O fearing/O arrest/O ./O 
They/O even/O have/O a/O credible/O chance/O of/O obtaining/O justice/O for/O their/O clients/O sooner/O or/O later/O ./O 
It/O 's/O different/O in/O China/LOCATION -/O more/O than/O ever/O since/O the/O security/O law/O came/O into/O effect/O ./O 
It/O 's/O paradoxical/O that/O the/O more/O the/O country/O opens/O up/O and/O becomes/O connected/O to/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O world/O ,/O the/O more/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O tightening/O the/O reins/O ./O 
Three/O further/O security/O laws/O are/O currently/O under/O examination/O ./O 
First/O ,/O there/O is/O an/O anti-terrorism/O law/O which/O would/O force/O Chinese/O internet/O companies/O to/O build/O hidden/O back/O doors/O into/O their/O programs/O for/O the/O government/O ./O 
This/O recalls/O the/O beginning/O of/O the/O year/O when/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O demanded/O that/O foreign/O financial/O institutes/O publish/O the/O source/O codes/O of/O their/O software/O for/O better/O surveillance/O ./O 
There/O is/O also/O a/O draft/O law/O to/O control/O foreign/O NGOs/O more/O strictly/O and/O one/O that/O would/O limit/O foreign/O investment/O even/O more/O ./O 
The/O same/O holds/O true/O here/O as/O for/O the/O security/O law/O ./O 
Taking/O a/O tough/O line/O on/O foreign/O companies/O and/O keeping/O Western/O NGOs/O on/O a/O tight/O leash/O might/O go/O down/O well/O with/O the/O population/O ,/O but/O more/O arbitrariness/O and/O lack/O of/O transparency/O are/O a/O very/O high/O price/O for/O state/O and/O party/O leader/O <PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> to/O pay/O ./O 
By/O doing/O this/O ,/O he/O is/O only/O consolidating/O his/O power/O temporarily/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> correspondent/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON has/O lived/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O 20/O years/O ./O
