``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O militants/O have/O killed/O a/O Chinese/O national/O for/O the/O first/O time/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O reacted/O -/O but/O not/O with/O military/O force/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ,/O writes/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON ./O 
On/O Thursday/O ,/O the/O noon/O edition/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O state/O CCTV/ORGANIZATION channel/O announced/O the/O death/O of/O Chinese/O national/O <PERSON>Fan/O</PERSON> Jinghui/PERSON and/O Norway/LOCATION 's/O Ole/PERSON Johan/PERSON Grimsgaard-Ofstad/PERSON ./O 
Both/O fell/O into/O the/O hands/O of/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O terrorists/O in/O as-yet/O unknown/O circumstances/O and/O were/O killed/O with/O shots/O to/O the/O head/O ./O 
In/O the/O latest/O issue/O of/O the/O English-language/O online/O propaganda/O magazine/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Dabiq/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O ''/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> published/O images/O of/O the/O two/O hostages/O and/O said/O they/O had/O been/O killed/O ``/O after/O being/O abandoned/O by/O kafir/O -LSB-/O infidel/O -RSB-/O nations/O and/O organizations/O ./O ''/O 
The/O messages/O of/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON and/O Premier/O Li/PERSON Keqiang/PERSON were/O as/O clear/O as/O those/O of/O French/O President/O Francois/PERSON Hollande/PERSON :/O ``/O Terrorism/O is/O the/O public/O enemy/O of/O humanity/O ''/O and/O ``/O We/O must/O bring/O these/O criminals/O to/O justice/O ./O ''/O 
Held/O hostage/O for/O several/O months/O 
<PERSON>Fan/O</PERSON> ,/O a/O 50-year-old/O resident/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O was/O taken/O hostage/O by/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> extremists/O at/O the/O beginning/O of/O September/O ./O 
The/O terrorists/O demanded/O ransom/O money/O for/O him/O and/O his/O 48-year-old/O Norwegian/O co-hostage/O ./O 
Chinese/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Hong/PERSON Lei/PERSON said/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION had/O done/O everything/O to/O rescue/O them/O ./O 
Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON 
Prime/O Minister/O Li/PERSON has/O said/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION wants/O to/O boost/O protection/O of/O Chinese/O nationals/O and/O organizations/O abroad/O ,/O as/O the/O terror/O threat/O continues/O to/O mount/O ./O 
Even/O though/O no/O Chinese/O citizen/O died/O in/O Paris/LOCATION last/O week/O ,/O the/O latest/O issue/O of/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Dabiq/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O legitimized/O the/O attacks/O with/O the/O headline/O ``/O Just/O terror/O ./O ''/O 
Anyone/O who/O happened/O to/O be/O in/O Paris/LOCATION could/O have/O died/O ./O 
The/O murder/O of/O <PERSON>Fan/LOCATION Jinghui/LOCATION</PERSON> ,/O however/O ,/O must/O be/O seen/O as/O a/O clear/O ,/O specific/O message/O ./O 
The/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O aware/O that/O Chinese/O citizens/O are/O increasingly/O likely/O to/O fall/O victim/O to/O terrorism/O in/O crisis-ridden/O regions/O ./O 
In/O 2013/O ,/O 18/O Chinese/O citizens/O were/O taken/O hostage/O ./O 
The/O figure/O rose/O to/O at/O least/O 47/O last/O year/O ,/O and/O there/O could/O well/O be/O more/O as-yet/O unknown/O cases/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O denounced/O the/O attacks/O in/O Paris/LOCATION just/O like/O other/O states/O in/O the/O world/O ,/O but/O it/O does/O not/O want/O to/O use/O military/O force/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ,/O as/O opposed/O to/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O France/LOCATION and/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O 
Instead/O ,/O like/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O it/O favors/O negotiations/O in/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O always/O been/O in/O favor/O of/O involving/O Syrian/O President/O Bashar/PERSON al-Assad/PERSON in/O the/O talks/O ./O 
Berlin/LOCATION has/O now/O come/O around/O on/O this/O point/O :/O When/O she/O was/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION earlier/O this/O month/O ,/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON did/O not/O contradict/O Prime/O Minister/O when/O he/O said/O it/O was/O important/O to/O ``/O seize/O the/O opportunity/O to/O implement/O a/O political/O resolution/O and/O to/O set/O up/O an/O equal/O ,/O inclusive/O and/O open/O political/O dialogue/O ./O ''/O 
On/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O since/O 2011/O China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION have/O vetoed/O a/O resolution/O against/O Syria/LOCATION four/O times/O in/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION on/O the/O grounds/O that/O the/O West/LOCATION was/O interfering/O too/O much/O ./O 
As/O opposed/O to/O Moscow/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O stopped/O providing/O arms/O to/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION supplied/O anti-aircraft/O systems/O and/O missile/O technology/O until/O 2011/O ,/O but/O since/O then/O no/O arms/O deliveries/O can/O be/O proven/O ./O 
It/O must/O be/O said/O ,/O however/O ,/O that/O Tehran/LOCATION has/O supplied/O arms/O developed/O in/O China/LOCATION but/O produced/O in/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
<OTHER>Focus/ORGANIZATION on/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O 
Now/O that/O a/O Chinese/O national/O has/O been/O murdered/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O calling/O for/O attacks/O by/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O conflict-ridden/O northwestern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> to/O be/O categorized/O as/O international/O terrorism/O ./O 
For/O years/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O been/O fighting/O against/O radical/O elements/O of/O the/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O ,/O who/O train/O as/O terrorists/O in/O neighboring/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O also/O cooperate/O with/O the/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O ''/O 
Last/O year/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O state/O media/O announced/O that/O more/O than/O 300/O Chinese/O nationals/O had/O travelled/O to/O Syria/LOCATION and/O Iraq/LOCATION to/O join/O the/O ranks/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
On/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O exiled/O Uighurs/O have/O complained/O that/O their/O freedom/O of/O religion/O is/O becoming/O more/O and/O more/O restricted/O and/O that/O suspects/O are/O not/O given/O adequate/O means/O of/O legal/O defense/O ./O 
One/O thing/O is/O certain/O :/O The/O life/O of/O Uighurs/O in/O China/LOCATION will/O get/O tougher/O because/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> terrorism/O ./O 
Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON is/O considered/O to/O be/O one/O of/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O leading/O experts/O on/O China/LOCATION ./O 
He/O has/O lived/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O 20/O years/O ./O
