Islamabad/LOCATION wants/O to/O forge/O a/O ``/O greater/O ''/O <LOCATION>South/O Asia/O</LOCATION> economic/O alliance/O after/O India/LOCATION and/O its/O allies/O boycotted/O a/O regional/O summit/O ./O 
Experts/O say/O that/O Pakistani/O authorities/O are/O trying/O hard/O to/O avoid/O an/O international/O isolation/O ./O 
Last/O month/O ,/O India/LOCATION 's/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION announced/O that/O Prime/O Minister/O Narendra/PERSON Modi/PERSON would/O not/O participate/O in/O the/O South/ORGANIZATION Asian/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Regional/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SAARC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O summit/O ,/O which/O was/O to/O be/O held/O in/O November/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Increasing/O cross-border/O terrorist/O attacks/O in/O the/O region/O and/O growing/O interference/O in/O the/O internal/O affairs/O of/O member/O states/O by/O one/O country/O have/O created/O an/O environment/O that/O is/O not/O conducive/O to/O the/O successful/O holding/O of/O the/O 19th/O <ORGANIZATION>SAARC/O</ORGANIZATION> Summit/O ,/O ''/O a/O ministry/O statement/O said/O ./O 
``/O In/O the/O prevailing/O circumstances/O ,/O the/O Government/O of/O India/LOCATION is/O unable/O to/O participate/O in/O the/O proposed/O summit/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O ''/O it/O added/O ./O 
India/LOCATION 's/O regional/O allies/O Bangladesh/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Bhutan/LOCATION also/O boycotted/O the/O summit/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O these/O diplomatic/O snubs/O ,/O the/O Pakistani/O government/O had/O to/O cancel/O the/O meeting/O ./O 
Modi/PERSON refused/O to/O participate/O in/O the/O SAARC/ORGANIZATION summit/O ,/O which/O was/O to/O be/O held/O in/O November/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ``/O Islamabad/LOCATION is/O facing/O a/O serious/O foreign/O policy/O crisis/O since/O the/O attack/O on/O an/O Indian/O army/O base/O in/O Uri/LOCATION ,/O Kashmir/LOCATION ./O 
With/O India/LOCATION ,/O Bangladesh/LOCATION and/O other/O major/O countries/O pulling/O out/O of/O the/O SAARC/ORGANIZATION summit/O ,/O it/O is/O definitely/O a/O major/O embarrassment/O for/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Ali/PERSON K./PERSON Chishti/PERSON ,/O a/O Karachi-based/O security/O and/O defense/O analyst/O ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION described/O India/LOCATION 's/O withdrawal/O from/O the/O SAARC/ORGANIZATION summit/O as/O ``/O unfortunate/O ./O ''/O 
But/O reports/O have/O now/O emerged/O that/O Pakistani/O authorities/O are/O exploring/O the/O possibility/O of/O a/O ``/O greater/O ''/O <LOCATION>South/O Asia/O</LOCATION> economic/O grouping/O ./O 
By/O including/O China/LOCATION ,/O Iran/LOCATION and/O some/O Central/O Asian/O nations/O in/O the/O bloc/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION aims/O to/O counter/O Indian/O influence/O on/O SAARC/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O A/O `/O greater/O '/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION alliance/O is/O coming/O about/O ./O 
Iran/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION and/O Central/O Asian/O states/O are/O part/O of/O it/O ,/O ''/O Mushahid/PERSON Hussain/PERSON ,/O a/O Pakistani/O senator/O ,/O told/O reporters/O on/O Tuesday/O ,/O October/O 11/O ,/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Impediments/O to/O the/O Pakistani/O plan/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O investing/O massively/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O has/O signed/O an/O economic/O project/O with/O Islamabad/LOCATION worth/O $/O 46/O billion/O -LRB-/O 41/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O ./O 
With/O the/O <U_LOCATION>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION aims/O to/O expand/O its/O clout/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O across/O <LOCATION>Central/O</LOCATION> and/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION while/O countering/O US/LOCATION and/O Indian/O influence/O ./O 
The/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> would/O link/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O southern/O Gwadar/LOCATION port/O on/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION to/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ./O 
It/O also/O includes/O plans/O to/O create/O road/O ,/O rail/O and/O oil/O pipeline/O links/O to/O improve/O connectivity/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
The/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> project/O has/O been/O strongly/O opposed/O by/O local/O communities/O ,/O ethnic/O groups/O and/O leaders/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O smaller/O provinces/O Senator/O Hussain/PERSON believes/O that/O an/O alliance/O between/O the/O SAARC/ORGANIZATION countries/O ,/O China/LOCATION and/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION would/O be/O beneficial/O for/O everyone/O ./O 
``/O The/O countries/O in/O the/O region/O are/O trying/O to/O forge/O economic/O alliances/O ./O 
Many/O officials/O from/O the/O Central/O Asian/O countries/O have/O visited/O Islamabad/LOCATION in/O the/O past/O few/O months/O ./O 
Pakistani/O PM/O Nawaz/PERSON Sharif/PERSON will/O soon/O tour/O the/O region/O ./O 
The/O country/O 's/O authorities/O believe/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION can/O play/O a/O vital/O role/O in/O linking/O up/O <LOCATION>Central/O</LOCATION> and/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
They/O think/O they/O can/O exploit/O this/O opportunity/O ,/O ''/O Bakar/PERSON Najamuddin/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O on/O international/O relations/O at/O the/O Islamabad-based/O National/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Science/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Technology/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Najamuddin/PERSON denies/O reports/O that/O some/O Central/O Asian/O countries/O are/O reluctant/O to/O work/O with/O Islamabad/LOCATION because/O of/O its/O alleged/O support/O to/O Islamist/O militants/O ./O 
``/O There/O is/O a/O militancy/O problem/O in/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION as/O well/O as/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ./O 
You/O ca/O n't/O blame/O Pakistan/LOCATION for/O these/O problems/O ./O 
Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O too/O ,/O has/O to/O work/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION despite/O its/O warming/O ties/O with/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION ./O 
It/O is/O far/O more/O costly/O for/O India/LOCATION to/O connect/O to/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION through/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O geostrategic/O significance/O ca/O n't/O be/O undermined/O ,/O ''/O the/O expert/O underlined/O ./O 
But/O analyst/O Aman/PERSON Memon/PERSON believes/O a/O <LOCATION>South/O Asia/O</LOCATION> -/O Central/O Asian/O grouping/O can/O not/O be/O formed/O until/O Islamabad/LOCATION abandons/O ``/O support/O ''/O for/O certain/O Islamists/O ./O 
``/O Pakistan/LOCATION wants/O to/O counter/O Indian/O influence/O ,/O but/O peace/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION is/O the/O most/O crucial/O thing/O in/O forging/O that/O kind/O of/O an/O alliance/O ./O 
It/O 's/O not/O only/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O but/O also/O Central/O Asian/O countries/O that/O are/O critical/O of/O Pakistan-based/O militants/O ./O 
They/O are/O unhappy/O with/O Islamabad/LOCATION 's/O regional/O policies/O that/O are/O emboldening/O Islamists/O ,/O ''/O Memon/PERSON told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O `/O economic/O colony/O '/O 
Experts/O point/O to/O the/O fact/O that/O in/O the/O present/O scenario/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION is/O relying/O too/O much/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
They/O say/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O more/O than/O willing/O to/O support/O China/LOCATION in/O its/O regional/O ambitions/O and/O be/O a/O ``/O client/O state/O ,/O ''/O given/O that/O the/O US/LOCATION has/O very/O little/O to/O offer/O economically/O and/O geo-politically/O in/O the/O present/O circumstances/O ./O 
Is/O Islamabad/LOCATION relying/O too/O much/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION ?/O 
``/O Islamabad/LOCATION has/O no/O other/O option/O but/O to/O increase/O cooperation/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O do/O what/O it/O says/O ,/O ''/O development/O analyst/O Maqsood/PERSON Ahmad/PERSON Jan/PERSON told/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
``/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ca/O n't/O be/O as/O big/O an/O investor/O as/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O US/LOCATION is/O unreliable/O ,/O and/O the/O Pakistani/O government/O needs/O money/O urgently/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
<PERSON>Jan/O</PERSON> goes/O on/O to/O say/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION has/O sold/O out/O to/O China/LOCATION for/O $/O 46/O billion/O ,/O referring/O to/O the/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> project/O ./O 
``/O I/O think/O the/O Chinese/O aid/O is/O not/O for/O free/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O economy/O is/O not/O that/O big/O ,/O so/O Beijing/LOCATION will/O now/O take/O over/O most/O of/O our/O income-generating/O sectors/O ./O ''/O 
But/O Ahsan/PERSON Iqbal/PERSON ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O minister/O for/O planning/O and/O development/O ,/O believes/O the/O forthcoming/O economic/O deals/O with/O China/LOCATION would/O be/O beneficial/O for/O his/O country/O ./O 
``/O The/O real/O opportunity/O of/O this/O <U_LOCATION>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> is/O that/O it/O changes/O the/O scope/O of/O the/O relationship/O from/O geopolitics/O to/O geo-economics/O ,/O ''/O Iqbal/PERSON told/O journalists/O ,/O adding/O that/O the/O projects/O would/O have/O a/O ``/O significant/O transformative/O effect/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O economy/O ./O ''/O 
<PERSON>Jan/O</PERSON> ,/O however/O ,/O does/O not/O agree/O with/O Iqbal/PERSON 's/O assessment/O of/O Sino-Pakistani/O economic/O ties/O ./O 
``/O This/O will/O turn/O us/O into/O China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O colony/O instead/O ./O ''/O 
Additional/O reporting/O by/O Sattar/PERSON Khan/PERSON ,/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Islamabad/LOCATION correspondent/O ./O
