President-elect/O Trump/PERSON seems/O to/O want/O to/O fiddle/O with/O the/O long-established/O ``/O one-China/O ''/O policy/O ./O 
For/O him/O ,/O politics/O appear/O to/O be/O a/O matter/O of/O business/O ./O 
But/O he/O 's/O wrong/O ./O 
China/LOCATION will/O not/O engage/O in/O any/O deal/O ,/O says/O Rodion/PERSON Ebbighausen/PERSON ./O 
Even/O before/O taking/O office/O as/O US/LOCATION President/O ,/O Donald/PERSON Trump/PERSON has/O managed/O to/O attack/O the/O foreign/O policy/O foundations/O shared/O by/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION ./O 
He/O did/O that/O by/O throwing/O into/O doubt/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O commitment/O to/O the/O so-called/O ``/O one-China/O ''/O policy/O ,/O according/O to/O which/O there/O is/O only/O one/O China/LOCATION in/O the/O world/O and/O the/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O its/O true/O representative/O ./O 
Any/O country/O that/O wants/O to/O establish/O diplomatic/O relations/O with/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION must/O recognize/O the/O one-China/O policy/O and/O relinquish/O official/O ties/O with/O Taiwan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION has/O complied/O with/O these/O demands/O for/O the/O past/O 37/O years/O ./O 
Since/O his/O surprise/O victory/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION presidential/O elections/O ,/O Trump/PERSON 's/O statements/O and/O gestures/O have/O struck/O a/O raw/O nerve/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
In/O an/O infraction/O of/O diplomatic/O protocol/O ,/O he/O entertained/O a/O telephonic/O conversation/O with/O Taiwan/LOCATION 's/O leader/O Tsai/PERSON Ing-wen/PERSON ./O 
This/O was/O then/O followed/O by/O a/O tweet/O ,/O ``/O Did/O China/LOCATION ask/O us/O if/O it/O was/O OK/O to/O devalue/O their/O currency/O -LRB-/O making/O it/O hard/O for/O our/O companies/O to/O compete/O -RRB-/O ,/O heavily/O tax/O our/O products/O going/O into/O their/O country/O -LRB-/O the/O US/LOCATION does/O n't/O tax/O them/O -RRB-/O or/O to/O build/O a/O massive/O military/O complex/O in/O the/O middle/O of/O the/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ?/O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O so/O !/O ''/O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Rodion/PERSON Ebbighausen/PERSON 
Foreign/O policy/O is/O no/O business/O 
The/O comment/O shows/O how/O Trump/PERSON sees/O the/O world/O :/O For/O him/O ,/O politics/O is/O all/O about/O trade/O ,/O big/O business/O and/O deal-making/O ./O 
But/O he/O has/O to/O understand/O that/O international/O relations/O are/O not/O solely/O about/O doing/O business/O and/O making/O money/O ./O 
By/O questioning/O the/O one-China/O policy/O ,/O Trump/PERSON has/O targeted/O one/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O core/O interests/O ./O 
A/O pillar/O on/O which/O the/O ruling/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION 's/O legitimacy/O rests/O is/O the/O defense/O and/O preservation/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O territorial/O integrity/O ./O 
And/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O Macau/LOCATION ,/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O ,/O in/O particular/O ,/O Taiwan/LOCATION are/O -/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O point/O of/O view/O -/O inalienable/O parts/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Any/O deviation/O from/O this/O point/O of/O view/O would/O call/O into/O question/O the/O political/O narrative/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION has/O propagated/O and/O solidified/O over/O decades/O ./O 
There/O is/O even/O the/O danger/O of/O a/O revolt/O by/O a/O hyper-nationalistic/O population/O ,/O whose/O nationalism/O has/O been/O stoked/O by/O the/O party/O for/O years/O ,/O particularly/O over/O the/O Taiwan/LOCATION issue/O ./O 
Taiwan/LOCATION is/O at/O the/O core/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O national/O interests/O ./O 
And/O no/O country/O stands/O ready/O to/O trade/O away/O its/O core/O national/O interests/O ,/O certainly/O not/O for/O some/O business/O deal/O ./O 
A/O lose-lose/O situation/O Trump/PERSON 's/O move/O is/O a/O dangerous/O misjudgment/O ,/O and/O it/O 's/O hard/O to/O see/O anyone/O gaining/O anything/O from/O it/O ./O 
Because/O of/O their/O extensive/O economic/O ties/O ,/O both/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION would/O suffer/O massively/O from/O a/O worsening/O of/O relations/O ,/O which/O could/O even/O lead/O to/O a/O trade/O war/O between/O the/O two/O sides/O ./O 
And/O Taiwan/LOCATION faces/O the/O threat/O of/O becoming/O a/O pawn/O in/O the/O geopolitical/O game/O between/O the/O two/O Pacific/LOCATION powers/O ./O 
There/O are/O already/O many/O unresolved/O crises/O in/O the/O world/O ./O 
And/O it/O is/O completely/O incomprehensible/O why/O Trump/PERSON wants/O to/O create/O another/O one/O without/O any/O need/O ./O 
Have/O something/O to/O say/O ?/O 
Add/O your/O comments/O below/O ./O 
The/O thread/O will/O remain/O open/O for/O 24/O hours/O after/O publication/O ./O
