Microsoft/ORGANIZATION learned/O years/O ago/O that/O China/LOCATION and/O other/O states/O were/O hacking/O into/O users/O '/O hotmail/O accounts/O but/O did/O nothing/O to/O warn/O their/O customers/O ./O 
That/O policy/O is/O about/O to/O change/O ./O 
Microsoft/ORGANIZATION Corp/ORGANIZATION experts/O concluded/O several/O years/O ago/O that/O Chinese/O authorities/O had/O hacked/O into/O more/O than/O a/O thousand/O <ORGANIZATION>Hotmail/O</ORGANIZATION> email/O accounts/O ,/O targeting/O international/O leaders/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Tibetan/O and/O Uighur/O minorities/O in/O particular/O -/O but/O it/O decided/O not/O to/O tell/O the/O victims/O ,/O allowing/O the/O hackers/O to/O continue/O their/O campaign/O ,/O according/O to/O former/O employees/O of/O the/O company/O ./O 
On/O Wednesday/O ,/O after/O a/O series/O of/O requests/O for/O comment/O from/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O Microsoft/ORGANIZATION said/O it/O will/O change/O its/O policy/O and/O in/O the/O future/O tell/O its/O email/O customers/O when/O it/O suspects/O there/O has/O been/O a/O government/O hacking/O attempt/O ./O 
Microsoft/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Frank/PERSON Shaw/PERSON said/O the/O company/O was/O never/O certain/O of/O the/O origin/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Hotmail/O</ORGANIZATION> attacks/O ./O 
The/O company/O also/O confirmed/O for/O the/O first/O time/O that/O it/O had/O not/O called/O ,/O emailed/O or/O otherwise/O told/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Hotmail/O</ORGANIZATION> users/O that/O their/O electronic/O correspondence/O had/O been/O collected/O ./O 
The/O company/O declined/O to/O say/O what/O role/O the/O exposure/O of/O the/O <ORGANIZATION>Hotmail/O</ORGANIZATION> campaign/O played/O in/O its/O decision/O to/O make/O the/O policy/O shift/O ./O 
The/O first/O public/O signal/O of/O the/O attacks/O came/O in/O May/O 2011/O ,/O though/O no/O direct/O link/O was/O immediately/O made/O with/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O ./O 
That/O 's/O when/O security/O firm/O Trend/ORGANIZATION Micro/ORGANIZATION Inc/ORGANIZATION announced/O it/O had/O found/O an/O email/O sent/O to/O someone/O in/O Taiwan/LOCATION that/O contained/O a/O miniature/O computer/O program/O ./O 
Obama/PERSON threatened/O to/O impose/O US/LOCATION sanctions/O on/O Chinese/O hackers/O who/O persist/O with/O cyber/O crimes/O The/O program/O took/O advantage/O of/O a/O previously/O undetected/O flaw/O in/O Microsoft/ORGANIZATION 's/O own/O web/O pages/O to/O direct/O <ORGANIZATION>Hotmail/O</ORGANIZATION> and/O other/O free/O Microsoft/ORGANIZATION email/O services/O to/O secretly/O forward/O copies/O of/O all/O of/O a/O recipient/O 's/O incoming/O mail/O to/O an/O account/O controlled/O by/O the/O attacker/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>Trend/O Micro/O</ORGANIZATION> found/O more/O than/O a/O thousand/O victims/O ,/O and/O Microsoft/ORGANIZATION patched/O the/O vulnerability/O before/O the/O security/O company/O announced/O its/O findings/O publicly/O ./O 
Attacks/O began/O in/O 2009/O Microsoft/ORGANIZATION also/O launched/O its/O own/O investigation/O that/O year/O ,/O finding/O that/O some/O interception/O had/O begun/O in/O July/O 2009/O and/O had/O compromised/O the/O emails/O of/O top/O Uighur/O and/O Tibetan/O leaders/O in/O multiple/O countries/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O Japanese/O and/O African/O diplomats/O ,/O human/O rights/O lawyers/O and/O others/O in/O sensitive/O positions/O inside/O China/LOCATION ,/O two/O former/O Microsoft/ORGANIZATION employees/O said/O ./O 
They/O spoke/O separately/O and/O on/O the/O condition/O that/O they/O not/O be/O identified/O ./O 
Watch/O video/O 01:30/O 
Share/O A/O short/O history/O of/O hacking/O 
Send/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION Twitter/ORGANIZATION Google/ORGANIZATION +/O <ORGANIZATION>Whatsapp/O Tumblr/O</ORGANIZATION> linkedin/O stumble/O Digg/ORGANIZATION reddit/O <ORGANIZATION>Newsvine/O</ORGANIZATION> Permalink/O http://dw.com/p/1AT9p/O 
Hacking/O ,/O Cybercrime/O or/O Cyberwarfare/O 
Some/O of/O the/O attacks/O had/O come/O from/O a/O Chinese/O network/O known/O as/O AS4808/O ,/O which/O has/O been/O associated/O with/O major/O spying/O campaigns/O ,/O including/O a/O 2011/O attack/O on/O EMC/ORGANIZATION Corp/ORGANIZATION 's/O security/O division/O RSA/O that/O U.S./LOCATION intelligence/O officials/O publicly/O attributed/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
To/O see/O the/O report/O click/O here/O http://www.secureworks.com/cyber-threat-intelligence/threats/sindigoo//O 
Microsoft/ORGANIZATION officials/O did/O not/O dispute/O that/O most/O of/O the/O attacks/O came/O from/O China/LOCATION ,/O but/O said/O some/O came/O from/O elsewhere/O ./O 
They/O did/O not/O give/O further/O detail/O ./O 
bik/rg/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O <ORGANIZATION>AFP/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O
