A/O Thai/O military/O court/O has/O put/O on/O trial/O two/O foreigners/O accused/O of/O bombing/O a/O Hindu/O shrine/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION in/O 2015/O that/O killed/O 20/O people/O and/O injured/O more/O than/O 120/O ./O 
It/O was/O one/O of/O the/O deadliest/O attacks/O in/O the/O country/O in/O decades/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O
Thai/O court/O indicts/O two/O for/O Bangkok/LOCATION shrine/O bombing/O
Rights/O groups/O slam/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O Uighur/O repatriation/O Thailand/LOCATION has/O forcibly/O sent/O back/O to/O China/LOCATION over/O 100/O Uighur/O Muslims/O who/O had/O been/O detained/O in/O the/O country/O since/O last/O year/O ./O 
The/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION has/O condemned/O the/O decision/O ,/O saying/O the/O Uighurs/O could/O face/O persecution/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O -LRB-/O 09.07.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Malaysia/LOCATION detains/O eight/O over/O Bangkok/LOCATION blast/O 
Malaysian/O police/O have/O arrested/O eight/O people/O on/O suspicion/O of/O being/O involved/O in/O the/O deadly/O bombing/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION last/O month/O ./O 
The/O worst/O attack/O in/O the/O city/O 's/O history/O has/O already/O impacted/O the/O country/O 's/O tourism/O industry/O ./O -LRB-/O 23.09.2015/O -RRB-/O 
Thailand/LOCATION 's/O military-appointed/O lawmakers/O meet/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION Thailand/LOCATION 's/O military-dominated/O legislature/O has/O held/O its/O first/O session/O ,/O after/O the/O army/O took/O power/O in/O a/O coup/O on/O May/O 22/O ./O 
The/O body/O is/O expected/O to/O appoint/O a/O prime/O minster/O and/O cabinet/O later/O this/O year/O ./O -LRB-/O 08.08.2014/O -RRB-/O 
The/O ethnic/O Uighur/O defendants/O of/O Chinese/O nationality/O were/O driven/O straight/O into/O the/O military/O court/O building/O Tuesday/O ,/O preventing/O reporters/O from/O approaching/O them/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Mieraili/PERSON Yusufu/PERSON</U_PERSON> and/O <U_PERSON>Bilal/PERSON Mohammad/PERSON</U_PERSON> are/O accused/O of/O being/O behind/O the/O August/O 17/O ,/O 2015/O bombing/O of/O the/O <LOCATION>Erawan/O</LOCATION> shrine/O that/O killed/O 20/O people/O -/O 14/O of/O them/O tourists/O ./O 
Prosecutors/O accuse/O <U_PERSON>Mohammed/PERSON</U_PERSON> of/O placing/O the/O bomb/O inside/O a/O backpack/O at/O the/O shrine/O and/O say/O <U_PERSON>Mieraili/PERSON</U_PERSON> was/O involved/O in/O transporting/O the/O device/O ./O 
Both/O have/O pleaded/O not/O guilty/O at/O a/O recent/O pre-trial/O hearing/O where/O they/O broke/O down/O in/O tears/O and/O complained/O of/O mistreatment/O at/O the/O hands/O of/O authorities/O which/O he/O said/O threatened/O him/O with/O deportation/O and/O menaced/O him/O with/O a/O police/O dog/O ./O 
Defense/O attorneys/O say/O they/O do/O n't/O expect/O proceedings/O to/O be/O swift/O ./O 
``/O Today/O is/O the/O first/O day/O for/O witness/O testimony/O .../O I/O think/O it/O -LRB-/O the/O trial/O -RRB-/O will/O last/O until/O next/O year/O ./O 
It/O will/O take/O quite/O some/O time/O ,/O ''/O Chuchart/PERSON Kanpai/PERSON ,/O a/O defense/O attorney/O said/O ./O 
Prosecutors/O allege/O the/O bombing/O was/O revenge/O by/O a/O people-smuggling/O gang/O whose/O activities/O were/O disrupted/O by/O a/O crackdown/O ./O 
But/O others/O speculate/O the/O violence/O could/O be/O the/O work/O of/O Uighur/O separatists/O angry/O that/O Thailand/LOCATION in/O July/O had/O forcibly/O repatriated/O scores/O of/O their/O brethren/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O where/O they/O could/O face/O persecuted/O ./O 
Thai/O national/O Kanya/PERSON Mayoon/PERSON ,/O 36/O ,/O lost/O her/O sister/O Prani/PERSON Srisuwa/PERSON in/O the/O bombing/O and/O says/O he/O 's/O not/O convinced/O authorities/O are/O interested/O in/O getting/O real/O answers/O ./O 
``/O It/O seemed/O like/O they/O just/O wanted/O to/O close/O the/O case/O quickly/O ,/O ''/O she/O told/O the/O AFP/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O ./O 
``/O I/O just/O want/O the/O real/O masterminds/O to/O be/O arrested/O and/O punished/O ./O ''/O 
The/O shrine/O is/O popular/O among/O ethnic/O Chinese/O tourists/O ,/O who/O made/O up/O a/O majority/O of/O the/O dead/O with/O five/O from/O Malaysia/LOCATION ,/O five/O from/O China/LOCATION and/O two/O from/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ./O 
Thailand/LOCATION 's/O military/O courts/O were/O strengthened/O to/O try/O civilians/O in/O ``/O national/O security/O ''/O cases/O after/O a/O May/O 2014/O military/O coup/O ./O 
The/O defendants/O have/O been/O held/O at/O an/O army/O base/O since/O their/O arrest/O in/O late/O August/O and/O early/O September/O 2015/O ./O 
No/O other/O details/O of/O their/O interrogation/O have/O been/O revealed/O ./O 
Some/O of/O the/O 15/O other/O suspects/O are/O Turks/O ,/O with/O whom/O Uighurs/O share/O ethnic/O bonds/O ,/O and/O Turkey/LOCATION is/O home/O to/O a/O large/O Uighur/O community/O ./O 
The/O August/O 17/O ,/O 2015/O bombing/O of/O the/O <LOCATION>Erawan/O</LOCATION> shrine/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION 's/O most/O popular/O shopping/O district/O of/O Ratchaprasong/LOCATION was/O one/O of/O the/O deadliest/O acts/O of/O violence/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION in/O decades/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O deadliest/O attacks/O in/O decades/O The/O Uighur/O minority/O claims/O cultural/O and/O religious/O repression/O in/O their/O homeland/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O northwest/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O many/O have/O fled/O the/O restive/O region/O in/O recent/O years/O ./O 
Thai/O police/O 's/O conduct/O raised/O questions/O when/O the/O office/O 's/O then-chief/O -/O who/O has/O since/O gone/O on/O to/O become/O head/O of/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O soccer/O federation/O -/O awarded/O his/O officers/O an/O $/O 80,000/O reward/O that/O had/O been/O open/O to/O the/O public/O ./O 
jar/rc/O -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O
