Pakistani/O Prime/O Minister/O Sharif/PERSON has/O hailed/O the/O <U_LOCATION>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O as/O a/O harbinger/O of/O change/O for/O the/O region/O ./O 
But/O analyst/O Siegfried/PERSON O./PERSON Wolf/PERSON tells/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> the/O project/O comes/O with/O a/O big/O price/O for/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> recommends/O 
Gwadar/LOCATION --/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O impoverished/O colony/O or/O an/O economic/O hub/O ?/O 
Despite/O much-vaunted/O Chinese-Pakistani/O development/O projects/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Gwadar/LOCATION city/O ,/O the/O locals/O still/O have/O no/O access/O to/O clean/O water/O ./O 
And/O separatists/O have/O vowed/O to/O resist/O what/O they/O say/O is/O Sino-Pakistani/O colonization/O ./O -LRB-/O 14.04.2016/O -RRB-/O 
China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O corridor/O creating/O new/O conflicts/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION 
Pakistani/O PM/O Sharif/PERSON has/O inaugurated/O a/O two-day/O <U_LOCATION>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> summit/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O hailing/O the/O project/O as/O a/O milestone/O for/O his/O country/O ./O 
But/O opposition/O to/O the/O project/O is/O increasing/O amid/O new/O conflicts/O ./O -LRB-/O 29.08.2016/O -RRB-/O 
Brahamdagh/PERSON Bugti/PERSON :/O `/O China-Pakistan/O deal/O usurps/O Balochistan/LOCATION 's/O resources/O '/O 
In/O an/O interview/O with/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O <LOCATION>Baloch/PERSON</LOCATION> leader/O Brahamdagh/PERSON Bugti/PERSON says/O the/O recent/O multi-billion/O dollar/O economic/O corridor/O deal/O between/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION is/O aimed/O at/O colonizing/O the/O Balochistan/LOCATION province/O ,/O and/O must/O be/O resisted/O ./O -LRB-/O 24.04.2015/O -RRB-/O 
On/O Sunday/O ,/O November/O 13/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O top/O civilian/O and/O military/O leaders/O inaugurated/O a/O new/O international/O route/O which/O connects/O the/O country/O 's/O renovated/O southwestern/O Gwadar/LOCATION port/O to/O the/O Chinese/O city/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> as/O part/O of/O a/O joint/O multi-billion-dollar/O project/O ,/O the/O <U_LOCATION>China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O ./O 
The/O first/O convoy/O of/O Chinese/O trucks/O carrying/O goods/O for/O sale/O abroad/O arrived/O in/O the/O <OTHER>South/LOCATION Asian/LOCATION</OTHER> country/O on/O Saturday/O ,/O and/O the/O Pakistani/O authorities/O saw/O them/O off/O on/O Sunday/O ./O 
Last/O year/O ,/O China/LOCATION announced/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> worth/O $/O 46/O billion/O -LRB-/O 41/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O ./O 
With/O the/O project/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION aims/O to/O expand/O its/O influence/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O across/O <LOCATION>Central/O</LOCATION> and/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION in/O order/O to/O counter/O US/LOCATION and/O Indian/O influence/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> also/O includes/O plans/O to/O create/O road/O ,/O rail/O and/O oil/O pipeline/O links/O to/O improve/O connectivity/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION is/O grappling/O with/O an/O acute/O economic/O crisis/O ./O 
Experts/O say/O that/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> can/O certainly/O stir/O the/O much-needed/O economic/O activity/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
In/O his/O speech/O on/O Sunday/O ,/O Pakistani/O Prime/O Minister/O Nawaz/PERSON Sharif/PERSON said/O that/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> would/O benefit/O some/O three/O billion/O people/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
``/O The/O participants/O of/O the/O pilot/O convoy/O ,/O who/O have/O made/O it/O to/O Gwadar/LOCATION ,/O are/O the/O harbingers/O of/O development/O and/O progress/O ,/O that/O this/O region/O is/O to/O see/O soon/O ,/O ''/O Sharif/PERSON told/O audience/O at/O the/O ceremony/O that/O included/O his/O country/O 's/O powerful/O army/O chief/O Raheel/PERSON Sharif/PERSON and/O senior/O Chinese/O officials/O ./O 
``/O The/O Enemies/O of/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> are/O enemies/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Sharif/PERSON said/O ,/O vowing/O to/O provide/O security/O to/O all/O foreign/O investors/O ./O 
The/O security/O situation/O in/O Baluchistan/LOCATION ,/O where/O Gwadar/LOCATION is/O located/O ,/O is/O worsening/O ,/O with/O ``/O <ORGANIZATION>Islamic/O State/O</ORGANIZATION> ''/O -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O claiming/O two/O large-scale/O attacks/O in/O the/O past/O few/O weeks/O ./O 
On/O Saturday/O ,/O the/O group/O attacked/O a/O Sufi/O shrine/O in/O the/O Lasbela/LOCATION district/O of/O the/O volatile/O Baluchistan/LOCATION province/O ,/O killing/O at/O least/O 50/O worshippers/O ./O 
Wolf/PERSON :/O `/O There/O is/O a/O big/O question/O mark/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O ability/O to/O secure/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/O</U_LOCATION> projects/O '/O The/O <LOCATION>Baluch/O</LOCATION> separatists/O strongly/O oppose/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O saying/O that/O the/O bigger/O Punjab/LOCATION province/O want/O to/O reap/O all/O the/O benefits/O while/O using/O their/O lands/O and/O resources/O to/O implement/O the/O project/O ./O 
Ignoring/O the/O concerns/O of/O the/O local/O communities/O and/O their/O leaders/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION vowed/O to/O continue/O with/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> at/O all/O costs/O ./O 
The/O military/O says/O that/O those/O opposing/O the/O economic/O corridor/O plan/O are/O against/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O economic/O prosperity/O and/O are/O ``/O traitors/O ./O ''/O 
Will/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> prove/O to/O be/O a/O game/O changer/O for/O the/O Pakistani/O economy/O ?/O 
How/O is/O the/O domestic/O opposition/O to/O the/O project/O and/O a/O deteriorating/O security/O situation/O complicating/O Islamabad/LOCATION 's/O ambitions/O ?/O 
In/O a/O <ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> interview/O ,/O Siegfried/PERSON O/PERSON Wolf/PERSON ,/O a/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Heidelberg/ORGANIZATION ,/O who/O is/O currently/O researching/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> and/O has/O written/O several/O scholarly/O papers/O on/O the/O issue/O ,/O talks/O about/O some/O of/O the/O pressing/O questions/O related/O to/O the/O project/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>DW/O</ORGANIZATION> :/O Pakistani/O Prime/O Minister/O Nawaz/PERSON Sharif/PERSON says/O the/O project/O would/O bring/O unprecedented/O progress/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O the/O region/O ./O 
Do/O you/O agree/O with/O his/O statement/O ?/O 
Siegfried/PERSON O/PERSON Wolf/PERSON :/O The/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> project/O will/O open/O the/O way/O for/O Chinese/O investments/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
This/O is/O much/O needed/O as/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O trying/O to/O reduce/O its/O dependence/O on/O the/O US/LOCATION support/O ,/O which/O Pakistani/O authorities/O think/O could/O be/O further/O at/O stake/O when/O India-friendly/O US/LOCATION President-elect/O Donald/PERSON Trump/PERSON takes/O office/O in/O January/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> has/O the/O potential/O to/O boost/O the/O South/O Asian/O country/O 's/O national/O economy/O but/O not/O all/O Pakistani/O provinces/O will/O profit/O from/O this/O economic/O ``/O game/O changer/O ./O ''/O 
We/O see/O that/O provincial/O asymmetries/O related/O to/O infrastructure/O ,/O energy/O projects/O and/O budget/O allocations/O are/O skewed/O in/O favor/O of/O the/O Punjab/LOCATION province/O ,/O where/O the/O Pakistani/O civilian/O and/O military/O ruling/O classes/O hail/O from/O ./O 
Also/O ,/O areas/O like/O <LOCATION>Gilgit-Baltistan/PERSON</LOCATION> will/O be/O severely/O affected/O by/O the/O negative/O impacts/O of/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> projects/O ,/O particularly/O on/O the/O environment/O ./O 
Additionally/O ,/O the/O economic/O corridor/O project/O will/O most/O likely/O lack/O regional/O connectivity/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O deteriorating/O relations/O with/O India/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION will/O hinder/O the/O reach/O and/O scope/O of/O the/O project/O ./O 
Rights/O groups/O accuse/O the/O military/O of/O committing/O grave/O human/O rights/O abuses/O in/O Baluchistan/LOCATION 
<OTHER>Security/LOCATION</OTHER> problems/O have/O mired/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> with/O numerous/O militant/O attacks/O in/O Baluchistan/LOCATION and/O other/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O ,/O but/O Beijing/LOCATION says/O it/O is/O confident/O the/O Pakistani/O military/O is/O in/O control/O ./O 
Can/O Islamabad/LOCATION ensure/O security/O for/O the/O project/O ?/O 
<U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O success/O depends/O largely/O on/O regional/O stability/O ,/O security/O ,/O and/O rule/O of/O law/O ./O 
Without/O these/O guarantees/O ,/O Chinese/O companies/O will/O be/O hesitant/O to/O make/O more/O investments/O beyond/O the/O current/O agreements/O ./O 
Consequently/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O stepping/O up/O its/O security/O engagement/O regarding/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> -/O the/O deployment/O of/O an/O increased/O number/O of/O troops/O along/O the/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> route/O and/O new/O counter-terrorism/O policies/O accompanied/O by/O special/O laws/O to/O empower/O the/O military/O and/O its/O intelligence/O services/O are/O some/O examples/O ./O 
Despite/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O number/O of/O terrorist/O attacks/O in/O the/O country/O has/O dropped/O ,/O terrorists/O are/O still/O able/O to/O carry/O out/O major/O attacks/O ./O 
There/O is/O a/O big/O question/O mark/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O ability/O to/O secure/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/O</U_LOCATION> projects/O ./O 
Some/O analysts/O say/O that/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> would/O benefit/O China/LOCATION more/O than/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
Some/O even/O say/O it/O would/O turn/O Pakistan/LOCATION into/O china/LOCATION 's/O ``/O economic/O colony/O ./O ''/O 
What/O is/O your/O take/O on/O that/O ?/O 
These/O new/O Chinese/O investments/O could/O boost/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O economy/O but/O at/O the/O same/O time/O it/O will/O also/O create/O dependency/O ./O 
The/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> projects/O come/O with/O a/O price/O ./O 
Besides/O infrastructural/O and/O economic/O linkages/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O also/O aiming/O for/O security/O and/O political/O connectivity/O ./O 
Islamabad/LOCATION will/O be/O expected/O to/O align/O its/O political/O decision/O making/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O approach/O towards/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O beyond/O ./O 
Subsequently/O ,/O the/O argument/O that/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> will/O turn/O Pakistan/LOCATION into/O China/LOCATION 's/O client/O state/O will/O be/O strengthened/O ./O 
Last/O year/O ,/O China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION signed/O deals/O related/O to/O energy/O and/O infrastructure/O projects/O worth/O $/O 46/O billion/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> has/O claimed/O two/O attacks/O in/O Baluchistan/LOCATION in/O the/O past/O few/O weeks/O ./O 
Is/O the/O group/O expanding/O in/O the/O province/O ?/O 
Will/O it/O be/O a/O problem/O for/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> implementation/O ?/O 
There/O is/O no/O doubt/O that/O IS/O activities/O are/O increasing/O in/O the/O Afghanistan-Pakistan/O region/O ./O 
It/O definitely/O poses/O a/O serious/O challenge/O to/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
We/O must/O not/O forget/O that/O terrorist/O organizations/O like/O IS/O and/O <ORGANIZATION>al/O Qaeda/O</ORGANIZATION> are/O critical/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O handling/O of/O its/O Uighur/O Muslim/O population/O ./O 
There/O is/O a/O threat/O that/O these/O groups/O will/O identify/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> projects/O as/O potential/O targets/O in/O their/O so-called/O ``/O jihad/O against/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Much/O will/O depend/O on/O how/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O security/O establishment/O deals/O with/O this/O new/O threat/O ./O 
With/O the/O impending/O decline/O of/O <ORGANIZATION>IS/O</ORGANIZATION> in/O Iraq/LOCATION ,/O we/O should/O expect/O an/O influx/O of/O more/O jihadists/O not/O only/O in/O Syria/LOCATION but/O also/O in/O the/O Afghanistan-Pakistan/O region/O ./O 
Which/O countries/O in/O the/O region/O are/O opposing/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O and/O why/O ?/O 
Every/O country/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O including/O India/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O is/O in/O favor/O of/O regional/O economic/O cooperation/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O main/O problem/O with/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> lies/O in/O the/O fact/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O trying/O to/O gain/O strategic/O and/O political/O leverage/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION by/O increasing/O connectivity/O through/O economic/O linkages/O ./O 
The/O fact/O that/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> is/O combined/O with/O a/O remarkable/O increase/O of/O security/O and/O defense/O cooperation/O between/O Islamabad/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION can/O be/O identified/O as/O an/O indicator/O that/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> goes/O far/O beyond/O trade/O and/O economic/O collaboration/O ./O 
This/O has/O alarmed/O Indian/O policy/O makers/O ./O 
Gwadar/LOCATION lacks/O fundamental/O necessities/O of/O life/O like/O clean/O water/O 
Also/O ,/O the/O fact/O that/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> includes/O the/O disputed/O territory/O of/O Gilgit-Baltistan/LOCATION inside/O Pakistan/LOCATION will/O create/O further/O problems/O ./O 
The/O area/O is/O close/O to/O Kashmir/LOCATION ,/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION 's/O major/O conflict/O zone/O ./O 
Getting/O strengthened/O by/O <U_LOCATION>CPEC/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> in/O those/O areas/O ,/O some/O Pakistan-based/O terrorist/O groups/O could/O seek/O to/O destabilize/O India-administered/O Kashmir/LOCATION ./O 
This/O will/O have/O international/O repercussions/O ./O 
Siegfried/PERSON O./PERSON Wolf/PERSON is/O a/O researcher/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Heidelberg/ORGANIZATION <OTHER>'s/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> South/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION ./O 
He/O is/O also/O the/O director/O of/O research/O at/O the/O Brussels-based/O <ORGANIZATION>South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION Democratic/O Forum/O</ORGANIZATION> -LRB-/O SADF/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O 
The/O interview/O was/O conducted/O by/O Shamil/PERSON Shams/PERSON ./O
