The/O central/O government/O order/O aims/O to/O show/O respect/O for/O minorities/O ./O 
However/O the/O move/O is/O also/O intended/O to/O put/O a/O stop/O to/O disagreements/O with/O the/O Han/O and/O to/O win/O the/O favour/O of/O oil-rich/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> countries/O ./O 
There/O is/O the/O influence/O of/O astrology/O too/O ,/O which/O predicts/O revolts/O and/O the/O overthrow/O of/O governments/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O 
In/O a/O week/O 's/O time/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O world/O will/O celebrate/O the/O New/O Year/O under/O the/O zodiac/O sign/O of/O the/O Pig/O ./O 
But/O for/O the/O Year/O of/O the/O Pig/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O banned/O all/O adverts/O showing/O this/O animal/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION is/O hoping/O to/O gain/O kudos/O from/O Islamic/O states/O for/O its/O sensitivity/O and/O respect/O for/O their/O religious/O convictions/O even/O if/O it/O continues/O repressing/O the/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O ,/O especially/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
In/O letter/O to/O advertising/O agencies/O ,/O the/O main/O state/O television/O CCTV/ORGANIZATION warned/O that/O ``/O since/O <LOCATION>China/O</LOCATION> is/O a/O multi-cultural/O country/O ,/O out/O of/O respect/O for/O the/O religious/O convictions/O of/O Muslims/O ,/O images/O of/O pigs/O must/O be/O avoided/O in/O 2007/O ./O ''/O 
TV/O sources/O said/O :/O ``/O This/O was/O indicated/O to/O us/O from/O top/O government/O quarters/O .../O to/O protect/O harmony/O between/O different/O religions/O and/O ethnic/O groups/O ''/O ./O 
It/O seems/O that/O the/O order/O has/O come/O from/O the/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION Standing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION <OTHER>of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION that/O wants/O the/O Year/O of/O the/O Pig/O -LRB-/O starting/O on/O 18/O February/O -RRB-/O to/O be/O celebrated/O without/O offending/O the/O country/O 's/O 21/O million/O Muslims/O ./O 
The/O order/O has/O created/O problems/O for/O big/O firms/O :/O they/O had/O already/O designed/O their/O publicity/O spots/O ,/O focused/O on/O the/O presence/O of/O pigs/O ,/O but/O now/O they/O must/O create/O new/O ones/O within/O a/O few/O days/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>Nestlé/O</ORGANIZATION> had/O prepared/O a/O cartoon/O of/O a/O beaming/O little/O pig/O celebrating/O a/O ``/O Happy/O Year/O of/O the/O Pig/O ''/O ./O 
Coca/ORGANIZATION Cola/ORGANIZATION had/O two/O cartoons/O ,/O one/O with/O a/O panda/O and/O the/O other/O with/O a/O pig/O ,/O but/O they/O will/O not/O broadcast/O the/O one/O with/O the/O pig/O in/O areas/O with/O big/O Muslim/O communities/O ./O 
The/O media/O have/O given/O the/O news/O importance/O and/O reported/O the/O enthusiastic/O response/O from/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> communities/O ./O 
For/O example/O ,/O Huo/PERSON Engjie/PERSON ,/O director/O in/O <LOCATION>Shanghai/O</LOCATION> of/O the/O Association/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Minorities/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O :/O ``/O Even/O if/O we/O -LSB-/O Muslims/O -RSB-/O are/O less/O than/O 2/O %/O of/O the/O Chinese/O population/O ,/O this/O ban/O shows/O how/O much/O the/O government/O respects/O us/O ./O 
It/O 's/O really/O moving/O ./O ''/O 
The/O Muslim/O population/O in/O China/LOCATION is/O divided/O into/O Hui/O --/O Chinese/O who/O have/O converted/O to/O Islam/ORGANIZATION --/O and/O Uighurs/O ./O 
The/O Hui/O ,/O around/O 15/O million/O ,/O are/O present/O especially/O in/O <LOCATION>Ningxia/PERSON</LOCATION> -LRB-/O Central/LOCATION China/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O Shaanxi/LOCATION ,/O Qinghai/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O always/O displayed/O considerable/O tact/O towards/O them/O ./O 
For/O decades/O ,/O while/O Catholics/O were/O forbidden/O from/O going/O to/O <LOCATION>Rome/O</LOCATION> ,/O the/O government/O subsidized/O Muslim/O pilgrimages/O to/O <LOCATION>Mecca/O</LOCATION> ./O 
However/O ,/O China/LOCATION implements/O a/O repressive/O and/O colonizing/O policy/O towards/O the/O Uighurs/O -LRB-/O of/O Turkish/O origin/O ,/O around/O eight/O million/O -RRB-/O ,/O aimed/O at/O putting/O a/O stop/O to/O autonomist/O aspirations/O and/O fundamentalist/O infiltrations/O from/O <LOCATION>Pakistan/O</LOCATION> and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
According/O to/O a/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> daily/O ,/O in/O 2005/O China/LOCATION arrested/O 18,227/O Uighurs/O on/O charges/O of/O ``/O threatening/O national/O security/O ''/O ./O 
Hundreds/O have/O been/O condemned/O to/O death/O ./O 
In/O January/O ,/O police/O attacked/O a/O training/O camp/O and/O killed/O 18/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O ,/O claiming/O without/O proof/O that/O that/O they/O were/O terrorists/O ./O 
For/O some/O years/O ,/O tension/O has/O also/O been/O growing/O with/O the/O Hui/O ,/O above/O all/O for/O social/O reasons/O ./O 
The/O Han/O --/O the/O Chinese/O race/O par/O excellence/O --/O are/O preferred/O in/O employment/O and/O trade/O and/O this/O has/O created/O resentment/O among/O the/O Hui/O and/O consequent/O clashes/O ./O 
There/O has/O also/O been/O a/O growth/O of/O Muslim/O integralism/O among/O the/O Hui/O ,/O owing/O to/O the/O influence/O of/O pilgrimages/O and/O the/O meeting/O of/O the/O ``/O Chinesized/O ''/O Islam/O of/O the/O Hui/O with/O more/O fundamentalist/O Pakistani/O and/O Saudi/O doctors/O of/O the/O Koran/O ./O 
The/O decision/O to/O ban/O images/O of/O the/O pig/O is/O an/O attempt/O to/O show/O ,/O at/O home/O and/O abroad/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O great/O respect/O for/O the/O Muslim/O world/O ./O 
After/O all/O ,/O China/LOCATION buys/O plenty/O of/O oil/O from/O Muslim/O countries/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O central/O Asia/LOCATION and/O Africa/LOCATION so/O it/O must/O be/O hoping/O this/O approach/O will/O draw/O appreciation/O from/O the/O Muslim/O world/O ./O 
The/O ban/O on/O images/O of/O the/O pig/O is/O being/O debated/O in/O many/O blog/O sites/O too/O ./O 
People/O from/O the/O ethnic/O Hui/O group/O consider/O the/O ban/O to/O be/O an/O exaggeration/O and/O show/O tolerance/O ./O 
``/O This/O New/O Year/O feast/O is/O a/O feast/O of/O the/O Han/O ,/O it/O 's/O not/O ours/O ./O 
We/O know/O how/O much/O importance/O the/O Han/O give/O to/O this/O animal/O -LSB-/O pig/O -RSB-/O ,/O it/O 's/O useless/O to/O ban/O it/O ,/O ''/O said/O one/O woman/O ./O 
Some/O believe/O the/O reason/O behind/O the/O ban/O on/O images/O of/O the/O pig/O lies/O in/O the/O fear/O that/O this/O year/O will/O be/O marked/O by/O clashes/O ,/O conflicts/O and/O dynastical/O changes/O ./O 
According/O to/O Chinese/O astrologists/O ,/O 2007/O is/O a/O year/O of/O the/O Pig/O marked/O by/O ``/O fire/O and/O water/O ''/O ,/O two/O contrasting/O elements/O that/O indicate/O the/O possibility/O of/O wars/O and/O conflicts/O ./O 
``/O There/O will/O be/O much/O disharmony/O that/O could/O lead/O to/O tensions/O and/O revolts/O to/O the/O point/O of/O overthrowing/O governments/O ''/O ./O
