New/O violence/O in/O the/O western/O Chinese/O province/O ,/O the/O theater/O of/O clashes/O between/O Beijing/LOCATION officers/O and/O Muslim/O separatists/O ./O 
The/O police/O say/O they/O reacted/O to/O an/O attack/O by/O the/O group/O of/O Muslims/O ;/O an/O association/O that/O defends/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O Uyghurs/O instead/O speaks/O of/O a/O ``/O deliberate/O attack/O ''/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
Six/O dead/O and/O three/O arrested/O :/O the/O tally/O is/O from/O an/O operation/O carried/O out/O by/O Chinese/O police/O in/O the/O western/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O a/O majority/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> area/O inhabited/O by/O ethnic/O Uyghurs/O ,/O which/O for/O some/O time/O has/O seen/O episodes/O of/O violence/O between/O separatists/O and/O the/O central/O government/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O initial/O version/O of/O events/O ,/O late/O yesterday/O evening/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kasghar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> a/O police/O patrol/O came/O across/O nine/O suspects/O ./O 
The/O group/O is/O believed/O to/O have/O reacted/O to/O the/O command/O to/O halt/O from/O the/O agents/O by/O pulling/O out/O knives/O ;/O the/O officers/O opened/O fire/O ,/O killing/O six/O people/O and/O wounding/O three/O ./O 
Sources/O from/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uygur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O an/O association/O that/O defends/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O ,/O based/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O affirms/O that/O the/O police/O deliberately/O fired/O on/O the/O group/O after/O they/O decided/O to/O surrender/O ./O 
It/O is/O not/O the/O first/O time/O that/O the/O province/O ,/O once/O known/O as/O eastern/O <U_LOCATION>Turkestan/O</U_LOCATION> ,/O has/O seen/O episodes/O of/O violence/O between/O pro-autonomy/O Islamic/O groups/O and/O the/O Chinese/O army/O ,/O conducting/O a/O genuine/O colonization/O of/O the/O region/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION accuses/O the/O Uyghurs/O of/O promoting/O terrorist/O attacks/O ,/O and/O decided/O to/O conduct/O yet/O another/O security/O crackdown/O in/O view/O of/O the/O Olympics/O ./O
