In/O a/O surprise/O move/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O raised/O the/O prices/O of/O gas/O ,/O diesel/O and/O electrical/O power/O by/O 15/O per/O cent/O ./O 
Consumers/O protest/O and/O analysts/O say/O measure/O is/O pointless/O without/O more/O efficient/O national/O energy/O policies/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O 
In/O an/O unexpected/O move/O the/O Chinese/O government/O raised/O the/O prices/O of/O fuel/O and/O power/O over/O night/O ./O 
The/O decision/O could/O fan/O inflation/O and/O trigger/O social/O unrest/O ./O 
The/O reaction/O on/O international/O markets/O was/O immediate/O ;/O oil/O prices/O fell/O with/O crude/O oil/O futures/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION sliding/O 2/O per/O cent/O as/O investors/O expect/O the/O jump/O to/O pare/O growth/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O energy/O demand/O ./O 
The/O retail/O ``/O guidance/O ''/O price/O for/O petrol/O was/O raised/O by/O 16.7/O per/O cent/O to/O 6,980/O yuan/O a/O tonne/O ;/O that/O for/O diesel/O by/O 18.1/O per/O cent/O to/O 6,520/O yuan/O a/O tonne/O ./O 
Retail/O electricity/O prices/O went/O up/O by/O an/O average/O 4.7/O per/O cent/O ,/O except/O for/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O areas/O hit/O in/O May/O by/O the/O Sichuan/LOCATION earthquake/O ./O 
In/O order/O to/O stifle/O social/O unrest/O the/O government/O also/O imposed/O temporary/O ceilings/O on/O coal/O whose/O prices/O must/O not/O be/O higher/O than/O those/O reached/O yesterday/O until/O further/O orders/O ./O 
The/O last/O measure/O seems/O however/O quite/O pointless/O since/O coal/O is/O used/O only/O industry/O and/O to/O a/O lesser/O extent/O in/O the/O rural/O areas/O where/O it/O is/O mined/O ./O 
Higher/O fuel/O prices/O will/O instead/O affect/O the/O rich/O southern/O regions/O and/O the/O big/O metropolitan/O centres/O like/O Shanghai/LOCATION where/O there/O was/O a/O run/O on/O gas/O stations/O by/O drivers/O anxious/O to/O buy/O gas/O before/O the/O new/O price/O kicked/O in/O ./O 
The/O government/O has/O tried/O to/O defend/O its/O decision/O to/O hike/O fuel/O prices/O ./O 
``/O Due/O to/O the/O sharp/O spike/O in/O international/O oil/O prices/O ,/O some/O refineries/O had/O to/O be/O shut/O down/O ,/O with/O queues/O at/O petrol/O stations/O and/O rationing/O re-emerging/O in/O some/O regions/O ,/O ''/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Reform/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O NDRC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O said/O ./O 
``/O Appropriate/O increases/O in/O fuel/O prices/O will/O help/O raise/O supply/O and/O promote/O energy/O conservation/O ./O ''/O 
``/O The/O increase/O is/O helpful/O ,/O but/O given/O they/O are/O losing/O US$/O 50/O for/O each/O barrel/O they/O process/O ,/O they/O are/O still/O far/O from/O returning/O to/O profitability/O ,/O unless/O more/O measures/O are/O taken/O ,/O ''/O <ORGANIZATION>Kim/PERSON Eng/O Securities/O</ORGANIZATION> analyst/O Larry/PERSON Grace/PERSON said/O ./O
