This/O is/O the/O opinion/O of/O experts/O ,/O who/O say/O there/O is/O widespread/O dissatisfaction/O with/O China/LOCATION among/O the/O population/O ./O 
The/O region/O is/O poorly/O developed/O ,/O although/O it/O is/O rich/O in/O oil/O and/O gas/O ./O 
Significant/O Han/O immigration/O is/O creating/O clashes/O with/O the/O Uygurs/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION must/O ``/O address/O the/O political/O causes/O behind/O the/O violence/O ''/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
The/O four/O security/O guards/O stabbed/O yesterday/O -LRB-/O three/O died/O -RRB-/O at/O a/O checkpoint/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Yamanya/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O a/O county/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Shule/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> about/O 30/O kilometers/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O were/O the/O victims/O of/O the/O third/O attack/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> in/O one/O week/O ./O 
The/O four/O or/O five/O aggressors/O got/O out/O of/O a/O vehicle/O that/O had/O been/O stopped/O for/O a/O routine/O check/O ,/O and/O attacked/O the/O guards/O ,/O all/O of/O whom/O were/O young/O Uygurs/O ./O 
On/O August/O 4/O ,/O a/O ``/O homemade/O ''/O bomb/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> killed/O 16/O guards/O and/O wounded/O another/O 16/O ,/O and/O on/O the/O 10th/O ,/O a/O series/O of/O bombs/O exploded/O at/O public/O buildings/O ,/O shops/O -LRB-/O in/O the/O photo/O -RRB-/O and/O hotels/O in/O the/O county/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Kuqa/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O 400/O kilometers/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O killed/O 11/O people/O ,/O including/O 10/O attackers/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O say/O there/O are/O no/O connections/O among/O the/O three/O attacks/O ,/O although/O the/O victims/O are/O all/O soldiers/O in/O the/O Chinese/O army/O ./O 
Experts/O like/O John/PERSON Harrison/PERSON of/O the/O Singapore-based/O International/ORGANIZATION Centre/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Violence/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Terrorism/ORGANIZATION Research/ORGANIZATION doubt/O that/O there/O is/O a/O connection/O with/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Eastern/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O a/O known/O terrorist/O group/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> that/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O identified/O as/O responsible/O for/O the/O first/O attack/O ./O 
Harrison/PERSON says/O there/O is/O widespread/O dissatisfaction/O among/O the/O Uygur/O population/O ,/O and/O says/O that/O in/O the/O long/O term/O ,/O China/LOCATION ``/O should/O address/O the/O political/O causes/O behind/O the/O violence/O ''/O ,/O which/O he/O identifies/O in/O cultural/O ,/O religious/O ,/O and/O ethnic/O differences/O between/O the/O Uygurs/O ,/O the/O native/O people/O of/O the/O area/O who/O are/O still/O in/O the/O majority/O ,/O and/O the/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O whose/O immigration/O Beijing/LOCATION strongly/O favors/O ./O 
But/O in/O the/O short/O term/O ,/O security/O measures/O should/O be/O reviewed/O ,/O since/O ``/O new/O attacks/O are/O likely/O ,/O as/O long/O as/O there/O is/O media/O attention/O on/O the/O Olympics/O ''/O ./O 
The/O methods/O used/O suggest/O poorly/O organized/O groups/O striking/O victims/O at/O random/O ./O 
Li/PERSON Wei/PERSON ,/O an/O anti-terrorism/O expert/O for/O the/O China/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Contemporary/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION Relations/ORGANIZATION ,/O tells/O the/O South/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Morning/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION that/O there/O are/O also/O economic/O reasons/O ,/O especially/O ``/O the/O imbalanced/O development/O between/O other/O areas/O and/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O southern/O and/O northern/O parts/O within/O the/O region/O ''/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O rich/O in/O energy/O resources/O ,/O which/O in/O general/O are/O exploited/O to/O the/O advantage/O of/O the/O rich/O southern/O provinces/O ./O 
This/O discontent/O ,/O combined/O with/O ethnic/O and/O religious/O differences/O ,/O means/O that/O ``/O Uygurs/O ,/O particularly/O the/O young/O ,/O will/O easily/O be/O irritated/O and/O provoked/O to/O take/O radical/O action/O ''/O ./O 
Groups/O of/O exiled/O Uygurs/O have/O distanced/O themselves/O from/O these/O actions/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON</U_PERSON> of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> says/O that/O 90/O people/O have/O been/O arrested/O and/O tortured/O in/O prison/O over/O the/O attacks/O ,/O without/O any/O proof/O ./O 
The/O groups/O of/O Uygur/O exiles/O accuse/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O arresting/O more/O than/O 100/O people/O each/O year/O ,/O and/O torturing/O them/O in/O prison/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> have/O so/O far/O downplayed/O the/O attacks/O ./O 
After/O the/O first/O one/O ,/O <PERSON>Shi/ORGANIZATION Dagang/ORGANIZATION</PERSON> ,/O head/O of/O the/O communist/O party/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O called/O it/O a/O ``/O minor/O incident/O ''/O and/O insisted/O that/O most/O of/O the/O population/O is/O against/O terrorism/O ./O 
Yesterday/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Yusufujiang/PERSON Memet/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O head/O of/O the/O county/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Kuqa/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O expressed/O his/O concern/O that/O ``/O the/O terrorist/O attacks/O will/O definitely/O have/O a/O negative/O effect/O on/O tourism/O development/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kuqa/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ''/O ,/O a/O spot/O on/O the/O ancient/O silk/O road/O ./O
