Beijing/LOCATION says/O it/O is/O a/O conspiracy/O against/O its/O power/O ./O 
The/O Uyghurs/O say/O the/O uprising/O is/O a/O sign/O of/O dissatisfaction/O with/O the/O Han/O colonization/O and/O political/O and/O economic/O repression/O ./O 
A/O similar/O scheme/O to/O that/O of/O Tibetan/O revolts/O last/O year/O ./O 
China/LOCATION prepares/O for/O 60/O years/O of/O the/O founding/O of/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION with/O a/O crackdown/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O <OTHER>Agencies/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> -RRB-/O -/O 
Violence/O and/O clashes/O between/O demonstrators/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O army/O and/O police/O in/O the/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> last/O night/O have/O resulted/O in/O at/O least/O 140/O dead/O and/O 800/O wounded/O ./O 
The/O official/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION agency/O reports/O this/O morning/O that/O all/O is/O calm/O ./O 
The/O police/O has/O already/O arrested/O hundreds/O of/O demonstrators/O ,/O but/O is/O searching/O for/O 10/O important/O leaders/O of/O the/O revolt/O ./O 
The/O government/O has/O declared/O that/O the/O instigators/O of/O violence/O are/O exiled/O Uygurs/O ,/O including/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O exiled/O after/O spending/O years/O in/O Chinese/O prisons/O ./O 
Members/O of/O the/O community/O of/O exiled/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/LOCATION</OTHER> claim/O that/O the/O demonstration/O had/O begun/O peacefully/O and/O that/O the/O police/O fired/O indiscriminately/O on/O the/O crowd/O ./O 
According/O to/O some/O local/O witnesses/O ,/O yesterday/O evening/O ,/O between/O 2/O and/O 3/O thousand/O Uygurs/O ,/O the/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> ethnic/O group/O living/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O gathered/O in/O the/O streets/O in/O central/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O and/O clashed/O with/O at/O least/O 1000police/O ./O 
Police/O charged/O the/O crowd/O ,/O firing/O on/O them/O and/O dispersing/O protesters/O who/O went/O on/O to/O break/O windows/O and/O burn/O cars/O and/O buses/O ./O 
To/O date/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> is/O under/O a/O strict/O curfew/O ./O 
The/O demonstrators/O said/O they/O wanted/O to/O demonstrate/O against/O their/O marginalisation/O by/O the/O Han/O -LRB-/O Chinese/O -RRB-/O population/O that/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O throughout/O China/LOCATION controls/O the/O local/O economy/O and/O administration/O ./O 
More/O precisely/O ,/O they/O were/O protesting/O the/O death/O of/O two/O Uygurs/O in/O southern/O China/LOCATION ,/O in/O a/O series/O of/O cashes/O between/O workers/O from/O the/O two/O ethnic/O groups/O ./O 
According/O to/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O clashes/O occurred/O in/O Shaoguan/LOCATION -LRB-/O Guangdong/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O and/O were/O caused/O by/O a/O false/O accusation/O of/O rape/O of/O workers/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
It/O should/O be/O noted/O that/O the/O lack/O of/O a/O labour/O force/O in/O south/O China/LOCATION ,/O has/O forced/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O facilitate/O the/O emigration/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O people/O towards/O the/O coast/O ./O 
But/O this/O has/O given/O rise/O to/O difficulties/O and/O increased/O competition/O for/O jobs/O ,/O particularly/O as/O many/O Chinese/O firms/O ,/O hit/O by/O the/O crisis/O ,/O lay/O off/O their/O workers/O ./O 
Revolts/O over/O work/O and/O unemployment/O are/O on/O the/O increase/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Internal/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION ,/O there/O are/O at/O least/O 87/O thousand/O a/O year/O ./O 
If/O the/O crisis/O deepens/O ,/O there/O is/O a/O risk/O that/O this/O type/O of/O trade/O union/O struggle/O will/O turn/O into/O an/O inter-ethnic/O war/O ./O 
Uprisings/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> date/O back/O over/O half/O a/O century/O ./O 
The/O Uygur/O population/O claim/O more/O autonomy/O from/O the/O central/O government/O and/O groups/O of/O Muslims/O in/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Islamic/LOCATION Movement/LOCATION of/LOCATION East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION</U_ORGANIZATION> are/O responsible/O for/O terrorist/O attacks/O ./O 
The/O Beijing/LOCATION regime/O 's/O heavy/O hand/O can/O be/O seen/O in/O the/O large/O number/O of/O arrests/O and/O death/O sentences/O ,/O which/O number/O in/O their/O hundreds/O each/O year/O ./O 
In/O order/O to/O curb/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION controls/O the/O entire/O religious/O life/O of/O the/O Uygurs/O :/O controlling/O the/O speeches/O of/O imams/O ,/O banning/O young/O people/O from/O participating/O in/O prayer/O in/O the/O mosque/O until/O they/O are/O 18/O ,/O the/O continued/O demolition/O of/O mosques/O and/O Islamic/O schools/O ./O 
According/O to/O Forum/ORGANIZATION <ORGANIZATION>18/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O a/O <OTHER>Protestant/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> agency/O based/O in/O Oslo/LOCATION ,/O religious/O persecution/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> has/O primarily/O economic/O reasons/O and/O is/O intended/O to/O stamp/O out/O the/O identity/O of/O the/O Uygurs/O and/O expropriate/O the/O areas/O wealth/O in/O oil/O and/O natural/O gas/O ./O 
Because/O of/O this/O ,/O over/O the/O years/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O promoted/O migration/O to/O the/O region/O of/O millions/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O who/O are/O now/O at/O least/O 50/O %/O of/O the/O approximately/O 20/O million/O residents/O :/O they/O have/O taken/O control/O of/O trade/O and/O places/O of/O power/O ,/O while/O the/O Uygurs/O -LRB-/O 42/O %/O -RRB-/O are/O mainly/O farmers/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O attaches/O all/O responsibilities/O for/O the/O uprising/O to/O groups/O of/O exiled/O Uygurs/O and/O in/O particular/O to/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O now/O exiled/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O after/O spending/O over/O 5/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O having/O defended/O the/O greater/O autonomy/O of/O his/O ethnicity/O ./O 
According/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>Xinhua/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O yesterday/O 's/O demonstration/O was/O ``/O an/O organized/O and/O premeditated/O violent/O crime/O ''/O to/O overthrow/O the/O power/O of/O the/O Chinese/O ./O 
But/O the/O Uygurs/O in/O exile/O claim/O that/O the/O demonstrations/O are/O a/O sign/O of/O the/O Uygurs/O intolerance/O of/O Han/O political/O and/O economic/O discrimination/O and/O oppression/O ./O 
Experts/O from/O <ORGANIZATION>Human/O Rights/O Watch/O</ORGANIZATION> say/O that/O in/O labelling/O the/O ethnic/O clashes/O ``/O subversive/O ''/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O is/O adopting/O a/O method/O already/O used/O and/O abused/O in/O the/O uprisings/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION last/O year/O ./O 
Uygurs/O and/O human/O rights/O activists/O '/O fear/O that/O in/O the/O coming/O days/O there/O will/O be/O an/O increase/O in/O repression/O :/O there/O have/O already/O been/O raids/O and/O arrests/O in/O the/O universities/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O preparing/O for/O October/O to/O celebrate/O 60/O years/O of/O the/O founding/O of/O the/O Peoples/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION and/O is/O implementing/O heavy/O checks/O and/O arrests/O to/O avoid/O any/O unpleasant/O surprises/O ./O
