The/O prisoners/O held/O responsible/O for/O murder/O and/O other/O crimes/O during/O the/O protests/O last/O July/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O evidently/O wish/O to/O close/O criminal/O investigations/O immediately/O and/O with/O exemplary/O sentences/O :/O in/O less/O than/O a/O month/O the/O death/O sentence/O is/O handed/O down/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
Today/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 6/O more/O men/O were/O sentenced/O to/O death/O and/O another/O to/O life/O imprisonment/O for/O murder/O and/O other/O crimes/O committed/O in/O the/O street/O protests/O last/O July/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O the/O regional/O capital/O ,/O which/O killed/O at/O least/O 197/O dead/O and/O 1,600/O injured/O according/O to/O official/O figures/O ./O 
<U_ORGANIZATION>The/O Urumqi/O Intermediate/O Court/O of/O the/O People/O</U_ORGANIZATION> sentenced/O to/O death/O <U_PERSON>Abdukerim/PERSON Abduwayit/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O <U_PERSON>Yeni/PERSON Yusup/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O <U_PERSON>Abdulla/PERSON Mettohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O <U_PERSON>Adil/PERSON Rozi/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O <U_PERSON>Nurel/PERSON Wuxiu'er/PERSON</U_PERSON> and/O <U_PERSON>Alim/PERSON Metyusup/PERSON</U_PERSON> ./O 
<U_PERSON>Tayirejan/PERSON Abulimit/PERSON</U_PERSON> was/O ``/O only/O ''/O given/O a/O life/O sentence/O because/O he/O admitted/O the/O charges/O of/O murder/O and/O robbery/O and/O helped/O the/O police/O to/O capture/O <U_PERSON>Metyusup/PERSON Alim/O</U_PERSON>.
<ORGANIZATION>Xinhua/O</ORGANIZATION> reports/O do/O not/O specify/O the/O ethnicity/O of/O the/O convicted/O ,/O but/O they/O appear/O to/O be/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
The/O protests/O ,/O which/O erupted/O in/O reaction/O to/O the/O murder/O of/O two/O Uyghurs/O by/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O resulted/O in/O veritable/O urban/O warfare/O between/O the/O two/O ethnic/O groups/O ./O 
Since/O then/O the/O city/O is/O guarded/O by/O the/O army/O and/O police/O ./O 
Today/O the/O area/O around/O the/O court/O was/O closed/O down/O to/O all/O traffic/O ./O 
State/O television/O showed/O empty/O streets/O heavily/O patrolled/O by/O police/O ./O 
After/O the/O riots/O ,/O the/O police/O arrested/O thousands/O of/O people/O ./O 
Uyghur/O groups/O in/O exile/O denounce/O that/O their/O plight/O is/O being/O almost/O totally/O ignored/O ./O 
In/O September/O the/O authorities/O announced/O charges/O against/O 21/O people/O for/O murder/O ,/O fire/O ,/O theft/O and/O damage/O ./O 
Two/O days/O ago/O there/O was/O a/O death/O sentence/O ,/O a/O sentence/O to/O life/O imprisonment/O and/O others/O to/O numerous/O years/O in/O prison/O ,/O against/O the/O ethnic/O Han/O held/O responsible/O for/O the/O murder/O of/O the/O two/O Uyghurs/O that/O sparked/O the/O protests/O of/O July/O -LRB-/O in/O the/O picture/O :/O the/O trial/O of/O two/O days/O ago/O ./O -RRB-/O
