In/O recent/O days/O there/O have/O been/O a/O number/O of/O unprovoked/O attacks/O on/O passers-by/O ,/O at/O least/O 14/O dead/O and/O 40/O wounded/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O announce/O clampdown/O on/O ``/O illegal/O religious/O activities/O ''/O ./O 
Experts/O :/O greater/O respect/O for/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O minority/O ,/O if/O you/O want/O to/O avoid/O a/O crescendo/O of/O violence/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
Beijing/LOCATION blames/O Islamic/O militants/O for/O attacks/O on/O passers-by/O yesterday/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O which/O have/O caused/O at/O least/O 14/O dead/O and/O 40/O wounded/O ,/O and/O announced/O a/O crackdown/O against/O ``/O illegal/O religious/O activities/O ''/O ,/O just/O as/O today/O Muslims/O began/O the/O holy/O month/O of/O Ramadan/O ./O 
Experts/O urge/O China/LOCATION to/O respect/O the/O rights/O and/O culture/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O Muslims/O if/O it/O wants/O to/O avoid/O an/O escalation/O of/O violence/O ./O 
On/O the/O night/O of/O July/O 30/O ,/O two/O men/O armed/O with/O knives/O attacked/O and/O killed/O a/O truck/O driver/O ,/O then/O drove/O the/O vehicle/O into/O pedestrians/O stabbed/O and/O killed/O six/O ,/O with/O at/O least/O 28/O injured/O ./O 
The/O crowd/O surrounded/O and/O stopped/O the/O truck/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O attackers/O died/O and/O another/O was/O captured/O ./O 
On/O the/O afternoon/O of/O July/O 31/O an/O explosion/O killed/O three/O people/O ./O 
Then/O a/O dozen/O men/O attacked/O passersby/O and/O police/O ./O 
Police/O shot/O and/O killed/O ``/O 4/O suspects/O ''/O ,/O as/O reported/O by/O the/O state/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Media/O sources/O reported/O clashes/O and/O other/O incidents/O in/O the/O city/O ,/O but/O the/O rigid/O censorship/O prevents/O clearer/O information/O ./O 
The/O attacks/O came/O after/O the/O violent/O clashes/O between/O crowds/O and/O police/O July/O 18/O with/O at/O least/O four/O dead/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Hotan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O also/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O home/O to/O the/O Uyghurs/O who/O are/O Muslim/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O speak/O of/O a/O terrorist/O attack/O against/O the/O police/O ,/O while/O Uyghur/O sources/O accused/O them/O of/O having/O opened/O fire/O for/O no/O reason/O against/O peaceful/O demonstrators/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O encouraged/O immigration/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O to/O the/O area/O ,/O to/O an/O extent/O that/O the/O native/O Uyghurs/O are/O now/O a/O minority/O ./O 
Zhang/PERSON Chunxian/PERSON ,/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION chief/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O has/O announced/O extensive/O operations/O against/O the/O religious/O extremists/O and/O the/O ``/O repression/O of/O illegal/O religious/O activity/O ./O ''/O 
This/O raises/O fears/O that/O the/O police/O crackdown/O on/O the/O Muslim/O community/O is/O a/O provocation/O ,/O given/O the/O fact/O that/O it/O is/O the/O beginning/O of/O Ramadan/O ,/O the/O holy/O month/O of/O fasting/O and/O prayer/O for/O Muslims/O ./O 
Many/O experts/O agree/O that/O the/O violence/O has/O no/O underlying/O strategy/O ,/O rather/O it/O expresses/O the/O widespread/O discontent/O among/O the/O Uyghurs/O at/O the/O lack/O of/O respect/O for/O their/O rights/O ,/O culture/O and/O religion/O ./O 
Joseph/PERSON Cheng/PERSON Yu-shek/PERSON ,/O a/O professor/O of/O social/O and/O public/O administration/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Hong/ORGANIZATION Kong/ORGANIZATION ,/O explains/O that/O ,/O to/O avoid/O growing/O protests/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION should/O reconsider/O its/O policy/O towards/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O to/O date/O concerned/O only/O with/O sending/O funds/O to/O promote/O its/O economic/O development/O ./O 
Instead/O it/O should/O pay/O attention/O to/O respecting/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O Uyghurs/O ,/O their/O culture/O ,/O language/O and/O religion/O of/O the/O minority/O ./O 
``/O The/O central/O government/O -/O said/O Cheng/PERSON -/O has/O not/O learned/O the/O lessons/O from/O previous/O incidents/O ./O ''/O
