From/O now/O until/O 8/O July/O ,/O Pakistani/O Prime/O Minister/O will/O be/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O discuss/O energy/O and/O investments/O ./O 
The/O construction/O of/O a/O road-and-rail/O corridor/O between/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O and/O Gwadar/LOCATION -LRB-/O Baluchistan/LOCATION -RRB-/O on/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION is/O crucial/O ./O 
This/O way/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION could/O solve/O its/O energy/O crisis/O ,/O but/O in/O return/O ,/O it/O will/O likely/O have/O to/O ``/O stop/O ''/O the/O emergence/O of/O Islamic/O fundamentalism/O ./O 
Islamabad/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O 
Energy/O ,/O transport/O and/O investment/O are/O on/O the/O agenda/O Pakistan/LOCATION Prime/O Minister/O Nawaz/PERSON Sharif/PERSON is/O taking/O with/O him/O as/O he/O begins/O today/O a/O six-day/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION -LRB-/O 3-8/O July/O -RRB-/O ./O 
His/O ultimate/O aim/O is/O to/O revive/O his/O country/O 's/O economy/O ,/O which/O has/O been/O paralysed/O by/O an/O energy/O crisis/O and/O violent/O Islamic/O fundamentalism/O ./O 
The/O construction/O of/O a/O road/O and/O rail/O corridor/O between/O <U_LOCATION>Kashgar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O in/O the/O western/O Chinese/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O and/O the/O port/O of/O Gwadar/LOCATION -LRB-/O Baluchistan/LOCATION <OTHER>province/LOCATION</OTHER> -RRB-/O on/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION is/O part/O of/O the/O broader/O picture/O ./O 
The/O fact/O that/O Sharif/PERSON chose/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O his/O first/O official/O trip/O abroad/O after/O his/O victory/O in/O the/O 11/O May/O elections/O is/O significant/O ./O 
During/O his/O stay/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O he/O is/O expected/O to/O meet/O at/O least/O three/O members/O of/O the/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION ,/O namely/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ,/O Premier/O Li/PERSON Keqiang/PERSON and/O Vice/O Premier/O Zhang/PERSON Dejiang/PERSON ./O 
The/O Kashgar-Gwadar/O project/O is/O of/O great/O interest/O to/O both/O countries/O ./O 
``/O Sharif/PERSON knows/O that/O Gwadar/LOCATION has/O significant/O geopolitical/O and/O economic/O importance/O for/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O Rashid/PERSON Ahmed/PERSON Khan/PERSON ,/O a/O professor/O of/O international/O relations/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Sargodha/ORGANIZATION in/O Punjab/LOCATION ./O 
``/O It/O can/O provide/O a/O short/O route/O for/O Chinese/O crude/O imports/O from/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION and/O for/O its/O exports/O to/O the/O region/O ./O ''/O 
Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokeswoman/O Hua/PERSON Chunying/PERSON agrees/O ./O 
The/O project/O ``/O will/O help/O both/O countries/O as/O well/O as/O the/O development/O of/O the/O whole/O region/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
In/O addition/O to/O trade/O ,/O many/O analysts/O see/O the/O port/O of/O Gwadar/LOCATION as/O part/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O plan/O to/O increase/O its/O naval/O power/O and/O influence/O in/O the/O Indian/LOCATION Ocean/LOCATION ,/O considered/O the/O future/O centre/O of/O international/O energy/O exchanges/O ./O 
The/O Kashgar-Gwadar/O line/O starts/O in/O the/O heart/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O and/O cross/O into/O Baluchistan/LOCATION ,/O a/O desert/O province/O bordering/O Iran/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O among/O the/O poorest/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
Both/O areas/O have/O often/O been/O the/O scene/O of/O sectarian/O clashes/O ./O 
In/O recent/O days/O ,/O fresh/O unrest/O broke/O out/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> between/O indigenous/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O -LRB-/O who/O are/O Turkic/O and/O Muslim/O -RRB-/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O the/O majority/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION blamed/O the/O attacks/O on/O Islamic/O extremists/O trained/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O in/O camps/O run/O by/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ./O 
Baluchistan/LOCATION has/O been/O in/O the/O hands/O of/O paramilitary/O forces/O for/O decades/O ./O 
The/O exploitation/O of/O gas/O and/O mineral/O resources/O by/O the/O government/O has/O unleashed/O attacks/O by/O extremist/O and/O separatist/O movements/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION groups/O ./O 
If/O approved/O ,/O the/O project/O might/O force/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O find/O a/O final/O settlement/O to/O the/O fundamentalist/O emergency/O that/O has/O ravaged/O the/O country/O ,/O a/O problem/O many/O blame/O on/O the/O central/O government/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O 
This/O view/O is/O share/O by/O Afghan/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION Chief/O General/O Sher/PERSON Mohammad/PERSON Karimi/PERSON who/O said/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION controlled/O and/O gave/O shelter/O to/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION leaders/O ,/O deliberately/O unleashing/O fighters/O on/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O If/O -LSB-/O Pakistan/LOCATION -RSB-/O put/O pressure/O on/O -LSB-/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION -RSB-/O leadership/O or/O convinced/O them/O what/O to/O do/O ,/O that/O can/O help/O a/O lot/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O
