The/O police/O took/O Tan/PERSON Wen/PERSON away/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Muen/PERSON</U_LOCATION> church/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O the/O provincial/O capital/O ,/O and/O seized/O Bibles/O and/O other/O religious/O books/O without/O any/O legal/O documents/O to/O justify/O the/O raid/O ./O 
According/O to/O some/O sources/O ,/O it/O is/O retaliation/O for/O a/O complaint/O lodged/O by/O the/O religious/O against/O the/O local/O Public/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O 
Police/O in/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> have/O arrested/O the/O pastor/O Tan/PERSON Wen/PERSON ,/O confiscated/O Bibles/O and/O other/O religious/O books/O of/O present/O in/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Muen/O</U_LOCATION> church/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O threatened/O local/O Christians/O with/O ``/O serious/O consequences/O ''/O if/O they/O continue/O to/O meet/O to/O pray/O ./O 
The/O raid/O took/O place/O on/O 4/O August/O during/O a/O function/O presided/O over/O by/O the/O pastor/O ./O 
According/O to/O eyewitnesses/O ,/O quoted/O by/O <ORGANIZATION>China/LOCATION Aid/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O about/O 20/O police/O officers/O raided/O the/O church/O at/O 9.30/O during/O the/O religious/O function/O ./O 
The/O police/O showed/O no/O warrant/O or/O other/O legal/O documents/O to/O justify/O their/O action/O ,/O but/O they/O stopped/O the/O ceremony/O and/O locked/O the/O pastor/O ./O 
Some/O agents/O confiscated/O the/O Bibles/O ,/O hymn/O books/O and/O other/O religious/O texts/O in/O the/O church/O ./O 
The/O faithful/O tried/O to/O find/O out/O the/O charges/O brought/O against/O him/O ,/O but/O in/O response/O an/O official/O warned/O them/O ``/O not/O to/O gather/O in/O church/O together/O ./O ''/O 
At/O the/O moment/O the/O pastor/O is/O being/O held/O at/O the/O police/O station/O located/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xishan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O where/O he/O will/O remain/O for/O 15/O days/O ./O 
According/O to/O some/O sources/O ,/O the/O arrest/O was/O in/O retaliation/O for/O the/O complaint/O lodged/O by/O the/O pastor/O against/O the/O Public/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION <OTHER>of/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/ORGANIZATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O which/O denied/O his/O congregation/O ``/O without/O valid/O reasons/O ''/O permission/O to/O meet/O and/O pray/O together/O ./O 
In/O China/LOCATION ,/O only/O registered/O religious/O groups/O are/O allowed/O ./O 
But/O there/O are/O more/O unofficial/O Protestant/O Christians/O -LRB-/O about/O 80/O million/O -RRB-/O than/O members/O of/O the/O Three-Self/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O about/O 20/O million/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Lest/O the/O situation/O get/O out/O of/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION 's/O control/O ,/O for/O almost/O five/O years/O there/O has/O been/O a/O campaign/O to/O eliminate/O the/O underground/O communities/O or/O merge/O them/O into/O the/O official/O ones/O ./O
