The/O Government/O of/O the/O Western/O Province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> has/O placed/O mosques/O under/O monitoring/O and/O prohibited/O groups/O of/O study/O and/O prayer/O ./O 
After/O the/O invitation/O to/O lunch/O ,/O charges/O of/O ``/O premeditated/O offenses/O ''/O when/O they/O do/O not/O eat/O ./O 
Activists/O denounce/O :/O ``/O these/O policies/O are/O new/O fuel/O to/O the/O fire/O ''/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O 
While/O all/O the/O Muslim/O world/O observes/O the/O precepts/O strictly/O linked/O to/O the/O holy/O month/O of/O Ramadan/O ,/O Muslims/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Province/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> of/O China/LOCATION suffer/O a/O new/O wave/O of/O repression/O and/O restrictions/O designed/O to/O stop/O them/O from/O observing/O the/O rules/O laid/O down/O by/O their/O religion/O for/O this/O period/O ./O 
Chinese/O Government/O officials/O ,/O Uygur/O ethnic/O activists/O groups/O have/O denounced/O ,/O arrive/O to/O invite/O the/O community/O 's/O religious/O leaders/O for/O lunch/O to/O make/O them/O embarrassed/O and/O have/O an/O excuse/O to/O accuse/O them/O of/O ``/O premeditated/O offenses/O ''/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Dilxadi/PERSON Rexiti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O spokesman/O for/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Uygurs/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O says/O :/O ``/O Some/O representatives/O of/O the/O Government/O go/O to/O the/O homes/O of/O important/O members/O of/O the/O community/O to/O offer/O fruits/O and/O drinks/O during/O the/O day/O ,/O when/O instead/O the/O Koran/O requires/O us/O to/O fast/O until/O sunset/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O the/O authorities/O have/O banned/O any/O study/O group/O of/O religious/O texts/O and/O they/O have/O put/O the/O mosques/O under/O surveillance/O ''/O ./O 
Ramadan/O ,/O which/O began/O two/O days/O ago/O ,/O requires/O the/O faithful/O to/O abstain/O from/O food/O ,/O drink/O ,/O tobacco/O and/O sexual/O activities/O during/O the/O day/O ./O 
In/O the/O province/O ,/O which/O has/O long/O been/O the/O epicenter/O of/O violence/O and/O tensions/O between/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O -LRB-/O one/O time/O a/O majority/O in/O the/O territory/O -RRB-/O and/O the/O Han/O ethnicity/O ,/O these/O provocations/O are/O likely/O to/O ignite/O sparks/O of/O new/O clashes/O ./O 
According/O to/O Katrina/PERSON Lantos/PERSON Swett/PERSON ,/O of/O the/O U.S./ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Religious/ORGANIZATION Freedom/ORGANIZATION ,/O ``/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policies/O launched/O in/O the/O name/O of/O security/O are/O likely/O to/O put/O at/O risk/O the/O stability/O of/O the/O area/O ''/O ./O 
The/O Uyghurs/O are/O Muslim/O and/O Turkish/O speaking/O :/O for/O several/O decades/O they/O have/O a/O conflictual/O relationship/O with/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION Government/ORGANIZATION ./O 
After/O a/O few/O -LRB-/O failed/O -RRB-/O attempts/O to/O gain/O independence/O as/O ``/O <U_LOCATION>East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ''/O ,/O ethnic/O leaders/O have/O asked/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O preserve/O the/O language/O ,/O culture/O and/O religion/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O Government/O -/O while/O giving/O tax/O and/O social/O breaks/O -/O has/O decided/O instead/O to/O use/O the/O heavy/O hand/O and/O launched/O a/O campaign/O of/O repression/O and/O control/O throughout/O the/O area/O ./O 
For/O some/O time/O ,/O indeed/O ,/O religious/O instruction/O has/O been/O prohibited/O to/O minors/O -LRB-/O who/O ca/O n't/O even/O enter/O the/O mosques/O -RRB-/O ./O
