According/O to/O the/O central/O and/O provincial/O authorities/O ,/O two/O assailants/O and/O an/O innocent/O civilian/O were/O killed/O on/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> railway/O station/O ./O 
The/O identity/O of/O one/O of/O the/O two/O made/O public/O :/O a/O 39/O year-old/O Chinese/O citizen/O of/O Uyghur/O ethnicity/O ./O 
Foreign/O based/O ethnic/O groups/O report/O 100/O arrests/O ,/O but/O without/O giving/O precise/O data/O ./O 
Experts/O :/O ``/O They/O want/O to/O raise/O the/O bar/O in/O the/O armed/O confrontation/O with/O the/O authorities/O ''/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O 
Yesterday/O 's/O bomb/O attack/O on/O the/O train/O station/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O capital/O of/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O ``/O is/O the/O work/O of/O religious/O extremists/O ,/O who/O have/O long/O been/O under/O a/O subversive/O and/O separatist/O influence/O ''/O ./O 
This/O is/O according/O to/O provincial/O authorities/O ,/O quoted/O by/O the/O official/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/O ./O 
In/O the/O attack/O both/O the/O terrorists/O and/O an/O innocent/O civilian/O were/O killed/O :/O 79/O people/O were/O injured/O ,/O some/O are/O in/O critical/O condition/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O two/O assailants/O was/O identified/O :/O <U_PERSON>Sedirdin/O Sawut/O</U_PERSON> ,/O a/O Chinese/O citizen/O aged/O 39/O ,/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Aksu/PERSON</U_LOCATION> county/O ./O 
The/O attack/O took/O place/O shortly/O after/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON 's/O departure/O from/O the/O region/O :/O the/O Chinese/O leader/O spent/O 4/O days/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O his/O first/O official/O visit/O to/O the/O area/O ,/O during/O which/O he/O urged/O people/O to/O ``/O better/O understand/O the/O separatism/O ''/O of/O some/O local/O fringe/O groups/O to/O be/O able/O to/O ``/O fight/O it/O better/O ''/O ./O 
According/O to/O several/O analysts/O and/O experts/O ,/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O attack/O took/O place/O to/O coincide/O with/O Xi/PERSON 's/O visit/O of/O demonstrates/O that/O the/O extremists/O ``/O want/O to/O raise/O the/O bar/O ''/O in/O the/O armed/O confrontation/O with/O the/O authorities/O ./O 
The/O central/O authorities/O have/O not/O clarified/O how/O they/O are/O going/O to/O investigate/O the/O case/O ./O 
Some/O groups/O of/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/LOCATION</OTHER> living/O abroad/O say/O that/O at/O least/O 100/O people/O have/O already/O been/O arrested/O ,/O but/O without/O giving/O precise/O data/O ./O 
Certainly/O security/O in/O the/O area/O has/O been/O significantly/O stepped/O up/O ,/O and/O the/O normal/O police/O forces/O stationed/O in/O the/O region/O have/O be/O joined/O by/O at/O least/O 2/O battalions/O from/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
It/O is/O the/O homeland/O of/O ethnic/O Uyghurs/O ,/O a/O Turkic-speaking/O ,/O mostly/O Muslim/O people/O that/O has/O always/O sought/O independence/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
The/O central/O government/O has/O sent/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O to/O the/O region/O to/O try/O to/O make/O them/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
It/O has/O also/O imposed/O serious/O restrictions/O on/O freedom/O of/O religion/O ,/O Muslim/O practices/O ,/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O indigenous/O language/O and/O the/O local/O culture/O ./O 
Since/O 2009/O Chinese/O police/O and/O the/O military/O have/O held/O the/O region/O under/O a/O special/O regime/O ,/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION imposed/O following/O clashes/O that/O left/O nearly/O 200/O people/O dead/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O various/O episodes/O of/O violence/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O long/O prison/O sentences/O were/O imposed/O and/O dozens/O of/O death/O penalties/O were/O carried/O out/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O blame/O Muslim/O extremists/O for/O the/O wave/O of/O violence/O ./O 
Uyghur/O exiles/O claim/O instead/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O ``/O exaggerating/O ''/O the/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O to/O justify/O repression/O against/O indigenous/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
For/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/PERSON</OTHER> are/O responsible/O for/O the/O recent/O spate/O of/O violent/O attacks/O ,/O including/O the/O 1/O March/O 2014/O attack/O at/O the/O Kunming/LOCATION railway/O station/O by/O knives-wielding/O men/O that/O left/O 29/O people/O dead/O and/O more/O than/O 150/O wounded/O ,/O and/O the/O 28/O October/O 2013/O incident/O when/O an/O SUV/O plunged/O into/O a/O crowd/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O then/O burst/O into/O flames/O ,/O killing/O three/O people/O ./O 
The/O government/O believe/O that/O the/O ethnic/O group/O is/O behind/O these/O attacks/O ./O
