Yining/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Forum/ORGANIZATION 18/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O --/O
Children/O are/O not/O allowed/O inside/O Catholic/O churches/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O north-western/O China/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O this/O according/O to/O Fr/ PERSON Sun/PERSON Zin/PERSON Shin/PERSON ,/O a/O Catholic/O priest/O in/O Yining/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O Ili-Kazakh/U_LOCATION autonomous/O prefecture/O -RRB-/O ,/O who/O spoke/O to/O Forum/ORGANIZATION 18/ORGANIZATION ./O
Father/O Sun/PERSON said/O one/O schoolboy/O who/O managed/O to/O get/O into/O last/O December/O 's/O Christmas/O service/O in/O Nilka/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O 120/O km/O east/O of/O Yining/U_LOCATION -RRB-/O despite/O a/O police/O checkpoint/O to/O prevent/O this/O was/O subsequently/O beaten/O by/O his/O teacher/O who/O had/O seen/O him/O go/O inside/O ./O
The/O clergyman/O said/O that/O in/O Nilka/U_LOCATION state/O officials/O visit/O Catholic/O families/O and/O warn/O them/O that/O they/O would/O have/O ``/O problems/O at/O work/O ''/O if/O their/O children/O do/O not/O stop/O attending/O church/O ./O
He/O complained/O about/O intimidations/O by/O local/O authorities/O and/O strict/O controls/O over/O minorities/O designed/O to/O keep/O them/O away/O from/O religion/O ./O
Religious/O groups/O come/O in/O fact/O under/O the/O jurisdiction/O of/O the/O Religious/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O RAB/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O and/O interference/O has/O reached/O the/O point/O that/O the/O authorities/O even/O demanded/O Catholics/O reduce/O the/O size/O of/O the/O cross/O on/O their/O church/O ./O
Father/O Sun/PERSON is/O adamant/O :/O ``/O We/O are/O citizens/O and/O taxpayers/O just/O as/O much/O as/O the/O atheists/O ,/O but/O in/O the/O eyes/O of/O the/O state/O we/O are/O second-class/O people/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O
``/O We/O have/O the/O absurd/O situation/O that/O we/O are/O paying/O taxes/O and/O these/O same/O officials/O and/O law-enforcement/O agencies/O watch/O us/O and/O prevent/O us/O from/O professing/O our/O faith/O ''/O ./O
What/O is/O worse/O ,/O according/O to/O Father/PERSON Sun/PERSON ,/O holding/O services/O anywhere/O but/O in/O the/O four/O registered/O churches/O of/O the/O prefecture/O is/O banned/O ./O
``/O In/O many/O towns/O we/O do/O n't/O have/O a/O registered/O church/O ,/O but/O we/O have/O parishioners/O ,/O ''/O he/O explained/O ,/O ``/O yet/O we/O are/O categorically/O forbidden/O to/O hold/O services/O in/O private/O apartments/O under/O threat/O of/O several/O days/O '/O administrative/O arrest/O ./O
The/O authorities/O basically/O regard/O believers/O as/O potential/O terrorists/O ./O
I/O am/O not/O afraid/O to/O speak/O about/O this/O openly/O ./O
I/O want/O the/O whole/O world/O to/O know/O about/O the/O problems/O of/O believers/O in/O the/O Xinjiang-Uighur/U_LOCATION Autonomous/U_LOCATION Region/U_LOCATION ''/O ./O
Yining/U_LOCATION is/O 100/O kilometres/O -LRB-/O 60/O miles/O -RRB-/O east/O of/O the/O Kazakh/O border/O and/O 600/O kilometres/O -LRB-/O 375/O miles/O -RRB-/O from/O the/O capital/O Ürümqi/U_LOCATION ./O
Orthodox/O Christians/O do/O n't/O fare/O much/O better/O even/O though/O for/O them/O the/O main/O problems/O are/O the/O lack/O of/O clergy/O and/O places/O of/O worship/O ./O
Under/O Chinese/O law/O foreign/O clergymen/O can/O work/O in/O China/LOCATION only/O if/O they/O have/O a/O permit/O from/O the/O central/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O for/O now/O there/O are/O no/O Orthodox/O priests/O who/O are/O Chinese/O citizens/O ./O
In/O December/O 2003/O ,/O the/O dean/O of/O the/O Zharkent/LOCATION prefecture/O of/O the/O Astana/LOCATION and/O Almaty/ORGANIZATION Orthodox/ORGANIZATION diocese/O of/O neighbouring/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ,/O Fr/O Vianor/PERSON Ivanov/PERSON ,/O spent/O a/O week/O under/O house-arrest/O in/O Yining/U_LOCATION and/O was/O then/O deported/O from/O China/LOCATION for/O illegally/O working/O with/O local/O Orthodox/O believers/O ./O
Protestants/O are/O more/O cautious/O ./O
Luda/PERSON Li/PERSON ,/O the/O pastor/O of/O the/O local/O Protestant/O church/O ,/O said/O that/O she/O and/O her/O community/O had/O no/O problems/O with/O the/O authorities/O since/O they/O closely/O adhere/O to/O RAB/ORGANIZATION rules/O ./O
She/O said/O the/O rules/O forbid/O holding/O services/O except/O in/O registered/O churches/O ,/O adding/O that/O baptisms/O can/O be/O performed/O only/O after/O prior/O authorisation/O from/O secular/O authorities/O ./O
Similarly/O ,/O religious/O marriage/O is/O allowed/O only/O after/O it/O has/O been/O registered/O with/O civil/O authorities/O ./O
Ethnic/O Uighur/O and/O Dungan/O imams/O and/O Yen/PERSON Shi/PERSON ,/O the/O only/O local/O Buddhist/O monk/O ,/O declined/O to/O talk/O to/O Forum/ORGANIZATION 18/ORGANIZATION without/O RAB/ORGANIZATION approval/O ./O
Yen/PERSON Shi/PERSON did/O say/O however/O that/O ``/O even/O local/O people/O who/O want/O to/O find/O out/O about/O Buddhism/ORGANIZATION have/O to/O get/O the/O permission/O of/O the/O Religious/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION before/O talking/O with/O me/O ''/O ./O
