Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O
The/O UN/ORGANIZATION 's/O chief/O torture/O investigator/O has/O praised/O China/LOCATION 's/O leaders/O for/O acknowledging/O the/O widespread/O abuse/O of/O prisoners/O in/O the/O nation/O 's/O jails/O ,/O as/O he/O began/O a/O historic/O 12-day/O fact-finding/O mission/O ./O
Manfred/PERSON Novak/PERSON ,/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION 's/O special/O rapporteur/O on/O torture/O ,/O said/O Beijing/LOCATION had/O offered/O him/O freer/O access/O to/O detainees/O than/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION was/O prepared/O to/O give/O him/O on/O a/O recently/O scrapped/O trip/O to/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ./O
``/O There/O is/O a/O growing/O awareness/O that/O torture/O is/O quite/O widely/O practised/O in/O the/O common/O criminal/O proceedings/O -LSB-/O in/O China/LOCATION -RSB-/O by/O the/O police/O and/O that/O something/O needs/O to/O be/O done/O ,/O ''/O Mr/O Nowak/PERSON said/O in/O an/O interview/O on/O Tuesday/O ./O
``/O I/O see/O my/O visit/O also/O as/O part/O of/O this/O growing/O awareness/O ./O ''/O
Mr/O Nowak/PERSON arrived/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION on/O Monday/O for/O an/O unprecedented/O trip/O after/O receiving/O government/O assurances/O it/O would/O cooperate/O with/O him/O and/O allow/O him/O unannounced/O visits/O to/O prisons/O and/O private/O talks/O with/O prisoners/O ./O
``/O I/O 'm/O very/O grateful/O to/O the/O Chinese/O government/O that/O they/O did/O invite/O me/O and/O also/O that/O they/O accepted/O my/O terms/O of/O reference/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O
``/O I/O see/O this/O as/O an/O opening/O up/O of/O governmental/O policy/O in/O relation/O to/O UN/ORGANIZATION special/O procedures/O and/O I/O had/O very/O good/O first/O meetings/O -LSB-/O on/O Monday/O -RSB-/O with/O the/O officials/O from/O the/O ministry/O of/O foreign/O affairs/O and/O justice/O ./O ''/O
However/O Mr/O Nowak/PERSON did/O not/O try/O to/O gloss/O over/O the/O widespread/O human/O rights/O abuses/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O jails/O ./O
``/O China/LOCATION is/O a/O huge/O country/O and/O it/O has/O of/O course/O a/O long/O tradition/O of/O torture/O and/O ill/O treatment/O and/O you/O ca/O n't/O change/O that/O from/O one/O day/O to/O the/O other/O ,/O so/O it/O is/O a/O policy/O of/O taking/O small/O steps/O ,/O ''/O Mr/O Nowak/PERSON said/O ./O
``/O People/O have/O been/O sentenced/O to/O death/O and/O afterwards/O it/O turned/O out/O that/O the/O `/O victims/O '/O actually/O were/O alive/O ,/O so/O it/O was/O clear/O that/O the/O only/O reason/O why/O they/O have/O been/O sentenced/O to/O death/O and/O executed/O was/O that/O their/O confession/O had/O been/O extracted/O by/O torture/O ./O ''/O
Aside/O from/O prisons/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Mr/O Nowak/PERSON will/O visit/O the/O Tibetan/O capital/O of/O Lhasa/LOCATION ,/O before/O going/O onto/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION and/O Yining/U_LOCATION in/O the/O Uighur/O Muslim-populated/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O ./O
Police/O in/O both/O regions/O have/O engaged/O in/O long-standing/O crackdowns/O on/O separatism/O ,/O and/O human/O rights/O groups/O regularly/O report/O widespread/O abuse/O of/O detainees/O there/O ./O
The/O visit/O by/O Nowak/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O the/O first/O special/O rapporteur/O on/O torture/O to/O visit/O China/LOCATION ,/O comes/O after/O years/O of/O negotiations/O between/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION and/O China/LOCATION on/O allowing/O unfettered/O access/O to/O prisons/O ,/O private/O talks/O with/O detainees/O and/O no/O retaliation/O on/O prisoners/O ./O
In/O the/O early/O 1990s/O ,/O a/O UN/ORGANIZATION special/O rapporteur/O on/O arbitrary/O detention/O visited/O prisons/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O
But/O prisoners/O were/O punished/O for/O what/O they/O told/O the/O investigator/O ,/O rights/O group/O say/O ./O
``/O They/O were/O given/O longer/O sentences/O and/O some/O were/O even/O beaten/O ,/O ''/O Nicholas/PERSON Becquelin/PERSON ,/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION director/O for/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION in/O China/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O ./O
``/O The/O UN/ORGANIZATION does/O not/O want/O to/O see/O this/O happen/O again/O ,/O so/O that/O is/O why/O it/O has/O taken/O so/O long/O to/O get/O this/O visit/O again/O ./O ''/O
Mr/O Nowak/PERSON said/O that/O the/O terms/O of/O reference/O for/O his/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION were/O better/O than/O what/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION had/O offered/O on/O a/O proposed/O visit/O to/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION in/O Cuba/LOCATION ,/O where/O prisoners/O from/O the/O wars/O in/O Iraq/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION are/O being/O held/O ./O
``/O It/O was/O made/O clear/O by/O the/O Pentagon/ORGANIZATION that/O they/O would/O not/O be/O willing/O to/O accept/O my/O terms/O of/O reference/O ,/O so/O there/O was/O no/O other/O option/O than/O to/O finally/O cancel/O the/O mission/O ,/O ''/O Mr/O Nowak/PERSON said/O ./O
Nowak/PERSON last/O week/O cancelled/O his/O scheduled/O December/O 6/O visit/O to/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION after/O failing/O to/O win/O assurances/O from/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION that/O he/O would/O be/O able/O to/O meet/O detainees/O privately/O ./O
