Tibetan/O monks/O ,/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION Muslims/O ,/O but/O also/O non/O violent/O dissidents/O ,/O farmers/O and/O members/O of/O underground/O religious/O communities/O are/O among/O those/O arrested/O ./O
Youth/O crime/O climbs/O by/O 19.1/O per/O cent/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O SCMP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O --/O
China/LOCATION 's/O courts/O were/O not/O idle/O in/O 2004/O ./O
More/O than/O 800,000/O people/O were/O arrested/O last/O year/O for/O endangering/O state/O security/O or/O for/O being/O involved/O in/O activities/O regarded/O as/O separatist/O ,/O terrorist/O or/O extremist/O ./O
In/O total/O ,/O 811,102/O people/O were/O held/O ,/O an/O 8.3/O per/O cent/O increase/O from/O 2003/O ./O
The/O courts/O last/O year/O prosecuted/O 867,186/O people/O in/O connection/O with/O those/O crimes/O ./O
In/O his/O annual/O report/O to/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O NPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O Jia/PERSON Chunwang/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Procuratorate/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O that/O security/O situation/O in/O 2004/O was/O ``/O grave/O ''/O requiring/O continuous/O efforts/O to/O crackdown/O on/O criminal/O activities/O ./O ''/O
-LSB-/O We/O were/O -RSB-/O resolute/O in/O smashing/O crimes/O which/O endanger/O state/O security/O and/O those/O criminal/O activities/O carried/O out/O by/O separatists/O ,/O religious/O extremists/O and/O violent/O terrorists/O ,/O ''/O Mr/O Jia/PERSON told/O NPC/ORGANIZATION members/O ./O
Endangering/O state/O security/O is/O a/O term/O China/LOCATION 's/O communist/O leaders/O use/O to/O detain/O people/O who/O oppose/O their/O rule/O and/O ideological/O control/O ,/O including/O peaceful/O dissidents/O ./O
Thousands/O of/O dissidents/O are/O jailed/O every/O year/O for/O allegedly/O endangering/O state/O security/O by/O engaging/O in/O pro-democracy/O activities/O or/O publishing/O essays/O on/O the/O internet/O that/O are/O seen/O as/O subversive/O ./O
Tibetan/O monks/O and/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION Muslims/O in/O northwest/O China/LOCATION who/O advocate/O independence/O are/O often/O targeted/O by/O Chinese/O authorities/O as/O terrorists/O ,/O separatists/O or/O religious/O extremists/O ./O
Clergymen/O and/O laity/O from/O underground/O Christian/O communities/O are/O also/O arrested/O for/O ``/O endangering/O public/O order/O ''/O ./O
Opposition/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O communist/O leadership/O is/O growing/O though/O ,/O as/O a/O stark/O lack/O of/O economic/O opportunities/O among/O the/O country/O 's/O 800/O million/O rural/O dwellers/O becomes/O increasingly/O evident/O ,/O raising/O fears/O of/O social/O unrest/O and/O turmoil/O ./O
In/O his/O speech/O to/O the/O NPC/ORGANIZATION on/O Saturday/O ,/O Prime/O Minister/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON said/O dealing/O with/O simmering/O unrest/O was/O a/O key/O priority/O of/O his/O government/O this/O year/O ,/O acknowledging/O the/O country/O faced/O ``/O glaring/O ''/O social/O problems/O ./O
The/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Procuratorate/ORGANIZATION also/O released/O data/O for/O corruption/O within/O the/O party/O ./O
Courts/O heard/O 24,184/O cases/O concerning/O officials/O last/O year/O ,/O 5.2/O per/O cent/O more/O than/O in/O 2003/O ./O
Six/O ministerial-level/O officials/O and/O 772/O officials/O above/O the/O county/O level/O were/O convicted/O of/O abusing/O power/O ,/O bribery/O and/O embezzling/O public/O funds/O ./O
The/O investigations/O helped/O recover/O 4.56/O billion/O yuan/O -LRB-/O $/O 456/O million/O ,/O US$/O 600/O million/O -RRB-/O of/O state/O funds/O ./O
The/O Chinese/O courts/O heard/O 644,248/O criminal/O cases/O ,/O with/O 767,951/O people/O sentenced/O ,/O up/O 1.5/O per/O cent/O and/O 2.8/O per/O cent/O respectively/O from/O 2003/O ./O
Criminal/O cases/O involving/O juveniles/O rose/O 19.1/O per/O cent/O ,/O with/O 70,086/O young/O people/O sentenced/O ./O
One/O of/O the/O areas/O to/O be/O highlighted/O by/O Mr/O Jia/PERSON is/O the/O investigation/O into/O fake/O products/O ./O
About/O 2,500/O people/O were/O arrested/O and/O 2,124/O charged/O with/O selling/O and/O producing/O fake/O milk/O powder/O ,/O fake/O wine/O ,/O fake/O medicine/O ,/O fake/O fertiliser/O and/O fake/O pesticide/O last/O year/O ,/O up/O 56/O per/O cent/O from/O 2003/O ./O
