After/O 10/O days/O of/O joint/O military/O exercises/O ,/O leaders/O of/O the/O armed/O forces/O of/O China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION have/O said/O they/O are/O ready/O for/O joint/O action/O to/O eradicate/O terrorism/O ,/O extremism/O and/O separatism/O in/O their/O territories/O ./O
Islamabad/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O --/O
China/LOCATION ``/O is/O ready/O to/O conduct/O an/O anti-terrorism/O drive/O in/O Asia/LOCATION with/O Pakistan/LOCATION for/O lasting/O peace/O and/O mutual/O prosperity/O ''/O ,/O said/O the/O Chinese/O General/O Lu/PERSON Dengming/PERSON ,/O Chief/O of/O Staff/O of/O the/O Chendu/LOCATION military/O region/O ./O
He/O was/O speaking/O at/O the/O concluding/O session/O of/O 10/O days/O of/O joint/O military/O exercises/O between/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION ./O
The/O general/O said/O :/O ``/O For/O many/O years/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION have/O remained/O focused/O on/O economic/O development/O and/O regional/O stability/O ;/O at/O the/O same/O time/O we/O are/O confronting/O three/O evil/O forces/O --/O terrorism/O ,/O extremism/O and/O separatism/O ./O ''/O
In/O such/O a/O scenario/O ,/O ``/O the/O whole/O world/O must/O benefit/O each/O other/O and/O enhance/O cooperation/O to/O combat/O these/O evils. Beijing/LOCATION is/O against/O all/O forms/O of/O terrorism/O and/O insists/O on/O international/O cooperation/O and/O the/O conducting/O of/O anti-terrorism/O campaigns/O ./O ''/O
Li/PERSON said/O the/O Pakistani/O army/O is/O ``/O highly/O professional/O :/O it/O has/O advanced/O technological/O arms/O and/O dedicated/O troops/O ./O
We/O were/O impressed/O by/O the/O high/O quality/O of/O the/O exercises/O ./O ''/O
The/O statements/O made/O by/O the/O Pakistani/O Corps/O Commander/O ,/O General/O Tariq/PERSON Majid/PERSON ,/O were/O in/O the/O same/O vein/O ./O
He/O told/O a/O press/O conference/O :/O ``/O Our/O country/O and China/LOCATION have/O many/O shared/O enemies/O :/O standing/O united/O ,/O we/O can/O eliminate/O the/O menace/O of/O terrorism/O ,/O which/O is/O affecting/O the/O entire/O fabric/O of/O human/O society/O ./O ''/O
The/O issue/O of/O terrorism/O is/O keenly/O felt/O by Beijing/LOCATION that/O is/O trying/O in/O all/O ways/O possible/O to/O prevent/O what/O it/O calls/O ``/O popular/O uprisings/O ''/O in/O the/O northern/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O the/O homeland/O of/O the/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O of/O Muslim/O faith/O ./O
The/O region/O borders/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O Mongolia/LOCATION and/O three/O ex-Soviet/O Republics/O of/O central Asia/LOCATION ./O
Many/O human/O rights/O activists/O insist/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O is/O used/O as/O an/O excuse/O by/O the/O Communist/O government/O to/O persecute/O the/O Uighur/O minority/O ./O
The/O decision/O to/O hold/O the/O exercises/O was/O taken/O during/O the/O visit/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION of/O the/O Chinese/O president/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON and/O they/O follow/O another/O set/O held/O in/O China/LOCATION in/O 2004/O ./O
The/O recent/O drills/O were/O unique/O because/O they/O marked/O the/O first/O time/O Chinese/O troops/O left/O their/O country/O to/O do/O exercises/O abroad/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION is/O the/O main/O supplier/O of/O conventional/O arms/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION but/O many/O analysts/O claim/O the/O Chinese/O government/O also/O backs/O Islamabad/LOCATION 's/O nuclear/O and/O missile/O programmes/O ./O
