The/O exiled/O activist/O warns/O that/O young/O women/O are/O being/O forced/O to/O work/O long/O hours/O in/O factories/O far/O from/O their/O homes/O ,/O and/O are/O months/O behind/O in/O their/O salaries/O ./O
Over/O 240/O thousand/O women/O have/O already/O been/O ``/O transferred/O ''/O ./O
Kadeer/U_PERSON urges/O US/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION to/O monitor/O the/O situation/O and/O pressure/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
Washington/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
The/O Chinese/O government/O is/O forcing/O young/O Uyghur/O women/O to/O leave/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION and/O travel/O to/O work/O in/O far/O off/O factories/O ./O
Rebiya/U_PERSON Kadeer/U_PERSON ,/O exiled/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION since/O 2005/O after/O having/O spent/O 5/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O having/O defended/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O Chinese/O Uyghur/O 's/O has/O appealed/O to/O the/O US/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION to/O monitor/O these/O transfers/O and/O intervene/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O stop/O these/O deportations/O ./O
Kadeer/U_PERSON explained/O that/O 240,000/O people/O ,/O mostly/O women/O single/O and/O ranging/O in/O age/O from/O 16/O to/O 25/O ,/O from/O southern/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION were/O the/O Uyghur/O are/O still/O a/O majority/O over/O the/O Han/O ,/O are/O being/O transferred/O under/O the/O guise/O of/O ``/O employment/O opportunities/O ''/O ./O
Once/O far/O from/O their/O homes/O the/O young/O women/O are/O being/O exploited/O ,/O as/O ``/O cheap/O slave/O labour/O and/O potential/O sex/O workers/O ''/O and/O faced/O harsh/O treatment/O with/O 12-hour/O work/O days/O and/O often/O saw/O wages/O withheld/O for/O months/O ./O
The/O government/O ``/O broke/O no/O opposition/O ''/O in/O this/O policy/O ,/O which/O many/O Uyghurs/O ``/O see/O as/O one/O of/O the/O most/O humiliating/O policies/O to/O date/O ''/O by/O Chinese/O authorities/O ./O
There/O is/O also/O the/O suspicion/O --/O she/O adds/O --/O that/O they/O aim/O to/O force/O these/O women/O to/O marry/O Han/O men/O ./O
Kadeer/U_PERSON nominated/O for/O the/O last/O year/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O ,/O is/O admired/O by/O many/O but/O is/O considered/O a/O criminal/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O her/O children/O who/O still/O live/O in/O the/O country/O are/O subjected/O to/O routine/O persecution/O ,/O charges/O and/O arrests/O ./O
