Workers/O who/O protest/O for/O their/O rights/O are/O arrested/O and/O mistreated/O ,/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION they/O might/O even/O be/O accused/O of/O being/O dangerous/O Muslim/O separatists/O ./O
One/O oil/O worker/O talks/O about/O her/O story/O ,/O one/O of/O abuses/O and/O government/O collusion/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
Xiao/PERSON Yishan/PERSON worked/O from/O 1984/O to/O 2000/O in/O a/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION refinery/O owned/O by/O the/O China/ORGANIZATION National/ORGANIZATION Petroleum/ORGANIZATION Corporation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O until/O the/O company/O laid/O off/O more/O than/O 360,000/O workers/O -LRB-/O between/O 1999/O and/O 2002/O -RRB-/O ./O
Speaking/O to/O Han/PERSON Dongfang/PERSON ,/O trade/O union/O activist/O and/O editor/O of/O the/O China/ORGANIZATION Labour/ORGANIZATION Bullettin/ORGANIZATION ,/O she/O related/O a/O long/O tale/O about/O an/O almost/O hopeless/O fight/O for/O workers/O rights/O ./O
In/O 2000/O when/O she/O was/O on/O maternity/O leave/O ,/O her/O boss/O called/O her/O and/O told/O her/O to/O come/O back/O right/O away/O or/O lose/O her/O job/O ``/O without/O getting/O a/O cent/O ./O ''/O
Back/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION she/O was/O forced/O to/O sign/O a/O seniority/O buyout/O contract/O for/O 4,500/O yuan/O per/O year/O of/O employment/O in/O which/O she/O agreed/O to/O sever/O her/O employment/O relationship/O with/O the/O company/O ./O
She/O estimates/O that/O around/O 20,000/O workers/O like/O herself/O terminated/O their/O employment/O contracts/O at/O a/O similar/O rate/O ./O
Although/O there/O was/O a/O branch/O of/O the/O All/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Federation/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Trade/ORGANIZATION Unions/ORGANIZATION at/O her/O company/O ,/O Xiao/PERSON said/O it/O was/O completely/O ineffectual/O ,/O never/O supported/O the/O workers/O and/O always/O grovelled/O to/O management/O ./O
Xiao/PERSON later/O discovered/O that/O workers/O at/O oilfields/O in/O other/O parts/O of/O China/LOCATION had/O received/O payouts/O of/O 12,000/O yuan/O for/O each/O year/O of/O employment/O
In/O 2001/O ,/O nearly/O 6,000/O former/O employees/O staged/O a/O protest/O at/O Xiao/PERSON 's/O refinery/O ,/O but/O after/O the/O demonstration/O the/O authorities/O drew/O up/O a/O hit/O list/O and/O arrested/O 15/O alleged/O leaders/O ./O
CNPC/ORGANIZATION Xinjiang/U_LOCATION management/O asked/O to/O meet/O workers/O '/O representatives/O to/O discuss/O their/O grievances/O but/O later/O one/O of/O the/O representatives/O ,/O Chen/PERSON Faling/PERSON ,/O was/O arrested/O and/O imprisoned/O ,/O he/O was/O let/O go/O after/O 30/O days/O when/O workers/O petitioned/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION regional/O government/O ./O
Eventually/O Xiao/PERSON and/O her/O fellow/O workers/O did/O get/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O present/O their/O case/O ./O
They/O were/O received/O by/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION officials/O but/O after/O two/O hours/O of/O meeting/O they/O were/O beaten/O ,/O thrown/O out/O ,/O put/O on/O a/O train/O and/O sent/O back/O to Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
All/O the/O while/O the/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION was/O growing/O ,/O hiring/O between/O 60,000/O and/O 80,000/O workers/O ,/O but/O none/O among/O those/O previously/O laid/O off/O ./O
In/O 2005/O another/O group/O of/O former/O oil/O workers/O ,/O including/O Xiao/PERSON ,/O went/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION once/O more/O with/O a/O new/O petition/O ./O
This/O time/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION management/O promised/O the/O company/O would/O pay/O the/O school/O fees/O and/O medical/O expenses/O of/O those/O workers/O who/O had/O been/O laid-off/O and/O provide/O employment/O for/O their/O children/O if/O necessary/O ./O
However/O ,/O the/O company/O has/O yet/O to/O honour/O its/O promise/O ./O
The/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION is/O one/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O leading/O oil/O companies/O ./O
It/O spun/O off/O most/O of/O its/O domestic/O assets/O into/O a/O separate/O company/O ,/O PetroChina/ORGANIZATION ,/O during/O a/O restructuring/O ./O
It/O is/O listed/O on/O the/O Honk/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION and/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION stock/O exchanges/O ./O
At/O least/O 4,000/O former/O oil/O workers/O are/O still/O seeking/O adequate/O compensation/O from/O the/O company/O ,/O but/O are/O doing/O so/O low/O key/O out/O of/O fear/O that/O public/O protests/O might/O be/O used/O to/O accuse/O them/O of/O being/O Muslim/O separatists/O ./O
Meanwhile/O Xiao/PERSON has/O developed/O a/O tumour/O ./O
She/O lives/O with/O her/O husband/O and/O nine-year-old/O son/O ./O
Their/O only/O income/O is/O the/O 400/O yuan/O the/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION is/O paying/O to/O her/O ,/O but/O the/O monthly/O for/O their/O flat/O is/O 180/O yuan/O ./O
