Two/O Japanese/O reporters/O arrested/O and/O beaten/O :/O they/O were/O ``/O investigating/O ''/O the/O attack/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
Tokyo/LOCATION has/O said/O it/O will/O lodge/O official/O protests/O ./O
Meanwhile/O ,/O there/O is/O controversy/O over/O yesterday/O 's/O attack/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
Tighter/O security/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O elsewhere/O ./O
But/O for/O the/O IOC/ORGANIZATION ,/O there/O are/O no/O serious/O problems/O over/O human/O rights/O ,/O censorship/O ,/O security/O ,/O and/O pollution/O ./O
What/O the/O athletes/O of/O Nepal/LOCATION are/O thinking/O as/O they/O depart/O for/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O
Two/O Japanese/O reporters/O have/O been/O arrested/O and/O beaten/O by/O the/O Chinese/O police/O in/O Kashgar/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O where/O they/O were/O investigating/O the/O attack/O that/O killed/O 16/O policemen/O yesterday/O ./O
Japanese/O government/O spokesman/O Nobutaka/PERSON Machimura/PERSON says/O that/O ``/O our/O embassy/O is/O of/O course/O gathering/O information/O from/O the/O authorities/O ''/O ,/O but/O that/O if/O the/O news/O is/O confirmed/O ,/O ``/O we/O plan/O to/O protest/O strongly/O ''/O ./O
The/O formal/O accusation/O may/O be/O that/O of/O photographing/O military/O installations/O in/O the/O area/O ,/O but/O there/O are/O some/O who/O say/O that/O the/O journalists/O were/O ``/O unwelcome/O ''/O for/O wanting/O to/O shed/O light/O on/O the/O attack/O ./O
The/O state/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION says/O that/O the/O bombs/O were/O made/O by/O the/O Islamic/O movement/O of/O eastern/O Turkestan/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O another/O name/O for/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O which/O has/O also/O threatened/O attacks/O during/O the/O Olympics/O ,/O and/O that/O yesterday/O two/O suspects/O were/O arrested/O ./O
18/O ``/O foreign/O agitators/O ''/O have/O also/O been/O arrested/O for/O previous/O protests/O ,/O but/O without/O any/O connection/O to/O the/O bomb/O ./O
But/O the/O exile/O Rebiya/U_PERSON Kadeer/U_PERSON ,/O president/O of/O the/O Uyghur/U_ORGANIZATION American/U_ORGANIZATION Association/U_ORGANIZATION ,/O responds/O that/O the/O population/O is/O rejecting/O such/O acts/O of/O violence/O ,/O and/O the/O government/O has/O not/O provided/O any/O proof/O of/O what/O it/O is/O saying/O ./O
For/O Dilxadi/U_PERSON Rexiti/U_PERSON ,/O of/O the/O information/O center/O of/O eastern/O Turkestan/U_LOCATION ,/O ``/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O the/O attack/O was/O a/O terrorist/O plot/O ./O
It/O is/O an/O armed/O struggle/O ,/O and/O this/O is/O in/O response/O to/O the/O persistent/O suppression/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O in/O the/O region/O ''/O ./O
He/O also/O denounces/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O attempt/O ``/O to/O represent/O the/O entire/O Uyghur/O people/O as/O terrorists/O ''/O ./O
The/O Islamic/O Uyghurs/O charge/O that/O for/O years/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O been/O a/O carrying/O out/O a/O genuine/O cultural/O genocide/O ,/O with/O frequent/O arrests/O over/O accusations/O of/O terrorism/O ,/O and/O torture/O in/O the/O prisons/O ./O
The/O police/O check/O each/O vehicle/O that/O enters/O Kashgar/U_LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O residents/O are/O afraid/O ``/O that/O it/O will/O be/O even/O harder/O for/O us/O now/O ''/O ./O
Forces/O have/O also/O been/O deployed/O in/O Lhasa/LOCATION ,/O the/O capital/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O where/O ``/O antiterrorism/O exercises/O ''/O are/O taking/O place/O during/O these/O days/O ,/O to/O prevent/O possible/O protests/O ./O
Meanwhile/O ,/O more/O than/O 110,000/O policemen/O and/O 1.4/O million/O volunteers/O are/O watching/O over/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O especially/O on/O the/O main/O roads/O and/O bridges/O and/O the/O most/O heavily/O trafficked/O places/O ,/O like/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION and/O Changan/LOCATION Avenue/LOCATION ./O
Hotels/O ,/O hostels/O ,/O and/O taxi/O drivers/O are/O being/O asked/O to/O call/O the/O police/O immediately/O if/O one/O of/O their/O clients/O is/O from/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION or/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O
But/O this/O tension/O must/O not/O be/O very/O noticeable/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O where/O Jacques/PERSON Rogge/PERSON ,/O president/O of/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Olympic/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O has/O said/O that/O ``/O I/O believe/O these/O Olympics/O will/O change/O the/O country/O ,/O and/O will/O also/O change/O the/O perception/O of/O the/O world/O towards/O this/O country/O ''/O ,/O without/O providing/O any/O more/O explanation/O ./O
Meanwhile/O ,/O today/O a/O blanket/O of/O smog/O covered/O Beijing/LOCATION again/O -LRB-/O in/O the/O photo/O -RRB-/O ,/O and/O on/O pollution/O he/O responded/O that/O ``/O our/O medical/O commission/O has/O indicated/O that/O there/O is/O no/O health/O problem/O for/O every/O event/O lasting/O under/O an/O hour/O and/O taking/O place/O at/O indoor/O arenas/O ''/O ,/O while/O the/O long/O distance/O competitions/O like/O the/O marathon/O or/O bicycle/O races/O could/O be/O moved/O ./O
But/O some/O of/O the/O 32/O members/O of/O Nepal/LOCATION 's/O team/O are/O more/O concerned/O about/O the/O situation/O of/O human/O rights/O than/O about/O pollution/O ./O
Deepak/PERSON Bista/PERSON ,/O who/O competes/O in/O taekwondo/O and/O represents/O Nepal/LOCATION 's/O greatest/O hope/O ,/O says/O that/O ``/O limited/O press/O access/O and/O internet/O does/O n't/O ensure/O freedom/O of/O expression/O in/O any/O country/O ''/O ./O
Marathon/O runner/O Arjun/PERSON Basnet/PERSON is/O also/O perplexed/O ,/O while/O the/O other/O athletes/O and/O coaches/O are/O ``/O concentrating/O only/O on/O the/O competitions/O ''/O ,/O and/O are/O in/O any/O place/O tranquil/O over/O the/O ``/O general/O security/O ''/O ./O
Shamsher/PERSON ,/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Olympic/O committee/O of/O Asia/LOCATION ,/O concludes/O that/O ``/O Chinese/O decision/O for/O limited/O website/O access/O is/O their/O private/O matter/O ''/O ./O
-LRB-/O Kalpit/PERSON Parajuli/PERSON contributed/O to/O this/O report/O from/O Nepal/LOCATION -RRB-/O
