The/O authorities/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION are/O preparing/O a/O special/O law/O ./O
In/O China/LOCATION special/O law/O and/O order/O legislation/O means/O more/O powers/O to/O the/O police/O and/O less/O freedom/O to/O the/O people/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
Xinjiang/U_LOCATION wants/O to/O quickly/O pass/O special/O laws/O to/O deal/O with/O separatism/O in/O the/O autonomous/O region/O ,/O Chinese/O newspapers/O reported/O yesterday/O without/O any/O explanation/O ./O
This/O is/O a/O sign/O that/O the/O protests/O that/O broke/O out/O on/O 5/O July/O will/O be/O met/O with/O harsh/O measures/O ./O
Officially/O 197/O people/O died/O during/O the/O violent/O clashes/O and/O more/O 1,700/O were/O wounded/O ./O
Analysts/O note/O that/O China/LOCATION already/O has/O some/O of/O the/O toughest/O anti-secession/O laws/O on/O the/O books/O ;/O any/O new/O law/O will/O simply/O give/O more/O powers/O to/O the/O police/O and/O increase/O already/O harsh/O penalties/O ,/O thus/O further/O limiting/O civil/O liberties/O ./O
Speaking/O to/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION Eligen/PERSON Imibakhi/PERSON ,/O chairman/O of/O the/O Standing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Xinjiang/U_ORGANIZATION Regional/U_ORGANIZATION People/U_ORGANIZATION 's/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O that/O this/O month/O 's/O protests/O were/O caused/O by/O the/O ``/O three/O forces/O ,/O ''/O namely/O ``/O extremism/O ,/O separatism/O and/O terrorism/O ''/O ./O
For/O years/O China/LOCATION has/O used/O this/O unholy/O trinity/O to/O justify/O its/O persecution/O of/O Uyghurs/O ,/O charging/O them/O with/O being/O dangerous/O terrorists/O ./O
Chinese/O authorities/O insist/O that/O demonstrations/O in/O early/O July/O were/O organised/O by/O secessionist/O groups/O ,/O not/O the/O spontaneous/O action/O of/O ordinary/O people/O ./O
The/O mouthpiece/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION ,/O yesterday/O blamed/O foreign/O groups/O like/O the/O Munich-based/O World/U_ORGANIZATION Uyghur/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O WUC/U_ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O and/O exiled/O Uyghyr/O leader/O Rebiya/U_PERSON Kadeer/U_PERSON for/O masterminding/O the/O violence/O ,/O an/O accusation/O which/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION reprinted/O today/O ./O
Uyghurs/O have/O dismissed/O Chinese/O charges/O ,/O saying/O the/O protests/O were/O peaceful/O until/O police/O intervened/O ./O
Instead/O WUC/U_ORGANIZATION representative/O in/O Japan/LOCATION Ilham/U_PERSON Mahmut/U_PERSON called/O on/O China/LOCATION to/O allow/O a/O third/O party/O to/O hold/O an/O independent/O investigation/O into/O the/O incidents/O ./O
Meanwhile/O Xingjian/U_LOCATION 's/O capital/O of/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION remains/O an/O ethnically-divided/O powder/O keg/O ./O
Uyghurs/O have/O become/O a/O minority/O in/O their/O own/O city/O ,/O restricted/O to/O the/O poorest/O neighbourhoods/O ./O
Ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O now/O make/O up/O more/O than/O 70/O per/O cent/O of/O the/O city/O 's/O 2.3/O million/O residents/O ,/O encouraged/O to/O settle/O in/O this/O faraway/O outpost/O through/O incentives/O and/O promises/O of/O positions/O of/O power/O ./O
The/O violent/O demonstrations/O have/O traumatised/O both/O groups/O ;/O each/O claiming/O that/O media/O coverage/O of/O the/O events/O has/O distorted/O what/O actually/O happened/O ./O
Officially/O ,/O 1,400/O Uyghurs/O have/O been/O arrested/O for/O their/O involvement/O in/O the/O protests/O ,/O a/O figure/O treated/O with/O scorn/O by/O Uyghurs/O ,/O some/O of/O whom/O claim/O that/O as/O many/O 20,000/O have/O been/O detained/O ,/O including/O innocent/O passers-by/O caught/O up/O in/O the/O events/O ./O
