Exiled/O Uyghur/O leader/O says/O China/LOCATION did/O not/O draw/O any/O lesson/O from/O the/O Olympics/O ,/O continues/O to/O violate/O human/O rights/O ./O
According/O to/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ,/O she/O is/O to/O blame/O for/O fomenting/O the/O July/O unrest/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
Exiled/O Uygur/O leader/O Rebiya/U_PERSON Kadeer/U_PERSON sharply/O criticised/O the/O Frankfurt/O Book/O Fair/O for/O inviting/O China/LOCATION as/O its/O guest/O this/O year/O ,/O arguing/O the/O country/O should/O not/O be/O honoured/O given/O its/O poor/O human/O rights/O track/O record/O ./O
``/O It/O is/O just/O not/O right/O to/O welcome/O a/O country/O ,/O where/O executions/O are/O a/O daily/O occurrence/O and/O human/O rights/O are/O treated/O with/O disrespect/O ,/O ''/O said/O Kadeer/U_PERSON ,/O who/O has/O been/O in/O exile/O for/O the/O past/O two/O years/O and/O now/O leads/O the/O World/U_ORGANIZATION Uyghur/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION ./O
``/O Before/O the/O Olympic/O Games/O ,/O the/O world/O was/O of/O the/O opinion/O China/LOCATION would/O be/O forced/O to/O respect/O human/O rights/O more/O as/O the/O world/O turned/O its/O attention/O to/O the/O games/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O
``/O Instead/O of/O drawing/O lessons/O from/O that/O event/O ,/O the/O book/O fair/O invited/O China/LOCATION as/O its/O guest/O -LSB-/O .../O -RSB-/O but/O what/O happened/O on/O July/O 5/O demonstrates/O how/O China/LOCATION treats/O human/O rights/O and/O its/O citizens/O ''/O ./O
She/O was/O referring/O here/O to/O the/O violent/O unrest/O that/O broke/O out/O in/O July/O and/O shook/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwest/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
The/O ethnic/O violence/O that/O ensued/O left/O 200/O people/O dead/O ;/O thousands/O more/O were/O arrested/O for/O involvement/O in/O anti-Chinese/O protests/O ./O
China/LOCATION instead/O blames/O Kadeer/U_PERSON for/O orchestrating/O the/O violence/O ./O
In/O an/O editorial/O ,/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION yesterday/O accused/O her/O and/O the/O Germany-based/O group/O she/O heads/O of/O using/O the/O internet/O to/O instigate/O the/O deadly/O riots/O in/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ,/O and/O thus/O of/O unscrupulously/O sending/O people/O to/O their/O death/O ,/O a/O charge/O also/O made/O in/O the/O much/O awaited/O report/O into/O the/O unrest/O the/O Chinese/O government/O released/O two/O days/O ago/O ./O
Following/O the/O clashes/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION arrested/O scores/O of/O people/O ./O
So/O far/O ,/O 21/O have/O been/O tried/O by/O the/O people/O 's/O courts/O and/O 12/O have/O been/O sentenced/O to/O death/O ./O
Various/O NGOs/O have/O slammed/O China/LOCATION 's/O court/O system/O of/O violating/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O accused/O ./O
In/O response/O ,/O an/O anonymous/O mainland/O legal/O authority/O said/O that/O trials/O were/O ``/O carried/O out/O according/O to/O our/O national/O constitution/O and/O law/O ,/O ''/O adding/O that/O judicial/O ``/O independence/O is/O a/O core/O part/O of/O sovereignty/O ./O
Foreign/O governments/O and/O organisations/O have/O no/O right/O to/O intervene/O ./O ''/O
