China/LOCATION seeks/O alliances/O in/O Muslim/O world/O to/O stop/O possible/O terror/O attacks/O against/O overseas/O Chinese/O diplomatic/O and/O civilian/O interest/O ./O
Uyghur/O leader/O Rebiya/U_PERSON Kadeer/U_PERSON rejects/O al-Qaeda/ORGANIZATION 's/O violence/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION calls/O on/O Turkish/O Prime/O Minister/O Erdogan/PERSON to/O apologise/O for/O saying/O that/O last/O week/O 's/O anti-Uyghur/O repression/O was/O akin/O to/O genocide/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
China/LOCATION is/O trying/O to/O stem/O a/O wave/O of/O sympathy/O in/O favour/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O cause/O whilst/O taking/O steps/O to/O deal/O with/O threats/O by/O Islamic/O groups/O against/O overseas/O Chinese/O ./O
Meanwhile/O exiled/O Uyghur/O leader/O Rebiya/U_PERSON Kadeer/U_PERSON ,/O whom/O Beijing/LOCATION accuses/O of/O being/O in/O league/O with/O terror/O groups/O ,/O condemns/O al-Qaeda/ORGANIZATION threats/O against/O China/LOCATION ./O
Yesterday/O Algerian-based/O offshoot/O al-Qaeda/ORGANIZATION in/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Maghreb/ORGANIZATION issued/O a/O threat/O to/O target/O Chinese/O nationals/O working/O in/O North/LOCATION Africa/LOCATION as/O revenge/O against/O the/O oppression/O and/O killing/O of/O Uyghurs/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
In/O response/O ``/O we/O will/O keep/O a/O close/O eye/O on/O developments/O and/O make/O joint/O efforts/O with/O relevant/O countries/O to/O take/O all/O necessary/O measures/O to/O ensure/O the/O safety/O of/O overseas/O Chinese/O institutions/O and/O people/O ,/O ''/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Qin/PERSON Gang/PERSON said/O ,/O adding/O that/O the/O ``/O Chinese/O government/O opposes/O terrorism/O in/O any/O form/O and/O we/O 'd/O like/O to/O increase/O our/O co-operation/O with/O related/O countries/O to/O fight/O terrorism/O ,/O offering/O safety/O ''/O to/O Chinese/O nationals/O ./O
As/O part/O of/O their/O diplomatic/O offensive/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O appealed/O to/O the/O Muslim/O world/O to/O understand/O its/O policies/O and/O actions/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
In/O Washington/LOCATION Rebiya/U_PERSON Kadeer/U_PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O US-based/O World/U_ORGANIZATION Uyghur/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O in/O a/O statement/O released/O on/O the/O organisation/O 's/O website/O that/O she/O did/O ``/O not/O believe/O violence/O is/O a/O solution/O to/O any/O problem/O ''/O ./O
Responding/O to/O threats/O made/O by/O the/O Algerian/O offshoot/O of/O al-Qaeda/ORGANIZATION ,/O she/O noted/O that/O ``/O global/O terrorists/O should/O not/O take/O advantage/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O people/O 's/O legitimate/O aspirations/O and/O the/O current/O tragedy/O in/O East/U_ORGANIZATION Turkistan/U_ORGANIZATION to/O commit/O acts/O of/O terrorism/O targeting/O Chinese/O diplomatic/O missions/O or/O civilians/O ./O ''/O
In/O spite/O of/O this/O statement/O Chinese/O authorities/O continue/O to/O accuse/O Ms/O Kadeer/U_PERSON of/O being/O behind/O last/O week/O 's/O unrest/O in/O league/O with/O ``/O three/O forces/O ''/O ,/O i.e./O separatists/O ,/O extremists/O and/O terrorists/O ./O
In/O general/O governments/O in/O the/O Muslim/O world/O have/O remained/O silent/O over/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION massacre/O ,/O choosing/O to/O safeguard/O their/O good/O trading/O relations/O with/O mainland/O China/LOCATION ,/O concerned/O they/O too/O might/O be/O criticised/O for/O suppressing/O domestic/O opposition/O ./O
Turkish/O Prime/O Minister/O Recep/PERSON Tayyip/PERSON Erdogan/PERSON was/O the/O only/O discordant/O voice/O ./O
Commenting/O the/O situation/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION he/O said/O that/O Chinese/O action/O was/O akin/O to/O genocide/O ./O
Turks/O and/O Uyghurs/O are/O related/O in/O terms/O of/O language/O ,/O culture/O and/O religion/O ./O
Yesterday/O China/LOCATION 's/O English-language/O newspaper/O China/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION urged/O Mr/O Erdogan/PERSON to/O ``/O take/O back/O his/O remarks/O .../O which/O constitute/O interference/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O internal/O affairs/O ''/O ,/O describing/O his/O comments/O as/O ``/O irresponsible/O and/O groundless/O ./O ''/O
