A/O year/O after/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O clashed/O with/O at/O least/O 200/O killed/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O placed/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION under/O tight/O controls/O ,/O urging/O people/O to/O stay/O indoors/O ./O
NGO/O claims/O dozens/O of/O executions/O were/O carried/O out/O in/O secret/O ./O
Urumqi/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
Xinjiang/U_LOCATION 's/O capital/O of/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION is/O calm/O ,/O unnaturally/O so/O ,/O on/O the/O first/O anniversary/O of/O the/O crackdown/O that/O left/O hundreds/O of/O ethnic/O Uyghurs/O dead/O or/O injured/O ./O
Eager/O to/O avoid/O a/O repeat/O of/O last/O year/O 's/O unrest/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O deployed/O thousands/O of/O police/O ,/O many/O trucked/O in/O from/O neighbouring/O provinces/O ,/O and/O installed/O 40,000/O security/O cameras/O throughout/O the/O city/O ./O
The/O unrest/O left/O nearly/O 200/O people/O dead/O and/O 1,700/O injured/O ./O
It/O is/O not/O known/O how/O many/O were/O arrested/O ,/O but/O Uighur/O dissidents/O put/O the/O number/O in/O the/O tens/O of/O thousands/O ./O
On/O 5/O July/O 2009/O ,/O following/O a/O protest/O dispersed/O by/O police/O ,/O young/O Uyghur/O men/O attacked/O neighbourhoods/O inhabited/O by/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O who/O have/O settled/O in/O the/O province/O ./O
The/O next/O day/O ,/O Han/O Chinese/O retaliated/O in/O what/O became/O China/LOCATION 's/O worst/O ethnic/O clashes/O in/O decades/O ./O
On/O Saturday/O ,/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION issued/O a/O statement/O questioning/O China/LOCATION 's/O official/O version/O of/O events/O ,/O saying/O that/O it/O is/O not/O clear/O how/O many/O people/O were/O killed/O or/O by/O whom/O ./O
In/O camera/O trials/O convicted/O 198/O people/O ,/O allegedly/O for/O their/O involvement/O in/O the/O riots/O ./O
Of/O these/O ,/O 26/O were/O sentenced/O to/O death/O ./O
At/O least/O ,/O nine/O have/O already/O been/O executed/O ./O
For/O Uyghur/O resistance/O leader/O Rebiya/U_PERSON Kadeer/U_PERSON ,/O who/O lives/O in/O exile/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION after/O barely/O avoiding/O the/O death/O penalty/O herself/O ,/O the/O free/O world/O knows/O what/O is/O happening/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION but/O does/O nothing/O to/O avoid/O annoying/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
In/O the/O city/O of/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION itself/O ,/O residents/O are/O reporting/O an/O unnaturally/O calm/O ,/O saying/O that/O Chinese/O authorities/O are/O telling/O ethnic/O Uyghurs/O to/O stay/O indoors/O ./O
