Five/O more/O people/O ,/O probably/O all/O Uyghurs/O ,/O have/O been/O sentenced/O to/O death/O for/O their/O involvement/O in/O last/O July/O 's/O riots/O ./O
The/O authorities/O also/O announce/O more/O investments/O in/O the/O province/O ./O
Experts/O say/O the/O money/O will/O likely/O benefit/O ruling/O groups/O whilst/O ethnic/O Uyghurs/O will/O be/O further/O dispossessed/O of/O their/O natural/O riches/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
Four/O more/O Uyghurs/O have/O been/O sentenced/O to/O death/O for/O their/O involvement/O in/O last/O July/O 's/O riots/O in/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION capital/O of/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ./O
The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O also/O announced/O plans/O to/O increase/O investments/O in/O the/O region/O ./O
Experts/O however/O expect/O the/O surge/O in/O money/O to/O benefit/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O settlers/O at/O the/O expense/O of/O indigenous/O Uyghurs/O ./O
On/O Tuesday/O ,/O a/O court/O in/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION sentenced/O four/O more/O people/O to/O death/O for/O ''/O extremely/O serious/O crimes/O ''/O ,/O said/O Ma/PERSON Xinchun/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O the/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION government/O 's/O press/O office/O ,/O who/O did/O not/O elaborate/O more/O on/O the/O issue/O ./O
A/O fifth/O defendant/O was/O also/O sentenced/O to/O death/O but/O was/O given/O a/O two-year/O reprieve/O --/O a/O penalty/O usually/O commuted/O to/O life/O in/O prison/O ./O
Based/O on/O their/O names/O ,/O all/O those/O given/O death/O sentences/O appeared/O to/O be/O Uyghurs/O ./O
This/O verdict/O brings/O to/O 26/O the/O number/O of/O death/O penalties/O imposed/O following/O the/O July/O riots/O ;/O some/O have/O already/O been/O carried/O out/O ./O
Uyghurs/O have/O become/O a/O minority/O in/O their/O own/O land/O -LRB-/O 46/O per/O cent/O of/O 21/O million/O residents/O -RRB-/O after/O China/LOCATION adopted/O a/O policy/O of/O mass/O immigration/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O into/O the/O region/O ./O
By/O and/O large/O ,/O newcomers/O get/O special/O treatment/O in/O business/O and/O government/O employment/O ./O
On/O 5/O July/O 2009/O ,/O some/O Uyghurs/O attacked/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O rioting/O and/O burning/O cars/O ./O
In/O the/O next/O two/O days/O ,/O Han/O Chinese/O struck/O back/O ,/O targeting/O Uyghurs/O ./O
At/O least/O 197/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O the/O clashes/O with/O many/O thousands/O more/O injured/O ,/O partly/O as/O a/O result/O of/O police/O repression/O ./O
Based/O on/O the/O available/O evidence/O ,/O almost/O all/O of/O those/O arrested/O or/O sentenced/O to/O death/O are/O ethnic/O Uyghurs/O ./O
Meanwhile/O ,/O senior/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION leader/O Zhou/PERSON Yongkang/PERSON said/O the/O party/O 's/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION would/O hold/O a/O conference/O later/O this/O year/O ''/O to/O make/O a/O plan/O to/O support/O the/O development/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION and/O promote/O the/O long-term/O stability/O and/O prosperity/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O ''/O
In/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Chinese/O leaders/O discussed/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION problem/O for/O two/O days/O ./O
Developing/O the/O region/O 's/O oil/O and/O gas/O reserves/O was/O one/O of/O the/O issues/O on/O the/O table/O ./O
Xinxiang/U_LOCATION 's/O economy/O grew/O by/O 8/O per/O cent/O last/O year/O ./O
Like/O a/O recent/O meeting/O on/O troubled/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O which/O lies/O next/O to/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O this/O meeting/O underscored/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O belief/O that/O the/O cure/O to/O ethnic/O strife/O lies/O in/O faster/O economic/O development/O ,/O rather/O than/O a/O rethink/O of/O strict/O ,/O top-down/O political/O controls/O ,/O said/O Nicholas/PERSON Bequelin/PERSON ,/O a/O researcher/O on/O China/ORGANIZATION with/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION ./O
Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION have/O many/O things/O in/O common/O ./O
In/O both/O regions/O ,/O Chinese/O policy/O is/O one/O of/O persecution/O of/O the/O indigenous/O population/O through/O repression/O and/O discrimination/O as/O well/O as/O large-scale/O investments/O designed/O to/O encourage/O settlers/O -LRB-/O see/O Willy/PERSON Wo-lap/PERSON Lam/PERSON ,/O ``/O New/O policy/O on/O Tibet/LOCATION :/O repression/O and/O modernization/O ,/O ''/O in/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION ,/O 26/O January/O 2010/O -RRB-/O ./O
In/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O indigenous/O Uyghurs/O have/O long/O complained/O that/O economic/O development/O has/O disproportionately/O benefited/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O who/O hold/O all/O the/O key/O positions/O in/O government/O and/O business/O ./O
What/O is/O more/O ,/O the/O region/O is/O being/O stripped/O of/O its/O natural/O riches/O to/O the/O benefit/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O coastal/O provinces/O ./O
``/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION is/O much/O more/O important/O than/O Tibet/LOCATION in/O high/O politics/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O because/O of/O its/O oil/O and/O gas/O and/O strategic/O importance/O ,/O ''/O said/O Bequelin/PERSON ./O
It/O is/O in/O fact/O a/O key/O transit/O point/O for/O pipelines/O coming/O from/O Iran/LOCATION and/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O
In/O early/O January/O ,/O funding/O for/O public/O security/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION was/O nearly/O doubled/O --/O from/O 1.54/O billion/O yuan/O to/O 2.89/O billion/O yuan/O -LRB-/O from/O US$/O 225/O million/O to/O US$/O 425/O million/O -RRB-/O --/O for/O 2010/O ./O
