About/O 55/O members/O of/O unofficial/O Churches/O are/O arrested/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION and/O Hubei/LOCATION between/O Christmas/O and/O Epiphany/O as/O China/LOCATION 's/O anti-Christian/O crackdown/O continues/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
China/LOCATION 's/O central/O government/O has/O recently/O intensified/O its/O crackdown/O on/O unofficial/O Protestant/O Churches/O ./O
At/O least/O 44/O people/O were/O arrested/O in/O the/O central/O province/O of/O Hebei/LOCATION and/O the/O northwestern/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
In/O one/O incident/O ,/O on/O Friday/O ,/O about/O 30/O Christians/O ,/O including/O a/O pastor/O and/O a/O church/O elder/O ,/O were/O rounded/O up/O by/O police/O and/O government/O officials/O in/O Handan/LOCATION ,/O Hebei/LOCATION ,/O whilst/O they/O were/O attending/O a/O Bible/O study/O meeting/O ,/O this/O according/O to/O Rev/O Zhang/PERSON Mingxuan/PERSON ,/O pastor/O and/O president/O of/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Home/ORGANIZATION Church/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION who/O was/O phoned/O by/O one/O of/O the/O people/O arrested/O ./O
A/O day/O earlier/O ,/O police/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION detained/O 14/O Christians/O at/O the/O Nongwushi/U_LOCATION police/O station/O ,/O Aksu/U_LOCATION district/O ./O
``/O They/O were/O questioned/O because/O they/O were/O meeting/O illegally/O ,/O ''/O local/O police/O Chief/O Chen/PERSON Xiaolong/PERSON said/O ./O
``/O We/O advised/O them/O to/O go/O to/O a/O registered/O church/O instead/O ,/O ''/O Chen/PERSON said/O ./O
Out/O of/O the/O group/O of/O 14/O ,/O 11/O were/O held/O for/O more/O than/O 12/O hours/O ,/O ``/O But/O they/O have/O all/O been/O released/O now/O ,/O ''/O the/O police/O chief/O added/O ./O
In/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O a/O wave/O of/O persecution/O has/O struck/O Han/O and/O Uyghur/O Christians/O alike/O between/O Christmas/O and/O Epiphany/O On/O Christmas/O Day/O ,/O police/O broke/O into/O the/O home/O of/O Wang/PERSON Qiyue/PERSON ,/O a/O 7-year-old/O widow/O ,/O and/O disrupted/O a/O Christmas/O gathering/O ./O
On/O the/O same/O day/O ,/O people/O invaded/O the/O home/O of/O 69-year-old/O hemiplegic/O He/PERSON Cuiying/PERSON where/O some/O Christians/O were/O praying/O ./O
More/O than/O 30/O Bibles/O and/O spiritual/O books/O were/O confiscated/O ./O
Later/O ,/O five/O elderly/O Christians/O were/O arrested/O with/O no/O cause/O and/O fined/O 5,000/O Yuan/O each/O ./O
