Eleven/O mentally/O disabled/O workers/O forced/O to/O work/O in/O slave-like/O conditions/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O fed/O the/O same/O food/O as/O dogs/O and/O beaten/O for/O every/O mistake/O they/O made/O ,/O at/O no/O salary/O and/O unable/O to/O escape/O ./O
Forced/O labour/O is/O still/O widespread/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O in/O what/O is/O tantamount/O to/O a/O modern/O version/O of/O slavery/O ./O
The/O government/O says/O it/O is/O fighting/O the/O problem/O ,/O but/O the/O latter/O has/O a/O way/O of/O reappearing/O on/O a/O regular/O basis/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
Eleven/O disabled/O people/O were/O forced/O to/O work/O in/O slave-like/O conditions/O at/O the/O Jiaersi/U_ORGANIZATION Green/U_ORGANIZATION Construction/U_ORGANIZATION Material/U_ORGANIZATION Chemical/U_ORGANIZATION Factory/U_ORGANIZATION in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O newspapers/O reported/O recently/O ./O
The/O plant/O is/O now/O shut/O down/O after/O police/O moved/O in/O ,/O but/O many/O wonder/O how/O this/O could/O go/O on/O for/O so/O long/O ,/O especially/O in/O the/O wake/O of/O the/O Shanxi/LOCATION scandal/O of/O 2007/O and/O the/O government/O 's/O repeated/O claims/O of/O success/O in/O the/O fight/O against/O this/O modern/O form/O of/O slavery/O ./O
Press/O reports/O said/O that/O the/O 11/O workers/O at/O the/O building/O materials/O plant/O put/O in/O long/O hours/O ,/O suffered/O regular/O beatings/O and/O were/O given/O the/O same/O food/O as/O the/O dogs/O ./O
None/O were/O paid/O ,/O some/O for/O up/O to/O four/O years/O ./O
Anyone/O trying/O to/O flee/O the/O factory/O was/O routinely/O beaten/O ./O
According/O to/O factory/O owner/O Li/PERSON Xinglin/PERSON ,/O the/O workers/O were/O legally/O contracted/O to/O work/O at/O the/O facility/O by/O an/O aid/O agency/O for/O the/O disabled/O based/O in/O Sichuan/LOCATION ./O
Li/PERSON claimed/O he/O paid/O the/O agency/O a/O lump/O sum/O of/O 9,000/O yuan/O for/O five/O workers/O and/O then/O an/O additional/O 300/O yuan/O per/O worker/O per/O month/O ./O
Police/O issued/O an/O arrest/O warrant/O for/O the/O founder/O of/O the/O organisation/O ,/O but/O he/O remains/O at/O large/O ./O
Chinese/O authorities/O admit/O that/O human/O trafficking/O is/O a/O problem/O in/O the/O country/O ;/O one/O that/O police/O has/O failed/O so/O far/O to/O eradicate/O ./O
However/O ,/O the/O country/O 's/O Public/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION has/O claimed/O great/O victories/O in/O the/O fight/O against/O this/O form/O of/O labour/O exploitation/O ./O
Seventeen/O thousand/O children/O and/O women/O were/O freed/O by/O police/O and/O 15,673/O suspects/O arrested/O between/O April/O 2009/O and/O September/O 2010/O ,/O it/O reported/O ./O
Between/O January/O and/O July/O of/O this/O year/O ,/O 1,238/O people/O were/O sentenced/O to/O death/O ,/O life/O in/O prison/O or/O jail/O terms/O greater/O than/O five/O years/O ,/O this/O according/O to/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION data/O ./O
However/O ,/O the/O numbers/O leave/O many/O questions/O unanswered/O about/O slave/O workers/O ,/O who/O appear/O to/O be/O popping/O up/O all/O over/O the/O place/O ./O
In/O 2007/O ,/O the/O authorities/O found/O thousands/O of/O people/O forced/O to/O work/O in/O brick/O kilns/O in/O the/O provinces/O of/O Henan/LOCATION and/O Shanxi/LOCATION ,/O subjected/O to/O regular/O beatings/O for/O not/O working/O quick/O enough/O ,/O living/O on/O near-starvation/O diets/O ,/O sleeping/O in/O cold/O ,/O unheated/O rooms/O ,/O closely/O watched/O by/O dogs/O and/O guards/O ./O
At/O least/O one/O disabled/O worker/O was/O beaten/O to/O death/O by/O a/O guard/O because/O he/O ``/O did/O not/O work/O fast/O enough/O ''/O ./O
A/O parliamentary/O investigation/O found/O that/O some/O 53,000/O migrant/O workers/O were/O employed/O in/O more/O than/O 2,000/O illegal/O brick/O kilns/O in/O Shanxi/LOCATION alone/O ./O
Since/O then/O ,/O similar/O cases/O of/O slavery/O have/O been/O reported/O sporadically/O around/O China/LOCATION ,/O suggesting/O the/O problem/O has/O not/O been/O eliminated/O ./O
In/O 2007/O ,/O in/O some/O places/O local/O politicians/O were/O found/O to/O be/O directly/O involved/O in/O brick/O kilns/O ./O
In/O May/O of/O this/O year/O ,/O police/O rescued/O 34/O people/O forced/O to/O work/O at/O a/O brick/O kiln/O in/O northern/O China/LOCATION 's/O Hebei/LOCATION province/O ./O
Eleven/O people/O were/O detained/O for/O ``/O using/O methods/O such/O as/O beating/O ,/O electrocuting/O ,/O intimidating/O ,/O and/O restrictions/O on/O freedom/O ,/O to/O force/O migrant/O workers/O to/O engage/O in/O heavy/O manual/O labour/O ''/O ./O
