The/O exiled/O Uyghur/O leader/O sees/O through/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O charges/O of/O terrorism/O in/O Hotan/U_LOCATION clashes/O two/O days/O ago/O and/O demands/O China/LOCATION cease/O arbitrary/O arrests/O and/O torture/O ./O
Meanwhile/O ,/O Uyghur/O sources/O speak/O of/O at/O least/O 20/O dead/O and/O 70/O arrested/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O
Tension/O in/O Hotan/U_LOCATION ,/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O remains/O high/O after/O the/O clashes/O between/O police/O and/O protesters/O on/O July/O 19/O ./O
The/O World/U_ORGANIZATION Uyghur/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION reports/O that/O there/O were/O at/O least/O 20/O Uyghurs/O killed/O -LRB-/O 14/O crushed/O to/O death/O and/O 6/O killed/O by/O gun/O shots/O -RRB-/O and/O 70/O arrested/O ./O
Rebiya/U_PERSON Kadeer/U_PERSON ,/O leader/O of/O the/O Congress/U_ORGANIZATION ,/O responding/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O accusations/O states/O that/O the/O real/O terrorists/O are/O the/O Chinese/O leaders/O ./O
The/O massive/O police/O presence/O is/O visible/O only/O at/O the/O Nuerbage/U_LOCATION police/O station/O ,/O site/O of/O the/O clashes/O ,/O and/O around/O some/O government/O offices/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION insists/O that/O it/O was/O a/O terrorist/O attack/O ,/O by/O assailants/O armed/O with/O knives/O ,/O axes/O and/O Molotov/O cocktails/O praising/O ``/O Allah/O the/O one/O God/O ''/O and/O invoking/O ``/O holy/O war/O ''/O ,/O brandishing/O banners/O with/O extremist/O slogans/O ,/O with/O 18/O deaths/O -LRB-/O 14/O protesters/O ,/O 2/O policemen/O and/O 2/O civilians/O -RRB-/O and/O 4/O terrorists/O arrested/O ./O
The/O head/O of/O the/O local/O police/O station/O Abulaiti/U_PERSON Maitiniyazi/U_PERSON claims/O the/O attackers/O were/O almost/O all/O from/O out/O of/O town/O ./O
But/O the/O Congress/U_ORGANIZATION reports/O that/O the/O police/O opened/O fire/O on/O unarmed/O peaceful/O protesters/O who/O then/O reacted/O and/O they/O accused/O the/O police/O of/O premeditated/O killing/O ./O
It/O explains/O that/O the/O demonstrators/O were/O protesting/O against/O an/O unjust/O expropriation/O of/O their/O land/O and/O demanding/O news/O of/O their/O relatives/O who/O ``/O disappeared/O ''/O during/O the/O ethnic/O violence/O of/O July/O 2009/O ./O
Rebiya/U_PERSON Kadeer/U_PERSON ,/O Uyghur/O leaders/O imprisoned/O in/O China/LOCATION for/O years/O for/O crimes/O of/O opinion/O and/O forced/O into/O exile/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O denies/O both/O the/O terrorist/O plot/O ,/O because/O of/O the/O Uyghurs/O were/O armed/O and/O asks/O that/O ``/O the/O Chinese/O government/O stops/O this/O sort/O of/O terrorist/O activity/O against/O a/O peaceful/O people/O and/O respects/O the/O culture/O and/O national/O identity/O of/O the/O Uyghurs/O ./O ''/O
``/O China/LOCATION -/O she/O adds/O -/O has/O no/O right/O to/O talk/O of/O `/O terrorist/O attacks/O '/O ,/O until/O it/O allows/O its/O citizens/O freedom/O of/O speech/O and/O assembly/O ./O ''/O
``/O Finally/O ,/O China/LOCATION should/O cease/O arbitrary/O detention/O ,/O unfair/O executions/O and/O torture/O in/O prison/O ./O ''/O
Kadeer/U_PERSON speaks/O of/O a/O region/O ready/O to/O explode/O ,/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O which/O robs/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION of/O oil/O and/O other/O natural/O resources/O ,/O encouraging/O the/O immigration/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O who/O occupy/O positions/O of/O power/O and/O appling/O strict/O control/O measures/O ,/O with/O bans/O and/O arrests/O even/O against/O the/O practice/O and/O teaching/O of/O the/O Islamic/O religion/O ./O
``/O The/O Uyghurs/O --/O she/O concludes/O ,/O speaking/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Free/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION -/O have/O no/O rights/O ,/O no/O job/O ,/O no/O money/O ,/O so/O they/O have/O nothing/O to/O lose/O ./O ''/O
Ethnic/O clashes/O erupted/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION between/O the/O native/O Uyghurs/O and/O Han/O immigrants/O ,/O in/O July/O 2009/O ,/O which/O caused/O at/O least/O 200/O deaths/O ./O
Since/O then/O the/O region/O has/O been/O guarded/O by/O police/O ,/O who/O often/O speak/O of/O having/O to/O act/O against/O Islamic/O extremists/O ,/O while/O Uyghur/O sources/O speak/O of/O systematic/O abuse/O ./O
