Xinhua/ORGANIZATION does/O not/O report/O reasons/O for/O the/O clashes/O ./O
The/O World/U_ORGANIZATION Uyghur/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION say/O clashes/O sparked/O by/O Uyghurs/O frustration/O ,/O colonized/O and/O oppressed/O by/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O
For/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O groups/O are/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O and/O this/O slows/O the/O spread/O of/O Islam/O among/O the/O young/O ./O
The/O Uyghurs/O accuse/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O wanting/O to/O destroy/O their/O culture/O and/O faith/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O
Twelve/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O clashes/O between/O Uyghur/O demonstrators/O and/O police/O in/O Yecheng/U_LOCATION ,/O 250/O km/O south-east/O of/O Kashgar/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION -RRB-/O ./O
The/O clash/O took/O place/O yesterday/O at/O about/O 18/O -LRB-/O local/O time/O -RRB-/O ./O
Xinhua/ORGANIZATION did/O not/O report/O the/O reasons/O for/O the/O revolt/O and/O says/O only/O that/O the/O Uighurs/O were/O ``/O violent/O ''/O and/O ``/O armed/O with/O knives/O ,/O ''/O a/O local/O newspaper/O called/O them/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O ./O
The/O World/U_ORGANIZATION Uyghur/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION ,/O based/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O says/O that/O according/O to/O local/O sources/O ,/O the/O group/O killed/O seven/O policemen/O and/O three/O civilians/O ,/O two/O of/O the/O assailants/O were/O shot/O at/O by/O police/O ./O
According/O to/O the/O organization/O the/O reasons/O seem/O the/O Uyghur/O 's/O frustration/O ./O
They/O are/O banned/O from/O any/O public/O gathering/O and/O criticism/O of/O government/O policy/O ./O
The/O Uyghurs/O are/O a/O Muslim/O group/O of/O Turkish/O origin/O and/O account/O for/O 45/O %/O of/O the/O population/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
40/O %/O is/O composed/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O who/O arrived/O in/O the/O region/O as/O part/O of/O a/O project/O of/O colonization/O ,/O after/O a/O brief/O period/O of/O independence/O as/O East/U_LOCATION Turkistan/U_LOCATION ./O
China/LOCATION wants/O to/O prevent/O the/O population/O ,/O whose/O territory/O is/O rich/O in/O oil/O and/O gas/O ,/O creating/O an/O independent/O state/O ./O
The/O Uyghurs/O instead/O demand/O greater/O independence/O from/O the/O Han/O who/O dominate/O the/O economy/O and/O politics/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
In/O July/O 2009/O a/O series/O of/O initially/O peaceful/O demonstrations/O in/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ,/O turned/O into/O clashes/O with/O police/O and/O conflicts/O between/O Uyghurs/O and/O Han/O ,/O causing/O hundreds/O of/O deaths/O ./O
Clashes/O also/O took/O place/O last/O summer/O in/O the/O city/O of/O Hotan/U_LOCATION ,/O where/O groups/O of/O Uyghurs/O raided/O a/O police/O headquarters/O ./O
China/LOCATION accuses/O the/O Uyghurs/O of/O terrorism/O and/O controls/O the/O situation/O with/O an/O iron/O fist/O ./O
And/O because/O the/O Uyghur/O are/O Muslims/O ,/O it/O also/O controls/O the/O mosques/O ,/O Koranic/O schools/O and/O slows/O the/O spread/O of/O the/O Islamic/O faith/O among/O young/O people/O ./O
The/O Uyghurs/O accuse/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O wanting/O to/O destroy/O their/O culture/O and/O faith/O ./O
This/O is/O enough/O to/O justify/O a/O new/O clash/O of/O growth/O controls/O and/O security/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O in/O the/O preparation/O for/O the/O Beijing/ORGANIZATION National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O parliament/O which/O meets/O once/O a/O year/O ./O
