Six/O Uyghurs/O were/O arrested/O last/O Friday/O accused/O of/O trying/O to/O hijack/O a/O plane/O ./O
Two/O have/O died/O under/O police/O guard/O ./O
Uyghur/O groups/O based/O abroad/O say/O they/O were/O tortured/O after/O they/O got/O involved/O in/O an/O interethnic/O row/O ./O
The/O ``/O authorities/O captured/O six/O people/O and/O had/O a/O chance/O to/O bring/O them/O to/O court/O to/O show/O what/O really/O happened/O in/O the/O incident/O ./O
If/O China/LOCATION were/O a/O country/O ruled/O by/O law/O ,/O they/O could/O have/O done/O this/O ./O ''/O
Urumqi/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O
Two/O of/O the/O six/O Uyghur/O men/O who/O allegedly/O tried/O to/O hijack/O a/O plane/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O troubled/O northwestern/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION region/O have/O died/O in/O hospital/O under/O police/O guard/O from/O the/O injuries/O they/O sustained/O when/O passengers/O subdued/O them/O ./O
Exile/O groups/O have/O disputed/O the/O official/O version/O of/O event/O ,/O blaming/O torture/O instead/O ./O
According/O to/O Chinese/O officials/O ,/O the/O six/O tried/O to/O hijack/O a/O plane/O after/O it/O took/O off/O from/O Hotan/U_LOCATION airport/O bound/O for/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ,/O in/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION Autonomous/U_LOCATION Region/U_LOCATION ,/O but/O were/O stopped/O by/O passengers/O and/O crew/O ./O
The/O plane/O returned/O to/O the/O Hotan/U_LOCATION airport/O and/O the/O six/O were/O taken/O into/O police/O custody/O ./O
The/O Germany-based/O World/U_ORGANIZATION Uyghur/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O WUC/U_ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O which/O monitors/O human/O and/O religious/O rights/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O has/O a/O different/O version/O of/O events/O ,/O saying/O that/O the/O plane/O turned/O around/O after/O a/O fight/O broke/O out/O between/O Uyghur/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O passengers/O over/O seating/O arrangements/O ./O
The/O ``/O authorities/O captured/O six/O people/O and/O had/O a/O chance/O to/O bring/O them/O to/O court/O to/O show/O what/O really/O happened/O in/O the/O incident/O ./O
If/O China/LOCATION were/O a/O country/O ruled/O by/O law/O ,/O they/O could/O have/O done/O this/O ,/O ''/O WUC/U_ORGANIZATION general/O secretary/O Dolkun/U_PERSON Isa/U_PERSON said/O ./O
The/O northern/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION has/O been/O a/O sore/O spot/O for/O China/LOCATION 's/O Communist/O government/O ./O
Since/O it/O was/O annexed/O under/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON ,/O its/O largest/O group/O ,/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O Muslims/O ,/O have/O sought/O to/O re-establish/O the/O region/O 's/O independence/O as/O East/U_LOCATION Turkestan/U_LOCATION ./O
Beijing/LOCATION has/O countered/O this/O push/O by/O a/O policy/O of/O total/O control/O ,/O banning/O the/O local/O language/O and/O preventing/O minors/O from/O attending/O mosques/O ./O
The/O six/O suspects/O -/O Musa/U_PERSON Yusup/U_PERSON ,/O Ababekri/U_PERSON Ibrahim/U_PERSON ,/O Ershidinqari/U_PERSON Imin/U_PERSON ,/O Memeteli/U_PERSON Yusup/U_PERSON ,/O Yasin/U_PERSON Memet/U_PERSON ,/O and/O Omer/U_PERSON Imin-are/U_PERSON all/O from/O the/O southern/O city/O of/O Kashgar/U_LOCATION ,/O ranging/O in/O age/O between/O 26/O and/O 30/O years/O ./O
The/O names/O of/O the/O two/O who/O died/O have/O not/O been/O released/O ./O
Various/O sources/O claim/O they/O died/O under/O torture/O in/O an/O attempt/O to/O extract/O a/O confession/O of/O terrorism/O ./O
On/O 1/O July/O ,/O Zhou/PERSON Yongkang/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O Political/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Legislative/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O condemned/O in/O a/O speech/O suspicious/O deaths/O in/O prison/O and/O the/O use/O of/O violence/O against/O detainees/O ./O
For/O him/O ,/O ``/O law/O enforcement/O must/O always/O and/O under/O all/O circumstances/O uphold/O the/O positions/O of/O the/O central/O government/O ,/O centred/O on/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ./O ''/O
