Search/O is/O on/O for/O two/O men/O from/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION and/O four/O cars/O with/O the/O license/O plates/O from/O the/O region/O ./O
It/O could/O have/O been/O a/O suicide/O terrorist/O attack/O ./O
Uyghur/O intellectual/O calls/O for/O more/O caution/O ./O
AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION sources/O :/O Not/O only/O the/O Uyghurs/O ,/O but/O entire/O Chinese/O population/O is/O tired/O and/O dissatisfied/O with/O the/O leadership/O ./O
Strong/O censorship/O on/O information/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O
Beijing/LOCATION police/O suspect/O that/O yesterday/O 's/O incident/O -/O where/O a/O car/O drove/O into/O some/O tourists/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O and/O then/O exploded/O ,/O killing/O all/O passengers/O -/O was/O carried/O out/O by/O Uyghurs/O suicide/O terrorists/O ./O
The/O incident/O occurred/O almost/O under/O the/O large/O portrait/O of/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON that/O dominates/O the/O front/O of/O the/O Imperial/LOCATION Palace/LOCATION ,/O a/O few/O dozen/O meters/O from/O Zhongnanhai/LOCATION ,/O home/O to/O many/O leaders/O ./O
The/O incident/O took/O place/O yesterday/O at/O noon/O and/O in/O addition/O to/O the/O three/O people/O in/O the/O car/O -LRB-/O an/O SUV/O -RRB-/O ,/O killed/O a/O further/O two/O people/O ,/O a/O Chinese/O man/O and/O a/O Filipino/O national/O ,/O leaving/O 38/O injured/O ./O
Police/O and/O firefighters/O have/O cordoned/O off/O the/O area/O from/O public/O view/O ./O
Today/O ,/O the/O English/O edition/O of/O the/O Global/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION ,/O part/O of/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O that/O the/O police/O have/O linked/O the/O incident/O with/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION and/O some/O Uyghur/O suspects/O ./O
But/O the/O Chinese/O edition/O does/O not/O mention/O anything/O about/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
Yesterday/O ,/O all/O day/O censors/O removed/O any/O news/O or/O comments/O about/O the/O incident/O from/O the/O web/O ,/O allowing/O only/O the/O official/O version/O of/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ./O
Last/O night/O and/O today/O the/O police/O launched/O a/O manhunt/O to/O gather/O information/O on/O two/O Uyghur/O men/O and/O four/O cars/O with/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION license/O plate/O ./O
Ilham/U_PERSON Tohti/U_PERSON ,/O a/O Uyghur/O intellectual/O ,/O writing/O on/O the/O website/O Uighurbiz.net/O ,/O pleaded/O for/O caution/O because/O it/O is/O easy/O to/O blame/O the/O Uyghurs/O and/O increase/O control/O over/O the/O ethnic/O minority/O ./O
The/O western/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION has/O been/O shaken/O by/O Islamic/O Uyghur/O nationalist/O movements/O for/O decades/O ./O
For/O the/O most/O part/O they/O seek/O greater/O autonomy/O from/O the/O cultural/O and/O commercial/O dictatorship/O of/O the/O central/O government/O that/O has/O colonized/O the/O region/O with/O millions/O of/O Han/O immigrants/O and/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O soldiers/O ./O
The/O settlement/O also/O involves/O religion/O :/O Islam/ORGANIZATION is/O strongly/O controlled/O in/O Uyghur/O schools/O ,/O mosques/O ,/O and/O society/O ./O
In/O the/O past/O there/O have/O been/O incidents/O and/O clashes/O between/O Uyghurs/LOCATION and/O Han/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O as/O well/O as/O attacks/O that/O the/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O branded/O as/O ``/O terrorist/O ''/O ,/O though/O often/O conducted/O with/O makeshift/O equipment/O -LRB-/O petrol/O bombs/O ,/O knives/O ,/O plastic/O ,/O etc./O .../O -RRB-/O ./O
The/O Chinese/O edition/O of/O the/O Global/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION today/O warns/O against/O ``/O politicizing/O ''/O the/O incident/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION too/O ./O
Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O site/O of/O the/O infamous/O massacre/O on/O June/O 4/O ,/O 1989/O ,/O is/O subject/O to/O a/O heavy/O security/O cordon/O to/O prevent/O even/O the/O slightest/O protest/O ./O
In/O China/LOCATION ,/O large-scale/O corruption/O d/O throughout/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION has/O led/O to/O over/O 180/O thousand/O ``/O mass/O incidents/O ''/O a/O year/O ,/O in/O which/O different/O groups/O -/O farmers/O ,/O workers/O ,/O retirees/O ,/O ex-military/O ,/O .../O -/O Clashed/O with/O police/O ,/O often/O violently/O ./O
A/O source/O for/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION said/O :/O ``/O The/O party/O is/O seeking/O to/O water/O down/O this/O incident/O ,/O but/O it/O reveals/O the/O profound/O dissatisfaction/O and/O fatigue/O of/O the/O whole/O population/O ,/O not/O only/O of/O the/O Uyghurs/O ''/O ./O
