Beijing/LOCATION confirms/O the/O wave/O of/O arrests/O that/O started/O in/O late/O August/O ./O
A/O farmer/O arrested/O for/O downloading/O books/O about/O separatism/O ./O
For/O the/O World/U_ORGANIZATION Uyghur/U_ORGANIZATION Council/U_ORGANIZATION ,/O it/O is/O an/O attempt/O to/O ``/O to/O suppress/O Uyghurs/O '/O use/O of/O the/O Internet/O ''/O ./O
Urumqi/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O
Police/O in/O the/O Chinese/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION have/O arrested/O 139/O people/O ,/O all/O ethnic/O Uyghurs/O ,/O for/O allegedly/O spreading/O jihad/O ,/O the/O official/O China/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION reported/O ./O
The/O wave/O of/O arrests/O began/O in/O late/O August/O and/O concerned/O people/O who/O used/O the/O Internet/O ``/O inappropriately/O ''/O ./O
A/O farmer/O in/O Hotan/U_LOCATION was/O detained/O after/O he/O uploaded/O e-books/O about/O secessionism/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION confirmed/O the/O arrests/O ,/O pointing/O to/O violent/O incidents/O in/O the/O region/O to/O indicate/O a/O rising/O militant/O threat/O among/O the/O ethnic/O minority/O ,/O as/O evidenced/O by/O the/O fact/O that/O many/O Uyghurs/O ,/O it/O claims/O ,/O fought/O in/O Syria/LOCATION 's/O civil/O war/O and/O then/O returned/O home/O to/O put/O their/O militant/O experience/O into/O practice/O ./O
These/O allegations/O ,/O however/O ,/O have/O not/O been/O backed/O by/O evidence/O ./O
Dilshat/U_PERSON Rexit/U_PERSON ,/O a/O spokesman/O for/O the/O overseas-based/O World/U_ORGANIZATION Uygur/U_ORGANIZATION Congress/U_ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION deems/O a/O separatist/O group/O ,/O said/O that/O the/O claims/O were/O a/O ``/O total/O distortion/O of/O the/O truth/O ''/O aimed/O at/O blocking/O Uyghurs/O from/O going/O online/O ./O
Those/O who/O were/O detained/O had/O only/O ``/O expressed/O discontent/O with/O Chinese/O rule/O and/O systematic/O repression/O in/O the/O area/O ''/O ,/O he/O explained/O ./O
For/O him/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O goal/O ``/O is/O to/O suppress/O Uyghurs/O '/O use/O of/O the/O Internet/O to/O obtain/O information/O and/O express/O different/O points/O of/O view/O ''/O ./O
Xinjiang/U_LOCATION province/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O
It/O is/O the/O homeland/O of/O ethnic/O Uyghurs/O ,/O a/O Turkic-speaking/O ,/O mostly/O Muslim/O people/O that/O has/O always/O sought/O independence/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
The/O central/O government/O has/O sent/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O to/O the/O region/O to/O try/O to/O make/O them/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O
It/O has/O also/O imposed/O serious/O restrictions/O on/O freedom/O of/O religion/O ,/O Muslim/O practices/O ,/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O indigenous/O language/O and/O the/O local/O culture/O ./O
Since/O 2009/O ,/O a/O special/O system/O of/O Chinese/O police/O and/O army/O control/O has/O been/O in/O place/O ,/O imposed/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION after/O the/O riots/O in/O which/O nearly/O 200/O people/O lost/O their/O lives/O ./O
As/O a/O result/O of/O the/O violence/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O people/O were/O detained/O and/O dozens/O were/O sentenced/O to/O death/O ./O
Chinese/O authorities/O have/O blamed/O the/O violence/O on/O Muslim/O extremists/O ,/O but/O exiles/O claim/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O ``/O exaggerating/O ''/O the/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O to/O justify/O the/O repression/O against/O the/O Uyghur/O people/O ./O
