The/O government/O blames/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O of/O using/O knives/O to/O stab/O people/O and/O detonating/O explosives/O at/O a/O railway/O station/O in/O the/O provincial/O capital/O of/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ./O
Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON ,/O who/O had/O just/O left/O the/O region/O after/O a/O four-day/O visit/O ,/O vowed/O to/O deploy/O a/O ``/O strike-first/O approach/O against/O terrorists/O ''/O ./O
Urumqi/U_LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O
A/O violent/O attack/O ,/O described/O by/O the/O authorities/O as/O a/O clear/O act/O of/O terrorism/O ,/O rocked/O the/O capital/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O northeastern/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION province/O last/O night/O ./O
The/O area/O has/O been/O seething/O for/O a/O long/O time/O with/O ethnic/O tensions/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O ,/O the/O indigenous/O Turkic/O Muslim/O population/O ./O
Three/O people/O were/O killed/O and/O 79/O were/O injured/O when/O a/O group/O of/O attackers/O used/O knives/O and/O detonated/O explosives/O at/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION 's/O south/O railway/O station/O ./O
China/LOCATION 's/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON had/O just/O concluded/O a/O visit/O to/O the/O region/O ,/O the/O first/O since/O his/O election/O as/O head/O of/O state/O ./O
Xinjiang/U_LOCATION 's/O local/O government/O said/O the/O attack/O began/O with/O an/O explosion/O at/O an/O exit/O of/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION South/U_LOCATION Station/U_LOCATION at/O around/O 7.10/O pm/O as/O the/O train/O from/O Chengdu/LOCATION arrived/O ./O
``/O According/O to/O initial/O police/O investigations/O .../O the/O attackers/O used/O knives/O to/O stab/O people/O at/O the/O station/O exit/O ,/O and/O detonated/O explosives/O at/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O ''/O it/O was/O reported/O ./O
The/O station/O was/O immediately/O closed/O ./O
In/O reacting/O to/O the/O incident/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O president/O called/O on/O local/O authorities/O to/O take/O ``/O decisive/O actions/O ''/O to/O ``/O suppress/O the/O terrorists/O '/O rampant/O momentum/O ''/O ./O
In/O Xi/PERSON 's/O view/O ,/O ``/O The/O battle/O to/O combat/O violence/O and/O terrorism/O will/O not/O allow/O even/O a/O moment/O of/O slackness/O ,/O ''/O and/O that/O ``/O it/O was/O essential/O ''/O to/O ``/O deeply/O understand/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION separatism/O ''/O ./O
The/O province/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O
Its/O Uighur/O Muslim/O minority/O ,/O who/O number/O about/O nine/O million/O ,/O have/O long/O sought/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O
The/O central/O government/O ,/O for/O its/O part/O ,/O has/O brought/O in/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O settlers/O to/O make/O Han/O Chinese/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O it/O has/O severely/O curtailed/O Muslim/O religious/O worship/O as/O well/O as/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O local/O language/O and/O culture/O ./O
Since/O 2009/O Chinese/O police/O and/O the/O military/O have/O held/O the/O region/O under/O a/O special/O regime/O ,/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION imposed/O following/O clashes/O that/O left/O nearly/O 200/O people/O dead/O ./O
As/O a/O result/O of/O various/O episodes/O of/O violence/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O long/O prison/O sentences/O were/O imposed/O and/O dozens/O of/O death/O penalties/O were/O carried/O out/O ./O
Chinese/O authorities/O blame/O Muslim/O extremists/O for/O the/O wave/O of/O violence/O ./O
Uighur/O exiles/O claim/O instead/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O ``/O exaggerating/O ''/O the/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O to/O justify/O repression/O against/O indigenous/O Uighurs/O ./O
For/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Uighurs/O are/O responsible/O for/O the/O recent/O spate/O of/O violent/O attacks/O ,/O including/O the/O 1/O March/O 2014/O attack/O at/O the/O Kunming/LOCATION railway/O station/O by/O knives-wielding/O men/O that/O left/O 29/O people/O dead/O and/O more/O than/O 150/O wounded/O ,/O and/O the/O 28/O October/O 2013/O incident/O when/O an/O SUV/O plunged/O into/O a/O crowd/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O then/O burst/O into/O flames/O ,/O killing/O three/O people/O ./O
