The/O police/O shot/O one/O of/O the/O attackers/O ,/O all/O armed/O with/O knives/O and/O sharp/O weapons/O ./O
No/O details/O on/O motive/O ./O
Episode/O follows/O attacks/O at/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION and/O Kunming/LOCATION stations/O ,/O government/O accuses/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION separatists/O for/O both/O ./O
Guangzhou/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O
At/O least/O six/O people/O were/O injured/O this/O morning/O in/O a/O train/O station/O in/O Guangzhou/LOCATION -LRB-/O southern/O province/O of/O Guangdong/LOCATION -RRB-/O by/O a/O group/O of/O men/O armed/O with/O knives/O ./O
The/O police/O shot/O one/O of/O the/O attackers/O ,/O according/O to/O information/O provided/O the/O city/O 's/O public/O security/O bureau/O ./O
At/O the/O moment/O there/O are/O no/O details/O on/O what/O happened/O ,/O nor/O the/O reasons/O for/O the/O attack/O ,/O which/O took/O place/O five/O days/O after/O the/O attack/O on/O the/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION train/O station/O ,/O in/O the/O western/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ./O
A/O picture/O published/O on/O the/O website/O of/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION shows/O a/O crowd/O of/O people/O evacuated/O and/O an/O ambulance/O at/O the/O scene/O ./O
The/O six/O injured/O were/O taken/O to/O hospital/O for/O further/O treatment/O and/O investigations/O are/O still/O ongoing/O ./O
This/O is/O the/O third/O attack/O in/O a/O train/O station/O in/O the/O country/O ,/O after/O the/O ones/O in/O Kunming/LOCATION and/O Urumqi/U_LOCATION ./O
Beijing/LOCATION considers/O the/O separatists/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION -/O home/O to/O the/O Uyghur/O ,/O an/O ethnic/O Turkic/O speaking/O peoples/O who/O profess/O Islam/ORGANIZATION -/O responsible/O for/O both/O ./O
The/O province/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION :/O The/O Uyghurs/O have/O always/O tried/O to/O gain/O independence/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O who/O in/O turn/O have/O sent/O in/O the/O millions/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O to/O try/O to/O make/O them/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O
In/O addition/O ,/O the/O central/O government/O imposes/O severe/O restrictions/O on/O religious/O freedom/O ,/O the/O practice/O of/O Islam/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O local/O language/O and/O culture/O ./O
