Charge/O laid/O by/O Xu/PERSON Hairong/PERSON ,/O regional/O anti-corruption/O chief/O ,/O certain/O that/O some/O high/O ranking/O members/O ``/O promote/O violent/O terrorist/O attacks/O ''/O in/O the/O region/O with/O special/O status/O ,/O to/O maintain/O economic/O benefits/O ./O
``/O Some/O Party/ORGANIZATION officials/O do/O not/O believe/O in/O Marxism/O but/O in/O ghosts/O ./O ''/O
Over/O the/O last/O two/O months/O clashes/O have/O increased/O between/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O the/O Muslim/O minority/O ./O
Police/O killed/O more/O than/O 40/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O in/O one/O week/O ./O
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O
Some/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION would/O support/O the/O terrorist/O bombings/O that/O have/O taken/O place/O in/O recent/O months/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O the/O Special/O Administrative/O Region/O in/O northwest/O China/LOCATION ./O
This/O is/O the/O charge/O laid/O by/O Xu/PERSON Hairong/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O anti-corruption/O department/O of/O the/O region/O ,/O who/O claims/O that/O some/O political/O leaders/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION are/O benefitting/O from/O the/O clashes/O between/O Uyghur/O separatists/O and/O the/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
Speaking/O to/O the/O state-run/O China/ORGANIZATION Dicipline/ORGANIZATION Inspection/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION ,/O Xu/PERSON said/O :/O ''/O Some/O communist/O cadres/O .../O even/O support/O or/O take/O part/O in/O violent/O terrorist/O attacks/O ''/O ,/O and/O added/O that/O they/O ''/O wavering/O on/O the/O big/O issues/O of/O opposing/O anti-separatism/O and/O maintaining/O ethnic/O unity/O ''/O ./O
Xu/PERSON did/O not/O give/O further/O details/O on/O the/O matter/O ./O
The/O Uyghurs/O ,/O a/O Turkic/O speaking/O Muslim/O ethnic/O group/O and/O the/O majority/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION ,/O are/O seeking/O cultural/O and/O religious/O autonomy/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
The/O Chinese/O central/O government/O ,/O however/O ,/O has/O made/O clear/O on/O several/O occasions/O that/O it/O aims/O to/O defeat/O ``/O at/O any/O cost/O ''/O the/O ``/O three/O evils/O ''/O afflicting/O the/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION :/O terrorism/O ,/O separatism/O and/O religious/O extremism/O ./O
Ethnic/O tensions/O in/O the/O region/O often/O result/O in/O violence/O ./O
On/O 18/O September/O ,/O some/O Uyghur/O rebels/O attacked/O a/O coal/O mine/O leaving/O 50/O victims/O ./O
On/O November/O 18/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION announced/O that/O it/O had/O identified/O and/O eliminated/O the/O leaders/O of/O the/O attack/O and/O their/O families/O ,/O a/O total/O of/O 17/O people/O ./O
Just/O a/O few/O days/O ago/O that/O the/O Chinese/O police/O killed/O another/O 28/O members/O of/O a/O Uyghur/O ``/O terrorist/O group/O ''/O ./O
The/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O of/O atheist/O ideology/O ,/O prohibits/O members/O from/O belonging/O to/O a/O religion/O ./O
This/O also/O applies/O to/O the/O Uyghurs/O ,/O who/O are/O banned/O from/O any/O public/O demonstration/O of/O their/O faith/O ./O
Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION schools/O and/O offices/O suppress/O the/O celebration/O of/O Ramadan/O ./O
According/O to/O Xu/PERSON Hairong/PERSON ,/O some/O officials/O persist/O in/O their/O beliefs/O despite/O the/O ban/O :/O ``/O Some/O are/O undecided/O in/O their/O ideals/O ,/O confused/O in/O their/O beliefs/O ./O
They/O do/O not/O believe/O in/O Marxism-Leninism/O but/O in/O ghosts/O ,/O and/O lack/O in/O loyalty/O to/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION ./O ''/O
