Bangkok/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/U_ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O
The/O activist/O Joshua/PERSON Wong/PERSON ,/O 19/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O most/O famous/O faces/O of/O the/O Occupy/O Central/O protests/O in/O 2014/O ,/O has/O been/O detained/O by/O Thai/O authorities/O on/O arriving/O at/O Suvarnabhum/LOCATION airport/O according/O to/O a/O statement/O by/O Demosisto/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O founded/O by/O Wong/PERSON and/O other/O students/O ./O
Wong/PERSON would/O set/O to/O meet/O university/O students/O ,/O at/O the/O invitation/O of/O a/O colleague/O ,/O the/O student/O activist/O Netiwit/PERSON Chotipatpaisal/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O waiting/O for/O him/O at/O the/O airport/O ./O
The/O decision/O to/O block/O Wong/PERSON was/O taken/O by/O immigration/O authorities/O ./O
Under/O current/O norms/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION residents/O can/O enter/O Thailand/LOCATION for/O 30/O days/O ./O
But/O in/O the/O case/O of/O Wong/LOCATION ,/O the/O authorities/O fear/O that/O he/O might/O trigger/O a/O series/O of/O pro-democracy/O demonstrations/O ,/O like/O those/O of/O Occupy/O Central/O ,/O which/O lasted/O nearly/O three/O months/O ./O
Wong/PERSON was/O set/O to/O meet/O the/O students/O of/O Chulalongkorn/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION to/O commemorate/O the/O 1976/O student/O massacre/O ,/O by/O the/O military/O junta/O of/O the/O time/O ./O
According/O Netiwit/PERSON ,/O the/O Thai/O authorities/O have/O ``/O received/O a/O letter/O from/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ''/O to/O stop/O Wong/PERSON 's/O activities/O ./O
The/O Demosisto/ORGANIZATION /O party/O is/O in/O favor/O of/O independence/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O which/O absolutely/O unacceptable/O by/O China/LOCATION ./O
Last/O May/O Wong/PERSON could/O not/O enter/O Malaysia/LOCATION ,/O where/O he/O was/O expected/O for/O a/O conference/O on/O democracy/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O
Then/O he/O was/O sent/O back/O immediately/O to/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ./O
It/O is/O likely/O that/O this/O time/O Wong/PERSON will/O return/O to/O the/O territory/O without/O being/O able/O to/O meet/O the/O students/O ./O
Thailand/LOCATION seems/O increasingly/O prone/O to/O serving/O the/O needs/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O
Last/O year/O ,/O Gui/PERSON Minhai/PERSON ,/O a/O publisher/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION critical/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O disappeared/O while/O on/O vacation/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O
Later/O he/O appeared/O on/O Chinese/O state/O television/O ,/O ``/O confessing/O ''/O that/O he/O willingly/O gave/O himself/O up/O to/O the/O authorities/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O
Gui/PERSON is/O one/O of/O five/O publishers/O who/O ``/O disappeared/O ''/O for/O a/O long/O time/O and/O reappeared/O with/O televised/O ``/O confessions/O ''/O about/O their/O alleged/O crimes/O ./O
Last/O year/O ,/O two/O dissidents/O and/O their/O families/O ,/O who/O had/O sought/O asylum/O at/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ,/O were/O sent/O back/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O
Many/O Uyghurs/O -LRB-/O Muslims/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O who/O fled/O to/O Thailand/LOCATION ,/O were/O repatriated/O ./O
