Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O
The/O information/O office/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O State/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION has/O recently/O issued/O a/O white/O paper/O claiming/O that/O Muslims/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION have/O freedom/O unparalleled/O in/O other/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O ./O
``/O No/O resident/O has/O received/O discrimination/O or/O unjust/O treatment/O based/O on/O their/O religious/O or/O lack/O of/O religious/O belief/O ,/O ''/O the/O paper/O says/O ./O
However/O ,/O analysts/O contend/O that/O discrimination/O and/O prejudice/O are/O the/O normal/O state/O of/O affairs/O for/O Muslims/O ./O
Xinjiang/U_LOCATION is/O one/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O most/O turbulent/O provinces/O ./O
It/O is/O home/O to/O about/O 9/O million/O Uighurs/O ,/O a/O predominantly/O Muslim/O and/O Turkic/O ethnic/O group/O that/O has/O always/O sought/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O
For/O its/O part/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O central/O government/O has/O pursued/O a/O policy/O of/O settling/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O the/O province/O to/O make/O them/O the/O majority/O and/O thus/O quell/O social/O unrest/O ./O
This/O has/O meant/O serious/O restrictions/O on/O religious/O freedom/O ,/O Islamic/O practices/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O local/O language/O and/O culture/O ./O
On/O several/O occasions/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O prevented/O or/O restricted/O Ramadan/O fasting/O ,/O banned/O beards/O ,/O raided/O mosques/O ,/O and/O searched/O the/O homes/O of/O Muslim/O clerics/O ,/O to/O monitor/O potential/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O ./O
Since/O 2009/O ,/O the/O province/O has/O been/O under/O a/O special/O regime/O giving/O extra/O powers/O to/O police/O and/O army/O after/O clashes/O left/O nearly/O 200/O people/O dead/O ./O
The/O crackdown/O that/O followed/O the/O violence/O resulted/O in/O hundreds/O of/O prison/O sentences/O and/O dozens/O of/O death/O penalties/O ./O
Chinese/O authorities/O blamed/O the/O violence/O on/O Muslim/O extremists/O ,/O but/O Uighur/O exiles/O say/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O exaggerating/O the/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O to/O justify/O repression/O against/O the/O local/O population/O ./O
None/O of/O this/O is/O true/O according/O to/O the/O white/O paper/O ,/O which/O claims/O that/O freedom/O of/O religious/O belief/O in/O Xinjiang/U_LOCATION today/O ``/O can/O not/O be/O matched/O by/O that/O in/O any/O other/O historical/O period/O ,/O and/O is/O undeniable/O to/O anyone/O who/O respects/O the/O facts/O ''/O ./O
Yet/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O ``/O lies/O could/O not/O cover/O up/O the/O truth/O ''/O about/O its/O openly/O restrictive/O and/O prohibitive/O religious/O policies/O ,/O said/O Dilxat/U_PERSON Rexit/U_PERSON ,/O spokesman/O for/O the/O World/U_PERSON Uighur/U_PERSON Congress/U_PERSON in/O Germany/LOCATION ./O
