Beijing/LOCATION and/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION have/O launched/O a/O week-long/O military/O exercise/O in/O south-west/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O two/O countries/O hope/O the/O joint/O drill/O will/O strengthen/O mutual/O trust/O and/O enhance/O their/O co-operation/O combating/O terrorism/O ./O 
The/O drill/O has/O been/O nicknamed/O ``/O Hand-in-Hand/O 2007/O ''/O ./O 
It/O is/O aimed/O at/O tackling/O what/O China/LOCATION has/O termed/O the/O ``/O three/O evil/O forces/O of/O separatism/O ,/O religious/O extremism/O and/O terrorism/O ''/O ./O 
The/O week-long/O exercise/O in/O the/O Chinese/O south-western/O province/O of/O Yunnan/LOCATION involves/O almost/O a/O hundred/O troops/O from/O each/O country/O ,/O who/O will/O all/O take/O part/O in/O mock/O combats/O against/O terrorists/O ./O 
Senior/O military/O officers/O will/O observe/O the/O exercises/O and/O assess/O the/O operational/O methods/O and/O capabilities/O of/O the/O two/O sides/O ,/O especially/O their/O capacity/O to/O deal/O with/O surprises/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O foreign/O ministry/O has/O stated/O the/O aim/O of/O the/O joint/O anti-terror/O exercise/O as/O being/O to/O ``/O strengthen/O mutual/O understanding/O and/O trust/O ''/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION and/O their/O two/O armies/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O to/O enhance/O their/O co-operation/O combating/O terrorism/O ./O 
Hong/LOCATION Kong-based/LOCATION defence/O expert/O Pinkov/PERSON explained/O there/O was/O ``/O a/O necessity/O for/O such/O joint-military/O exercises/O because/O both/O China/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION face/O potential/O threats/O from/O terrorist/O attacks/O ./O ''/O 
Both/O countries/O have/O volatile/O border/O regions/O and/O their/O governments/O are/O struggling/O with/O minority/O groups/O campaigning/O for/O greater/O autonomy/O or/O outright/O independence/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O come/O down/O very/O hard/O on/O Uighur/O Muslims/O campaigning/O for/O an/O independent/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION --/O Beijing/LOCATION says/O their/O so-called/O ``/O violent/O separatist/O activities/O ''/O must/O be/O defeated/O ./O 
Whereas/O the/O Indian/O government/O faces/O difficulties/O from/O separatists/O in/O its/O north-eastern/O region/O and/O also/O faces/O cross-border/O terrorism/O from/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION is/O China/LOCATION 's/O ``/O all-weather/O ''/O friend/O and/O this/O relationship/O has/O caused/O a/O great/O deal/O of/O tension/O in/O China-India/LOCATION ties/O for/O decades/O ./O 
But/O over/O recent/O years/O ,/O China/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION have/O taken/O efforts/O to/O develop/O their/O trade/O and/O diplomatic/O relations/O ./O 
Pinkov/PERSON explained/O such/O ``/O joint/O military/O exercises/O like/O this/O are/O necessary/O for/O China/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION to/O establish/O mutual/O trust/O ./O 
From/O the/O Indian/O point/O of/O view/O ,/O China/LOCATION gave/O more/O support/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION in/O the/O India-Pakistan/O conflict/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION has/O held/O military/O exercises/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O 
India/LOCATION realises/O that/O that/O after/O the/O nuclear/O contest/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION broke/O out/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O position/O became/O more/O neutral/O ./O ''/O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O this/O joint/O drill/O ,/O a/O lingering/O border/O dispute/O between/O the/O two/O sides/O has/O also/O been/O played/O down/O ./O 
Both/O India/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION lay/O rival/O claim/O to/O Himalayan/LOCATION territory/O ./O 
New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION says/O China/LOCATION occupies/O almost/O 40,000/O square/O kilometres/O of/O its/O territory/O ,/O whereas/O Beijing/LOCATION claims/O 90,000/O square/O kilometres/O are/O actually/O part/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
In/O 1962/O ,/O this/O border/O dispute/O was/O the/O trigger/O for/O a/O short/O but/O bitter/O war/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O ./O 
Although/O the/O dispute/O has/O yet/O to/O be/O resolved/O ,/O both/O China/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION think/O it/O should/O not/O be/O an/O obstacle/O to/O bilateral/O relations/O ./O 
Major/O General/O Afsar/PERSON Karim/PERSON ,/O now/O retired/O from/O the/O Indian/O army/O ,/O hailed/O the/O exercise/O :/O ``/O Earlier/O the/O two/O sides/O were/O always/O at/O war/O but/O this/O joint/O drill/O shows/O that/O they/O want/O to/O work/O together/O and/O it/O 's/O good/O news/O ./O ''/O 
However/O ,/O Karim/PERSON pointed/O out/O that/O the/O fundamental/O difference/O between/O the/O two/O Asian/O giants/O lies/O elsewhere/O :/O ``/O There/O have/O been/O some/O improvements/O in/O ties/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION ./O 
But/O we/O must/O understand/O that/O the/O problem/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O is/O strategic/O ./O 
They/O are/O strategic/O competitors/O and/O this/O has/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O the/O joint/O drill/O ./O ''/O 
The/O success/O of/O this/O week/O 's/O drill/O will/O determine/O whether/O a/O full-scale/O joint/O military/O exercise/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION is/O launched/O ./O 
However/O ,/O experts/O think/O it/O is/O still/O a/O long/O way/O off/O ./O 
