President/O Dmitry/PERSON Medvedev/PERSON met/O his/O Chinese/O counterpart/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON and/O the/O leaders/O of/O four/O ex-Soviet/O Central/O Asian/O nations/O in/O a/O bid/O to/O secure/O support/O for/O Russia/LOCATION its/O standoff/O with/O the/O West/LOCATION over/O Georgia/LOCATION ./O 
Medvedev/PERSON was/O in/O Dushanbe/LOCATION ,/O the/O capital/O of/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ,/O on/O Thursday/O ,/O Aug./O 28/O ,/O for/O the/O second/O of/O two/O days/O of/O consultations/O with/O his/O partners/O in/O the/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Organization/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SCO/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O as/O Western/O leaders/O renewed/O their/O condemnation/O of/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O diplomatic/O recognition/O of/O breakaway/O regions/O of/O Georgia/LOCATION ./O 
The/O SCO/ORGANIZATION was/O formed/O in/O 2001/O as/O a/O counterweight/O to/O NATO/ORGANIZATION 's/O growing/O influence/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
``/O If/O we/O are/O talking/O about/O SCO/ORGANIZATION 's/O move/O from/O an/O economic/O organization/O to/O a/O military/O one/O ,/O then/O this/O has/O already/O happened/O ,/O ''/O Alexei/PERSON Mukhin/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O Moscow-based/O Center/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Information/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O the/O DPA/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O ./O 
``/O All/O the/O member/O states/O were/O willing/O in/O response/O to/O the/O strengthening/O of/O NATO/ORGANIZATION ./O ''/O 
With/O Russian/O troops/O still/O in/O key/O positions/O in/O Georgia/LOCATION ,/O tension/O with/O NATO/ORGANIZATION mounted/O as/O a/O top/O Russian/O general/O accused/O the/O alliance/O of/O building/O up/O its/O fleet/O in/O the/O Black/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Can/O NATO/ORGANIZATION indefinitely/O build/O up/O its/O forces/O and/O means/O there/O ?/O ''/O 
Anatoly/PERSON Nogovitsyn/PERSON ,/O the/O deputy/O chief/O of/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O general/O staff/O ,/O asked/O at/O a/O Moscow/LOCATION briefing/O ./O 
``/O It/O turns/O out/O it/O can/O not/O ./O ''/O 
He/O added/O that/O 10/O of/O the/O Western/O alliance/O 's/O vessels/O were/O currently/O patrolling/O the/O Black/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION and/O eight/O more/O were/O on/O route/O to/O join/O them/O ./O 
Medvedev/PERSON 's/O defiant/O recognition/O of/O Georgia/LOCATION 's/O separatist/O regions/O of/O Abkhazia/LOCATION and/O South/LOCATION Ossetia/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O conflict/O erupted/O early/O August/O ,/O has/O led/O to/O a/O sharp/O cooling/O of/O diplomatic/O relations/O ./O 
``/O We/O 're/O not/O afraid/O of/O anything/O ,/O of/O a/O new/O Cold/O War/O ,/O ''/O Medvedev/PERSON said/O on/O Tuesday/O ./O 
``/O If/O our/O partners/O want/O to/O maintain/O good/O relations/O with/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O they/O will/O understand/O our/O decision/O ./O ''/O 
But/O the/O move/O provoked/O NATO/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O some/O European/O allies/O to/O demand/O a/O ``/O reversal/O ''/O of/O the/O decision/O ./O 
So/O far/O ,/O the/O presidents/O of/O Belarus/LOCATION and/O Syria/LOCATION are/O the/O only/O allies/O to/O support/O the/O Russian/O move/O ./O 
While/O Georgia/LOCATION is/O not/O officially/O part/O of/O the/O summit/O agenda/O in/O the/O Tajik/O capital/O of/O Dushanbe/LOCATION ,/O a/O Kremlin/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O said/O it/O was/O ``/O obvious/O ''/O that/O the/O issue/O would/O take/O center/O stage/O ./O 
Moscow/LOCATION will/O be/O pushing/O for/O judicial/O support/O ,/O namely/O from/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O promises/O of/O tighter/O military/O cooperation/O from/O eastern/O allies/O ./O 
Russia/LOCATION can/O not/O expect/O China/LOCATION to/O recognize/O Abkhazia/LOCATION and/O South/LOCATION Ossetia/LOCATION because/O it/O faces/O similar/O problems/O with/O restless/O regions/O at/O home/O ,/O analysts/O said/O ./O 
China/LOCATION had/O no/O comment/O Wednesday/O on/O Russia/LOCATION recognizing/O the/O independence/O of/O two/O rebel/O Georgian/O provinces/O ,/O continuing/O its/O policy/O of/O saying/O virtually/O nothing/O about/O the/O situation/O ./O 
Foreign/O ministry/O spokesman/O Qin/PERSON Gang/PERSON ,/O on/O Tuesday/O ,/O elaborated/O only/O slightly/O when/O asked/O about/O the/O Russian/O parliament/O 's/O passing/O of/O motions/O to/O recognize/O South/LOCATION Ossetia/LOCATION and/O Abkhazia/LOCATION as/O independent/O nations/O ./O 
``/O We/O have/O noted/O the/O latest/O developments/O of/O the/O situation/O ,/O and/O we/O hope/O relevant/O parties/O find/O a/O proper/O resolution/O of/O the/O issue/O through/O dialogue/O ,/O ''/O Qin/PERSON said/O ./O 
The/O ministry/O added/O that/O it/O would/O contact/O the/O media/O when/O it/O had/O more/O to/O say/O ./O 
But/O in/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O lack/O of/O criticism/O is/O being/O seen/O as/O tacit/O agreement/O ./O 
``/O But/O silence/O on/O this/O question/O will/O de/O facto/O mean/O agreement/O ,/O and/O ,/O more/O importantly/O ,/O China/LOCATION will/O move/O to/O block/O any/O economic/O sanctions/O against/O Russia/LOCATION within/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O Mukhin/PERSON said/O ./O 
The/O parliament/O 's/O motions/O preceded/O Russian/O President/O Dmitry/PERSON Medvedev/PERSON 's/O decision/O to/O formally/O recognize/O the/O two/O regions/O as/O independent/O on/O Tuesday/O ./O 
Following/O the/O government/O 's/O line/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O state-run/O press/O has/O given/O the/O issue/O scant/O attention/O ./O 
The/O ,/O the/O mouthpiece/O of/O the/O ruling/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O carried/O only/O a/O small/O article/O Wednesday/O on/O page/O six/O ,/O giving/O a/O factual/O account/O of/O Medvedev/PERSON 's/O decision/O ./O 
The/O ,/O which/O focuses/O on/O international/O affairs/O ,/O ran/O the/O story/O on/O its/O front/O page/O but/O with/O no/O commentary/O ./O 
China/LOCATION faces/O a/O dilemma/O over/O the/O Georgian/O issue/O ./O 
While/O it/O has/O close/O ties/O with/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O it/O is/O facing/O its/O own/O problems/O with/O groups/O pushing/O for/O independence/O in/O its/O Buddhist/ORGANIZATION region/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Muslim/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O competition/O for/O influence/O within/O the/O SCO/ORGANIZATION also/O complicates/O any/O potential/O for/O rapprochement/O ./O 
The/O two/O nations/O hold/O different/O visions/O of/O what/O should/O become/O of/O the/O organization/O ,/O with/O China/LOCATION aiming/O for/O an/O expansion/O of/O trade/O benefits/O while/O Moscow/LOCATION wants/O increased/O military/O cooperation/O ./O 
Kazakhstan/LOCATION and/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O which/O host/O both/O US/LOCATION and/O Russian/O military/O bases/O ,/O have/O looked/O to/O balance/O their/O Russian/O ties/O with/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION in/O recent/O years/O and/O are/O likely/O to/O find/O this/O a/O compromising/O position/O ./O 
The/O Kremlin/ORGANIZATION said/O in/O a/O statement/O that/O high/O on/O the/O summit/O agenda/O would/O be/O reviewing/O procedures/O for/O admitting/O new/O members/O ,/O such/O as/O Iran/LOCATION which/O holds/O observer/O status/O in/O the/O club/O ./O 
The/O move/O would/O snub/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O drive/O to/O isolate/O the/O Islamic/O state/O ,/O which/O it/O suspects/O of/O harboring/O a/O nuclear/O weapons/O program/O ,/O while/O moving/O closer/O to/O realizing/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O goal/O of/O knitting/O an/O anti-hegemonic/O alliance/O to/O counter/O US/LOCATION policy/O ./O 
