Only/O four/O days/O ahead/O of/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympics/O ,/O unknown/O attackers/O have/O killed/O 16/O policemen/O in/O the/O remote/O western/O Chinese/O city/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION ,/O populated/O mainly/O by/O the/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION minority/O ./O 
The/O police/O suspect/O it/O was/O a/O terrorist/O act/O ./O 
The/O attack/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION on/O Monday/O morning/O was/O the/O most/O serious/O incident/O of/O anti-government/O violence/O in/O China鈥檚/LOCATION Xinjiang/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION for/O years/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O official/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O ,/O two/O men/O ,/O arriving/O in/O a/O truck/O ,/O threw/O grenades/O at/O members/O of/O the/O Armed/ORGANIZATION Police/ORGANIZATION ,/O killing/O 16/O of/O them/O ./O 
Another/O 16/O were/O injured/O ./O 
Other/O sources/O have/O confirmed/O the/O attack/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O repeatedly/O accused/O Uighur/O Islamists/O from/O Xinjiang/LOCATION of/O planning/O and/O conducting/O terrorist/O attacks/O aimed/O at/O disrupting/O the/O Olympics/O ./O 
Chinese/O terrorism/O expert/O Li/PERSON Wei/PERSON says/O :/O ``/O This/O incident/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION was/O planned/O by/O a/O terrorist/O organization/O ./O 
Their/O attack/O was/O directed/O against/O the/O Armed/ORGANIZATION Police/ORGANIZATION which/O is/O upholding/O the/O stability/O of/O society/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Muslim/O Uighurs/O ,/O who/O speak/O a/O Central/O Asian/O Turkic/O language/O very/O similar/O to/O Uzbek/O ,/O have/O a/O history/O of/O resisting/O Chinese/O rule/O ./O 
In/O the/O 1930s/O and/O the/O 1940s/O ,/O there/O were/O several/O attempts/O to/O proclaim/O an/O independent/O ``/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION ''/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
After/O the/O Communist/O takeover/O in/O 1949/O and/O especially/O in/O order/O to/O exploit/O the/O natural/O resources/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O millions/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O immigrants/O arrived/O in/O to/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O Uighurs/O today/O account/O for/O only/O half/O of/O the/O population/O ./O 
The/O capital/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O for/O example/O ,/O is/O a/O mainly/O Han/O Chinese/O city/O ,/O whereas/O the/O old/O Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION oasis/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION ,/O close/O to/O the/O borders/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ,/O remains/O predominantly/O Uighur/O ./O 
Many/O Uighurs/O complain/O that/O they/O don鈥檛/O have/O the/O same/O job/O opportunities/O as/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O and/O that/O their/O language/O ,/O culture/O and/O religion/O are/O discriminated/O against/O ./O 
Critics/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O have/O long/O maintained/O that/O it/O is/O deliberately/O exaggerating/O the/O religious/O aspect/O in/O this/O ethnic/O conflict/O in/O order/O to/O discredit/O Uighur/O separatists/O ./O 
Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON ,/O the/O Sweden-based/O spokesman/O of/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O an/O organization/O of/O exiles/O ,/O claims/O :/O ``/O China/LOCATION has/O succeeded/O in/O misusing/O the/O international/O war/O on/O terror/O and/O the/O upholding/O of/O law/O and/O order/O for/O the/O Olympics/O to/O systematically/O suppress/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
And/O this/O continuing/O oppression/O has/O forced/O the/O Uighurs/O to/O take/O up/O militant/O ways/O of/O resistance/O ./O 
We/O don鈥檛/O want/O to/O see/O this/O happen/O ,/O and/O we/O are/O rather/O worried/O about/O this/O ./O ''/O 
It/O is/O extremely/O difficult/O to/O estimate/O how/O many/O Uighurs/O have/O actually/O taken/O up/O arms/O to/O fight/O Chinese/O rule/O ./O 
Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON is/O worried/O that/O the/O conflict/O will/O lead/O to/O more/O violence/O in/O the/O future/O ./O 
``/O The/O international/O community/O has/O a/O responsibility/O to/O immediately/O apply/O diplomatic/O pressure/O on/O China/LOCATION and/O force/O it/O to/O immediately/O stop/O its/O policy/O of/O systematic/O oppression/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O says/O ./O 
But/O so/O far/O ,/O Western/O countries/O have/O not/O shown/O the/O same/O desire/O to/O support/O the/O Uighurs/O as/O they/O have/O for/O their/O southern/O neighbours/O ,/O the/O Tibetans/O ./O 
This/O might/O be/O because/O the/O Uighurs/O lack/O a/O charismatic/O leader/O such/O as/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O ;/O but/O it/O might/O also/O be/O due/O to/O the/O fear/O that/O Islamist/O militancy/O could/O spread/O further/O in/O already/O volatile/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
