Germany/LOCATION is/O considering/O granting/O asylum/O to/O prisoners/O being/O held/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ,/O a/O government/O spokesman/O said/O Monday/O ./O 
The/O move/O has/O been/O welcomed/O by/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION as/O it/O works/O to/O close/O the/O controversial/O prison/O camp/O ./O 
Thomas/PERSON Steg/PERSON ,/O German/O deputy/O government/O spokesman/O ,/O said/O on/O Monday/O ,/O Dec/LOCATION 22/LOCATION Germany/LOCATION strongly/O backed/O Obama/PERSON 's/O plans/O to/O shutter/O the/O detention/O facility/O and/O said/O Berlin/LOCATION was/O assessing/O the/O possibility/O of/O accepting/O inmates/O who/O declined/O to/O return/O to/O their/O home/O countries/O ./O 
``/O In/O our/O view/O Guantanamo/LOCATION must/O be/O closed/O on/O legal/O and/O humanitarian/O grounds/O ,/O in/O terms/O of/O international/O law/O and/O human/O rights/O ,/O and/O for/O moral/O reasons/O ,/O ''/O Steg/PERSON told/O reporters/O in/O Berlin/LOCATION ./O 
Steg/PERSON emphasized/O that/O it/O is/O up/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION to/O find/O a/O place/O for/O inmates/O it/O did/O not/O want/O to/O accept/O and/O who/O could/O not/O be/O returned/O to/O their/O home/O countries/O ./O 
``/O We/O would/O need/O to/O ,/O and/O want/O to/O ,/O examine/O this/O issue/O when/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION has/O made/O clear/O what/O its/O specific/O plans/O and/O timeline/O are/O ,/O ''/O Steg/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O If/O we/O begin/O to/O review/O such/O closure/O plans/O and/O take/O a/O stance/O ,/O then/O it/O can/O only/O be/O in/O a/O European/O context/O based/O on/O a/O discussion/O with/O all/O member/O states/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O Germany/LOCATION would/O reject/O any/O ``/O side/O deals/O ,/O swaps/O or/O conditions/O ''/O put/O forward/O by/O Washington/LOCATION linked/O to/O handing/O over/O Guantanamo/LOCATION prisoners/O ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION said/O on/O Monday/O it/O welcomed/O moves/O by/O European/O nations/O to/O take/O in/O prisoners/O from/O the/O controversial/O prison/O camp/O which/O has/O prompted/O worldwide/O criticism/O of/O what/O are/O considered/O aggressive/O detention/O practicies/O and/O which/O has/O opened/O the/O US/LOCATION to/O allegations/O of/O torture/O ./O 
An/O opening/O from/O Germany/LOCATION and/O other/O European/O countries/O to/O take/O prisoners/O marked/O ``/O positive/O steps/O forward/O ''/O by/O governments/O that/O had/O been/O reluctant/O to/O help/O out/O in/O the/O past/O ,/O US/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Sean/PERSON McCormack/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O Many/O of/O these/O countries/O have/O previously/O been/O unwilling/O to/O work/O with/O us/O to/O either/O resettle/O or/O to/O ,/O in/O some/O way/O ,/O detain/O these/O individuals/O under/O circumstances/O where/O they/O wo/O n't/O pose/O a/O threat/O to/O others/O ,/O ''/O McCormack/PERSON said/O ./O 
US/LOCATION President-elect/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON made/O it/O clear/O last/O week/O that/O he/O wants/O to/O shutter/O the/O detention/O facility/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ,/O Cuba/LOCATION ,/O which/O holds/O 255/O men/O arrested/O on/O suspicion/O of/O fighting/O for/O al-Qaeda/O or/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Yet/O many/O of/O the/O men/O have/O languished/O in/O the/O detention/O center/O of/O the/O US/LOCATION Naval/LOCATION Base/LOCATION for/O years/O without/O being/O charged/O ./O 
About/O 50/O are/O now/O thought/O to/O be/O innocent/O ,/O but/O have/O not/O been/O released/O because/O they/O would/O face/O torture/O or/O death/O if/O sent/O back/O to/O their/O countries/O of/O origin/O ./O 
Yet/O many/O do/O not/O want/O to/O live/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Rights/O groups/O have/O calls/O on/O EU/LOCATION countries/O to/O offer/O asylum/O to/O Guantanamo/LOCATION detainees/O ./O 
German/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON has/O long/O publicly/O advocated/O closing/O the/O camp/O for/O terror/O suspects/O ,/O situated/O at/O a/O US/LOCATION navy/O base/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION ./O 
In/O a/O surprise/O move/O ,/O Hamburg/ORGANIZATION 's/O interior/O minister/O Christoph/PERSON Ahlhaus/PERSON signaled/O on/O Monday/O that/O his/O state/O might/O be/O willing/O to/O take/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION prisoners/O ./O 
Ahlhaus/PERSON told/O the/O newspaper/O that/O prisoners/O who/O were/O shown/O to/O be/O innocent/O should/O be/O given/O the/O option/O of/O coming/O to/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
Germans/O have/O been/O particularly/O interested/O in/O the/O plight/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O a/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
Germany/LOCATION has/O a/O small/O Uighur/O community/O ,/O many/O of/O whom/O live/O in/O Munich/LOCATION ./O 
Hamburg/LOCATION 's/O Ahlhaus/O and/O fellow/O Christian/O Democrat/O Guenter/PERSON Nooke/PERSON ,/O the/O government/O 's/O human/O rights/O envoy/O ,/O are/O among/O the/O first/O high-ranking/O German/O politician/O to/O publicly/O call/O for/O Germany/LOCATION to/O consider/O taking/O in/O some/O of/O Guantanamo/LOCATION prisoners/O ./O 
Even/O so/O ,/O both/O politicians/O have/O been/O careful/O to/O say/O that/O Germany/LOCATION should/O not/O become/O a/O dumping/O ground/O for/O unwanted/O prisoners/O ./O 
Ruprecht/PERSON Polenz/PERSON ,/O chair/O of/O the/O foreign/O relations/O committee/O in/O the/O Bundestag/ORGANIZATION ,/O pointed/O out/O that/O just/O because/O a/O country/O wants/O to/O ``/O get/O rid/O of/O someone/O ''/O does/O not/O mean/O that/O person/O would/O automatically/O qualify/O for/O German/O asylum/O ./O 
Yet/O it/O could/O be/O enough/O if/O the/O Guantanamo/LOCATION prisoner/O had/O previously/O lived/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O Polenz/PERSON said/O ./O 
