A/O growing/O number/O of/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION countries/O are/O reportedly/O interested/O in/O helping/O US/LOCATION President-elect/O Obama/PERSON meet/O his/O promises/O to/O close/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION by/O taking/O in/O inmates/O from/O the/O controversial/O detention/O camp/O ./O 
Throughout/O his/O campaign/O ,/O US/LOCATION President-elect/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON promised/O to/O shutter/O the/O controversial/O military/O prison/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ,/O Cuba/LOCATION ./O 
And/O as/O his/O inauguration/O day/O draws/O nearer/O ,/O European/O countries/O are/O trying/O to/O find/O ways/O to/O help/O him/O keep/O that/O promise/O ./O 
One/O especially/O difficult/O question/O Obama/PERSON faces/O is/O what/O to/O do/O with/O those/O inmates/O who/O have/O been/O determined/O to/O pose/O no/O threat/O but/O who/O would/O face/O persecution/O and/O possibly/O torture/O if/O returned/O to/O their/O home/O country/O ./O 
That鈥檚/O where/O a/O half-dozen/O EU/ORGANIZATION nations/O would/O now/O like/O to/O step/O in/O ,/O according/O to/O a/O new/O report/O in/O ./O 
Thus/O far/O ,/O only/O Germany/LOCATION and/O Portugal/LOCATION have/O publicly/O acknowledged/O their/O willingness/O to/O accept/O former/O prisoners/O in/O their/O own/O countries/O ,/O with/O a/O German/O ministry/O spokesman/O saying/O Monday/O that/O German/O Foreign/O Minister/O Frank-Walter/PERSON Steinmeier/PERSON has/O instructed/O officials/O to/O look/O into/O political/O ,/O legal/O and/O logistical/O aspects/O of/O the/O matter/O ./O 
Portuguese/O Foreign/O Minister/O Lu铆s/PERSON Amado/PERSON likewise/O promoted/O the/O idea/O to/O his/O EU/ORGANIZATION counterparts/O in/O a/O letter/O made/O public/O recently/O ./O 
``/O The/O time/O has/O come/O for/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION to/O step/O forward/O ,/O ''/O he/O wrote/O ./O 
``/O As/O a/O matter/O of/O principle/O and/O coherence/O ,/O we/O should/O send/O a/O clear/O signal/O of/O our/O willingness/O to/O help/O the/O US/LOCATION government/O in/O that/O regard/O ,/O namely/O through/O the/O resettlement/O of/O detainees/O ./O 
As/O far/O as/O the/O Portuguese/O government/O is/O concerned/O ,/O we/O will/O be/O available/O to/O participate/O ./O ''/O 
The/O German/O foreign/O ministry/O has/O indicated/O that/O the/O issue/O of/O taking/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION inmates/O will/O be/O discussed/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION in/O January/O when/O the/O Czech/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION takes/O over/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION 's/O presidency/O ./O 
Around/O 250/O prisoners/O ,/O including/O the/O alleged/O mastermind/O of/O the/O Sept./O 11/O attacks/O ,/O are/O currently/O being/O held/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ./O 
Charges/O have/O still/O not/O been/O brought/O against/O dozens/O of/O detainees/O who/O have/O spent/O years/O at/O the/O controversial/O facility/O ./O 
Some/O German/O politicians/O have/O warned/O that/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O offer/O to/O accept/O inmates/O should/O not/O be/O unconditional/O ./O 
Wolfgang/PERSON Bosbach/PERSON ,/O deputy/O head/O of/O the/O conervative/O Christian/ORGANIZATION Democrats/ORGANIZATION '/O parliamentary/O group/O ,/O said/O Germany/LOCATION should/O not/O be/O the/O first/O and/O only/O country/O to/O take/O in/O Guantanamo/LOCATION prisoners/O but/O rather/O be/O part/O of/O a/O European/O initiative/O to/O help/O the/O prisoners/O ./O 
He/O added/O that/O Germany/LOCATION should/O consider/O helping/O those/O persons/O who/O ca/O n't/O return/O home/O on/O humanitarian/O grounds/O ,/O if/O they/O faced/O the/O threat/O of/O torture/O or/O the/O death/O penatly/O ./O 
But/O ,/O he/O said/O ,/O the/O danger/O that/O prisoners/O pose/O ``/O should/O not/O be/O played/O down/O ./O ''/O 
Germany/LOCATION is/O particularly/O interested/O in/O a/O group/O of/O 17/O Uighurs/O ./O 
A/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O from/O central/O Asia/LOCATION ,/O the/O Uighurs/O face/O political/O persecution/O in/O their/O homeland/O China/LOCATION ,/O according/O to/O human/O rights/O groups/O ./O 
Germany/LOCATION has/O a/O small/O Uighur/O community/O ,/O many/O of/O whom/O live/O in/O Munich/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION however/O remains/O opposed/O to/O talk/O of/O European/O nations/O taking/O in/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
The/O government/O there/O wants/O to/O see/O the/O 17/O Muslim/O Chinese/O terror/O suspects/O returned/O to/O China/LOCATION if/O Guantanamo/LOCATION is/O closed/O ./O 
``/O The/O 17/O terror/O suspects/O imprisoned/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION military/O base/O of/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION are/O members/O of/O the/O East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O has/O been/O listed/O as/O a/O terrorist/O organization/O by/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Qin/PERSON Gang/PERSON said/O this/O week/O ./O 
``/O For/O these/O terror/O suspects/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O always/O requested/O they/O be/O sent/O back/O to/O China/LOCATION and/O firmly/O opposes/O any/O country/O accepting/O them/O ,/O ''/O he/O told/O a/O news/O briefing/O ./O 
Though/O the/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O have/O been/O cleared/O of/O the/O label/O 鈥渆nemy/O combatant鈥/O by/O the/O Bush/PERSON administration/O ,/O they/O have/O not/O been/O allowed/O to/O leave/O Guantanamo/LOCATION ./O 
The/O U.S./LOCATION government/O has/O said/O it/O can/O not/O return/O the/O Uighurs/O to/O China/LOCATION because/O they/O would/O face/O persecution/O there/O and/O in/O 2006/O ,/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION allowed/O five/O Chinese/O Muslims/O to/O be/O released/O to/O Albania/LOCATION ./O 
State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Sean/PERSON McCormack/PERSON said/O the/O Bush/PERSON administration/O understood/O China/LOCATION 's/O point/O of/O view/O but/O needed/O to/O ``/O assure/O ourselves/O that/O if/O people/O are/O transferred/O out/O of/O Guantanamo/LOCATION under/O whatever/O status/O that/O they/O are/O not/O going/O to/O be/O mistreated/O in/O any/O way/O ,/O shape/O or/O form.鈥/O ``/O At/O this/O point/O we/O do/O n't/O believe/O that/O it/O would/O be/O the/O right/O thing/O to/O do/O to/O transfer/O these/O individuals/O back/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O told/O reporters/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ./O 
