China/LOCATION has/O executed/O British/O national/O Akmal/PERSON Shaikh/PERSON on/O charges/O of/O drug/O smuggling/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O first/O time/O a/O European/O has/O been/O executed/O in/O China/LOCATION in/O 50/O years/O ./O 
Akmal/PERSON Shaikh/PERSON ,/O 53/O ,/O was/O executed/O on/O Tuesday/O ,/O bringing/O to/O a/O close/O a/O legal/O and/O diplomatic/O dispute/O that/O has/O strained/O relations/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O United/LOCATION Kingdom/LOCATION ./O 
British/O Prime/O Minister/O Gordon/PERSON Brown/PERSON said/O in/O a/O statement/O :/O ``/O I/O condemn/O the/O execution/O of/O Akmal/PERSON Shaikh/PERSON in/O the/O strongest/O of/O terms/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O appalled/O and/O disappointed/O that/O our/O persistent/O requests/O for/O clemency/O have/O not/O been/O granted/O ./O ''/O 
Britain/LOCATION ,/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O international/O human/O rights/O groups/O had/O called/O for/O clemency/O for/O Shaikh/PERSON since/O he/O was/O given/O the/O death/O sentence/O in/O December/O 2008/O ./O 
``/O I/O am/O particularly/O concerned/O ,/O ''/O said/O Brown/PERSON ,/O ``/O that/O no/O mental/O health/O assessment/O was/O undertaken/O ./O ''/O 
Shaikh/PERSON 's/O family/O had/O cited/O his/O history/O of/O mental/O illness/O in/O their/O appeals/O ,/O saying/O his/O condition/O had/O worsened/O in/O recent/O years/O ./O 
The/O father/O of/O three/O from/O London/LOCATION had/O become/O estranged/O from/O his/O family/O -/O when/O they/O had/O last/O had/O regular/O contact/O with/O him/O ,/O in/O 2007/O ,/O he/O was/O living/O on/O the/O street/O in/O Poland/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O official/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O reported/O that/O the/O court/O said/O evidence/O provided/O by/O the/O British/O was/O not/O enough/O ./O 
``/O The/O materials/O provided/O by/O the/O British/O side/O were/O insufficient/O in/O proving/O that/O Akmal/PERSON has/O a/O mental/O illness/O and/O that/O Akmal/PERSON 's/O family/O has/O a/O history/O of/O mental/O illness/O ./O 
Akmal/PERSON himself/O also/O did/O not/O provide/O such/O materials/O ,/O ''/O said/O the/O court/O 's/O report/O ./O 
Shaikh/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O said/O to/O have/O suffered/O from/O bipolar/O disorder/O ,/O was/O arrested/O in/O September/O 2007/O at/O Urumqi/LOCATION Airport/LOCATION in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O with/O four/O kilograms/O of/O heroin/O in/O his/O suitcase/O ./O 
His/O family/O says/O he/O was/O tricked/O by/O drug/O smugglers/O ,/O who/O promised/O they/O would/O help/O him/O become/O a/O pop/O star/O ./O 
Relatives/O say/O Shaikh/PERSON was/O unaware/O his/O luggage/O contained/O drugs/O ./O 
According/O to/O Reprieve/O ,/O the/O British/O legal/O defense/O foundation/O that/O took/O the/O lead/O in/O publicizing/O Shaikh/PERSON 's/O case/O ,/O the/O last/O time/O a/O European/O was/O executed/O in/O China/LOCATION was/O in/O 1951/O ./O 
Italian/O Antonio/PERSON Riva/PERSON was/O put/O to/O death/O for/O his/O alleged/O involvement/O in/O a/O plot/O to/O assassinate/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON ./O 
mh/mk/AFP/O //O ReutersEditor/O :/O Chuck/PERSON Penfold/PERSON 
