A/O plan/O to/O demolish/O the/O historical/O centre/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION in/O China/LOCATION 's/O westernmost/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O has/O drawn/O opposition/O from/O the/O Uyghur/O community/O ,/O which/O makes/O up/O the/O majority/O of/O the/O city/O 's/O population/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O government/O ,/O the/O buildings/O in/O the/O city/O centre/O are/O dangerous/O and/O thus/O need/O to/O be/O demolished/O and/O rebuilt/O ./O 
900/O families/O have/O been/O moved/O into/O government/O housing/O ./O 
Despite/O an/O influx/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O recent/O decades/O ,/O Kashgar/LOCATION is/O mainly/O populated/O by/O Turkic-speaking/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uyghurs/ORGANIZATION and/O other/O Central/O Asian/O groups/O that/O consider/O Kashgar/LOCATION as/O one/O of/O the/O cradles/O of/O their/O culture/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O old/O city/O 's/O demolition/O plan/O ,/O 49,000/O homes/O will/O be/O destroyed/O ./O 
Henry/PERSON Szadziewski/PERSON ,/O the/O manager/O of/O the/O Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Project/ORGANIZATION in/O Washington/LOCATION DC/LOCATION ,/O expressed/O great/O concern/O stating/O that/O Kashgar/LOCATION is/O one/O of/O the/O centres/O of/O Uyghur/O culture/O ./O 
``/O The/O destruction/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION old/O city/O would/O be/O a/O catastrophe/O for/O the/O maintenance/O of/O Uyghur/O traditions/O ./O 
Many/O of/O the/O residents/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION have/O built/O their/O homes/O and/O their/O businesses/O in/O the/O same/O area/O ./O 
So/O moving/O them/O out/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION old/O city/O to/O very/O regimented/O living/O arrangements/O ,/O roughly/O eight/O kilometres/O way/O from/O the/O old/O city/O would/O also/O remove/O them/O from/O their/O livelihoods/O too/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
Szadziewski/PERSON also/O doubted/O the/O official/O explanation/O and/O assumed/O that/O this/O was/O a/O move/O by/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O to/O assimilate/O the/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
Attempts/O to/O assimilate/O the/O minority/O group/O into/O the/O dominant/O Han/O culture/O date/O back/O to/O well/O before/O 1949/O ./O 
Gardner/PERSON Bovingdon/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O on/O Xinjiang/LOCATION politics/O at/O Indiana/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O said/O the/O demolition/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION 's/O old/O city/O showed/O familiar/O patterns/O and/O compared/O it/O to/O the/O destruction/O of/O the/O old/O Uyghur/O quarter/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION 's/O capital/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O which/O he/O witnessed/O in/O the/O mid-1990s/O ./O 
He/O said/O that/O it/O was/O ``/O aimed/O at/O transforming/O neighbourhoods/O that/O were/O under/O Uyghur/O control/O into/O neighbourhoods/O that/O were/O more/O susceptible/O of/O police/O control/O which/O is/O generally/O Chinese/O control/O ,/O more/O susceptible/O of/O scrutiny/O by/O the/O government/O and/O so/O forth/O ./O 
And/O I/O think/O those/O aims/O are/O important/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION as/O well/O ./O ''/O 
Gardner/PERSON Bovingdon/PERSON said/O that/O there/O might/O be/O some/O justification/O for/O arguing/O that/O a/O growing/O Uyghur/O middle/O class/O and/O economic/O growth/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION had/O satisfied/O some/O people/O in/O the/O Uyghur/O community/O but/O he/O thought/O that/O ''/O the/O more/O important/O explanation/O is/O that/O political/O oppression/O has/O increased/O in/O the/O region/O in/O the/O 2000s/O ./O ''/O 
Kashgar/LOCATION ,/O a/O traditional/O trading/O point/O on/O the/O ancient/O Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION ,/O has/O a/O long/O and/O interesting/O past/O with/O a/O history/O stretching/O over/O 2000/O years/O ./O 
Its/O beautiful/O setting/O in/O a/O fertile/O oasis/O to/O the/O north/O of/O the/O Pamir/LOCATION Mountains/LOCATION and/O on/O the/O western/O edge/O of/O the/O Taklamakan/O desert/O ,/O along/O with/O its/O ancient/O buildings/O has/O made/O it/O a/O major/O tourist/O attraction/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
Marco/PERSON Polo/PERSON recorded/O a/O visit/O in/O the/O 13th/O century/O ./O 
Chinese/O officials/O have/O commented/O that/O some/O parts/O of/O the/O old/O city/O will/O be/O kept/O for/O purposes/O of/O tourism/O but/O this/O will/O probably/O be/O only/O a/O very/O sanitised/O version/O like/O a/O kind/O of/O ``/O open/O air/O museum/O ,/O ''/O feared/O Szadziewski/PERSON ./O 
``/O This/O is/O a/O pattern/O that/O we/O see/O in/O other/O places/O in/O China/LOCATION where/O old/O parts/O of/O cities/O are/O destroyed/O and/O then/O some/O pieces/O are/O left/O ,/O so/O that/O tourists/O can/O benefit/O ./O ''/O 
At/O this/O point/O ,/O it/O is/O still/O unclear/O what/O exactly/O will/O take/O the/O place/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION 's/O old/O city/O but/O its/O original/O Uyghur/O inhabitants/O will/O certainly/O not/O live/O there/O for/O much/O longer/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Fritzi/PERSON TitzmannEditor/PERSON :/O Grahame/PERSON Lucas/PERSON 
