Thousands/O of/O people/O have/O started/O to/O flee/O Xinjiang/LOCATION in/O western/O China/LOCATION since/O ethnic/O unrest/O erupted/O in/O the/O region/O last/O weekend/O ./O 
Security/O remained/O tight/O in/O the/O regional/O capital/O Urumqi/LOCATION on/O Friday/O ./O 
Many/O mosques/O in/O the/O city/O and/O also/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION stayed/O closed/O ./O 
Exiled/O Uighurs/O all/O over/O the/O world/O are/O concerned/O about/O the/O safety/O of/O their/O family/O members/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
25-year-old/O Haiyur/PERSON Kurban/PERSON lives/O in/O Munich/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O biggest/O Uighur/O community/O in/O Europe/LOCATION --/O numbering/O some/O 500/O --/O is/O based/O ./O 
Chi-Viet/PERSON Giang/PERSON met/O him/O ./O 
Everyday/O ,/O Haiyur/PERSON Kurban/PERSON watches/O the/O news/O to/O get/O more/O information/O about/O the/O situation/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
His/O eyes/O are/O focused/O on/O the/O screen/O ./O 
They/O show/O anger/O and/O worry/O as/O he/O sees/O all/O the/O violence/O and/O chaos/O on/O the/O streets/O of/O Urumqi/LOCATION where/O he/O still/O has/O many/O friends/O and/O relatives/O ./O 
It/O is/O hard/O to/O get/O any/O information/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O authorities/O are/O trying/O to/O control/O all/O information/O coming/O out/O of/O the/O province/O ./O 
They/O have/O shut/O down/O web-pages/O ,/O blocked/O telephone/O lines/O and/O also/O jammed/O foreign/O radio/O and/O television/O programmes/O ./O 
Since/O Kurban/PERSON heard/O about/O the/O hundreds/O of/O Uighur/O protesters/O being/O arrested/O by/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O ,/O he/O has/O desperately/O been/O trying/O to/O contact/O his/O family/O --/O he/O does/O not/O know/O whether/O they/O are/O safe/O or/O not/O ./O 
鈥淎t/O the/O moment/O ,/O I/O am/O very/O concerned/O about/O my/O family/O ./O 
They/O live/O in/O the/O area/O where/O the/O mass/O arrests/O of/O protesters/O took/O place/O ./O 
It/O is/O very/O important/O for/O me/O to/O get/O in/O touch/O with/O my/O family/O ./O 
But/O unfortunately/O ,/O the/O telephone/O lines/O are/O always/O busy/O ./O 
Nothing/O works/O ./O 
There/O is/O no/O getting/O through.鈥/O There/O was/O a/O trickle/O of/O information/O during/O the/O first/O days/O of/O the/O turmoil/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O at/O the/O very/O beginning/O of/O the/O bloody/O riots/O ./O 
Kurban/PERSON was/O able/O to/O talk/O to/O a/O friend/O of/O his/O there/O :/O 鈥淗e/O was/O right/O in/O the/O middle/O of/O this/O chaos/O ./O 
He/O was/O not/O participating/O ./O 
He/O was/O there/O by/O accident/O ./O 
He/O described/O to/O me/O what/O was/O going/O on/O ./O 
He/O said/O that/O there/O were/O a/O lot/O of/O people/O screaming/O on/O the/O streets/O ./O 
Then/O police/O forces/O appeared/O and/O used/O tear/O gas/O ./O 
There/O were/O explosions/O --/O it/O was/O absolute/O chaos.鈥/O There/O were/O reports/O about/O dead/O bodies/O in/O the/O streets/O of/O Urumqi/LOCATION ./O 
The/O number/O of/O victims/O is/O still/O unclear/O ./O 
The/O Uighurs/O and/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O blame/O each/O other/O for/O the/O bloodshed/O ./O 
Haiyur/PERSON Kurban/PERSON 's/O daily/O routine/O has/O changed/O ./O 
He/O can/O not/O get/O the/O pictures/O of/O violence/O out/O of/O his/O head/O ./O 
He/O has/O sleepless/O nights/O because/O he/O can鈥檛/O do/O anything/O :/O 鈥淭hese/O days/O ,/O I/O fall/O asleep/O at/O three/O o'clock/O in/O the/O morning/O and/O wake/O up/O at/O seven/O or/O eight/O ./O 
In/O my/O dreams/O ,/O I/O see/O all/O kinds/O of/O chaos/O ./O 
The/O events/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION have/O definitely/O had/O an/O impact/O on/O my/O normal/O daily/O life/O ./O 
In/O the/O past/O two/O days/O ,/O I/O have/O only/O eaten/O once/O ./O 
I/O have/O just/O lost/O my/O appetite.鈥/O The/O riots/O seem/O to/O have/O stopped/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION boosted/O its/O security/O forces/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION to/O get/O the/O situation/O under/O control/O and/O imposed/O a/O night/O curfew/O at/O the/O beginning/O of/O the/O week/O ./O 
But/O the/O rift/O between/O the/O Uighurs/O and/O Han-Chinese/O has/O deepened/O even/O more/O ./O 
It/O seems/O likely/O that/O the/O already/O fragile/O relationship/O between/O the/O two/O ethnic/O groups/O will/O remain/O damaged/O for/O decades/O ./O 
Normality/O will/O not/O come/O back/O any/O time/O soon/O --/O neither/O for/O the/O Uighurs/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION nor/O for/O Haiyur/LOCATION Kurban/LOCATION in/O Munich/LOCATION ./O 
Author/O :/O Chi-Viet/PERSON GiangEditor/PERSON :/O Anne/PERSON Thomas/PERSON 
