Over/O 140/O people/O have/O been/O killed/O in/O riots/O in/O western/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Some/O 800/O were/O injured/O and/O dozens/O were/O arrested/O on/O Sunday/O night/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O state/O media/O said/O the/O numbers/O were/O likely/O to/O rise/O ./O 
A/O protest/O by/O Uyghurs/O in/O the/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O turned/O violent/O on/O Sunday/O night/O ./O 
It/O was/O the/O bloodiest/O incident/O that/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O in/O the/O autonomous/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O had/O seen/O in/O years/O ./O 
By/O the/O end/O of/O the/O clashes/O ,/O over/O a/O hundred/O were/O dead/O and/O hundreds/O injured/O ./O 
Some/O 3,000/O demonstrators/O had/O taken/O to/O the/O streets/O on/O Sunday/O to/O call/O for/O an/O investigation/O into/O a/O fight/O between/O Uyghurs/LOCATION and/O Han/O Chinese/O workers/O at/O a/O factory/O in/O southern/O China/LOCATION last/O month/O that/O left/O two/O people/O dead/O ./O 
There/O were/O eyewitness/O reports/O that/O police/O had/O opened/O fire/O and/O deployed/O armoured/O cars/O to/O disperse/O the/O protests/O on/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Square/LOCATION in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ./O 
Dozens/O found/O themselves/O behind/O bars/O when/O the/O police/O started/O rounding/O up/O alleged/O key/O figures/O ./O 
The/O government/O blamed/O Uyghur/O groups/O in/O exile/O for/O inciting/O violence/O ./O 
State/O television/O showed/O images/O of/O rioters/O setting/O fires/O to/O cars/O and/O clashing/O with/O police/O ./O 
On/O Monday/O ,/O the/O governor/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Nuer/PERSON Baikeli/PERSON ,/O made/O the/O following/O statement/O :/O 鈥淎fter/O the/O fight/O ,/O some/O people/O incited/O others/O to/O go/O out/O onto/O the/O streets/O ./O 
Groups/O inside/O China/LOCATION used/O the/O Internet/O to/O call/O people/O to/O march/O onto/O Urumqi鈥檚/LOCATION People鈥檚/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ./O 
Some/O people/O did/O this/O on/O Sunday/O evening/O and/O demonstrated/O illegally/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O there/O were/O riots/O ./O 
Some/O uninformed/O civilians/O were/O also/O involved.鈥/O The/O autonomous/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O in/O China鈥檚/O extreme/O west/O ,/O borders/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Tajikistan/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
Just/O over/O eight/O million/O of/O the/O 19/O million/O inhabitants/O are/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
Most/O of/O them/O are/O Muslim/O ./O 
Next/O to/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O the/O region/O in/O China/LOCATION where/O the/O local/O ethnic/O minority/O is/O most/O dissatisfied/O ./O 
Supposedly/O to/O combat/O separatism/O and/O terrorism/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O pursued/O a/O policy/O of/O mass/O immigration/O of/O Hans/PERSON to/O the/O region/O over/O the/O past/O 50/O years/O ./O 
The/O army/O has/O a/O strong/O presence/O ./O 
The/O local/O population/O claims/O it/O is/O discriminated/O against/O socially/O ,/O culturally/O and/O economically/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION rejects/O such/O complaints/O by/O branding/O the/O Uyghur/O activists/O as/O separatist/O terrorists/O :/O 鈥淭he/O Chinese/O government/O has/O been/O trying/O to/O portray/O us/O as/O terrorists/O for/O years/O ,/O 鈥/O explains/O Asgar/PERSON Can/PERSON ,/O the/O vice/O president/O of/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O Munich/LOCATION ./O 
鈥淟ast/O year/O ,/O they/O said/O they/O had/O discovered/O a/O terrorist/O training/O camp/O ./O 
They/O should/O call/O for/O international/O observers/O and/O prove/O it/O ./O 
We/O think/O that/O the/O Chinese/O government/O is/O just/O staging/O it.鈥/O On/O Monday/O ,/O Dilxadi/PERSON Rexiti/PERSON ,/O a/O spokesman/O for/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O also/O denied/O the/O government鈥檚/O accusations/O that/O the/O protests/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION had/O been/O orchestrated/O to/O incite/O violence/O :/O 鈥淭he/O official/O statements/O are/O unfounded/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O wants/O to/O justify/O its/O military/O measures/O against/O the/O Uyghurs/O who/O demonstrated/O peacefully.鈥/O He/O also/O called/O on/O China/LOCATION to/O officially/O apologise/O for/O its/O oppressive/O policies/O against/O Uyghurs/ORGANIZATION and/O insisted/O that/O their/O demands/O be/O heard/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O the/O authorities/O said/O they/O had/O the/O city/O of/O Urumqi/LOCATION 鈥渦nder/O control鈥/O on/O Monday/O ./O 
Police/O continued/O to/O patrol/O the/O streets/O ,/O which/O were/O largely/O empty/O ,/O as/O shops/O remained/O close/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Anne/PERSON ThomasEditor/PERSON :/O Disha/PERSON Uppal/PERSON 
