The/O official/O program/O of/O US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON 's/O visit/O to/O Germany/LOCATION has/O been/O cut/O to/O just/O over/O half/O a/O day/O ./O 
US/LOCATION officials/O said/O this/O was/O due/O to/O security/O concerns/O ,/O but/O some/O in/O Berlin/LOCATION suspect/O cooling/O relations/O are/O to/O blame/O ./O 
At/O a/O government/O news/O conference/O ahead/O of/O the/O US/LOCATION president/O 's/O visit/O to/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O ministerial/O spokespeople/O were/O inundated/O with/O questions/O about/O the/O program/O of/O the/O visit/O ./O 
Why/O wo/O n't/O there/O be/O a/O meeting/O with/O ordinary/O citizens/O in/O the/O eastern/O German/O town/O of/O Dresden/LOCATION where/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON begins/O his/O stay/O in/O this/O country/O ?/O 
Why/O has/O the/O program/O for/O his/O visit/O to/O the/O cultural/O city/O of/O Weimar/LOCATION been/O drastically/O cut/O ?/O 
Could/O it/O be/O that/O the/O relationship/O between/O the/O German/O chancellor/O and/O the/O US/LOCATION president/O has/O taken/O a/O dive/O in/O recent/O months/O ?/O 
``/O The/O relationship/O between/O the/O German/O chancellor/O and/O the/O US/LOCATION president/O is/O good/O and/O cordial/O ,/O ''/O German/O government/O spokesman/O Ulrich/PERSON Wilhelm/PERSON told/O reporters/O ./O 
``/O It/O became/O even/O closer/O in/O early/O April/O through/O the/O two/O leaders/O '/O intensive/O and/O successful/O cooperation/O during/O the/O G20/O summit/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O at/O the/O NATO/ORGANIZATION summit/O ,/O where/O a/O new/O secretary-general/O was/O elected/O ./O 
``/O But/O it/O 's/O not/O just/O been/O business/O talks/O like/O these/O ./O 
Merkel/PERSON and/O Obama/PERSON have/O had/O a/O number/O of/O private/O conversations/O too/O which/O have/O led/O to/O this/O very/O friendly/O relationship/O ,/O which/O ought/O to/O be/O a/O perfect/O basis/O for/O their/O joint/O work/O towards/O resolving/O important/O political/O issues/O ./O ''/O 
The/O US/LOCATION administration/O expects/O Germany/LOCATION to/O grant/O a/O new/O home/O to/O a/O number/O of/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O as/O the/O Guantanamo/LOCATION detention/O camp/O closes/O down/O ./O 
But/O German/O state/O interior/O ministers/O and/O particularly/O those/O from/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON 's/O Christian/O Democrats/O are/O not/O in/O favor/O of/O this/O ./O 
Also/O ,/O the/O US/LOCATION president/O may/O again/O press/O for/O more/O German/O soldiers/O to/O be/O deployed/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O not/O just/O to/O the/O relatively/O stable/O northern/O part/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
Again/O ,/O no/O one/O in/O the/O German/O government/O has/O signaled/O yet/O that/O this/O wish/O might/O be/O fulfilled/O at/O some/O stage/O ./O 
Carsten/PERSON Voigt/PERSON ,/O the/O government/O coordinator/O for/O German-US/O relations/O ,/O insists/O that/O differences/O in/O opinion/O do/O not/O necessarily/O have/O to/O lead/O to/O a/O cooling/O of/O relations/O ,/O which/O he/O said/O were/O completely/O intact/O at/O present/O ./O 
Nor/O does/O he/O believe/O that/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON still/O bears/O a/O grudge/O against/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON for/O not/O having/O been/O allowed/O to/O address/O Berliners/O near/O the/O Brandenburg/O Gate/O last/O year/O while/O he/O was/O still/O on/O the/O campaign/O trail/O ./O 
According/O to/O some/O political/O observers/O ,/O the/O official/O program/O for/O the/O president/O 's/O visit/O actually/O highlights/O a/O rift/O between/O the/O German/O chancellor/O and/O her/O foreign/O minister/O ,/O Frank/PERSON Walter/PERSON Steinmeier/PERSON ,/O who/O will/O not/O be/O among/O the/O team/O accompanying/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON ./O 
``/O It/O is/O a/O rather/O short/O visit/O by/O Mr/O Obama/PERSON ,/O and/O it/O 's/O correct/O that/O the/O German/O foreign/O minister/O is/O not/O taking/O part/O in/O it/O ,/O ''/O foreign/O office/O spokesman/O Andreas/PERSON Peschke/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O The/O minister/O himself/O has/O made/O it/O clear/O in/O a/O number/O of/O recent/O interviews/O that/O he/O does/O n't/O like/O people/O complaining/O about/O what/O and/O whom/O the/O US/LOCATION president/O will/O not/O see/O during/O his/O brief/O stay/O here/O ./O 
``/O People/O should/O rather/O be/O happy/O about/O the/O fact/O that/O Mr/O Obama/PERSON is/O visiting/O Germany/LOCATION for/O the/O second/O time/O within/O the/O short/O period/O of/O his/O presidency/O so/O far/O ./O ''/O 
Government/O spokesman/O Ulrich/PERSON Wilhelm/PERSON hinted/O that/O if/O one/O were/O to/O ask/O both/O Merkel/PERSON and/O Steinmeier/PERSON about/O their/O stance/O on/O important/O foreign/O policy/O issues/O ,/O there/O 'd/O probably/O be/O two/O different/O answers/O 鈥/O and/O that/O would/O probably/O not/O go/O down/O too/O well/O with/O the/O American/O guests/O ./O 
``/O Foreign/O policy/O has/O to/O be/O consistent/O and/O must/O not/O be/O broken/O up/O into/O different/O pieces/O ,/O ''/O Wilhelm/PERSON says/O ./O 
``/O By/O and/O large/O ,/O we/O 've/O been/O trying/O hard/O to/O convey/O a/O well-coordinated/O foreign/O policy/O approach/O to/O our/O friends/O abroad/O ./O 
So/O ,/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O foreign/O minister/O will/O not/O be/O talking/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION president/O directly/O should/O not/O be/O interpreted/O as/O a/O rift/O between/O him/O and/O the/O chancellor/O ./O ''/O 
Author/O :/O Hardy/PERSON Graupner/PERSON -LRB-/O sje/O -RRB-/O Editor/O :/O Jennifer/PERSON Abrahmsohn/PERSON 
