Inner/O Mongolia/LOCATION is/O part/O of/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION ./O 
Ethnic/O Mongolians/O there/O have/O been/O fighting/O for/O their/O right/O to/O keep/O their/O cultural/O heritage/O alive/O ./O 
Their/O most/O prominent/O activist/O is/O Hada/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O now/O gone/O missing/O ./O 
In/O 1996/O a/O Chinese/O court/O had/O convicted/O ethnic/O Mongolian/O dissident/O Hada/PERSON on/O charges/O of/O separatism/O and/O espionage/O ./O 
After/O he/O had/O served/O his/O 15-year/O jail/O term/O ,/O everyone/O was/O awaiting/O his/O release/O ./O 
He/O was/O supposed/O to/O return/O home/O last/O Friday/O ./O 
``/O We/O don鈥檛/O have/O any/O knowledge/O about/O his/O whereabouts/O ./O 
We/O have/O been/O in/O contact/O with/O two/O of/O his/O relatives/O ./O 
Until/O this/O morning/O they/O have/O told/O us/O that/O they/O don鈥檛/O have/O any/O official/O statement/O from/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O about/O his/O whereabouts/O and/O condition/O ,/O ''/O says/O Enghebatu/PERSON Togochog/PERSON from/O the/O South/ORGANIZATION Mongolian/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Information/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION based/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
The/O 55-year/O old/O Hada/PERSON has/O always/O tried/O to/O preserve/O the/O religious/O and/O cultural/O heritage/O of/O ethnic/O Mongolians/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
As/O a/O student/O ,/O Hada/PERSON campaigned/O to/O save/O the/O Mongolian/O identity/O under/O Chinese/O rule/O :/O which/O meant/O language/O ,/O religion/O ,/O traditions/O and/O customs/O ./O 
Corinna/PERSON Francis/PERSON from/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION says/O the/O situation/O in/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION is/O difficult/O :/O ``/O There/O are/O serious/O restrictions/O on/O freedom/O of/O expression/O ./O 
Any/O statement/O of/O cultural/O identity/O is/O taken/O by/O the/O authorities/O as/O a/O kind/O of/O separatism/O or/O extremism/O ./O 
They/O are/O discriminated/O against/O in/O terms/O of/O employment/O ./O 
The/O Mongolian/O language/O is/O at/O risk/O of/O being/O phased/O out/O in/O schools/O and/O the/O educational/O system/O ./O ''/O 
The/O four/O million/O ethnic/O Mongolians/O now/O form/O a/O minority/O among/O the/O eighteen/O million/O Han/O Chinese/O living/O in/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION ./O 
Many/O say/O that/O the/O Chinese/O government/O is/O trying/O to/O eradicate/O Mongolian/O culture/O by/O imposing/O Chinese/O culture/O on/O young/O Mongolians/O 鈥/O a/O strategy/O also/O used/O to/O assimilate/O ethnic/O minorities/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION in/O western/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Hada/PERSON opened/O the/O Mongolian/O Academic/O Bookstore/O in/O the/O region/O 's/O capital/O ,/O Hohhot/LOCATION 鈥/O a/O meeting/O point/O for/O activists/O demanding/O greater/O minority/O rights/O ./O 
In/O 1992/O Hada/PERSON and/O other/O Mongolian/O intellectuals/O founded/O the/O Southern/ORGANIZATION Mongolian/ORGANIZATION Democracy/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION ./O 
It/O was/O the/O only/O Mongolian/O organization/O of/O its/O kind/O within/O China.The/O organization鈥檚/O goal/O was/O to/O push/O for/O political/O and/O social/O rights/O for/O Mongolians/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O constitution/O nominally/O grants/O self-governance/O and/O autonomy/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O ethnic/O minorities/O ./O 
Hada/PERSON was/O arrested/O and/O his/O Southern/ORGANIZATION Mongolian/ORGANIZATION Democracy/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION was/O forbidden/O after/O a/O protest/O demonstration/O in/O 1995/O ./O 
Hada/PERSON should/O have/O been/O released/O on/O the/O same/O day/O that/O the/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O ceremony/O for/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON was/O being/O held/O last/O week/O ./O 
But/O he/O has/O n't/O been/O seen/O since/O ./O 
``/O Well/O ,/O some/O internet/O posts/O in/O Chinese/O say/O that/O Hada/PERSON is/O dead/O and/O that/O a/O dead/O body/O was/O found/O ./O 
But/O this/O is/O not/O very/O likely/O ,/O ''/O says/O Togochog/PERSON ./O 
To/O add/O to/O the/O confusion/O ,/O some/O photos/O were/O anonymously/O posted/O on/O the/O internet/O shortly/O after/O the/O supposed/O release/O to/O prove/O that/O Hada/PERSON is/O still/O alive/O ./O 
Just/O days/O before/O Hada/PERSON was/O due/O to/O be/O released/O ,/O his/O wife/O and/O son/O were/O taken/O into/O police/O custody/O ./O 
Their/O whereabouts/O are/O also/O unknown/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Chi/PERSON Viet/PERSON GiangEditor/PERSON :/O Arun/PERSON Chowdhury/PERSON 
