As/O politically/O and/O ethnically-charged/O violence/O continues/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O three/O powerful/O nations/O who/O have/O hugely/O important/O strategic/O and/O geopolitical/O interests/O in/O the/O region/O are/O becoming/O particularly/O concerned/O ./O 
The/O Central/O Asian/O nation/O 's/O worst/O ethnic/O violence/O in/O decades/O ,/O which/O has/O reportedly/O left/O at/O least/O 179/O people/O dead/O ,/O many/O more/O injured/O and/O has/O forced/O tens/O of/O thousands/O to/O flee/O their/O homes/O ,/O has/O wider/O implications/O in/O a/O region/O full/O of/O strategic/O and/O geopolitical/O importance/O for/O the/O world/O 's/O biggest/O powers/O ./O 
The/O violence/O that/O erupted/O on/O Friday/O between/O Kyrgyz/O and/O Uzbek/O clans/O may/O have/O been/O ignited/O by/O the/O escalating/O tensions/O between/O the/O country/O 's/O two/O dominant/O ethnic/O groups/O but/O the/O conditions/O for/O the/O fighting/O have/O been/O created/O by/O the/O on-going/O unstable/O political/O situation/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ;/O a/O situation/O that/O has/O the/O fingerprints/O of/O the/O world/O 's/O most/O influential/O nations/O all/O over/O it/O ./O 
Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION 's/O wider/O role/O in/O international/O affairs/O is/O such/O that/O Russia/LOCATION and/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION continue/O to/O jostle/O for/O military/O influence/O there/O while/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O shares/O a/O 530-mile/O border/O with/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O pursues/O significant/O strategic/O and/O economic/O interests/O in/O the/O country/O and/O its/O surrounding/O region/O ./O 
This/O most/O recent/O uprising/O stems/O from/O the/O ousting/O of/O the/O Washington-friendly/O regime/O of/O President/O Kurmanbek/PERSON Bakiyev/PERSON in/O April/O which/O left/O the/O country/O in/O turmoil/O ./O 
Bakiyev/PERSON 's/O removal/O from/O power/O and/O the/O rise/O to/O power/O of/O the/O current/O provisional/O government/O has/O not/O only/O allowed/O ethnic/O tensions/O to/O reach/O boiling/O point/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION but/O could/O trigger/O a/O new/O struggle/O for/O proxy/O control/O of/O the/O country/O and/O the/O regional/O benefits/O which/O come/O with/O it/O ./O 
Bakiyev/PERSON 's/O installation/O as/O president/O in/O 2005/O with/O US/LOCATION backing/O may/O have/O provided/O Washington/LOCATION with/O a/O friendly/O government/O with/O whom/O to/O do/O business/O with/O but/O it/O also/O gave/O the/O US/LOCATION a/O significant/O foothold/O in/O a/O country/O that/O some/O strategists/O believe/O is/O paramount/O to/O its/O plans/O for/O regional/O dominance/O ./O 
Experts/O say/O that/O it/O has/O been/O a/O prime/O US/LOCATION strategic/O objective/O to/O increase/O its/O influence/O in/O the/O former/O Soviet/O states/O of/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION since/O the/O collapse/O of/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION in/O 1991/O ./O 
The/O inclusion/O of/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION and/O three/O other/O central/O Asian/O states/O in/O NATO/ORGANIZATION 's/O Partnership/O for/O Peace/O program/O in/O 1994/O ,/O was/O seen/O as/O a/O major/O step/O toward/O increasing/O US/LOCATION military/O presence/O in/O the/O region/O which/O eventually/O led/O to/O the/O US/LOCATION base/O at/O Manas/LOCATION ,/O outside/O Bishkek/LOCATION in/O the/O north/O ,/O being/O established/O ./O 
``/O During/O the/O April/O unrest/O ,/O the/O US/LOCATION Manas/ORGANIZATION Airbase/ORGANIZATION was/O closed/O and/O the/O vital/O supply/O route/O for/O sending/O military/O hardware/O and/O troops/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION was/O not/O being/O used/O ,/O ''/O Asher/PERSON Pirt/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O on/O Central/O Asian/O affairs/O and/O military/O issues/O ,/O told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O The/O US/LOCATION needs/O a/O stable/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION in/O order/O to/O keep/O the/O supply/O route/O working/O ./O ''/O 
``/O There/O is/O also/O the/O possibility/O of/O Uzbek/O intervention/O in/O the/O restive/O Osh/LOCATION region/O due/O to/O the/O fact/O that/O Uzbeks/O are/O being/O killed/O and/O hurt/O in/O the/O violence/O and/O any/O such/O intervention/O is/O likely/O to/O lead/O to/O further/O instability/O and/O will/O continue/O cause/O problems/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION principle/O supply/O route/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O its/O troops/O deployed/O there/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
``/O Another/O issue/O is/O if/O the/O instability/O spreads/O throughout/O the/O rest/O of/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O there/O is/O a/O rise/O of/O Islamic/O extremism/O this/O could/O significantly/O affect/O US/LOCATION interests/O in/O the/O region/O ./O ''/O 
While/O Manas/PERSON remains/O a/O key/O hub/O for/O US/LOCATION operations/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O it/O is/O also/O used/O as/O a/O NATO/ORGANIZATION base/O -/O a/O situation/O which/O angers/O and/O concerns/O Russia/LOCATION which/O fears/O the/O eastern/O enlargement/O of/O its/O former/O Cold/O War/O opponent/O ,/O putting/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION at/O the/O center/O of/O a/O power/O struggle/O for/O regional/O influence/O ./O 
``/O The/O current/O unrest/O is/O a/O major/O threat/O to/O the/O authority/O of/O the/O Kyrgyz/O government/O ,/O ''/O Dex/ORGANIZATION Torrike-Barton/ORGANIZATION ,/O an/O international/O security/O analyst/O ,/O told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION from/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O The/O provisional/O government/O is/O still/O very/O weak/O ./O 
If/O violence/O spreads/O beyond/O the/O cities/O currently/O affected/O ,/O then/O we/O could/O see/O major/O political/O instability/O ./O 
In/O that/O context/O ,/O all/O bets/O are/O off/O the/O table/O on/O whether/O the/O US/LOCATION can/O retain/O its/O airbase/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
There/O are/O plenty/O of/O political/O factions/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION who/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O see/O the/O Americans/O keep/O any/O sort/O of/O foothold/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
If/O Russia/LOCATION or/O the/O Collective/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Treaty/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION -/O the/O regional/O defence/O alliance/O -/O ultimately/O ends/O up/O intervening/O ,/O the/O same/O result/O is/O likely/O ./O ''/O 
Russia/LOCATION ,/O which/O itself/O has/O its/O own/O military/O base/O at/O the/O Kant/O airbase/O near/O Bishkek/LOCATION and/O a/O strategic/O naval/O base/O on/O Lake/LOCATION Issyk-Kul/LOCATION ,/O is/O highly/O suspicious/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION '/O interest/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION and/O the/O wider/O Eurasian/O region/O ./O 
Since/O the/O US-backed/O Bakiyev/PERSON regime/O was/O ousted/O in/O April/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION has/O unsurprisingly/O been/O the/O biggest/O supporter/O of/O the/O new/O provisional/O government/O ,/O presumably/O in/O the/O hope/O that/O if/O order/O is/O restored/O the/O swing/O of/O influence/O will/O return/O to/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
Washington/LOCATION 's/O plans/O for/O the/O regions/O sit/O very/O uncomfortably/O with/O the/O Kremlin/LOCATION ./O 
While/O the/O US/LOCATION may/O justify/O that/O its/O increased/O influence/O is/O mutually/O beneficial/O by/O claiming/O its/O presence/O will/O help/O stop/O the/O spread/O of/O Islamic/O fundamentalism/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O solve/O the/O hugely/O destabilizing/O problem/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION believes/O the/O US/LOCATION has/O another/O agenda/O ./O 
The/O Kremlin/ORGANIZATION says/O that/O Washington/LOCATION is/O aiming/O to/O prevent/O Russian/O and/or/O Chinese/O hegemony/O while/O securing/O energy/O resources/O and/O pipelines/O ./O 
