As/O the/O situation/O remains/O tense/O in/O the/O capital/O Bishkek/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION has/O voiced/O its/O concerns/O and/O there/O has/O been/O speculation/O about/O the/O fate/O of/O the/O US/LOCATION air/O base/O in/O Manas/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O violent/O clashes/O in/O Bishkek/LOCATION that/O left/O at/O least/O 75/O people/O dead/O this/O week/O ,/O a/O five-storey/O Chinese/O shopping/O mall/O was/O also/O looted/O and/O burnt/O down/O ./O 
The/O estimated/O losses/O are/O of/O up/O to/O four/O billion/O US/O dollars/O -LRB-/O almost/O three/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Although/O no/O Chinese/O national/O was/O hurt/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION immediately/O issued/O a/O statement/O expressing/O ``/O deep/O concern/O ''/O about/O the/O political/O situation/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O a/O key/O market/O for/O Chinese/O goods/O ./O 
Patrick/PERSON Dombrowsky/PERSON ,/O the/O director/O of/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Research/ORGANIZATION on/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION in/O Paris/LOCATION ,/O explained/O that/O China/LOCATION ``/O was/O very/O attentive/O about/O what/O was/O going/O to/O happen/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ''/O ./O 
``/O First/O of/O all/O ,/O because/O it/O is/O a/O country/O ,/O which/O has/O a/O common/O border/O with/O China/LOCATION and/O secondly/O because/O it/O is/O an/O Islamic/O country/O ./O 
By/O which/O I/O mean/O Bejing/LOCATION fears/O the/O possibility/O that/O the/O Islamic/O movements/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION could/O grow/O as/O a/O result/O of/O the/O situation/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Some/O estimated/O 50,000/O Uighurs/O currently/O live/O in/O the/O central/O Asian/O country/O ./O 
They/O charge/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O with/O political/O suppression/O in/O the/O western/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O while/O Beijing/LOCATION accuses/O them/O and/O other/O Uighurs/O living/O outside/O China/LOCATION of/O being/O ``/O separatists/O ''/O ./O 
Another/O concern/O about/O the/O politicial/O crisis/O in/O Bishkek/LOCATION has/O been/O the/O controversial/O US/LOCATION airbase/O in/O Manas/LOCATION ,/O some/O 35/O kilometers/O away/O from/O the/O Kyrgyz/O capital/O ./O 
The/O base/O ,/O which/O has/O fuelled/O some/O tension/O between/O Russia/LOCATION and/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O has/O been/O used/O to/O relay/O supplies/O to/O NATO/ORGANIZATION troops/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
It/O became/O even/O more/O significant/O after/O a/O US/LOCATION base/O in/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION was/O shut/O down/O in/O 2005/O ./O 
Omurbek/PERSON Tekebayev/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O in/O charge/O of/O constitutional/O matters/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION 's/O new/O interim/O government/O ,/O recently/O told/O the/O international/O media/O that/O the/O base/O 's/O future/O was/O shortlived/O ./O 
He/O also/O stated/O that/O Russia/LOCATION had/O played/O a/O role/O in/O the/O ousting/O of/O President/O Bakiyev/PERSON ./O 
But/O Moscow/LOCATION has/O denied/O these/O allegations/O ./O 
Annette/PERSON Bohr/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O at/O the/O London/LOCATION based/O think/O tank/O Chatham/ORGANIZATION House/ORGANIZATION ,/O thinks/O there/O would/O have/O been/O little/O reason/O for/O Russia/LOCATION to/O fuel/O the/O present/O crisis/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ./O 
Nor/O does/O she/O think/O the/O country/O 's/O new/O leader/O ,/O former/O Foreign/O Minister/O ,/O Roza/PERSON Otunbayeva/PERSON is/O likely/O to/O shut/O down/O the/O US/LOCATION base/O in/O Manas/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Otunbayeva/PERSON is/O a/O very/O Westernized/O figure/O ,/O ''/O she/O explained/O ./O 
``/O She/O is/O a/O known/O quantity/O for/O us/O ,/O someone/O we/O know/O quite/O well/O 鈥/O she/O 's/O acted/O as/O foreign/O minister/O on/O three/O occasions/O and/O has/O served/O as/O ambassador/O in/O London/LOCATION and/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ./O 
She/O speaks/O five/O or/O six/O languages/O ./O 
She/O has/O a/O reputation/O of/O being/O a/O very/O clean/O and/O experienced/O politician/O ./O 
It/O is/O very/O unlikely/O that/O she/O would/O suspend/O the/O current/O agrement/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Otunbayeva/PERSON has/O already/O assured/O Washington/LOCATION that/O the/O base/O will/O remain/O open/O despite/O the/O change/O in/O leadership/O ./O 
However/O ,/O some/O observers/O think/O she/O might/O want/O to/O renegotiate/O the/O contract/O and/O ask/O for/O more/O money/O from/O the/O US/LOCATION in/O return/O ./O 
It/O is/O widely/O thought/O that/O if/O the/O base/O were/O to/O be/O closed/O down/O ,/O it/O would/O be/O a/O huge/O setback/O for/O the/O Western-led/O mission/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O especially/O with/O regard/O to/O the/O surge/O in/O troops/O that/O is/O expected/O later/O this/O year/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Disha/O UppalEditor/O :/O Anne/PERSON Thomas/PERSON 
