The/O Turkish/O government/O criticised/O Chinese/O policy/O harshly/O after/O ethnic/O clashes/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION last/O year/O ./O 
But/O recently/O Turkish/O Foreign/O Minister/O Ahmet/PERSON Davutoglu/PERSON visited/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O tone/O changed/O ./O 
The/O visit/O the/O Turkish/O Foreign/O Minister/O Ahmet/PERSON Davutoglu/PERSON made/O at/O the/O end/O of/O October/O to/O China/LOCATION was/O very/O special/O ./O 
Later/O after/O praying/O in/O the/O Great/O Mosque/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION ,/O Davutoglu/PERSON described/O it/O as/O moving/O to/O the/O members/O of/O the/O Turkish/O delegation/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O grand/O gesture/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O allow/O a/O Turkish/O official/O to/O visit/O Kashgar/LOCATION for/O the/O first/O time/O ever/O -/O a/O city/O deep/O inside/O the/O Central/LOCATION Asian/LOCATION desert/LOCATION ,/O where/O over/O centuries/O several/O Turkish/O states/O existed.銆/O In/O his/O speech/O in/O Urumchi/LOCATION ,/O the/O capital/O of/O the/O Xinjiang/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION ,/O Davutoglu/PERSON described/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O a/O region/O to/O which/O Turkey/LOCATION has/O deep/O relations/O as/O special/O ./O 
These/O were/O clear/O words/O for/O those/O ,/O who/O know/O that/O the/O Turks/O and/O Uigurs/O have/O common/O ancestors/O ./O 
There/O was/O no/O reason/O for/O Chinese/O officials/O to/O protest/O because/O two/O days/O later/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION the/O same/O minister/O reassured/O his/O counterpart/O Yang/PERSON Jiechi/PERSON that/O Turkey/LOCATION still/O supported/O the/O ``/O one/O China/LOCATION ''/O policy/O and/O respected/O the/O territorial/O integrity/O of/O China/LOCATION without/O exceptions/O ./O 
This/O seems/O to/O be/O a/O backddown/O on/O Ankara/LOCATION 's/O part/O since/O Turkish/O Prime/O Minister/O Recep/PERSON Tayyip/PERSON Erdogan/PERSON accused/O China/LOCATION of/O genocide/O only/O last/O year/O ,/O after/O the/O death/O of/O several/O hundred/O demonstrators/O during/O clashes/O with/O the/O police/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Turkish/O expert/O Selcuk/PERSON Colakoglu/PERSON believes/O however/O it/O was/O not/O a/O question/O of/O Turkey/LOCATION backing/O down/O because/O but/O Ankara/LOCATION has/O always/O respected/O China/LOCATION 's/O right/O to/O fight/O separatism/O :/O 銆/O ``/O In/O recent/O contacts/O we/O have/O observed/O a/O special/O reference/O to/O the/O situation/O of/O Uigur/O Turks/O ./O 
We/O observe/O that/O the/O idea/O to/O broaden/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O Uigurs/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O to/O integrate/O them/O into/O the/O political/O and/O economic/O system/O is/O being/O spelled/O out/O at/O the/O highest/O level/O ./O 
And/O it/O is/O being/O emphasised/O that/O this/O would/O enhance/O Turkish-Chinese/O relations/O ./O ''/O 
Turkish/O strategists/O believe/O that/O China/LOCATION could/O build/O a/O very/O strong/O bridge/O to/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O if/O Beijing/LOCATION solved/O the/O problems/O of/O the/O Uigurs/O and/O supported/O them/O inn/O their/O efforts/O to/O retain/O their/O own/O culture/O ,/O and/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O interested/O in/O such/O a/O strong/O bridge/O to/O the/O most/O western/O part/O of/O Asia/LOCATION ./O 
Turkey/LOCATION learnt/O an/O important/O lesson/O in/O the/O aftermath/O of/O the/O quarrel/O with/O China/LOCATION about/O human/O rights/O ,/O Colakoglu/PERSON believes/O :/O ``/O Turkey/LOCATION was/O isolated/O in/O this/O issue/O ./O 
I/O mean/O ,/O starting/O with/O the/O Western/O countries/O and/O the/O countries/O ,/O who/O claim/O to/O be/O sensitive/O on/O human/O rights/O ,/O there/O has/O been/O very/O little/O international/O reaction/O ./O ''/O 
Since/O China/LOCATION does/O n't/O have/O a/O democratic/O system/O ,/O Turkey/LOCATION has/O been/O having/O difficulty/O in/O explaining/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION that/O protests/O like/O those/O against/O Chinese/O policy/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION are/O seen/O as/O normal/O events/O in/O a/O democracy/O like/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O says/O Colakoglu/PERSON ./O 
But/O recently/O the/O Chinese/O seem/O to/O have/O developmed/O more/O understanding/O of/O Ankara/LOCATION 's/O position/O ,/O he/O adds/O ,/O especially/O on/O terrorism/O ,/O even/O though/O there/O is/O a/O difference/O in/O the/O terminology/O ./O 
Speaking/O of/O terrorism/O ,/O Turkey/LOCATION means/O Al/ORGANIZATION Qaida/ORGANIZATION ,/O but/O China/LOCATION means/O Uigur/O separatists/O ./O 
But/O the/O days/O the/O Uigurs/O were/O the/O only/O dimension/O of/O Turkish-Chinese/O relations/O are/O long/O gone/O ,/O says/O Suat/PERSON Kiniklioglu/PERSON ,/O a/O member/O of/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Relations/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Turkish/O parliament/O :/O 銆/O ``/O We/O as/O a/O country/O ,/O who/O as/O I/O said/O ,/O engages/O now/O more/O with/O East/LOCATION ,/O South/O and/O West/LOCATION ,/O have/O a/O growing/O interest/O in/O how/O the/O Far/LOCATION East/LOCATION fares/O ,/O as/O we/O feel/O that/O both/O China/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION and/O over/O all/O the/O Far/LOCATION East/LOCATION is/O more/O dynamic/O ,/O has/O more/O growth/O and/O that/O the/O gravity/O of/O global/O attention/O is/O shifting/O more/O to/O the/O East/O ./O 
We/O feel/O that/O these/O are/O areas/O that/O we/O ca/O n't/O neglect/O ./O ''/O 
Turkish/O experts/O stress/O that/O in/O the/O past/O two/O years/O both/O countries/O had/O similar/O positions/O on/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION and/O Iran/LOCATION and/O thus/O they/O worked/O closely/O in/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Working/O relations/O are/O warm/O and/O the/O two/O countries/O have/O similar/O views/O on/O the/O global/O economy/O ./O 
So/O experts/O agree/O that/O there/O is/O likely/O to/O be/O more/O progress/O in/O Turkish-Chinese/LOCATION strategic/O ties/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Cem/PERSON SeyEditor/PERSON :/O Grahame/PERSON Lucas/PERSON 
