While/O western/O troops/O are/O fighting/O against/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O Al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Chinese/O state-run/O companies/O are/O securing/O resources/O ./O 
They/O are/O profiting/O from/O the/O troop/O deployments/O of/O the/O USA/LOCATION and/O its/O allies/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O now/O the/O West/LOCATION is/O getting/O increasingly/O irritated/O about/O it/O ./O 
But/O China/LOCATION says/O it/O is/O doing/O a/O lot/O for/O the/O stability/O of/O the/O country/O by/O investing/O in/O its/O economy/O ./O 
Despite/O demands/O made/O by/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O said/O sending/O its/O own/O troops/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION is/O not/O an/O option/O ./O 
Afghanistan/LOCATION has/O large/O deposits/O of/O copper/O and/O iron/O ore/O and/O Chinese/O state-run/O businesses/O are/O out/O to/O get/O it/O ./O 
Two/O years/O ago/O a/O Chinese/O mining/O consortiumbought/O the/O mining/O rights/O to/O a/O copper/O mine/O inAynak/O ,/O near/O Kabul/LOCATION ,/O for/O 3.4/O billion/O US/O dollars/O ./O 
It/O is/O the/O largest/O copper/O mine/O in/O the/O world/O and/O the/O consortium/O is/O aiming/O to/O produce/O 11/O million/O tons/O of/O copper/O there/O within/O the/O next/O 25/O years/O ./O 
Chinese/O state-owned/O enterprises/O are/O now/O interested/O in/O the/O iron/O ore/O mines/O in/O Hajijak/LOCATION ,/O central/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
Criticism/O from/O the/O West/LOCATION is/O getting/O louder/O ./O 
They/O say/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O capitalizing/O on/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O resources/O while/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O its/O allies/O are/O fighting/O against/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O Al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Conrad/PERSON Schetter/PERSON from/O Bonn/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION 's/O Center/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Research/ORGANIZATION says/O the/O West/O 's/O anger/O is/O understandable/O ./O 
``/O The/O Chinese/O strategy/O is/O to/O concentrate/O on/O economic/O aspects/O and/O stay/O as/O far/O away/O from/O politics/O as/O possible/O ,/O while/O relying/O on/O the/O Americans/O and/O NATO/ORGANIZATION to/O take/O care/O of/O terrorism/O ./O 
And/O they/O do/O n't/O feel/O they/O need/O to/O participate/O in/O the/O latter/O ,/O ''/O he/O says/O ./O 
South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Academy/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Social/ORGANIZATION Sciences/ORGANIZATION ,/O Ye/PERSON Hailin/PERSON ,/O says/O such/O accusations/O are/O plain/O nonsense/O ./O 
He/O says/O ,/O investment/O projects/O like/O in/O Aynak/O are/O part/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O development/O strategy/O and/O that/O China/LOCATION also/O has/O an/O interest/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O stability/O ./O 
By/O strengthening/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O regional/O economy/O ,/O jobs/O will/O be/O created/O and/O ,/O in/O the/O long/O run/O ,/O that/O would/O certainly/O help/O improve/O the/O situation/O there/O ./O 
``/O Stability/O has/O an/O impact/O on/O the/O order/O of/O society/O in/O northwest/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O says/O Ye/PERSON ./O 
``/O We/O do/O not/O want/O Afghanistan/LOCATION to/O become/O a/O training/O camp/O for/O extremists/O from/O all/O over/O the/O world/O ./O 
If/O that/O happens/O ,/O it/O would/O pose/O a/O threat/O for/O all/O of/O East/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O neighbors/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O interests/O are/O not/O only/O of/O economic/O nature/O ./O ''/O 
Statements/O like/O this/O are/O not/O enough/O to/O appease/O the/O West/O ./O 
US/LOCATION Secretary/O of/O State/ORGANIZATION Hillary/PERSON Clinton/PERSON asked/O for/O China/LOCATION 's/O help/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION on/O her/O first/O visit/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION in/O February/O last/O year/O ./O 
She/O suggested/O Chinese/O military/O intervention/O ,/O which/O the/O communist/O government/O turned/O down/O because/O ,/O as/O they/O said/O ,/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O USA/LOCATION have/O different/O goals/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
They/O said/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O NATO/ORGANIZATION would/O have/O to/O shoulder/O the/O responsibility/O alone/O ./O 
Bernt/PERSON Berger/PERSON from/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION explains/O ,/O ``/O When/O it/O comes/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O they/O do/O n't/O want/O it/O to/O look/O like/O they/O have/O the/O same/O security/O objectives/O as/O NATO/ORGANIZATION ./O ''/O 
However/O ,/O Berger/PERSON points/O out/O that/O Al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION is/O also/O a/O threat/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O as/O it/O shares/O a/O border/O with/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O its/O north-western/O province/O ,/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
This/O province/O is/O home/O to/O a/O large/O Muslim/O community/O ,/O the/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
Time/O and/O again/O ,/O civil/O unrest/O and/O riots/O break/O out/O ,/O with/O the/O Uyghur/O people/O fighting/O for/O their/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Berger/PERSON says/O Al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION is/O trying/O to/O turn/O this/O movement/O into/O an/O Islamist/O struggle/O --/O which/O means/O that/O NATO/ORGANIZATION is/O doing/O what/O is/O best/O for/O China/LOCATION by/O fighting/O terrorists/O in/O the/O Hindu/LOCATION Kush/LOCATION ./O 
Author/O :/O Christoph/PERSON Ricking/PERSON //O sbEditor/O :/O Grahame/PERSON Lucas/PERSON 
