Since/O 30/O years/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O pursuing/O its/O one-child/O policy/O aggressively/O to/O get/O its/O population/O under/O control/O ./O 
This/O policy/O ,/O however/O ,/O spells/O great/O problems/O for/O Chinese/O society/O ./O 
At/O the/O end/O of/O the/O 1970s/O ,/O following/O the/O 10-year/O long/O so-called/O Cultural/O Revolution/O ,/O China’s/O economy/O was/O on/O the/O verge/O of/O collapse/O ./O 
Poverty/O and/O housing/O shortages/O were/O the/O order/O of/O the/O day/O and/O there/O was/O an/O excess/O of/O manpower/O ./O 
The/O government/O was/O afraid/O that/O the/O country/O would/O not/O be/O able/O to/O provide/O for/O its/O citizens/O for/O long/O if/O the/O population/O continued/O to/O grow/O at/O the/O same/O pace/O ./O 
In/O order/O to/O reverse/O this/O trend/O ,/O the/O People’s/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION implemented/O birth/O control/O measures/O in/O 1979/O ./O 
Professor/O of/O Sociology/O ,/O Zhou/PERSON Xiaozheng/PERSON of/O the/O Renmin/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION in/O Peking/LOCATION remembers/O :/O ``/O Mao/PERSON Tse/PERSON Tung/PERSON was/O of/O this/O absurd/O opinion/O that/O the/O country/O would/O be/O stronger/O if/O there/O were/O more/O people/O ./O 
After/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O and/O Mao’s/O death/O ,/O the/O government/O that/O followed/O began/O working/O against/O this/O policy/O ./O ''/O 
Every/O family/O living/O in/O the/O city/O was/O permitted/O to/O have/O only/O one/O child/O and/O two/O years/O later/O ,/O the/O government/O made/O its/O one-child/O policy/O its/O topmost/O priority/O ./O 
The/O one-child/O family/O planning/O policy/O is/O practiced/O widely/O in/O China/LOCATION even/O today/O ./O 
In/O the/O case/O of/O a/O handicap/O or/O the/O death/O of/O the/O first/O child/O ,/O the/O law/O allows/O the/O family/O to/O have/O a/O second/O baby/O ./O 
In/O rural/O areas/O ,/O a/O family/O can/O have/O two/O children/O if/O the/O first/O child/O is/O a/O girl/O because/O traditionally/O ,/O people/O living/O in/O the/O countryside/O prefer/O male/O offspring/O as/O bearers/O of/O the/O family/O name/O ./O 
Ethnic/O minorities/O with/O a/O significantly/O lower/O population/O are/O not/O subjected/O to/O any/O such/O birth/O control/O laws/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O Commission/O for/O population/O and/O family/O planning/O believes/O that/O the/O one-child/O policy/O is/O a/O meaningful/O contribution/O to/O lower/O the/O rate/O of/O population/O growth/O ./O 
In/O the/O early/O 1970s/O ,/O the/O birth/O rate/O was/O 5.8/O children/O per/O woman/O ,/O today/O this/O figure/O is/O a/O mere/O 1.8/O ./O 
Without/O the/O policy/O ,/O China/LOCATION would/O have/O had/O 400/O million/O people/O more/O ,/O according/O to/O official/O statistics/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O in/O China/LOCATION do/O not/O just/O rely/O on/O their/O citizens/O obeying/O the/O law/O and/O sticking/O to/O having/O just/O one/O child/O per/O family/O ./O 
They/O also/O carry/O out/O forced/O abortions/O ,/O although/O experts/O say/O it/O is/O impossible/O to/O quote/O a/O figure/O ./O 
Practically/O every/O regional/O centre/O in/O China/LOCATION has/O an/O office/O for/O population/O and/O family/O planning/O and/O each/O one/O of/O these/O offices/O operates/O according/O to/O its/O own/O standards/O ./O 
According/O to/O a/O report/O published/O in/O 2009/O in/O the/O China/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION newspaper/O ,/O the/O number/O of/O abortions/O countrywide/O is/O 13/O million/O per/O year/O ./O 
Reggie/PERSON Littlejohn/PERSON ,/O lawyer/O and/O founder/O of/O the/O US-based/O human/O rights/O organization/O Women’s/O Rights/O Without/O Frontiers/O says/O the/O policy/O has/O little/O to/O do/O with/O family/O planning/O :/O ``/O To/O make/O people/O understand/O that/O population/O growth/O must/O be/O slowed/O down/O is/O one/O thing/O ./O 
But/O to/O force/O women/O to/O abort/O and/O to/O kill/O newborns/O is/O something/O entirely/O different/O ./O 
In/O my/O opinion/O ,/O the/O one/O child/O policy/O is/O violence/O sanctioned/O by/O the/O state/O -/O a/O massive/O breach/O of/O women’s/O rights/O ./O ''/O 
In/O a/O report/O that/O Littlejohn/PERSON presented/O before/O the/O US/LOCATION Congress/ORGANIZATION two/O years/O ago/O ,/O she/O talks/O about/O the/O fate/O of/O Wang/PERSON Liping/PERSON ./O 
Wang/PERSON was/O seven/O months/O pregnant/O with/O a/O child/O conceived/O out/O of/O marriage/O when/O she/O was/O attacked/O by/O unknown/O men/O and/O dragged/O to/O the/O hospital/O ./O 
She/O was/O forced/O to/O abort/O the/O child/O there/O ./O 
Wang/PERSON is/O one/O of/O the/O innumerable/O Chinese/O women/O who/O suffer/O the/O same/O fate/O ,/O says/O Littlejohn/PERSON :/O ``/O China/LOCATION has/O the/O highest/O rate/O for/O suicide/O among/O women/O ./O 
According/O to/O statistics/O ,/O everyday/O there/O are/O 500/O cases/O ./O 
But/O I/O do/O not/O want/O to/O claim/O that/O these/O are/O directly/O related/O to/O forced/O abortions/O ./O ''/O 
Abortions/O are/O a/O massive/O intrusion/O into/O the/O private/O sphere/O ./O 
They/O violate/O human/O rights/O of/O the/O affected/O women/O ,/O says/O Littlejohn/PERSON ./O 
She/O is/O calling/O on/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O put/O an/O end/O to/O this/O practice/O and/O has/O appealed/O to/O the/O international/O community/O to/O exert/O pressure/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION in/O this/O matter/O ./O 
For/O his/O part/O ,/O Zhou/PERSON Xiaozheng/PERSON of/O Renmin/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O has/O also/O appealed/O to/O his/O state/O to/O do/O away/O with/O the/O one-child/O law/O ./O 
It/O has/O negative/O consequences/O for/O society/O and/O leads/O to/O an/O ageing/O population/O ./O 
Adolescents/O could/O get/O increasingly/O egoistic/O ,/O he/O believes/O :/O ``/O Many/O single/O children/O develop/O a/O lack/O of/O social/O competence/O when/O they/O grow/O up/O without/O siblings/O and/O are/O showered/O with/O the/O love/O of/O their/O parents/O and/O grandparents/O instead/O ./O ''/O 
For/O Zhou/PERSON ,/O this/O law/O is/O an/O emergency/O measure/O from/O a/O bygone/O era/O of/O politics/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O it/O is/O time/O to/O adjust/O the/O policy/O to/O changing/O circumstances/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Xiegong/PERSON Fischer/PERSON //O mgEditor/O :/O Grahame/PERSON Lucas/PERSON 
