Google/ORGANIZATION made/O headlines/O almost/O a/O year/O ago/O ,/O as/O the/O company/O declared/O it/O would/O no/O longer/O respect/O the/O censorship/O guidelines/O handed/O down/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O 
Now/O it/O appears/O there/O could/O be/O a/O new/O storm/O brewing/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O the/O largest/O internet/O community/O in/O the/O world/O ,/O with/O 450/O million/O users/O ./O 
But/O they/O are/O not/O the/O freest/O ,/O as/O is/O commonly/O known/O ./O 
Now/O the/O government/O is/O coming/O up/O with/O a/O new/O plan/O to/O censor/O its/O citizens/O :/O to/O restrict/O phone/O calls/O via/O internet/O ./O 
The/O website/O of/O the/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Industry/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Information/ORGANIZATION Technology/ORGANIZATION warns/O :/O `/O we/O will/O counteract/O illegal/O telephone/O services/O ./O '/O 
Is/O the/O end/O near/O for/O Skype/ORGANIZATION and/O similar/O net/O services/O in/O China/LOCATION ?/O 
Zhang/PERSON Yufan/PERSON is/O a/O user/O and/O is/O concerned/O ./O 
``/O People/O who/O work/O in/O foreign/O commerce/O use/O online/O phone/O services/O ./O 
And/O also/O families/O whose/O children/O study/O abroad/O ./O ''/O 
Zhang/PERSON says/O he/O started/O using/O such/O services/O when/O he/O was/O in/O a/O long-distance/O relationship/O ./O 
``/O I/O would/O talk/O over/O the/O internet/O for/O two/O hours/O every/O day/O ./O 
If/O they/O really/O end/O up/O blocking/O Skype/ORGANIZATION ,/O I/O will/O use/O my/O computer/O skills/O to/O get/O around/O it/O ,/O like/O setting/O up/O a/O proxy/O server/O in/O another/O country/O so/O I/O can/O still/O `/O Skype/ORGANIZATION '/O ./O 
And/O if/O that/O doesn鈥檛/O work/O ,/O then/O I/O will/O have/O to/O accept/O having/O been/O robbed/O of/O a/O great/O service/O ./O ''/O 
There/O are/O still/O between/O 10/O to/O 20/O million/O Chinese/O citizens/O who/O phone/O online/O ./O 
And/O they/O are/O saving/O a/O heap/O of/O money/O ./O 
A/O telephone/O call/O from/O China/LOCATION to/O the/O USA/LOCATION typically/O costs/O around/O 80/O euro/O cents/O ,/O whereas/O with/O Skype/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O same/O call/O only/O costs/O two/O cents/O per/O minute/O ./O 
And/O these/O long/O distance/O calls/O account/O for/O about/O 70/O percent/O of/O revenue/O for/O China鈥檚/O telecommunications/O giants/O ./O 
Skype/ORGANIZATION ,/O Google/ORGANIZATION ,/O MSN/ORGANIZATION and/O hundreds/O of/O smaller/O Chinese/O companies/O are/O offering/O their/O services/O in/O trial/O runs/O in/O only/O four/O cities/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Kan/PERSON Kaili/PERSON of/O Beijing鈥檚/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Posts/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Telecommunications/ORGANIZATION thinks/O blocking/O such/O services/O would/O be/O a/O big/O mistake/O ./O 
``/O It/O is/O possible/O that/O the/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Industry/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Information/ORGANIZATION Technology/ORGANIZATION has/O announced/O this/O because/O it/O is/O under/O pressure/O by/O the/O Propaganda/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O police/O ./O ''/O 
That/O is/O what/O many/O insiders/O think/O ,/O as/O the/O manager/O of/O a/O small/O calling/O services/O provider/O told/O the/O ``/O South/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Morning/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION ''/O ./O 
After/O the/O bloody/O riots/O in/O the/O northwestern/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O in/O July/O 2009/O ,/O a/O telecommunications/O company/O was/O forced/O to/O shut/O down/O their/O internet/O calling/O services/O ./O 
This/O is/O a/O sign/O that/O people/O who/O are/O critical/O of/O the/O government/O use/O the/O internet/O to/O talk/O in/O private/O ./O 
But/O Kan/PERSON Kaili/PERSON says/O one/O of/O the/O problems/O is/O that/O most/O online/O phone/O services/O are/O offered/O by/O private/O companies/O ./O 
``/O They/O compete/O with/O the/O three/O big/O state/O companies/O ./O 
Its/O possible/O that/O such/O a/O step/O would/O only/O be/O taken/O to/O protect/O the/O state/O companies/O ./O ''/O 
To/O the/O question/O whether/O the/O government/O is/O more/O worried/O about/O the/O consumers/O or/O the/O interests/O of/O its/O own/O monopolies/O ,/O he/O says/O ,/O ``/O It/O is/O obvious/O that/O the/O government/O is/O sacrificing/O the/O interests/O of/O the/O people/O ./O ''/O 
This/O sacrifice/O could/O soon/O make/O China/LOCATION the/O only/O country/O in/O the/O world/O to/O ban/O online/O telephone/O calls/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Kan/PERSON Kaili/PERSON is/O certain/O this/O will/O not/O happen/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
He/O says/O the/O chances/O are/O ,/O ``/O zero/O ./O 
The/O government/O will/O never/O carry/O out/O this/O plan/O ./O 
If/O they/O shut/O down/O a/O company/O today/O and/O arrest/O its/O manager/O ,/O then/O a/O new/O one/O will/O pop/O up/O tomorrow/O ./O 
There/O are/O so/O many/O of/O these/O small/O service/O providers/O ./O ''/O 
He/O says/O that/O to/O be/O effective/O ,/O ``/O this/O could/O only/O possibly/O apply/O to/O the/O few/O big/O companies/O ./O 
Or/O maybe/O there/O really/O is/O nothing/O behind/O the/O statement/O ./O ''/O 
If/O he/O is/O right/O ,/O this/O would/O just/O be/O another/O ploy/O to/O ``/O keep/O face/O ''/O without/O hurting/O anyone/O ./O 
And/O with/O the/O many/O faces/O China/LOCATION has/O ,/O he/O could/O very/O well/O be/O right/O ./O 
