The/O plan/O is/O for/O China/LOCATION to/O become/O much/O greener/O ./O 
At/O least/O that/O 's/O what/O Prime/O Minister/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON has/O announced/O but/O Chinese/O NGOs/O are/O disappointed/O ./O 
They/O expected/O much/O more/O ambitious/O targets/O from/O the/O new/O five-year/O plan/O ./O 
It/O sounded/O like/O a/O mini-revolution/O when/O Prime/O Minister/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON spoke/O of/O restructuring/O the/O economy/O last/O Saturday/O in/O the/O Great/LOCATION Hall/LOCATION of/LOCATION the/LOCATION People/LOCATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
He/O said/O the/O growth/O model/O should/O become/O more/O sustainable/O ./O 
``/O We/O have/O to/O promote/O the/O protection/O of/O resources/O and/O the/O environment/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
But/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O the/O hard/O figures/O ,/O the/O five-year/O plan/O is/O less/O ambitious/O than/O expected/O in/O terms/O of/O setting/O goals/O to/O reduce/O greenhouse/O gases/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION wants/O to/O increase/O the/O proportion/O of/O non-fossil/O fuels/O used/O in/O China/LOCATION from/O 8/O to/O 11/O percent/O and/O concentrate/O more/O on/O hydropower/O and/O nuclear/O and/O solar/O energy/O ./O 
However/O ,/O this/O does/O not/O represent/O an/O overhaul/O of/O the/O energy/O sector/O ,/O complained/O Li/PERSON Yan/PERSON from/O Greenpeace/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O Seventy/O percent/O of/O the/O energy/O comes/O from/O coal/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O to/O reduce/O its/O dependence/O on/O coal/O and/O the/O government/O knows/O this/O ./O 
But/O because/O the/O country/O needs/O rapid/O growth/O because/O it/O 's/O dependent/O on/O exports/O and/O energy/O efficiency/O is/O so/O low/O ,/O nobody/O dares/O broach/O this/O subject/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O it/O is/O unclear/O whether/O the/O brakes/O will/O really/O be/O put/O on/O economic/O growth/O ./O 
Although/O the/O government/O has/O said/O it/O will/O aim/O for/O annual/O growth/O of/O only/O 7/O percent/O ,/O it/O made/O the/O same/O promise/O five/O years/O ago/O and/O that/O was/O not/O kept/O ./O 
The/O provinces/O do/O not/O seem/O keen/O to/O rally/O around/O the/O center/O in/O this/O regard/O either/O ./O 
Delegates/O from/O the/O northwest/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION were/O full/O of/O praise/O for/O the/O prime/O minister/O at/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O yet/O at/O the/O same/O time/O they/O announced/O growth/O targets/O of/O 10/O percent/O and/O called/O for/O more/O coal/O production/O ./O 
``/O In/O order/O to/O drive/O forward/O the/O industrialization/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION we/O need/O to/O generate/O electricity/O from/O coal/O ,/O we/O need/O the/O chemicals/O industry/O ,/O heavy/O industry/O 鈥/O we/O need/O all/O of/O these/O for/O our/O economic/O development/O ,/O ''/O one/O delegate/O argued/O ./O 
The/O goal/O stipulated/O by/O the/O new/O five-year/O plan/O is/O to/O cut/O energy/O and/O carbon/O intensity/O by/O 16/O to/O 17/O percent/O ./O 
But/O this/O is/O not/O enough/O said/O Li/PERSON Yan/PERSON because/O ``/O China/LOCATION faces/O huge/O environmental/O and/O energy-related/O problems/O ./O 
The/O government/O has/O to/O give/O clear/O and/O ambitious/O targets/O from/O top/O to/O bottom/O so/O that/O there/O is/O pressure/O at/O every/O level/O and/O in/O every/O sector/O ./O ''/O 
Other/O environment/O NGOs/O in/O China/LOCATION agree/O ./O 
The/O World/O Wide/O Fund/O for/O Nature/O recently/O said/O that/O green/O concepts/O should/O not/O only/O be/O an/O appendix/O to/O government/O policy/O but/O a/O central/O component/O ./O 
However/O ,/O as/O long/O as/O China/LOCATION needs/O growth/O to/O ensure/O social/O stability/O and/O the/O provinces/O cater/O only/O to/O their/O own/O requirements/O ,/O the/O environment/O is/O not/O likely/O to/O be/O a/O top/O priority/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Ruth/PERSON Kirchner/actEditor/PERSON :/O Thomas/PERSON B盲rthlein/PERSON 
