Waving/O colonial-era/O flags/O ,/O tens/O of/O thousands/O of/O pro-democracy/O protesters/O have/O staged/O a/O massive/O rally/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION demanding/O full/O electoral/O freedom/O ./O 
But/O will/O this/O be/O enough/O for/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O back/O down/O ?/O 
``/O The/O huge/O crowds/O gathered/O here/O reflect/O the/O willingness/O of/O the/O people/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION to/O take/O action/O and/O sacrifice/O for/O the/O sake/O of/O democracy/O ,/O ''/O said/O Joseph/PERSON Cheng/PERSON ./O 
The/O political/O science/O professor/O from/O the/O City/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Hong/ORGANIZATION Kong/ORGANIZATION is/O one/O of/O many/O city/O residents/O who/O took/O part/O in/O the/O this/O year/O 's/O July/O 1/O rally/O to/O mark/O the/O day/O the/O territory/O was/O returned/O to/O China/LOCATION in/O 1997/O after/O more/O than/O a/O century/O of/O British/O rule/O ./O 
Passions/O were/O running/O particularly/O high/O this/O time/O around/O as/O tens/O of/O thousands/O marched/O through/O the/O heart/O of/O the/O city/O demanding/O more/O democracy/O and/O accusing/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O taking/O their/O civil/O liberties/O away/O ./O 
Some/O ,/O chanting/O anti-Beijing/O slogans/O and/O waving/O colonial-era/O flags/O ,/O even/O called/O for/O the/O city/O 's/O chief/O executive/O to/O be/O sacked/O in/O a/O move/O seen/O by/O many/O as/O a/O direct/O challenge/O to/O the/O rule/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O 
The/O mass/O demonstration/O came/O just/O a/O day/O after/O polls/O closed/O in/O an/O unofficial/O referendum/O on/O democratic/O reform/O which/O drew/O an/O unexpectedly/O high/O turnout/O of/O nearly/O 800,000/O votes/O -/O more/O than/O a/O fifth/O of/O the/O city/O 's/O electorate/O -/O but/O was/O slammed/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION as/O an/O ``/O illegal/O farce/O ''/O that/O was/O ``/O tinged/O with/O mincing/O ludicrousness/O ./O ''/O 
The/O 10-day/O poll/O -/O which/O took/O place/O online/O and/O at/O physical/O polling/O stations/O -/O was/O intended/O to/O urge/O Chinese/O authorities/O to/O allow/O opposition/O democrats/O to/O run/O in/O a/O 2017/O citywide/O election/O for/O a/O new/O chief/O minister/O ./O 
The/O vote/O gave/O city/O residents/O three/O options/O on/O how/O the/O poll/O should/O be/O carried/O out/O -/O all/O of/O which/O included/O the/O public/O having/O some/O influence/O on/O the/O selection/O of/O candidates/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O promised/O direct/O elections/O in/O 2017/O ,/O but/O has/O ruled/O out/O allowing/O voters/O to/O choose/O who/O can/O run/O for/O the/O top/O job/O ./O 
Both/O the/O vote/O and/O the/O rally/O were/O organized/O by/O the/O pro-democratic/O protest/O group/O Occupy/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION with/O Love/O and/O Peace/O -LRB-/O OCLP/O -RRB-/O ./O 
In/O a/O DW/O interview/O ,/O Joseph/PERSON Cheng/PERSON ,/O described/O the/O poll/O as/O ``/O platform/O for/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION people/O to/O articulate/O their/O views/O on/O political/O reform/O ,/O ''/O adding/O that/O true/O universal/O suffrage/O was/O the/O only/O way/O to/O ensure/O that/O the/O people/O will/O have/O a/O meaningful/O choice/O and/O that/O the/O vote/O will/O be/O genuinely/O competitive/O ./O 
But/O Cheng/PERSON also/O pointed/O out/O that/O Chinese/O authorities/O are/O extremely/O sensitive/O to/O the/O idea/O of/O allowing/O such/O polls/O as/O they/O could/O be/O interpreted/O as/O a/O challenge/O to/O the/O CPC/ORGANIZATION 's/O authority/O ./O 
``/O The/O authorities/O are/O also/O very/O worried/O about/O similar/O votes/O being/O carried/O out/O in/O Taiwan/LOCATION or/O regions/O such/O as/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
Shortly/O before/O the/O referendum/O got/O underway/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O State/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Information/ORGANIZATION Office/ORGANIZATION issued/O a/O white/O paper/O on/O June/O 9/O reiterating/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION had/O ``/O comprehensive/O jurisdiction/O ''/O over/O the/O former/O British/O colony/O ./O 
The/O policy/O document/O stated/O that/O some/O people/O were/O ``/O confused/O or/O lopsided/O in/O their/O understanding/O of/O one/O country/O ,/O two/O systems/O and/O that/O this/O has/O led/O to/O ``/O many/O wrong/O views/O ''/O about/O the/O city/O 's/O economy/O ,/O society/O and/O the/O development/O of/O its/O political/O system/O ./O 
Robert/PERSON Daly/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O the/O Kissinger/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION on/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O US/LOCATION at/O the/O Woodrow/ORGANIZATION Wilson/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Scholars/ORGANIZATION ,/O says/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION is/O only/O as/O special/O as/O Beijing/LOCATION allows/O it/O to/O be/O ./O 
However/O ,/O it/O is/O not/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O interest/O that/O the/O territory/O functions/O simply/O as/O one/O more/O Chinese/O city/O ./O 
``/O Beijing/LOCATION benefits/O from/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O openness/O and/O from/O its/O attractiveness/O to/O foreign/O corporations/O ./O 
Cracking/O down/O too/O harshly/O on/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION would/O put/O the/O lie/O to/O overtures/O the/O PRC/LOCATION makes/O to/O Taiwan/LOCATION under/O the/O ``/O One/O Country/O ,/O Two/O Systems/O '/O banner/O ./O ''/O 
Most/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION residents/O are/O pragmatic/O and/O hope/O for/O good/O relations/O with/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION ,/O Daly/PERSON added/O ./O 
But/O they/O also/O want/O the/O city/O to/O remain/O unique/O and/O modern/O ./O 
The/O want/O to/O enjoy/O freedoms/O of/O speech/O ,/O information/O ,/O and/O association/O ,/O and/O they/O want/O to/O participate/O meaningfully/O in/O their/O own/O governance/O ./O 
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION 's/O Basic/O Law/O promised/O those/O things/O to/O the/O people/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION and/O since/O 1997/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O ,/O in/O the/O main/O ,/O honored/O its/O promise/O ./O 
``/O The/O recent/O White/O Paper/O issued/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O however/O ,/O called/O the/O promise/O into/O question/O with/O its/O implication/O that/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION administrative/O personnel/O ,/O including/O judges/O ,/O must/O now/O take/O direction/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
China/LOCATION scholar/O Perry/PERSON Link/PERSON told/O DW/O that/O the/O aim/O of/O the/O white/O paper/O was/O to/O intimidate/O democrats/O and/O make/O clear/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION intends/O to/O continue/O its/O `/O digestion/O '/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ./O 
``/O It/O appears/O to/O be/O a/O clear/O violation/O of/O Deng/PERSON Xiaoping/PERSON 's/O promise/O of/O ``/O one/O country/O ,/O two/O systems/O ''/O for/O fifty/O years/O ./O 
But/O in/O fact/O it/O is/O not/O really/O new/O ./O 
Deng/PERSON 's/O promise/O was/O never/O a/O promise/O in/O the/O conventional/O sense/O ,/O ''/O Link/PERSON said/O ./O 
Link/O believes/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O increasingly/O tight/O control/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION wo/O n't/O make/O much/O of/O a/O difference/O economically/O as/O most/O of/O the/O city/O 's/O tycoons/O are/O already/O allied/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Politically/O ,/O however/O ,/O this/O will/O sharpen/O and/O deepen/O the/O political/O problems/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O This/O will/O enforce/O a/O surface/O appearance/O of/O unity/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O but/O cover/O a/O resentful/O populace/O who/O will/O now/O have/O even/O more/O reason/O to/O feel/O resentful/O ''/O ,/O the/O China/LOCATION expert/O said/O ./O 
Tim/PERSON Pringle/PERSON ,/O a/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION permanent/O resident/O and/O senior/O lecturer/O at/O SOAS/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION London/ORGANIZATION ,/O has/O a/O similar/O view/O ./O 
He/O told/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION society/O had/O become/O increasingly/O polarized/O since/O 2003/O when/O the/O city/O witnessed/O the/O first/O great/O pro-democracy/O march/O of/O the/O post-colonial/O era/O ./O 
Pringle/PERSON explains/O that/O while/O a/O vibrant/O students/O and/O workers/O '/O movement/O has/O emergedwhat/O happens/O in/O the/O city/O does/O not/O take/O place/O in/O isolation/O ./O 
``/O If/O Beijing/LOCATION fails/O to/O exercise/O considerable/O influence/O over/O the/O arrangements/O for/O the/O next/O election/O of/O Chief/O Executive/O ,/O this/O would/O give/O succor/O to/O those/O demanding/O democratic/O reforms/O in/O the/O mainland/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O the/O chances/O of/O an/O entirely/O unfettered/O election/O in/O 2017/O are/O slim/O ./O ''/O 
Pringle/PERSON points/O to/O the/O fact/O that/O despite/O the/O massive/O support/O in/O favor/O of/O direct/O elections/O for/O the/O chief/O executive/O post/O ,/O there/O are/O also/O significant/O number/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION people/O who/O support/O Beijing/LOCATION as/O an/O expression/O of/O their/O patriotism/O or/O because/O they/O agree/O with/O the/O argument/O that/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION folks/O are/O more/O concerned/O with/O `/O making/O money/O '/O than/O engaging/O in/O political/O struggles/O ./O 
``/O While/O there/O is/O strong/O evidence/O to/O suggest/O that/O the/O majority/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION people/O support/O direct/O elections/O ,/O it/O is/O not/O the/O case/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O on/O a/O collision/O course/O with/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION residents/O in/O general/O ./O ''/O 
According/O to/O Daly/PERSON ,/O the/O protests/O will/O ,/O therefore/O ,/O have/O only/O a/O limited/O impact/O as/O China/LOCATION will/O continue/O to/O insist/O that/O only/O candidates/O who/O ``/O Love/O China/LOCATION ''/O -/O i.e./O take/O directions/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION when/O it/O chooses/O to/O provide/O it/O -/O are/O qualified/O to/O run/O for/O chief/O post/O ./O 
``/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION is/O ,/O irrevocably/O ,/O part/O of/O China/LOCATION and/O ,/O under/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION formula/O ,/O `/O without/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O there/O would/O be/O no/O new/O China/LOCATION ./O '/O 
That/O 's/O the/O bottom/O line/O ;/O the/O interests/O of/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION and/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION are/O one/O ./O 
Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION must/O operate/O under/O that/O umbrella/O ./O ''/O 
As/O for/O the/O pro-democracy/O campaign/O ,/O analysts/O argue/O Beijing/LOCATION will/O prefer/O to/O divide/O and/O weaken/O this/O movement/O and/O perhaps/O isolate/O its/O more/O ``/O radical/O ''/O wing/O rather/O than/O collide/O with/O it/O head-on/O ./O 
``/O A/O key/O challenge/O for/O the/O movement/O will/O be/O to/O maintain/O unity/O as/O some/O of/O the/O more/O radical/O actions/O planned/O unfold/O --/O such/O as/O occupying/O the/O central/O financial/O district/O --/O while/O leaving/O room/O for/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O compromise/O ,/O ''/O said/O Pringle/PERSON ./O 
Daly/PERSON shares/O a/O similar/O view/O :/O ``/O Beijing/LOCATION needs/O to/O find/O a/O way/O to/O acknowledge/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION demonstrators/O '/O concerns/O -/O to/O mollify/O them/O without/O emboldening/O them/O ./O 
But/O it/O 's/O getting/O harder/O to/O square/O that/O circle/O ./O 
To/O date/O ,/O mollification/O has/O n't/O been/O style/O of/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON ./O ''/O 
