Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON ,/O a/O well-known/O Uighur/O and/O a/O moderate/O critic/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policy/O towards/O the/O country/O 's/O Muslim/O minority/O ,/O is/O on/O trial/O in/O China/LOCATION on/O charges/O of/O ``/O separatism/O ./O ''/O 
DW/O takes/O a/O look/O at/O the/O scholar/O 's/O life/O ./O 
Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON is/O not/O a/O typical/O dissident/O 鈥/O the/O 44-year-old/O sees/O himself/O first/O and/O foremost/O as/O an/O economist/O ./O 
Born/O in/O 1969/O in/O the/O small/O town/O of/O Artux/LOCATION -LRB-/O also/O spelled/O Atush/PERSON or/O Atushi/O -RRB-/O ,/O in/O the/O western/O Chinese/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Tohti/PERSON moved/O to/O Changchun/LOCATION for/O higher/O education/O and/O from/O there/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O advance/O his/O career/O as/O a/O renowned/O economist/O ./O 
For/O several/O years/O ,/O Tohti/PERSON researched/O at/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Minzu/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O amongst/O other/O things/O ,/O about/O the/O Uighurs/O '/O social/O standing/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION Province/LOCATION ./O 
He/O came/O to/O the/O conclusion/O that/O the/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O in/O the/O province/O was/O not/O treated/O the/O same/O way/O as/O the/O majority/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
On/O the/O contrary/O ,/O he/O learned/O that/O there/O were/O fewer/O jobs/O for/O Uighurs/O and/O they/O were/O paid/O less/O for/O the/O same/O positions/O ./O 
He/O also/O found/O that/O the/O Uighurs/O were/O being/O systematically/O discriminated/O by/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O ./O 
Tohti/PERSON repeatedly/O criticized/O the/O central/O government/O 's/O policy/O against/O the/O minority/O ./O 
Unlike/O other/O Uighur/O critics/O 鈥/O such/O as/O the/O exiled/O leader/O Rebiyah/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON 鈥/PERSON Tohti/PERSON is/O viewed/O as/O a/O moderate/O critic/O ,/O always/O pushing/O for/O a/O better/O understanding/O between/O Uighurs/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
``/O Tohti/O is/O seen/O as/O mild/O and/O moderate/O ,/O ''/O says/O Chinese/O writer/O Wang/PERSON Lixiong/PERSON ./O 
``/O He/O is/O the/O only/O influential/O Uighur/O intellectual/O who/O believes/O that/O Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O a/O part/O of/O China/LOCATION and/O that/O it/O should/O be/O granted/O autonomy/O according/O to/O democratic/O principles/O ./O 
This/O way/O of/O thinking/O sets/O him/O apart/O from/O most/O Uighurs/O living/O in/O exile/O ,/O ''/O he/O says/O ./O 
In/O 2006/O ,/O Tohti/PERSON founded/O ``/O Uighur/O online/O ,/O ''/O a/O website/O designed/O to/O address/O Uighur/O issues/O ./O 
Two/O years/O later/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O shut/O down/O the/O site/O and/O arrested/O Tohti/PERSON on/O charges/O of/O promoting/O Uighur/O separatism/O ./O 
In/O July/O 2009/O ,/O deadly/O riots/O broke/O out/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION 's/O capital/O ,/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O claiming/O the/O lives/O of/O more/O than/O 150/O people/O ,/O and/O the/O economist/O was/O once/O again/O put/O under/O arrest/O after/O being/O charged/O with/O inciting/O the/O violence/O ./O 
But/O mounting/O international/O pressure/O led/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O release/O Tohti/PERSON a/O few/O weeks/O later/O ./O 
``/O There/O have/O always/O been/O tensions/O between/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O and/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O ''/O Tohti/PERSON told/O DW/O in/O September/O 2009/O ./O 
``/O But/O they/O had/O never/O led/O to/O mutual/O hatred/O ./O 
I/O believe/O that/O the/O trust/O between/O the/O Uighur/O minority/O and/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O is/O now/O destroyed/O ./O 
I/O also/O think/O that/O ethnic/O hatred/O has/O been/O taking/O shape/O ./O 
If/O Beijing/LOCATION ca/O n't/O bring/O the/O situation/O under/O control/O and/O continues/O to/O behave/O like/O a/O colonial/O power/O ,/O we/O will/O continue/O to/O witness/O tragedies/O such/O as/O this/O one/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
Following/O this/O incident/O ,/O Tohti/PERSON was/O repeatedly/O placed/O under/O house/O arrest/O ./O 
A/O few/O months/O ago/O ,/O the/O scholar/O was/O back/O in/O jail/O ./O 
After/O his/O arrest/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O he/O was/O sent/O to/O Urumqi/LOCATION -/O some/O 1550/O miles/O away/O -/O where/O Chinese/O prosecutors/O indicted/O the/O 44-year-old/O with/O ``/O separatism/O and/O inciting/O hatred/O ./O ''/O 
An/O incomprehensible/O charge/O ,/O said/O his/O lawyer/O ,/O Liu/PERSON Xiaoyuan/PERSON ./O 
``/O Tohti/O is/O against/O separatism/O ,/O ''/O he/O told/O the/O press/O ./O 
``/O He/O has/O only/O talked/O about/O some/O of/O the/O legal/O and/O cultural/O issues/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
He/O 's/O against/O splitting/O the/O country/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
``/O He/O 's/O never/O done/O anything/O illegal/O ,/O ''/O his/O wife/O ,/O Guzulnur/PERSON ,/O said/O during/O a/O break/O in/O the/O court/O proceedings/O ./O 
``/O He/O 's/O never/O talked/O about/O separating/O the/O country/O ./O 
He/O 's/O never/O opposed/O the/O government/O ./O 
He/O 's/O never/O opposed/O the/O people/O ./O 
He/O 's/O a/O scholar/O ./O ''/O 
The/O proceedings/O are/O set/O to/O last/O only/O two/O days/O ,/O but/O it/O remains/O unclear/O when/O the/O verdict/O will/O be/O pronounced/O ./O 
Tohti/O is/O facing/O a/O jail/O term/O that/O could/O last/O anything/O between/O ten/O years/O to/O life/O ,/O though/O the/O death/O sentence/O is/O also/O possible/O ./O 
Wang/PERSON Lixiong/PERSON regards/O the/O trial/O against/O Tohti/PERSON as/O a/O big/O mistake/O ./O 
``/O Tohti/PERSON wanted/O to/O build/O bridges/O between/O the/O Uighurs/O and/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
But/O now/O that/O he/O 's/O been/O arrested/O ,/O how/O can/O anyone/O say/O that/O the/O regime/O has/O a/O favorable/O policy/O towards/O Uighurs/O ?/O ''/O 
the/O writer/O said/O ./O 
``/O Tohti/O 's/O case/O will/O strenghten/O the/O radicals/O '/O belief/O that/O the/O `/O Middle/O Way/O '/O is/O absolutely/O impossible/O ./O 
They/O will/O also/O view/O this/O as/O a/O reason/O to/O avoid/O this/O path/O ./O ''/O 
But/O Tohti/PERSON wanted/O the/O opposite/O ./O 
He/O wanted/O to/O set/O an/O example/O that/O the/O ``/O Middle/O Way/O ''/O is/O indeed/O possible/O ,/O Wang/PERSON said/O ,/O adding/O that/O ,/O ``/O Now/O the/O radicals/O can/O claim/O they/O were/O right/O ./O ''/O 
