Beijing/LOCATION is/O considering/O reducing/O China/LOCATION 's/O list/O of/O capital/O offenses/O ./O 
It/O 's/O the/O first/O step/O on/O the/O road/O to/O reform/O but/O there/O 's/O still/O a/O long/O way/O to/O go/O ,/O says/O DW/O columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON ./O 
The/O Chinese/O legal/O system/O has/O traditionally/O been/O based/O on/O the/O principle/O of/O deterrence/O ./O 
As/O an/O old/O saying/O goes/O :/O Kill/O the/O chicken/O to/O scare/O the/O monkey/O -LRB-/O ``/O sha/O ji/O jing/O hou/O ''/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Most/O Chinese/O tend/O to/O nod/O in/O agreement/O when/O they/O hear/O it/O ,/O especially/O in/O rural/O areas/O ./O 
They/O firmly/O believe/O that/O it/O 's/O the/O only/O way/O to/O keep/O order/O in/O a/O country/O with/O a/O population/O of/O 1.3/O billion/O ./O 
But/O these/O days/O ,/O any/O news/O that/O someone/O has/O been/O wrongly/O sentenced/O to/O death/O elicits/O a/O growing/O sense/O of/O indignation/O ./O 
That/O indignation/O can/O fast/O turn/O on/O the/O regional/O representatives/O of/O the/O ruling/O Communist/ORGANIZATION party/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O is/O partly/O why/O to/O remove/O nine/O crimes/O from/O the/O list/O of/O offenses/O punishable/O by/O death/O ,/O including/O smuggling/O weapons/O ,/O ammunition/O and/O nuclear/O materials/O ;/O counterfeiting/O currencies/O ;/O raising/O funds/O by/O means/O of/O fraud/O ;/O and/O arranging/O for/O or/O forcing/O another/O person/O to/O engage/O in/O prostitution/O ./O 
The/O crime/O of/O ``/O fabricating/O rumors/O to/O mislead/O others/O during/O wartime/O ''/O is/O also/O under/O review/O ./O 
High/O number/O of/O executions/O With/O 2,400/O people/O put/O to/O death/O every/O year/O ,/O three/O times/O as/O many/O executions/O take/O place/O in/O China/LOCATION than/O in/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O world/O put/O together/O ./O 
The/O number/O is/O nevertheless/O in/O decline/O ./O 
While/O 12,000/O people/O were/O put/O to/O death/O in/O 2002/O ,/O the/O death/O penalty/O was/O carried/O out/O only/O 6,500/O times/O in/O 2007/O ./O 
to/O a/O third/O of/O what/O it/O was/O ./O 
In/O 2007/O Beijing/LOCATION granted/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Supreme/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION the/O power/O to/O review/O death/O penalty/O cases/O ./O 
Last/O year/O ,/O judges/O ordered/O provincial/O courts/O to/O reexamine/O nearly/O 40/O percent/O of/O death/O sentences/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O procedural/O errors/O ./O 
There/O are/O still/O stark/O differences/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O other/O countries/O that/O still/O use/O the/O death/O penalty/O ./O 
In/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O the/O most/O prominent/O of/O the/O countries/O criticized/O for/O using/O the/O death/O penalty/O ,/O its/O application/O is/O limited/O to/O aggravated/O murders/O ./O 
A/O total/O of/O 1,386/O people/O have/O been/O executed/O there/O since/O 1976/O ,/O just/O over/O half/O as/O many/O as/O those/O executed/O in/O China/LOCATION last/O year/O alone/O ./O 
The/O extensive/O catalogue/O of/O crimes/O regularly/O leads/O to/O some/O strange/O verdicts/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O judges/O ,/O because/O imprecisely/O formulated/O crimes/O allow/O judges/O a/O lot/O of/O room/O for/O interpretation/O in/O their/O decisions/O ./O 
One/O can/O say/O that/O this/O opens/O the/O door/O to/O arbitrary/O decisions/O of/O a/O political/O nature/O ./O 
Last/O year/O the/O verdict/O in/O the/O case/O against/O the/O former/O minister/O for/O railways/O ,/O Liu/PERSON Zhijun/PERSON ,/O caused/O a/O stir/O :/O a/O death/O sentence/O with/O reprieve/O for/O corruption/O ./O 
After/O two/O years/O good/O behavior/O ,/O such/O sentences/O are/O generally/O commuted/O to/O life/O imprisonment/O ./O 
Such/O verdicts/O are/O favored/O by/O judges/O in/O cases/O involving/O well/O known/O and/O well-connected/O people/O ./O 
In/O other/O cases/O ,/O the/O sentence/O is/O often/O decided/O even/O before/O the/O trial/O ./O 
Since/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON launched/O an/O anti-terror/O campaign/O in/O China/LOCATION in/O response/O to/O a/O series/O of/O attacks/O ,/O trials/O now/O tend/O to/O be/O brief/O ./O 
In/O early/O October/O ,/O 12/O suspected/O terrorists/O were/O condemned/O to/O death/O by/O a/O court/O in/O the/O unstable/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ./O 
Such/O draconian/O moves/O are/O unlikely/O to/O change/O much/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O long/O come/O under/O fire/O from/O the/O international/O community/O for/O its/O use/O of/O the/O death/O penalty/O ./O 
Xi/O is/O now/O taking/O a/O step/O in/O the/O right/O direction/O ,/O but/O there/O is/O still/O a/O long/O road/O ahead/O ./O 
Reforms/O have/O yet/O to/O be/O finalized/O ./O 
The/O list/O of/O capital/O offenses/O is/O slated/O to/O be/O reduced/O even/O more/O in/O a/O few/O months/O '/O time/O ./O 
Perhaps/O the/O next/O to/O go/O will/O be/O another/O antiquated/O ,/O vaguely/O formulated/O crime/O :/O aggravated/O vegetable/O theft/O ./O 
