A/O Chinese/O court/O has/O sentenced/O prominent/O Uighur/O scholar/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON to/O life/O in/O prison/O for/O ``/O separatism/O ./O ''/O 
Rights/O groups/O have/O slammed/O the/O controversial/O trial/O as/O a/O ``/O failure/O ''/O of/O the/O justice/O system/O and/O demanded/O Tohti/PERSON 's/O release/O ./O 
The/O accused/O denied/O all/O the/O charges/O in/O court/O ,/O but/O to/O no/O avail/O ./O 
The/O Urumqi/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Intermediate/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION sentenced/O Uighur/O academic/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON to/O life/O imprisonment/O and/O confiscated/O all/O his/O possessions/O ,/O an/O unusually/O harsh/O punishment/O for/O someone/O widely/O regarded/O as/O a/O moderate/O critic/O ./O 
While/O the/O sentence/O was/O being/O read/O out/O on/O Tuesday/O ,/O September/O 23/O ,/O Tohti/PERSON shouted/O ``/O I/O refuse/O it/O ,/O ''/O Li/PERSON Fangping/PERSON ,/O one/O of/O Tohti/PERSON 's/O lawyers/O ,/O told/O DW/O ,/O adding/O that/O the/O defendant/O ``/O will/O certainly/O appeal/O ./O ''/O 
Following/O the/O two-day/O trial/O on/O charges/O of/O separatism/O ,/O Jewher/PERSON Ilham/PERSON ,/O Tohti/PERSON 's/O daughter/O told/O DW/O that/O her/O father/O never/O had/O ``/O any/O thoughts/O of/O splitting/O the/O country/O ''/O and/O was/O therefore/O innocent/O ./O 
``/O He/O has/O done/O nothing/O wrong/O ./O 
Putting/O him/O in/O prison/O would/O be/O a/O foolish/O act/O ,/O ''/O said/O the/O 20-year-old/O who/O is/O currently/O studying/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Sophie/PERSON Richardson/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION director/O of/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O HRW/O -RRB-/O ,/O said/O the/O case/O exposed/O the/O ``/O wholesale/O failure/O ''/O of/O the/O Chinese/O judicial/O system/O ,/O as/O authorities/O failed/O to/O show/O any/O understanding/O of/O or/O interest/O in/O constructive/O criticism/O and/O relations/O with/O ethnic/O minorities/O ./O 
Born/O in/O 1969/O in/O a/O small/O town/O in/O the/O western/O Chinese/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Tohti/PERSON moved/O to/O Changchun/LOCATION for/O higher/O education/O and/O from/O there/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O advance/O his/O career/O as/O a/O renowned/O economist/O ./O 
For/O several/O years/O ,/O Tohti/PERSON researched/O at/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Minzu/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O amongst/O other/O things/O ,/O about/O the/O Uighurs/O '/O social/O standing/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION Province/LOCATION ./O 
He/O came/O to/O the/O conclusion/O that/O the/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O in/O the/O province/O was/O not/O treated/O the/O same/O way/O as/O the/O majority/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
He/O also/O found/O that/O the/O Uighurs/O were/O being/O systematically/O discriminated/O by/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O ./O 
Tohti/PERSON repeatedly/O criticized/O the/O central/O government/O 's/O policies/O against/O the/O minority/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Tohti/PERSON is/O viewed/O by/O many/O as/O a/O moderate/O critic/O ,/O always/O pushing/O for/O a/O better/O understanding/O between/O Uighurs/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
In/O 2006/O ,/O Tohti/PERSON founded/O ``/O Uighur/O online/O ,/O ''/O a/O website/O designed/O to/O address/O the/O minority/O group/O 's/O issues/O ./O 
Two/O years/O later/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O shut/O down/O the/O site/O and/O arrested/O Tohti/PERSON on/O charges/O of/O promoting/O Uighur/O separatism/O ./O 
Following/O the/O 2009/O Xinjiang/LOCATION riots/O ,/O the/O scholar/O was/O repeatedly/O placed/O under/O house/O arrest/O ./O 
In/O a/O 2013/O DW/O interview/O ,/O Tohti/PERSON referred/O to/O himself/O as/O a/O ``/O man/O in/O a/O cage/O ./O ''/O 
Just/O a/O few/O months/O later/O ,/O on/O January/O 15/O ,/O he/O was/O arrested/O at/O his/O home/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O later/O sent/O to/O Xinjiang/LOCATION 's/O capital/O Urumqi/LOCATION -/O some/O 1550/O miles/O away/O -/O where/O Chinese/O prosecutors/O indicted/O the/O 44-year-old/O with/O ``/O separatism/O and/O inciting/O hatred/O ./O ''/O 
Following/O Tohti/PERSON 's/O arrest/O ,/O Chinese/O writer/O Li/PERSON Jingrui/PERSON wrote/O on/O her/O microblog/O :/O ``/O While/O many/O wicked/O and/O messy/O problems/O are/O out/O there/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O they/O chose/O to/O jail/O Ilham/PERSON ,/O the/O one/O who/O is/O most/O moderate/O and/O most/O keen/O on/O reconciliation/O and/O dialogue/O ./O ''/O 
Although/O the/O case/O against/O the/O academic/O drew/O international/O attention/O ,/O no/O details/O of/O the/O trial/O -/O except/O for/O the/O court/O 's/O short/O messages/O -/O were/O published/O online/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O most/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O mainstream/O commentators/O remained/O silent/O on/O the/O issue/O ./O 
Tohti/PERSON 's/O lawyers/O said/O the/O prosecution/O cited/O the/O 44-year-old/O 's/O online/O writings/O and/O statements/O made/O in/O the/O classroom/O as/O evidence/O that/O he/O had/O fomented/O ethnic/O hatred/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
But/O the/O scholar/O rejected/O all/O the/O allegations/O ,/O stating/O that/O he/O had/O neither/O committed/O separatist/O actions/O nor/O had/O any/O such/O intentions/O ,/O said/O Li/PERSON ./O 
After/O the/O trial/O ,/O the/O court/O posted/O a/O message/O on/O its/O social/O media/O account/O ,/O saying/O ``/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O defendant/O and/O his/O lawyers/O had/O been/O fully/O protected/O according/O to/O law/O during/O the/O court/O proceedings/O ./O ''/O 
China/LOCATION 's/O resource-rich/O western/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O home/O to/O about/O 10/O million/O Uighurs/O ,/O who/O are/O mostly/O Sunni/O Muslims/O ./O 
Ethnic/O tensions/O have/O been/O simmering/O there/O for/O years/O and/O escalated/O into/O several/O deadly/O conflicts/O in/O the/O recent/O past/O ./O 
On/O September/O 21/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O three/O explosions/O killed/O at/O least/O two/O people/O and/O injured/O many/O others/O in/O central/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Over/O the/O past/O couple/O of/O months/O ,/O dozens/O have/O been/O killed/O in/O riots/O in/O the/O restive/O province/O ./O 
In/O addition/O ,/O the/O attacks/O have/O grown/O in/O scale/O and/O spilled/O into/O other/O parts/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O made/O ``/O terrorists/O and/O separatists/O ''/O responsible/O for/O the/O rising/O tensions/O in/O the/O region/O and/O reacted/O by/O tightening/O its/O already/O rigid/O control/O over/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O have/O vowed/O to/O quell/O the/O violence/O by/O stepping/O up/O security/O measures/O and/O imposing/O religious/O restrictions/O ./O 
However/O ,/O many/O rights/O groups/O and/O scholars/O believe/O that/O countering/O violence/O with/O violence/O is/O counter-productive/O and/O that/O the/O government/O should/O rather/O promote/O ethnic/O integration/O to/O restore/O the/O peace/O ./O 
They/O also/O blame/O the/O authorities/O for/O fuelling/O resentment/O through/O what/O they/O see/O as/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O oppressive/O cultural/O and/O religious/O policies/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON is/O one/O of/O these/O scholars/O who/O has/O ``/O consistently/O ,/O courageously/O ,/O peacefully/O ,/O and/O unambiguously/O advocated/O for/O greater/O understanding/O and/O dialogue/O between/O various/O communities/O ,/O and/O with/O the/O state/O ,/O ''/O said/O HRW/O 's/O Richardson/PERSON ./O 
``/O If/O this/O is/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O definition/O of/O `/O separatist/O '/O activities/O ,/O it/O 's/O hard/O to/O see/O tensions/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O between/O the/O communities/O decreasing/O ./O ''/O 
In/O the/O meantime/O ,/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION and/O several/O rights/O groups/O have/O called/O for/O Tohti/PERSON 's/O release/O ./O 
``/O The/O life/O sentence/O handed/O down/O to/O prominent/O Uighur/O academic/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON on/O charges/O of/O `/O separatism/O '/O is/O an/O affront/O to/O justice/O ,/O ''/O said/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O AI/O -RRB-/O ,/O adding/O that/O the/O `/O shameful/O judgment/O '/O has/O no/O basis/O in/O reality/O ./O 
Tohti/PERSON worked/O to/O peacefully/O build/O bridges/O between/O ethnic/O communities/O and/O for/O that/O he/O has/O been/O punished/O through/O politically/O motivated/O charges/O ,/O said/O William/PERSON Nee/PERSON ,/O AI/O 's/O China/LOCATION Researcher/O ,/O demanding/O the/O scholar/O 's/O immediate/O and/O unconditional/O release/O ./O 
The/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION also/O called/O for/O the/O scholar/O 's/O release/O after/O slamming/O the/O life/O sentence/O as/O ``/O completely/O unjustified/O ./O ''/O 
The/O EU/ORGANIZATION argued/O that/O the/O due/O process/O of/O law/O was/O not/O respected/O ,/O in/O particular/O with/O regard/O to/O the/O right/O to/O a/O proper/O defense/O ./O 
