Beijing/LOCATION does/O n't/O want/O to/O give/O up/O a/O good/O relationship/O with/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O but/O it/O 's/O also/O trying/O to/O maintain/O a/O policy/O of/O non-interference/O in/O the/O Crimean/O crisis/O ./O 
China/LOCATION could/O benefit/O from/O sanctions/O against/O Moscow/LOCATION -/O but/O at/O what/O price/O ?/O 
Non-interference/O in/O the/O affairs/O of/O other/O states/O :/O For/O decades/O ,/O this/O has/O been/O the/O principle/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O policy/O ./O 
This/O has/O meant/O that/O China/LOCATION keeps/O out/O of/O foreign/O conflicts/O ,/O and/O it/O expects/O the/O same/O from/O other/O countries/O -/O Russia/LOCATION included/O ./O 
In/O the/O case/O of/O Ukraine/LOCATION ,/O this/O principle/O has/O become/O a/O problem/O as/O it/O 's/O against/O China/LOCATION 's/O central/O political/O interest/O ,/O namely/O maintaining/O good/O relations/O with/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
``/O The/O Chinese-Russian/O relationship/O is/O currently/O in/O the/O best/O phase/O of/O our/O mutual/O history/O ,/O ''/O emphasized/O Foreign/O Minister/O Wang/PERSON Yi/PERSON at/O a/O press/O conference/O at/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION earlier/O this/O month/O ./O 
Wang/PERSON said/O that/O the/O countries/O trusted/O and/O supported/O each/O other/O ,/O adding/O that/O the/O two/O presidents/O were/O connected/O by/O a/O deep/O friendship/O ./O 
China/LOCATION needs/O Russia/LOCATION -/O as/O an/O ally/O against/O the/O West/O ./O 
In/O relation/O to/O the/O crisis/O in/O Crimea/LOCATION ,/O there/O has/O also/O been/O criticism/O from/O those/O in/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION who/O see/O the/O West/LOCATION as/O the/O aggressor/O ./O 
``/O The/O US-led/O West/O does/O not/O want/O a/O peaceful/O world/O and/O is/O meddling/O in/O world/O affairs/O ./O 
This/O creates/O unrest/O ,/O ''/O said/O Chen/PERSON Xinming/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O on/O Eastern/LOCATION Europe/LOCATION at/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION ,/O in/O an/O interview/O on/O German/O television/O ./O 
``/O Strategically/O ,/O China/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION need/O each/O other/O in/O order/O to/O deal/O with/O Western/O domination/O ./O ''/O 
The/O feeling/O of/O being/O surrounded/O by/O the/O West/O ,/O and/O especially/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O is/O of/O great/O importance/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O policy/O ,/O said/O Sven/PERSON Gareis/PERSON ,/O a/O China/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION M眉nster/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O In/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION sees/O an/O important/O partner/O which/O it/O looks/O to/O for/O support/O -/O and/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O it/O does/O not/O want/O to/O embarrass/O this/O partner/O ,/O ''/O he/O told/O DW/O ./O 
But/O Beijing/LOCATION also/O wants/O to/O maintain/O its/O principle/O of/O non-interference/O ./O 
No/O wonder/O ,/O then/O ,/O that/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O reluctant/O to/O weigh/O in/O on/O the/O question/O of/O the/O Crimean/O referendum/O ./O 
Speaking/O at/O a/O press/O conference/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Deputy/O Foreign/O Minister/O Baodong/PERSON Li/PERSON twice/O avoided/O the/O question/O of/O whether/O China/LOCATION will/O recognize/O the/O ./O 
``/O We/O hope/O all/O sides/O will/O keep/O a/O cool/O head/O and/O seek/O a/O political/O solution/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O further/O escalation/O should/O be/O avoided/O ./O 
He/O refused/O to/O comment/O further/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O support/O for/O its/O strategic/O partner/O hit/O a/O limit/O at/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION vote/O on/O Saturday/O -LRB-/O 15.03.2014/O -RRB-/O ,/O as/O the/O council/O sought/O to/O declare/O the/O Crimean/O referendum/O illegal/O ./O 
,/O while/O China/LOCATION chose/O to/O abstain/O ./O 
Speaking/O off/O the/O record/O ,/O Western/O diplomats/O called/O the/O move/O a/O ``/O slap/O in/O the/O face/O ''/O for/O Russia/LOCATION ;/O China/LOCATION usually/O votes/O along/O with/O its/O close/O ally/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
Luxembourg/LOCATION Foreign/O Minister/O Jean/PERSON Asselborn/PERSON ,/O who/O currently/O chairs/O the/O Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O praised/O China/LOCATION 's/O decision/O to/O reject/O any/O unilateral/O move/O by/O Russia/LOCATION to/O claim/O foreign/O territory/O ,/O along/O with/O its/O call/O for/O an/O international/O coordination/O group/O ./O 
This/O example/O ,/O in/O particular/O ,/O illustrates/O China/LOCATION 's/O quandary/O ,/O said/O Gareis/PERSON ./O 
On/O the/O one/O hand/O ,/O it/O did/O not/O want/O to/O give/O Russia/LOCATION a/O free/O pass/O in/O Crimea/LOCATION ./O 
On/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O China/LOCATION also/O did/O not/O want/O to/O support/O a/O resolution/O by/O the/O West/O ./O 
In/O addition/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O its/O weighty/O domestic/O political/O issues/O to/O bear/O in/O mind/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION can/O not/O support/O the/O referendum/O because/O we/O have/O our/O own/O problems/O ,/O ''/O said/O Eastern/LOCATION Europe/LOCATION expert/O Chen/PERSON Xinming/PERSON ./O 
These/O problems/O are/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION and/O Taiwan/LOCATION ,/O and/O if/O China/LOCATION lends/O its/O support/O to/O the/O referendum/O in/O Crimea/LOCATION ,/O then/O why/O would/O n't/O the/O same/O rules/O apply/O for/O these/O Chinese/O regions/O which/O are/O also/O striving/O for/O independence/O ?/O 
``/O In/O this/O sense/O ,/O it/O 's/O a/O nightmare/O scenario/O for/O China/LOCATION :/O a/O foreign/O power/O exerting/O military/O pressure/O to/O force/O a/O referendum/O ,/O causing/O part/O of/O the/O country/O to/O split/O off/O from/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O Gareis/PERSON ./O 
While/O Beijing/LOCATION continues/O to/O struggle/O with/O contradictions/O at/O the/O political/O level/O ,/O by/O the/O West/LOCATION against/O Russia/LOCATION could/O work/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O favor/O ./O 
``/O Russia/LOCATION would/O increasingly/O turn/O away/O from/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O and/O China/LOCATION would/O be/O the/O winners/O ,/O ''/O said/O Eckhard/PERSON Cordes/PERSON ,/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O Committee/ORGANIZATION on/ORGANIZATION Eastern/ORGANIZATION European/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Relations/ORGANIZATION for/O German/O industry/O associations/O ,/O in/O an/O interview/O with/O newsmagazine/O ``/O Focus/O ./O ''/O 
China/LOCATION ,/O already/O the/O largest/O purchaser/O of/O Russian/O oil/O ,/O would/O certainly/O be/O happy/O with/O such/O a/O development/O -/O and/O could/O become/O the/O ``/O laughing/O third/O party/O ''/O in/O the/O Ukraine/LOCATION crisis/O ,/O benefiting/O as/O the/O others/O fight/O ./O 
``/O But/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O China/LOCATION will/O allow/O itself/O to/O be/O guided/O by/O short-term/O interests/O and/O hope/O for/O profit/O ,/O ''/O said/O Gareis/PERSON ,/O adding/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION probably/O cares/O more/O about/O securing/O long-term/O stability/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
And/O China/LOCATION 's/O economy/O is/O reliant/O on/O maintaining/O good/O relations/O with/O Western/O governments/O ./O 
For/O this/O reason/O ,/O the/O tightrope/O China/LOCATION is/O walking/O with/O its/O Ukraine/LOCATION policy/O could/O become/O even/O wobblier/O in/O the/O coming/O weeks/O ./O 
At/O the/O end/O of/O March/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON is/O due/O to/O visit/O several/O Western/O European/O countries/O and/O may/O have/O to/O finally/O show/O his/O true/O colors/O ./O 
