As/O China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O and/O political/O clout/O grows/O ,/O so/O does/O the/O nation/O 's/O role/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
The/O country/O has/O already/O overtaken/O the/O US/LOCATION as/O the/O largest/O oil/O importer/O ./O 
But/O can/O Beijing/LOCATION also/O bring/O stability/O to/O the/O region/O ?/O 
With/O conflicts/O raging/O from/O Iran/LOCATION to/O Palestine/LOCATION and/O Syria/LOCATION to/O Iraq/LOCATION ,/O the/O events/O unfolding/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION are/O also/O being/O closely/O followed/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
And/O there/O is/O good/O reason/O for/O China/LOCATION 's/O interest/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
For/O the/O past/O two/O decades/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O engaging/O with/O the/O region/O for/O the/O same/O main/O reason/O as/O other/O rising/O powers/O have/O :/O oil/O ./O 
More/O than/O half/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O oil/O imports/O -/O some/O 2.9/O million/O barrels/O per/O day/O -/O come/O from/O this/O part/O of/O the/O world/O ./O 
And/O like/O other/O growing/O ,/O industrializing/O powers/O ,/O China/LOCATION needs/O the/O energy/O resources/O to/O power/O its/O economic/O expansion/O ./O 
Even/O as/O China/LOCATION has/O focused/O on/O diversifying/O its/O energy/O suppliers/O by/O increasingly/O looking/O to/O Russia/LOCATION and/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION for/O oil/O and/O gas/O ,/O any/O instability/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION heavily/O impacts/O global/O prices/O ,/O thus/O harming/O a/O net/O importer/O of/O energy/O like/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O surpassed/O the/O US/LOCATION as/O the/O world/O 's/O largest/O importer/O in/O late/O 2013/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O US/ORGANIZATION Energy/ORGANIZATION Information/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O EIA/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O 
Driven/O by/O the/O rapid/O growth/O in/O oil/O and/O gas/O imports/O ,/O Chinese/O trade/O with/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION has/O risen/O from/O around/O 20/O billion/O USD/O a/O decade/O ago/O to/O an/O estimated/O 230/O billion/O USD/O last/O year/O ,/O with/O the/O trade/O volume/O expected/O to/O exceed/O 500/O billion/O USD/O by/O 2020/O ./O 
Around/O 70/O percent/O of/O this/O trade/O is/O currently/O conducted/O with/O the/O six/O Gulf/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O GCC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O countries/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION Arab/LOCATION Emirates/LOCATION ,/O Oman/LOCATION ,/O Bahrain/LOCATION ,/O Qatar/LOCATION ,/O Kuwait/LOCATION and/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ,/O the/O latter/O of/O which/O is/O China/LOCATION 's/O largest/O source/O of/O imported/O oil/O ,/O ahead/O of/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
The/O GCC/ORGANIZATION together/O accounts/O for/O around/O one-third/O of/O Chinese/O oil/O imports/O ./O 
Given/O the/O scale/O of/O the/O economic/O interests/O involved/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O stepped/O up/O its/O involvement/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION in/O a/O number/O of/O areas/O ./O 
Just/O recently/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION announced/O it/O would/O speed/O up/O free/O trade/O talks/O with/O the/O GCC/ORGANIZATION in/O a/O bid/O to/O cut/O costs/O of/O fuel/O imports/O ,/O which/O are/O key/O for/O the/O country/O 's/O energy/O security/O ./O 
While/O oil/O and/O gas/O remain/O China/LOCATION 's/O overriding/O economic/O interests/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O the/O Asian/O giant/O 's/O fast-growing/O economy/O is/O also/O looking/O for/O new/O markets/O for/O its/O exports/O ,/O particularly/O as/O developed/O economies/O experience/O slower/O growth/O ./O 
Sam/PERSON Chester/PERSON ,/O analyst/O at/O the/O global/O investment/O firm/O Clarity/ORGANIZATION Capital/ORGANIZATION ,/O explains/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O seeking/O innovative/O technologies/O to/O import/O ,/O consumers/O to/O export/O to/O ,/O and/O strategic/O positioning/O at/O global/O transportation/O routes/O ./O 
All/O these/O factors/O have/O pushed/O Chinese/O firms/O to/O expand/O across/O the/O region/O ,/O with/O 22/O percent/O of/O the/O companies/O '/O global/O investment/O flowing/O directly/O to/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION last/O year/O ./O 
Chester/PERSON points/O out/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O that/O Israel/LOCATION has/O become/O a/O magnet/O for/O Chinese/O investment/O into/O its/O technology/O sector/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O negotiations/O on/O a/O free/O trade/O deal/O with/O Israel/LOCATION are/O set/O to/O begin/O this/O year/O ./O 
Rajiv/PERSON Biswas/PERSON ,/O Asia-Pacific/O Chief/O Economist/O for/O IHS/O Global/O Insight/O ,/O told/O DW/O that/O Chinese/O firms/O have/O also/O been/O playing/O a/O significant/O role/O in/O infrastructure/O development/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O with/O an/O estimated/O 30/O billion/O USD/O invested/O in/O projects/O over/O the/O past/O decade/O ,/O ranging/O from/O telecommunication/O to/O retail/O malls/O ./O 
Another/O example/O is/O the/O Suez/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Trade/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Zone/ORGANIZATION in/O Egypt/LOCATION ./O 
Launched/O in/O 2009/O ,/O the/O special/O market/O zone/O is/O home/O to/O more/O than/O 30/O Chinese/O enterprises/O ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O become/O a/O marginal/O arms/O seller/O in/O the/O region/O and/O one/O of/O the/O leading/O proliferators/O of/O small/O arms/O in/O the/O world/O ,/O with/O Middle/O Eastern/O countries/O as/O top/O recipients/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Peace/ORGANIZATION ./O 
In/O light/O of/O this/O development/O ,/O Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O German/O Marshall/ORGANIZATION Fund/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O explains/O that/O almost/O every/O state/O in/O the/O region/O has/O sought/O to/O benefit/O from/O enhanced/O trade/O and/O investment/O with/O China/LOCATION ,/O while/O attempting/O to/O leverage/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O geopolitical/O heft/O --/O whether/O through/O support/O in/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION or/O a/O direct/O security/O relationship/O ,/O for/O instance/O for/O Chinese/O workers/O in/O those/O countries/O ./O 
``/O Even/O some/O US-friendly/O states/O disillusioned/O with/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O handling/O of/O the/O politics/O in/O the/O region/O have/O started/O to/O turn/O to/O China/LOCATION as/O a/O potential/O long-term/O alternative/O force/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O however/O modest/O it/O is/O for/O now/O in/O political/O and/O security/O terms/O ,/O ''/O Small/O told/O DW/O ./O 
The/O region/O 's/O view/O of/O China/LOCATION at/O the/O moment/O seems/O so/O positive/O that/O according/O to/O a/O recent/O Pew/O global/O poll/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O favorability/O in/O the/O region/O was/O higher/O than/O that/O of/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O 
Biswas/PERSON explains/O that/O Middle/O Eastern/O states/O mainly/O regard/O China/LOCATION as/O a/O rising/O global/O economic/O power/O and/O therefore/O as/O an/O increasingly/O important/O market/O for/O energy/O and/O other/O key/O regional/O exports/O ,/O such/O as/O petrochemicals/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O so/O far/O managed/O to/O keep/O consistently/O close/O relationships/O with/O major/O regional/O players/O such/O as/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ,/O Egypt/LOCATION and/O Israel/LOCATION ;/O and/O Turkish/O ties/O are/O in/O good/O order/O after/O a/O difficult/O period/O in/O the/O aftermath/O of/O the/O inter-communal/O violence/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION in/O 2009/O ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O as/O Biswas/PERSON points/O out/O ,/O China/LOCATION continues/O to/O regard/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O which/O has/O been/O shunned/O by/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O as/O an/O important/O source/O of/O oil/O ,/O and/O has/O indicated/O that/O it/O is/O seeking/O better/O military/O cooperation/O with/O the/O country/O ./O 
Nadine/PERSON Godehardt/PERSON ,/O an/O Asia/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SWP/O -RRB-/O ,/O has/O a/O similar/O view/O ./O 
The/O analyst/O argues/O that/O the/O Chinese/O have/O a/O rather/O pragmatic/O approach/O to/O dealing/O with/O every/O country/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION without/O having/O a/O clear/O political/O preference/O :/O ``/O The/O Chinese/O are/O talking/O to/O everyone/O -/O even/O with/O different/O factions/O within/O states/O -/O since/O they/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O annoy/O anyone/O ./O ''/O 
But/O while/O China/LOCATION has/O become/O what/O some/O would/O describe/O as/O an/O ``/O economic/O juggernaut/O ''/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O its/O political/O influence/O still/O remains/O minimal/O ./O 
That/O dichotomy/O -/O a/O Chinese/O foreign/O policy/O that/O is/O strong/O on/O economics/O ,/O light/O on/O politics/O -/O is/O what/O analyst/O Chester/PERSON describes/O as/O ``/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O global/O calling/O card/O ./O ''/O 
But/O the/O analyst/O also/O points/O out/O that/O this/O balancing/O act/O is/O especially/O hard/O to/O pull/O off/O in/O a/O region/O where/O politics/O too/O often/O trumps/O all/O ,/O and/O there/O is/O no/O shortage/O of/O sworn/O political/O enemies/O ./O 
So/O how/O has/O Beijing/LOCATION managed/O so/O far/O to/O brush/O off/O most/O requests/O of/O its/O regional/O partners/O to/O get/O more/O involved/O in/O regional/O political/O or/O security/O arrangements/O ?/O 
According/O to/O Chester/PERSON ,/O there/O are/O two/O main/O reasons/O for/O this/O :/O First/O ,/O the/O US/LOCATION political/O and/O security/O presence/O is/O still/O so/O strong/O in/O the/O region/O that/O there/O remains/O no/O acute/O need/O for/O China/LOCATION to/O shoulder/O more/O responsibilities/O in/O the/O near/O future/O ./O 
Second/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O relations/O with/O every/O Middle/LOCATION Eastern/LOCATION state/O are/O asymmetric/O ,/O Chester/PERSON argues/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION is/O always/O the/O much/O stronger/O partner/O in/O every/O relationship/O and/O as/O a/O result/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION sets/O the/O terms/O of/O its/O relations/O with/O its/O Arab/O ,/O Iranian/O ,/O Turkish/O and/O Israeli/O regional/O partners/O ./O ''/O 
Local/O partners/O are/O aware/O of/O this/O and/O so/O increasingly/O we/O can/O expect/O to/O see/O Jerusalem/LOCATION ,/O Cairo/LOCATION ,/O Riyadh/LOCATION ,/O Baghdad/LOCATION ,/O Tehran/LOCATION and/O Istanbul/LOCATION jockeying/O for/O influence/O in/O their/O respective/O bilateral/O relations/O with/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION expert/O added/O ./O 
Although/O China/LOCATION 's/O political/O interests/O in/O the/O region/O are/O mainly/O influenced/O by/O its/O resource/O needs/O ,/O the/O Arab/O Spring/O led/O the/O Chinese/O to/O partially/O re-examine/O their/O ways/O of/O dealing/O with/O the/O region/O ./O 
Before/O 2011/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION made/O little/O effort/O to/O understand/O or/O develop/O ties/O with/O domestic/O opposition/O groups/O and/O was/O far/O more/O reticent/O about/O its/O growing/O ties/O with/O Israel/LOCATION ./O 
But/O all/O this/O changed/O when/O Chinese/O workers/O were/O stranded/O at/O the/O onset/O of/O hostilities/O in/O Libya/LOCATION ./O 
Ever/O since/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O sought/O to/O expand/O ties/O with/O a/O range/O of/O groups/O -/O best/O seen/O in/O Iraq/LOCATION where/O Chinese/O firms/O and/O diplomats/O have/O reached/O out/O to/O wide/O range/O of/O parties/O -/O and/O has/O led/O Chinese/O officials/O and/O companies/O to/O openly/O embrace/O closer/O ties/O with/O Israel/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O direct/O military/O role/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION is/O modest/O ,/O but/O growing/O ./O 
As/O analyst/O Small/O points/O out/O ,/O the/O Libya/LOCATION evacuation/O was/O the/O first/O time/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O PLA/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O has/O sent/O assets/O to/O protect/O civilians/O in/O another/O region/O of/O the/O world/O ./O 
The/O rise/O of/O ``/O Islamic/O State/O ''/O -LRB-/O IS/O -RRB-/O has/O also/O made/O the/O region/O even/O more/O important/O to/O Chinese/O counter-terrorism/O concerns/O ,/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION claiming/O that/O hundreds/O of/O Chinese/O fighters/O have/O arrived/O in/O Syria/LOCATION and/O Iraq/LOCATION ,/O mostly/O Uighurs/O ,/O but/O even/O a/O small/O number/O of/O Hui/O Muslims/O ./O 
``/O Unlike/O al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O trod/O fairly/O carefully/O and/O tactically/O around/O China/LOCATION ,/O IS/O has/O included/O the/O `/O East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION '/O cause/O among/O its/O list/O of/O concerns/O and/O its/O leader/O ,/O Abu/PERSON Bakr/PERSON Al/PERSON Baghdadi/PERSON ,/O has/O made/O explicit/O reference/O to/O China/LOCATION in/O his/O speeches/O ,/O ''/O said/O Small/O ./O 
But/O will/O Beijing/LOCATION also/O leverage/O its/O significant/O ``/O soft/O power/O ''/O to/O help/O resolve/O conflicts/O in/O the/O region/O ?/O 
There/O are/O also/O many/O who/O believe/O Beijing/LOCATION could/O play/O a/O greater/O diplomatic/O role/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION Peace/O Process/O ,/O as/O the/O Palestinians/O view/O China/LOCATION as/O a/O more/O impartial/O actor/O ./O 
But/O so/O far/O these/O expectations/O have/O not/O been/O met/O ,/O with/O analysts/O arguing/O that/O ,/O in/O this/O context/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O still/O some/O way/O outside/O its/O comfort/O zone/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION still/O sees/O itself/O as/O a/O second-tier/O actor/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O not/O as/O one/O of/O the/O principal/O external/O powers/O influencing/O developments/O there/O ,/O ''/O said/O Small/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O tried/O to/O balance/O the/O geopolitics/O of/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION carefully/O ,/O accommodating/O but/O restraining/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION 's/O agenda/O on/O issues/O such/O as/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O and/O backing/O the/O Russian/O stance/O on/O issues/O such/O as/O Syria/LOCATION while/O attempting/O to/O portray/O itself/O as/O the/O more/O moderate/O ,/O balanced/O party/O in/O its/O backing/O for/O the/O government/O of/O Syrian/O President/O Bashar/PERSON al-Assad/PERSON 's/O government/O ,/O he/O argued/O ./O 
But/O this/O balancing/O act/O has/O been/O difficult/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O Chinese/O flags/O were/O set/O alight/O in/O various/O Arab/O capitals/O following/O the/O country/O 's/O veto/O of/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION resolutions/O on/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
In/O addition/O ,/O the/O country/O 's/O close/O relationship/O with/O Israel/LOCATION has/O been/O criticized/O by/O several/O Arab/O states/O ./O 
Chester/PERSON believes/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O not/O filling/O the/O political/O and/O security/O space/O maintained/O by/O the/O US/LOCATION even/O in/O situations/O where/O Washington/LOCATION has/O reduced/O its/O profile/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O he/O points/O out/O that/O a/O nation/O like/O Iraq/LOCATION ,/O where/O China/LOCATION has/O the/O largest/O investment/O in/O the/O country/O 's/O dominant/O oil/O industry/O ,/O remains/O dependent/O on/O the/O US/LOCATION for/O its/O political/O and/O security/O survival/O ./O 
``/O Even/O as/O the/O US/LOCATION has/O reduced/O its/O political/O and/O security/O commitments/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O made/O no/O inroads/O ./O ''/O 
As/O China/LOCATION 's/O energy/O imports/O from/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION continue/O to/O grow/O ,/O the/O country/O will/O seek/O to/O strengthen/O its/O economic/O and/O political/O ties/O with/O the/O region/O ./O 
But/O there/O is/O so/O far/O little/O evidence/O of/O any/O major/O security/O or/O defense/O pivot/O by/O China/LOCATION towards/O the/O region/O ./O 
``/O We/O are/O still/O not/O yet/O at/O the/O stage/O where/O China/LOCATION has/O an/O evolved/O political/O strategy/O for/O the/O region/O ,/O which/O still/O means/O that/O while/O its/O role/O as/O the/O region/O 's/O largest/O trade/O partner/O is/O clearly/O consequential/O it/O still/O punches/O below/O its/O weight/O there/O in/O diplomatic/O and/O security/O terms/O ,/O ''/O said/O Small/O ./O 
