Thai/O police/O have/O confirmed/O that/O they/O were/O warned/O by/O Russian/O intelligence/O about/O possible/O ``/O IS/O ''/O attacks/O on/O tourists/O ./O 
Thailand/LOCATION has/O increased/O security/O around/O popular/O tourist/O spots/O as/O its/O holiday/O high/O season/O begins/O ./O 
The/O authenticity/O of/O a/O leaked/O police/O memo/O containing/O a/O Russian/O intelligence/O warning/O was/O confirmed/O by/O Thai/O officials/O on/O Friday/O ./O 
The/O memo/O states/O that/O ten/O Syrians/O linked/O to/O the/O terrorist/O group/O ``/O Islamic/O State/O ''/O -LRB-/O IS/O -RRB-/O entered/O Thailand/LOCATION in/O October/O with/O the/O goal/O of/O attacking/O Russian/O interests/O ./O 
National/O police/O deputy/O spokesman/O Col./O Songpol/PERSON Wattanachai/PERSON confirmed/O the/O authenticity/O of/O the/O document/O while/O telling/O reporters/O that/O the/O details/O of/O the/O intelligence/O have/O not/O been/O verified/O ./O 
Deputy/O police/O spokesman/O ,/O Krissana/PERSON Phattanacharoen/PERSON ,/O confirmed/O ``/O the/O content/O of/O -LRB-/O the/O -RRB-/O letter/O is/O genuine/O ''/O ,/O but/O down/O played/O the/O danger/O posed/O to/O a/O specific/O country/O ./O 
``/O Yes/O it/O 's/O a/O threat/O ,/O not/O only/O to/O my/O country/O but/O also/O to/O other/O countries/O as/O well/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
The/O police/O memo/O ,/O which/O was/O dated/O November/O 17/O and/O marked/O as/O ``/O urgent/O ''/O and/O ``/O confidential/O ,/O ''/O cites/O a/O warning/O from/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Service/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O FSB/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O which/O said/O :/O ``/O They/O -LRB-/O the/O Syrians/O -RRB-/O travelled/O separately/O ./O 
Four/O went/O to/O Pattaya/LOCATION ,/O two/O to/O Phuket/LOCATION ,/O two/O to/O Bangkok/LOCATION and/O the/O other/O two/O to/O -LRB-/O an/O -RRB-/O unknown/O location/O ./O ''/O 
``/O The/O objectives/O of/O these/O people/O are/O to/O cause/O harm/O to/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O assets/O or/O those/O of/O its/O allies/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O the/O memo/O ./O 
Special/O Branch/O police/O within/O the/O document/O also/O urged/O for/O stronger/O security/O around/O areas/O which/O are/O popular/O for/O vacationers/O from/O IS/O opponent/O countries/O ,/O specifically/O :/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O Britain/LOCATION ,/O France/LOCATION ,/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O Sweden/LOCATION and/O Australia/LOCATION ./O 
Thai/O officials/O also/O announced/O on/O Friday/O that/O they/O have/O heightened/O security/O at/O all/O popular/O tourist/O spots/O ,/O but/O especially/O the/O island/O of/O Phuket/LOCATION ./O 
More/O than/O 1.6/O million/O Russian/O tourists/O visited/O Thailand/LOCATION in/O 2014/O ./O 
The/O vacation/O high-season/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION has/O just/O begun/O ,/O with/O numbers/O expected/O to/O spike/O during/O Christmas/O and/O New/O Year/O ./O 
``/O We/O have/O increased/O the/O number/O of/O officers/O at/O our/O patrols/O in/O tourist/O areas/O and/O will/O follow/O up/O on/O every/O lead/O ,/O ''/O officer-in-charge/O Kem/PERSON Junmookda/PERSON told/O the/O German/O news/O agency/O DPA/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O There/O is/O no/O reason/O to/O panic/O ./O 
Increased/O security/O measures/O have/O already/O been/O in/O place/O since/O the/O bomb/O attack/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION in/O August/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
in/O August/O ,/O with/O the/O attack/O being/O linked/O to/O militants/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION minority/O ./O 
There/O has/O been/O little/O sign/O of/O IS/O activity/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION until/O now/O ,/O but/O experts/O believe/O that/O IS/O cells/O in/O other/O Southeast/LOCATION Asian/LOCATION countries/O are/O becoming/O more/O serious/O and/O established/O ./O 
Starting/O in/O September/O ,/O Russia/LOCATION launched/O air/O strikes/O against/O IS/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
One/O month/O later/O ,/O a/O Russian/O passenger/O plane/O was/O downed/O after/O who/O were/O mainly/O Russian/O vacationers/O ./O 
rs/rc/O -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O dpa/O ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 
