Thai/O police/O say/O a/O key/O suspect/O now/O in/O custody/O handed/O an/O explosive/O device/O in/O a/O backpack/O to/O a/O man/O who/O allegedly/O carried/O out/O a/O deadly/O attack/O on/O a/O Bangkok/LOCATION shrine/O last/O month/O ./O 
The/O motive/O for/O the/O blast/O remains/O unclear/O ./O 
Thai/O police/O said/O on/O Wednesday/O that/O a/O foreign/O national/O in/O last/O month/O 's/O deadly/O bombing/O at/O a/O popular/O Hindu/O shrine/O in/O the/O capital/O ,/O Bangkok/LOCATION ,/O has/O admitted/O to/O handing/O the/O alleged/O bomber/O a/O backpack/O containing/O a/O bomb/O just/O before/O the/O blast/O took/O place/O ./O 
``/O This/O is/O the/O area/O where/O he/O met/O the/O man/O in/O a/O yellow/O shirt/O to/O exchange/O the/O backpack/O ,/O ''/O national/O police/O spokesman/O Prawu/PERSON Thavornsiri/PERSON told/O reporters/O outside/O a/O Bangkok/LOCATION railway/O station/O ,/O where/O police/O were/O carrying/O out/O a/O reenactment/O of/O the/O suspect/O 's/O alleged/O movements/O before/O and/O after/O the/O bombing/O ./O 
A/O man/O wearing/O a/O yellow/O shirt/O was/O apparently/O placing/O the/O backpack/O at/O the/O shrine/O moments/O before/O the/O blast/O ./O 
The/O suspect/O ,/O 25-year-old/O Yusufu/PERSON Mierili/PERSON ,/O whose/O name/O has/O appeared/O in/O several/O variants/O ,/O is/O one/O of/O two/O foreign/O nationals/O detained/O under/O suspicion/O of/O involvement/O in/O which/O killed/O 20/O people/O ,/O mostly/O ethnic/O Chinese/O tourists/O ,/O at/O the/O well-known/O Erawan/LOCATION Shrine/LOCATION on/O the/O night/O of/O August/O 17/O ./O 
Mierili/PERSON was/O arrested/O last/O week/O at/O the/O Thai-Cambodia/O border/O in/O possession/O of/O a/O Chinese/O passport/O ./O 
Police/O say/O he/O has/O admitted/O playing/O a/O central/O role/O in/O the/O attack/O ,/O although/O his/O motive/O remains/O unclear/O ./O 
He/O has/O not/O yet/O been/O formally/O charged/O ./O 
Mierili/PERSON told/O police/O he/O had/O brought/O the/O backpack/O from/O an/O apartment/O in/O the/O Nong/LOCATION Chok/LOCATION district/O on/O the/O edge/O of/O Bangkok/LOCATION ./O 
in/O an/O apartment/O in/O Nong/PERSON Chok/PERSON during/O a/O raid/O on/O August/O 29/O during/O which/O the/O other/O foreign/O suspect/O was/O arrested/O ./O 
put/O forward/O is/O that/O the/O attack/O may/O have/O been/O to/O avenge/O the/O forced/O repatriation/O by/O Thailand/LOCATION of/O 109/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O to/O China/LOCATION in/O July/O ./O 
Police/O have/O said/O that/O the/O Chinese/O passport/O held/O by/O Mierili/PERSON gave/O his/O birthplace/O as/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O home/O to/O the/O Uighur/ORGANIZATION Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O ,/O which/O has/O long/O reported/O facing/O persecution/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Public/O reenactments/O before/O the/O media/O are/O a/O common/O feature/O of/O Thai/O criminal/O investigations/O ./O 
Critics/O of/O the/O practice/O say/O they/O imply/O a/O suspect/O 's/O guilt/O before/O the/O trial/O ./O 
tj/jil/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 
