China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION have/O been/O described/O as/O ``/O all/O weather/O friends/O ,/O ''/O but/O the/O nature/O of/O their/O ties/O remains/O secretive/O ./O 
DW/O talks/O to/O analyst/O Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON ,/O about/O some/O of/O the/O most/O sensitive/O aspects/O of/O this/O strategic/O relationship/O ./O 
Andrew/O Small/O :/O Although/O much/O of/O the/O language/O used/O to/O describe/O ties/O between/O the/O two/O sides/O can/O sound/O hyperbolic/O 鈥/O ``/O all-weather/O friends/O ,/O ''/O ``/O deeper/O than/O the/O deepest/O ocean/O ,/O ''/O ``/O sweeter/O than/O honey/O ''/O 鈥/O it/O reflects/O the/O unusual/O nature/O of/O a/O secretive/O relationship/O that/O is/O the/O only/O real/O friendship/O that/O either/O side/O has/O ./O 
Founded/O on/O a/O shared/O enmity/O for/O India/LOCATION ,/O the/O relationship/O has/O in/O some/O respects/O run/O deeper/O than/O formal/O alliances/O ,/O especially/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O nuclear/O cooperation/O ,/O and/O has/O been/O remarkably/O resilient/O over/O the/O dramatic/O economic/O and/O geopolitical/O shifts/O of/O the/O last/O few/O decades/O ./O 
China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION have/O never/O been/O treaty/O allies/O ,/O do/O not/O share/O any/O cultural/O reference/O points/O or/O values/O ,/O and/O even/O their/O militaries/O come/O from/O radically/O different/O traditions/O ./O 
Recent/O years/O have/O seen/O tensions/O over/O matters/O such/O as/O Uighur/O militants/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O Chinese/O fears/O about/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O ``/O Islamization/O ./O ''/O 
Yet/O the/O deep-rooted/O strategic/O alignment/O remains/O strong/O ,/O and/O all/O the/O more/O so/O as/O the/O stabilization/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O periphery/O becomes/O more/O important/O ,/O as/O the/O terrorist/O threat/O in/O China/LOCATION worsens/O ,/O and/O as/O China/LOCATION 's/O need/O grows/O for/O reliable/O partners/O who/O can/O help/O facilitate/O its/O take-off/O as/O a/O global/O power/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION has/O certainly/O been/O the/O greatest/O beneficiary/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O been/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O only/O wholly/O reliable/O arms/O supplier/O ,/O its/O diplomatic/O protector/O ,/O and/O is/O becoming/O an/O investor/O with/O a/O potentially/O transformative/O impact/O on/O the/O country/O 's/O fate/O ./O 
Given/O how/O important/O nuclear/O weapons/O are/O to/O the/O South/O Asian/O nation/O 's/O military/O capabilities/O and/O even/O identity/O ,/O the/O significance/O attached/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O essential/O role/O in/O the/O nuclear/O program/O can/O hardly/O be/O overstated/O ./O 
But/O China/LOCATION has/O derived/O advantage/O from/O the/O relationship/O too/O 鈥/O Pakistan/LOCATION has/O been/O a/O conduit/O for/O Beijing/LOCATION during/O its/O years/O of/O isolation/O ,/O and/O was/O a/O crucial/O intermediary/O for/O Beijing/LOCATION in/O establishing/O its/O relationship/O with/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O with/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ,/O and/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Its/O intelligence/O services/O '/O ties/O with/O militant/O groups/O in/O the/O region/O helped/O ,/O for/O many/O years/O ,/O to/O ensure/O that/O China/LOCATION was/O never/O a/O top-tier/O jihadi/O target/O ./O 
When/O China/LOCATION wants/O to/O establish/O naval/O facilities/O in/O a/O country/O it/O can/O trust/O in/O a/O crisis/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O the/O only/O reliable/O choice/O ./O 
But/O weighing/O benefits/O on/O a/O quid-pro-quo/O basis/O can/O be/O misleading/O -/O a/O strong/O ,/O capable/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O an/O asset/O to/O China/LOCATION in/O its/O own/O right/O ,/O given/O the/O Pakistani/O military/O 's/O continued/O desire/O to/O act/O as/O a/O counterbalance/O to/O India/LOCATION ./O 
Chinese/O support/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION acts/O as/O an/O important/O geopolitical/O investment/O ,/O whatever/O Pakistan/LOCATION gives/O in/O return/O ./O 
It/O is/O hard/O to/O avoid/O the/O fact/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O now/O a/O global/O power/O ,/O and/O Pakistan/LOCATION matters/O far/O less/O to/O China/LOCATION than/O vice/O versa/O -/O but/O as/O China/LOCATION debates/O shifts/O away/O from/O a/O non-aligned/O foreign/O policy/O ,/O and/O upgrades/O the/O importance/O of/O friends/O and/O allies/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O in/O a/O unique/O position/O ./O 
As/O one/O Chinese/O expert/O put/O it/O :/O ``/O If/O China/LOCATION decides/O to/O develop/O formal/O alliances/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION would/O be/O the/O first/O place/O we/O would/O turn/O ./O 
It/O may/O be/O the/O only/O place/O we/O could/O turn/O ./O ''/O 
China/LOCATION has/O been/O the/O principal/O source/O of/O external/O assistance/O for/O the/O Pakistani/O nuclear/O program/O 鈥/O crucial/O materials/O ,/O technical/O expertise/O ,/O bomb/O designs/O ,/O and/O even/O highly-enriched/O uranium/O -LRB-/O HEU/O -RRB-/O were/O provided/O by/O the/O Chinese/O side/O ,/O the/O only/O time/O a/O nuclear/O state/O has/O given/O HEU/O to/O a/O non-nuclear/O state/O for/O military/O use/O ./O 
China/LOCATION also/O sold/O ballistic/O missiles/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O helped/O the/O country/O develop/O its/O own/O capacities/O for/O missile/O production/O ./O 
The/O most/O important/O phase/O of/O cooperation/O on/O the/O nuclear/O program/O was/O in/O the/O 1980s/O ,/O during/O the/O earliest/O phase/O of/O the/O Pakistani/O program/O ,/O and/O for/O missile/O sales/O in/O the/O late/O 1980s/O and/O early/O 1990s/O ./O 
The/O initial/O details/O of/O the/O cooperation/O program/O between/O the/O two/O sides/O appear/O to/O have/O been/O agreed/O in/O the/O late/O 1970s/O and/O Chinese/O support/O has/O continued/O ever/O since/O ,/O even/O to/O the/O present/O day/O ./O 
Chinese/O backing/O for/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O program/O ensured/O that/O it/O could/O maintain/O its/O role/O as/O a/O balancer/O in/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION after/O India/LOCATION developed/O a/O bomb/O of/O its/O own/O ,/O continuing/O to/O keep/O Delhi/LOCATION strategically/O tied/O down/O by/O its/O western/O neighbor/O ./O 
China/LOCATION also/O hoped/O to/O benefit/O from/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O access/O to/O Western/O nuclear/O technologies/O 鈥/O such/O as/O European/O centrifuge/O designs/O 鈥/O given/O the/O deficiencies/O of/O its/O own/O nuclear/O program/O ,/O though/O in/O practice/O this/O does/O not/O appear/O to/O have/O translated/O into/O much/O benefit/O for/O the/O Chinese/O enrichment/O program/O ./O 
The/O willingness/O of/O both/O sides/O to/O cooperate/O on/O an/O area/O of/O such/O extreme/O sensitivity/O and/O crucial/O importance/O has/O provided/O much/O of/O the/O basis/O for/O the/O unusual/O level/O of/O trust/O that/O exists/O in/O the/O relationship/O 鈥/O as/O well/O as/O leaving/O Pakistan/LOCATION in/O China/LOCATION 's/O debt/O ./O 
China/LOCATION was/O initially/O concerned/O about/O the/O rise/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O who/O provided/O a/O safe/O haven/O for/O Uighur/O militant/O groups/O after/O they/O had/O taken/O power/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
At/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O instigation/O ,/O the/O two/O sides/O were/O able/O to/O reach/O an/O agreement/O 鈥/O following/O direct/O meetings/O by/O Chinese/O officials/O with/O Mullah/PERSON Omar/PERSON 鈥/O that/O saw/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION promise/O that/O their/O territory/O would/O n't/O be/O used/O for/O attacks/O on/O Chinese/O soil/O ,/O while/O China/LOCATION moved/O ahead/O with/O commercial/O cooperation/O ,/O modest/O arms/O sales/O ,/O and/O a/O degree/O of/O tacit/O recognition/O for/O the/O legitimacy/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION government/O ./O 
That/O deal/O has/O held/O ,/O and/O Chinese/O dealings/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION have/O continued/O ever/O since/O 鈥/O some/O Chinese/O officials/O claim/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O the/O only/O state/O other/O than/O Pakistan/LOCATION itself/O to/O maintain/O continuous/O contact/O with/O the/O Afghan/ORGANIZATION Taliban/ORGANIZATION leadership/O since/O 9/11/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O sought/O assurances/O from/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION that/O it/O will/O continue/O to/O distance/O itself/O from/O Uighur/O militant/O groups/O ,/O and/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION continues/O to/O benefit/O from/O some/O money/O ,/O some/O arms/O ,/O and/O a/O degree/O of/O political/O recognition/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
This/O now/O puts/O China/LOCATION in/O an/O important/O position/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O brokering/O reconciliation/O talks/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 鈥/O uniquely/O ,/O it/O is/O trusted/O by/O the/O Pakistanis/O ,/O the/O Afghan/O government/O ,/O and/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION leadership/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION does/O n't/O want/O to/O see/O a/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION takeover/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 鈥/O not/O least/O because/O they/O doubt/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O capacity/O to/O enforce/O the/O ``/O deal/O ''/O 鈥/O but/O does/O want/O to/O help/O facilitate/O a/O politically/O stable/O outcome/O there/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O role/O in/O this/O respect/O was/O very/O modest/O and/O very/O discreet/O but/O it/O has/O become/O more/O visible/O in/O recent/O months/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O certainly/O anxious/O about/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O future/O and/O the/O Chinese/O military/O 's/O planning/O for/O crises/O there/O reflects/O those/O fears/O ./O 
Some/O military/O intelligence/O officers/O put/O Pakistan/LOCATION second/O only/O to/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION in/O terms/O of/O the/O contingencies/O in/O regional/O states/O that/O worry/O China/LOCATION most/O ./O 
Chinese/O investments/O have/O been/O constrained/O by/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O instability/O and/O security/O threats/O to/O Chinese/O workers/O 鈥/O by/O some/O measures/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION has/O been/O the/O most/O dangerous/O place/O to/O be/O an/O overseas/O Chinese/O ./O 
There/O have/O also/O been/O tensions/O over/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O belief/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION has/O not/O been/O as/O robust/O in/O dealing/O with/O Uighur/O militants/O operating/O from/O its/O territory/O as/O China/LOCATION would/O have/O liked/O 鈥/O more/O members/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O terrorism/O ``/O hit/O list/O ''/O were/O killed/O by/O US/LOCATION drones/O than/O by/O the/O Pakistani/O army/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O some/O fears/O that/O this/O reflects/O rising/O Islamist/O sympathies/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION as/O a/O whole/O ,/O including/O in/O the/O army/O itself/O ./O 
The/O economic/O relationship/O has/O also/O been/O very/O weak/O 鈥/O many/O of/O the/O most/O ambitious/O plans/O have/O faltered/O for/O reasons/O that/O have/O as/O much/O to/O do/O with/O corruption/O and/O problems/O in/O the/O Pakistani/O economy/O as/O security/O threats/O ./O 
The/O two/O sides/O do/O n't/O even/O see/O eye-to-eye/O even/O on/O dealing/O with/O India/LOCATION 鈥/O China/LOCATION would/O like/O to/O see/O a/O relationship/O between/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION that/O is/O less/O volatile/O ,/O has/O a/O stronger/O economic/O component/O ,/O and/O more/O closely/O resembles/O the/O China-India/O relationship/O ./O 
The/O West/LOCATION has/O long/O sought/O to/O use/O China/LOCATION 's/O position/O of/O special/O influence/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O its/O advantage/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O one/O of/O the/O only/O countries/O with/O leverage/O over/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O during/O crises/O in/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION 鈥/O such/O as/O near-wars/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION 鈥/O Chinese/O diplomacy/O has/O played/O a/O crucial/O restraining/O role/O ./O 
Outside/O the/O context/O of/O crises/O ,/O however/O ,/O coordination/O with/O China/LOCATION has/O proved/O far/O more/O difficult/O ,/O and/O it/O has/O still/O tended/O to/O operate/O as/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O enabler/O and/O protector/O ,/O whether/O it/O comes/O to/O the/O use/O of/O groups/O such/O as/O Lashkar-e-Taiba/O or/O the/O rapidly/O growing/O Pakistani/O nuclear/O program/O ./O 
From/O an/O Indian/O perspective/O ,/O this/O is/O still/O the/O greatest/O concern/O ,/O and/O China/LOCATION is/O becoming/O less/O inhibited/O than/O it/O was/O in/O the/O past/O about/O certain/O sensitive/O areas/O of/O strategic/O support/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O such/O as/O the/O development/O of/O naval/O facilities/O or/O infrastructure/O projects/O in/O disputed/O Kashmir/LOCATION ./O 
In/O this/O respect/O ,/O the/O role/O of/O the/O China-Pakistan/O axis/O in/O the/O geopolitics/O of/O the/O region/O in/O tying/O India/LOCATION down/O in/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION is/O still/O central/O 鈥/O India/LOCATION wants/O to/O look/O east/O ,/O while/O China/LOCATION wants/O to/O ensure/O that/O it/O still/O has/O to/O keep/O a/O close/O eye/O on/O its/O west/O ./O 
But/O India/LOCATION ,/O the/O West/O and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION alike/O have/O some/O reason/O for/O hope/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O the/O role/O of/O the/O China-Pakistan/LOCATION relationship/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O future/O ./O 
China/LOCATION used/O to/O outsource/O its/O Afghanistan/LOCATION policy/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION but/O is/O now/O taking/O a/O far/O more/O active/O role/O in/O the/O planning/O for/O the/O aftermath/O of/O the/O West/O 's/O drawdown/O ./O 
While/O China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION will/O remain/O close/O partners/O there/O ,/O they/O do/O n't/O entirely/O see/O eye-to-eye/O 鈥/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O a/O greater/O interest/O than/O Islamabad/LOCATION in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O stability/O and/O expects/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O take/O Chinese/O concerns/O into/O account/O ./O 
In/O the/O past/O this/O might/O have/O remained/O a/O low/O priority/O matter/O for/O China/LOCATION but/O the/O escalation/O of/O terrorist/O attacks/O on/O the/O Chinese/O mainland/O has/O turned/O it/O into/O a/O top/O security/O concern/O ,/O and/O the/O hope/O is/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION will/O exert/O some/O degree/O of/O pressure/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O calculations/O ./O 
All/O sides/O ,/O including/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O will/O also/O benefit/O if/O China/LOCATION moves/O ahead/O with/O a/O major/O package/O of/O investment/O that/O could/O 鈥/O potentially/O 鈥/O help/O stabilize/O the/O Pakistani/O economy/O and/O its/O energy/O situation/O ,/O and/O turn/O it/O into/O a/O regional/O transshipment/O hub/O ./O 
Chinese/O investments/O are/O not/O purely/O for/O reasons/O of/O commerce/O or/O strategic/O economic/O geography/O 鈥/O China/LOCATION knows/O that/O its/O friend/O is/O facing/O an/O uncertain/O future/O and/O is/O prepared/O to/O make/O these/O commitments/O in/O part/O in/O order/O to/O help/O shore/O the/O country/O up/O ./O 
The/O relationship/O remains/O resilient/O ,/O and/O many/O of/O the/O pressures/O that/O might/O have/O been/O expected/O to/O derail/O it/O ,/O such/O as/O India/LOCATION 's/O rise/O ,/O or/O the/O growing/O threat/O of/O extremism/O ,/O have/O only/O served/O to/O emphasize/O its/O continued/O importance/O to/O Chinese/O interests/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION should/O be/O poised/O to/O benefit/O even/O more/O from/O the/O relationship/O in/O future/O 鈥/O the/O growing/O capabilities/O of/O the/O Chinese/O military/O hold/O out/O the/O promise/O of/O more/O advanced/O equipment/O ,/O and/O the/O vast/O financial/O resources/O that/O China/LOCATION can/O now/O bring/O to/O bear/O may/O finally/O transform/O the/O weakest/O element/O of/O the/O two/O sides/O '/O ties/O ./O 
The/O relationship/O hinges/O on/O what/O the/O Chinese/O describe/O as/O a/O secular-strategic/O rationale/O 鈥/O with/O India/LOCATION as/O its/O continued/O focal/O point/O 鈥/O and/O many/O of/O the/O economic/O plans/O still/O hinge/O on/O the/O security/O situation/O in/O various/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION should/O be/O one/O of/O the/O biggest/O winners/O from/O China/LOCATION 's/O rise/O as/O a/O global/O power/O but/O if/O its/O internal/O security/O deteriorates/O or/O if/O Chinese/O anxieties/O about/O the/O country/O 's/O political/O direction/O worsen/O ,/O it/O will/O be/O a/O great/O lost/O opportunity/O ./O 
./O 
