The/O Dalai/O Lama/O will/O join/O US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON at/O the/O National/O Prayer/O Breakfast/O ./O 
But/O while/O China/LOCATION strongly/O opposes/O the/O meeting/O ,/O analyst/O Robert/PERSON Barnett/PERSON tells/O DW/O tensions/O over/O the/O issue/O are/O likely/O to/O be/O short-lived/O ./O 
Obama/PERSON will/O meet/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON at/O the/O National/O Prayer/O Breakfast/O on/O Thursday/O ,/O February/O 5/O ,/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ./O 
It/O will/O be/O the/O fourth/O meeting/O between/O the/O two/O men/O and/O the/O first/O time/O they/O have/O been/O together/O in/O nearly/O a/O year/O ./O 
Each/O of/O the/O previous/O meetings/O has/O prompted/O objections/O from/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ,/O which/O regards/O the/O Tibetan/O spiritual/O leader/O an/O anti-Chinese/O separatist/O ./O 
According/O to/O media/O reports/O ,/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O will/O not/O have/O a/O speaking/O role/O at/O the/O prayer/O breakfast/O and/O will/O be/O seated/O with/O the/O audience/O ./O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O foreign/O ministry/O reacted/O by/O saying/O :/O ``/O We/O are/O opposed/O to/O any/O foreign/O leaders/O meeting/O with/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON in/O any/O form/O ./O ''/O 
China/LOCATION has/O ruled/O Tibet/LOCATION since/O 1950/O ,/O and/O many/O Tibetans/O feel/O their/O intensely/O Buddhist/O culture/O is/O at/O risk/O of/O erosion/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O political/O and/O economic/O domination/O ./O 
Robert/PERSON Barnett/PERSON Director/O of/O the/O Modern/ORGANIZATION Tibet/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION Program/ORGANIZATION at/O Columbia/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O says/O in/O a/O DW/O interview/O ,/O that/O while/O tensions/O in/O Sino-US/O ties/O are/O expected/O to/O rise/O due/O to/O this/O meeting/O ,/O they/O are/O likely/O to/O be/O very/O minor/O and/O short-lived/O as/O the/O two/O powers/O have/O far/O too/O much/O at/O stake/O to/O risk/O serious/O damage/O resulting/O from/O this/O issue/O ./O 
Robert/PERSON Barnett/PERSON :/O It/O is/O the/O public/O nature/O of/O this/O event/O that/O makes/O it/O important/O ./O 
But/O this/O importance/O is/O of/O an/O unusual/O and/O unequal/O kind/O ,/O because/O this/O event/O is/O much/O more/O important/O for/O the/O Chinese/O side/O than/O for/O the/O Americans/O ./O 
And/O this/O gives/O the/O US/LOCATION side/O and/O the/O Tibetans/O a/O diplomatic/O advantage/O in/O this/O instance/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O result/O of/O differing/O views/O about/O political/O symbolism/O ./O 
In/O the/O West/LOCATION ,/O encounters/O of/O this/O kind/O can/O be/O presented/O as/O relatively/O inconsequential/O rituals/O celebrating/O notional/O values/O or/O good/O will/O ,/O rather/O than/O concrete/O policies/O ./O 
But/O Chinese/O diplomats/O regard/O symbolic/O events/O as/O extremely/O significant/O politically/O ./O 
So/O they/O treat/O any/O public/O encounter/O between/O the/O US/LOCATION President/O and/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON as/O if/O it/O marked/O a/O major/O upgrade/O in/O official/O US/LOCATION support/O for/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON 's/O objectives/O ./O 
There/O has/O only/O been/O one/O such/O public/O meeting/O before/O ,/O which/O was/O when/O President/O Bush/PERSON awarded/O the/O Congressional/O Gold/O Medal/O to/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O in/O public/O in/O 2007/O ./O 
Though/O the/O Americans/O did/O not/O see/O this/O as/O a/O significant/O political/O event/O ,/O it/O was/O viewed/O as/O a/O very/O major/O setback/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O and/O they/O shifted/O their/O Tibet/LOCATION policy/O to/O a/O markedly/O tougher/O stance/O immediately/O afterwards/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O it/O then/O became/O clear/O that/O a/O major/O reason/O why/O Chinese/O officials/O had/O always/O complained/O so/O vociferously/O about/O private/O meetings/O in/O the/O past/O had/O been/O exactly/O to/O deter/O western/O leaders/O from/O ever/O agreeing/O to/O a/O public/O meeting/O ./O 
And/O till/O this/O week/O they/O surely/O believed/O that/O they/O had/O persuaded/O President/O Obama/PERSON not/O to/O go/O to/O that/O stage/O with/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ./O 
So/O this/O is/O an/O important/O moment/O for/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O a/O diplomatic/O rebuff/O ./O 
The/O National/O Prayer/O Breakfast/O is/O held/O by/O a/O number/O of/O US/LOCATION congressmen/O in/O February/O each/O year/O to/O celebrate/O their/O support/O for/O religious/O freedom/O ,/O and/O the/O President/O always/O attends/O it/O ./O 
So/O his/O attendance/O at/O the/O event/O can/O be/O seen/O as/O relating/O to/O religion/O rather/O than/O politics/O ,/O and/O as/O having/O no/O bearing/O on/O Sino-US/O policy/O ./O 
Indeed/O ,/O State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION officials/O have/O already/O pointed/O out/O that/O it/O is/O not/O even/O a/O meeting/O -/O it/O 's/O just/O an/O appearance/O by/O the/O two/O leaders/O at/O the/O same/O event/O ,/O at/O which/O they/O may/O not/O even/O speak/O more/O than/O a/O few/O words/O together/O ./O 
So/O this/O is/O a/O smart/O device/O for/O them/O ,/O actually/O much/O milder/O than/O a/O private/O meeting/O ,/O but/O at/O the/O same/O time/O sufficient/O to/O reassure/O their/O domestic/O audience/O that/O they/O have/O not/O yielded/O to/O Chinese/O pressure/O ./O 
This/O puts/O China/LOCATION 's/O diplomats/O in/O a/O somewhat/O awkward/O position/O ./O 
They/O will/O look/O overly/O aggressive/O abroad/O if/O they/O complain/O too/O much/O about/O an/O event/O that/O is/O clearly/O relatively/O minor/O for/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O but/O they/O will/O look/O unusually/O weak/O if/O they/O back/O down/O from/O their/O long-held/O principle/O of/O objecting/O aggressively/O to/O meetings/O of/O any/O kind/O between/O national/O leaders/O and/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ./O 
And/O this/O week/O they/O have/O already/O declared/O that/O this/O week/O 's/O encounter/O in/O DC/O is/O actually/O ``/O a/O meeting/O ''/O -/O so/O now/O Beijing/LOCATION can/O not/O easily/O retreat/O from/O the/O position/O that/O it/O has/O created/O for/O itself/O ./O 
The/O two/O leaders/O 鈥/O one/O political/O and/O one/O religious/O ,/O at/O least/O in/O theory/O 鈥/O are/O principal/O participants/O at/O the/O event/O ./O 
The/O President/O will/O give/O the/O keynote/O speech/O ,/O and/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON is/O expected/O to/O say/O a/O prayer/O ./O 
But/O the/O two/O may/O not/O speak/O together/O at/O all/O ,/O or/O only/O briefly/O ,/O and/O if/O they/O do/O ,/O it/O is/O most/O likely/O to/O be/O about/O the/O issue/O of/O religious/O freedom/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O event/O last/O year/O ,/O President/O Obama/PERSON in/O his/O speech/O listed/O countries/O where/O there/O are/O significant/O restrictions/O on/O religions/O ,/O and/O specifically/O mentioned/O the/O pressures/O faced/O by/O Tibetan/O Buddhists/O and/O Uighur/O Muslims/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
It/O was/O only/O one/O sentence/O ,/O but/O it/O was/O the/O main/O item/O in/O the/O media/O reports/O the/O next/O day/O ./O 
That/O is/O likely/O to/O be/O on/O the/O agenda/O for/O this/O year/O 's/O event/O as/O well/O ./O 
The/O President/O is/O going/O to/O reassure/O the/O Chinese/O at/O some/O point/O ,/O either/O in/O his/O speech/O or/O through/O a/O spokesman/O ,/O that/O his/O view/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O sovereignty/O over/O Tibet/LOCATION has/O not/O changed/O ,/O and/O that/O he/O does/O not/O support/O Tibetan/O independence/O ./O 
But/O otherwise/O the/O focus/O is/O likely/O to/O be/O on/O symbolism/O rather/O than/O content/O ./O 
The/O Dalai/O Lama/O had/O unusual/O success/O in/O the/O past/O 25/O years/O in/O getting/O the/O Tibetan/O issue/O onto/O the/O agenda/O of/O Western/O governments/O and/O the/O Western/O media/O ,/O and/O has/O met/O at/O least/O 71/O national/O leaders/O since/O 2000/O alone/O ./O 
This/O ,/O with/O other/O factors/O 鈥/O such/O as/O the/O popular/O support/O he/O received/O when/O first/O allowed/O to/O visit/O Taiwan/LOCATION in/O 1997/O 鈥/O led/O the/O Chinese/O to/O hold/O ten/O rounds/O of/O talks/O with/O his/O representatives/O over/O the/O eight/O years/O from/O 2002/O ./O 
But/O after/O 2008/O ,/O when/O major/O unrest/O broke/O out/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O policy/O in/O China/LOCATION became/O much/O more/O reactive/O and/O conservative/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O diplomacy/O in/O Western/LOCATION Europe/LOCATION became/O more/O aggressive/O and/O successful/O ,/O the/O talks/O with/O the/O exile/O Tibetans/O ground/O to/O a/O halt/O ,/O and/O the/O number/O of/O western/O leaders/O ready/O to/O receive/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O dropped/O to/O around/O two/O a/O year/O ./O 
So/O this/O shared/O event/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION President/O is/O of/O great/O significance/O to/O the/O exile/O Tibetans/O as/O a/O signal/O to/O China/LOCATION that/O the/O Tibet/LOCATION issue/O is/O still/O a/O live/O one/O for/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O one/O for/O which/O the/O US/LOCATION will/O risk/O at/O least/O a/O modicum/O of/O Chinese/O displeasure/O ./O 
That/O kind/O of/O messaging/O was/O relatively/O effective/O in/O the/O 1990s/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O not/O known/O whether/O it/O will/O work/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION today/O ,/O where/O there/O is/O a/O new/O and/O much/O more/O robust/O leadership/O than/O in/O the/O recent/O past/O ./O 
The/O Dalai/O Lama/O and/O his/O officials/O take/O the/O view/O that/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON will/O turn/O out/O to/O be/O more/O open/O to/O negotiation/O than/O his/O predecessors/O ,/O because/O of/O reports/O that/O his/O father/O was/O friendly/O towards/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON in/O the/O past/O ,/O and/O rumors/O that/O his/O wife/O or/O others/O near/O him/O might/O be/O sympathetic/O towards/O Buddhism/O ./O 
No-one/O knows/O whether/O or/O not/O Beijing/LOCATION will/O or/O will/O not/O move/O towards/O serious/O talks/O with/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O in/O the/O future/O ,/O or/O if/O western/O support/O will/O make/O this/O outcome/O more/O likely/O or/O less/O ./O 
China/LOCATION argues/O that/O for/O any/O politician/O to/O meet/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON in/O any/O capacity/O means/O that/O that/O politician/O supports/O Tibetan/O independence/O ./O 
This/O is/O ,/O for/O non-Chinese/O observers/O ,/O the/O oddest/O and/O most/O puzzling/O of/O their/O arguments/O ,/O because/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON gave/O up/O asking/O for/O independence/O twenty/O years/O ago/O ./O 
He/O has/O said/O since/O then/O that/O all/O he/O seeks/O is/O a/O ``/O high/O degree/O of/O autonomy/O ''/O or/O ``/O genuine/O autonomy/O ''/O for/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O which/O he/O accepts/O would/O be/O part/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
There/O is/O in/O fact/O a/O series/O of/O arguments/O that/O lies/O behind/O the/O Chinese/O accusation/O ./O 
According/O to/O that/O argument/O ,/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON asked/O for/O autonomy/O in/O the/O early/O 1950s/O ,/O but/O then/O changed/O to/O seeking/O independence/O in/O the/O 1960s/O and/O 1970s/O ./O 
Then/O ,/O in/O the/O late/O 1980s/O ,/O he/O stopped/O calling/O for/O independence/O ,/O but/O still/O asked/O for/O ``/O association/O ''/O between/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O a/O form/O of/O independence/O ./O 
So/O Chinese/O officials/O argue/O that/O these/O precedents/O are/O signs/O of/O duplicity/O ./O 
They/O often/O point/O to/O the/O fact/O that/O he/O still/O refers/O to/O Tibet/LOCATION as/O a/O country/O or/O level/O other/O accusations/O against/O him/O which/O they/O say/O show/O he/O is/O stirring/O up/O foreign/O powers/O to/O undermine/O China/LOCATION 's/O unity/O ./O 
Whether/O sound/O or/O not/O ,/O this/O view/O is/O not/O limited/O to/O officials/O and/O is/O very/O strongly/O felt/O within/O China/LOCATION ./O 
There/O are/O some/O observers/O who/O feel/O that/O the/O involvement/O of/O the/O Western/O powers/O in/O the/O Tibetan/O issue/O exacerbates/O tensions/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O leads/O to/O more/O repressive/O and/O defensive/O polices/O by/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Others/O argue/O that/O China/LOCATION will/O not/O make/O concessions/O to/O Tibetans/O without/O foreign/O pressure/O ./O 
But/O that/O pressure/O is/O seen/O as/O provocative/O by/O many/O people/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O probably/O the/O vast/O majority/O ./O 
So/O this/O argument/O is/O unresolved/O ./O 
There/O is/O also/O a/O thesis/O put/O forward/O by/O some/O Western/O scholars/O ,/O and/O by/O some/O Tibetans/O too/O ,/O that/O symbolic/O gestures/O of/O foreign/O support/O are/O counter-productive/O or/O even/O damaging/O ./O 
News/O of/O the/O event/O this/O week/O will/O be/O relayed/O into/O Tibet/LOCATION by/O Tibetan-language/O and/O Chinese-language/O radio/O stations/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O so/O people/O will/O know/O about/O it/O and/O many/O will/O quietly/O celebrate/O it/O ./O 
But/O ,/O according/O to/O this/O argument/O ,/O this/O risks/O leading/O some/O Tibetans/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION to/O believe/O that/O Western/O support/O is/O significant/O and/O practical/O 鈥/O although/O it/O is/O clear/O to/O outsiders/O that/O it/O is/O only/O moral/O or/O symbolic/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O Tibetans/O might/O sacrifice/O themselves/O or/O stage/O immensely/O dangerous/O protest/O under/O a/O false/O impression/O that/O effective/O support/O will/O come/O to/O their/O aid/O in/O the/O form/O of/O major/O Western/O pressure/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
It/O will/O lead/O to/O some/O tensions/O ,/O but/O these/O are/O likely/O to/O be/O very/O minor/O and/O short-lived/O 鈥/O these/O two/O powers/O have/O far/O too/O much/O at/O stake/O to/O risk/O serious/O damage/O accruing/O from/O this/O issue/O ./O 
And/O these/O days/O there/O are/O plenty/O of/O policy/O advisers/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION who/O will/O be/O arguing/O that/O a/O joint/O appearance/O at/O a/O Prayer/O Breakfast/O where/O nothing/O much/O is/O said/O is/O a/O domestic/O media/O exercise/O about/O which/O China/LOCATION need/O only/O make/O token/O complaints/O ./O 
We/O do/O n't/O know/O which/O side/O will/O dominate/O in/O this/O argument/O ,/O but/O we/O can/O be/O sure/O that/O it/O will/O take/O place/O ./O 
The/O optimum/O outcome/O of/O this/O event/O would/O be/O if/O it/O showed/O that/O the/O US/LOCATION has/O found/O a/O symbolic/O ,/O mild/O way/O to/O demonstrate/O robustness/O to/O its/O home/O audience/O and/O concerns/O to/O China/LOCATION regarding/O the/O situation/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION without/O damaging/O overall/O relations/O ./O 
