Beijing/LOCATION and/O the/O West/LOCATION share/O similar/O problems/O with/O Islamic/O terrorists/O ,/O but/O they/O deal/O with/O them/O differently/O ,/O writes/O DW/O columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O West/LOCATION ,/O terrorist/O attacks/O in/O Tunisia/LOCATION and/O France/LOCATION made/O last/O Friday/O a/O black/O day/O :/O 38/O dead/O in/O Sousse/LOCATION and/O a/O decapited/O businessman/O in/O Lyon/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O black/O day/O was/O on/O Monday/O of/O last/O week/O ,/O with/O a/O death/O toll/O of/O 28/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION ./O 
Uighurs/O armed/O with/O knives/O and/O explosives/O killed/O several/O policemen/O who/O opened/O fire/O on/O the/O assailants/O at/O a/O police/O checkpoint/O ./O 
Most/O of/O the/O dead/O are/O said/O to/O be/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O who/O belong/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O ./O 
The/O situation/O is/O not/O as/O clear/O as/O in/O Tunis/LOCATION ./O 
While/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O mostly/O remained/O silent/O about/O the/O case/O ,/O the/O West/LOCATION has/O provided/O transparent/O reports/O about/O the/O attacks/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ./O 
Yet/O neither/O the/O West/O ,/O nor/O China/LOCATION ,/O has/O a/O grip/O on/O Islam-related/O terrorism/O ./O 
Even/O a/O nation/O like/O China/LOCATION ,/O with/O its/O extensive/O surveillance/O systems/O ,/O has/O not/O succeeded/O ./O 
In/O spring/O -/O after/O months/O of/O tranquility/O -/O leaders/O in/O the/O troubled/O Chinese/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION announced/O that/O authorities/O had/O traced/O and/O broken/O up/O more/O than/O 180/O terrorist/O groups/O ./O 
The/O latest/O attack/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION must/O have/O greatly/O disappointed/O those/O who/O have/O tried/O to/O tackle/O problems/O by/O using/O large-scale/O surveillance/O and/O tough/O action/O ./O 
Until/O now/O -/O apart/O from/O small/O towns/O -/O the/O capital/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O has/O been/O the/O main/O scene/O of/O attacks/O in/O the/O province/O ./O 
But/O even/O there/O ,/O it/O has/O quieted/O down/O lately/O after/O China/LOCATION weathered/O two/O years/O of/O terrorism/O in/O 2013/O and/O 2014/O ,/O the/O most/O intense/O phase/O in/O recent/O history/O It/O started/O in/O October/O ,/O 2013/O ,/O when/O a/O car/O bomb/O went/O off/O amid/O crowds/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O leaving/O its/O passengers/O and/O two/O tourists/O dead/O ./O 
Subsequently/O ,/O further/O attacks/O on/O the/O streets/O and/O squares/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION followed/O until/O March/O 1/O of/O last/O year/O ,/O when/O assailants/O yielding/O knives/O and/O cleavers/O killed/O 39/O people/O at/O the/O central/O train/O station/O in/O Kunming/LOCATION ,/O the/O capital/O of/O the/O central/O Chinese/O province/O of/O Yunnan/LOCATION ./O 
Since/O then/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O realized/O that/O it/O 's/O no/O longer/O dealing/O with/O just/O lone/O ,/O Muslim/O Uighur/O fanatics/O ,/O but/O that/O international/O terrorism/O has/O reached/O China/LOCATION ,/O even/O if/O the/O attacks/O were/O not/O sophisticated/O ./O 
The/O frightening/O statistics/O show/O that/O from/O 2010/O to/O the/O end/O of/O 2014/O ,/O 468/O people/O were/O killed/O and/O another/O 548/O injured/O in/O terrorist/O attacks/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION responded/O :/O Thousands/O of/O police/O and/O security/O forces/O were/O deployed/O to/O the/O streets/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O including/O personnel/O from/O cities/O in/O other/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
The/O government/O adopted/O a/O harsher/O tone/O :/O ``/O One/O must/O sweat/O more/O in/O peace/O to/O bleed/O less/O in/O war/O ''/O or/O ``/O terrorists/O must/O be/O trampled/O like/O rats/O ''/O were/O typical/O phrases/O used/O by/O leaders/O ./O 
When/O they/O set/O bounties/O for/O suspicious-looking/O people/O ,/O or/O people/O with/O long/O beards/O ,/O authorities/O revealed/O their/O own/O fears/O and/O insecurity/O ./O 
Even/O the/O arrest/O of/O Uighur/O lawyer/O Ilham/PERSON Tothi/PERSON -LRB-/O headline/O picture/O -RRB-/O in/O September/O 2014/O did/O not/O change/O anything/O :/O Tothi/PERSON supported/O the/O Uighur/O minority/O ,/O but/O always/O affirmed/O that/O he/O was/O not/O an/O advocate/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION 's/O independence/O from/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION ./O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O he/O was/O sentenced/O to/O life/O imprisonment/O for/O incitement/O of/O ethnic/O hatred/O ./O 
This/O verdict/O may/O have/O created/O an/O involuntary/O martyr/O and/O perhaps/O even/O provoked/O further/O acts/O of/O terrorism/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
While/O these/O methods/O do/O not/O match/O with/O political/O ideas/O in/O the/O West/LOCATION ,/O there/O are/O parallels/O to/O other/O measures/O :/O In/O the/O future/O ,/O Chinese/O soldiers/O will/O also/O be/O sent/O abroad/O to/O fight/O against/O terrorist/O groups/O ,/O as/O long/O as/O they/O are/O given/O permission/O by/O the/O country/O in/O which/O they/O are/O deployed/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION and/O the/O West/O could/O well/O collaborate/O in/O such/O operations/O ./O 
However/O ,/O past/O foreign/O intervention/O missions/O have/O shown/O 鈥/O especially/O in/O the/O USA/LOCATION 鈥/O how/O tricky/O this/O could/O be/O in/O practice/O :/O In/O the/O end/O ,/O the/O chaos/O is/O often/O greater/O than/O before/O an/O operation/O ./O 
Another/O type/O of/O cooperation/O would/O make/O more/O sense/O :/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O attempting/O to/O stabilize/O poor/O regions/O by/O providing/O extensive/O economic/O aid/O ./O 
The/O expanded/O ,/O New/LOCATION Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION will/O run/O through/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O region/O bordering/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION aims/O to/O raise/O the/O standards/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O poorer/O west/O to/O those/O of/O the/O wealthier/O coastal/O areas/O in/O the/O east/O by/O implementing/O infrastructure/O projects/O and/O granting/O subsidies/O ./O 
In/O early/O 2014/O the/O security/O budget/O of/O the/O provincial/O government/O was/O raised/O to/O one/O billion/O US/O dollars/O -LRB-/O 895/O millon/O euros/O -RRB-/O ./O 
And/O ,/O in/O addition/O to/O high-speed/O trains/O and/O new/O highways/O ,/O a/O new/O project/O was/O officially/O given/O the/O green/O light/O last/O week/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION :/O Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O set/O to/O become/O a/O main/O location/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O textile/O industry/O by/O 2020/O ./O 
More/O than/O one/O million/O jobs/O will/O be/O created/O over/O the/O next/O eight/O years/O :/O In/O other/O words/O ,/O make/O wares/O ,/O not/O wars/O ./O 
The/O strategy/O is/O to/O develop/O the/O economy/O and/O thus/O deprive/O the/O terrorists/O of/O their/O support/O within/O the/O population/O ;/O the/O reasoning/O behind/O this/O being/O that/O people/O who/O are/O doing/O well/O financially/O will/O lose/O interest/O in/O suicide/O attacks/O ./O 
Even/O the/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O not/O completely/O certain/O of/O the/O strategy/O 's/O success/O ,/O but/O an/O attempt/O is/O definitely/O worth/O the/O effort/O ./O 
And/O in/O any/O case/O ,/O it/O would/O be/O useful/O to/O explore/O the/O extent/O to/O which/O the/O West/O and/O China/LOCATION can/O fight/O side/O by/O side/O against/O terrorism/O ./O 
