Cooperating/O with/O China/LOCATION to/O combat/O the/O self-proclaimed/O 鈥淚slamic/O State鈥/O would/O be/O easier/O if/O China/LOCATION was/O more/O constitutional/O ,/O says/O DW鈥檚/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON ./O 
After/O the/O deadly/O attacks/O in/O Paris/LOCATION ,/O landmarks/O in/O more/O than/O 60/O cities/O around/O the/O world/O paid/O tribute/O in/O lights/O ./O 
The/O Oriental/LOCATION Pearl/LOCATION Tower/LOCATION in/O Shanghai/LOCATION joined/O in/O ,/O lit/O up/O over/O the/O weekend/O in/O the/O French/O tricolore/O of/O red/O ,/O white/O and/O blue/O to/O show/O support/O 鈥/O an/O unprecedented/O action/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
As/O expected/O ,/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON denounced/O the/O attacks/O as/O 鈥渂arbaric/O terrorist/O acts鈥/O and/O expressed/O his/O condolences/O on/O Saturday/O ,/O just/O moments/O before/O traveling/O to/O the/O G-20/O summit/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
Xi/O also/O expressed/O China/LOCATION 's/O commitment/O to/O work/O closely/O with/O other/O countries/O against/O terrorism/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION combats/O the/O ``/O Islamic/O State/O ''/O -LRB-/O ``/O IS/O ''/O -RRB-/O along/O the/O country/O 's/O western/O borders/O with/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
It/O was/O not/O a/O coincidence/O that/O ,/O on/O Saturday/O ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O state-controlled/O media/O published/O rare/O images/O of/O armed/O units/O fighting/O against/O terrorist/O groups/O in/O the/O problematic/O western/O region/O of/O Xingjiang/LOCATION ./O 
The/O images/O showed/O policemen/O in/O full/O black/O armor/O ready/O to/O seize/O a/O house/O in/O a/O rural/O area/O ./O 
The/O caption/O read/O :/O 鈥淧aris/O has/O been/O attacked/O in/O one/O of/O the/O worst/O terrorist/O acts/O in/O history/O ,/O injuring/O and/O killing/O hundreds/O ./O 
On/O the/O other/O side/O of/O the/O world/O ,/O Chinese/O policemen/O successfully/O take/O down/O a/O terrorist/O operation/O after/O 56/O days/O of/O pursuit.鈥/O The/O images/O came/O from/O a/O state/O security-run/O microblog/O ./O 
./O 
The/O message/O may/O work/O in/O China/LOCATION but/O not/O in/O the/O West/LOCATION ./O 
If/O anything/O ,/O it/O is/O not/O perceived/O with/O gratitude/O or/O reassurance/O ,/O but/O with/O worry/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O authorities/O deal/O with/O non-violent/O minorities/O and/O protesters/O the/O same/O way/O that/O the/O West/O deals/O with/O terrorists/O :/O shoot/O first/O ,/O ask/O questions/O later/O ./O 
Alleged/O sympathizers/O and/O masterminds/O are/O met/O with/O the/O same/O fate/O ./O 
The/O arrest/O of/O Professor/O Ilham/PERSON Tothi/PERSON last/O year/O is/O just/O one/O example/O ./O 
He/O received/O a/O life/O sentence/O after/O a/O simple/O two-day/O trial/O ,/O accused/O of/O establishing/O a/O 鈥渃riminal/O syndicate鈥/O for/O Uyghur/O separatism/O ./O 
True/O or/O not/O ,/O the/O conviction/O is/O incomprehensible/O ./O 
While/O on/O one/O hand/O the/O sentence/O works/O as/O a/O deterrent/O ,/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O Tothi鈥榮/O sentence/O is/O perceived/O as/O such/O an/O injustice/O that/O even/O moderate/O Chinese/O Muslims/O have/O gone/O into/O hiding/O ./O 
They/O are/O also/O now/O prepared/O to/O resort/O to/O violence/O more/O than/O before/O ./O 
Their/O anger/O towards/O the/O unconstitutional/O actions/O of/O the/O state/O security/O and/O party/O grows/O large/O ./O 
Since/O the/O massacre/O in/O Paris/LOCATION ,/O Europe/LOCATION 's/O desire/O for/O tough/O action/O is/O as/O widespread/O as/O ever/O and/O reminiscent/O of/O America/LOCATION 's/O response/O after/O the/O September/O 11/O terrorist/O attacks/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O drastic/O measures/O and/O France/LOCATION 's/O state/O of/O emergency/O though/O differ/O significantly/O ./O 
French/O authorities/O are/O allowed/O to/O search/O homes/O ,/O arrest/O suspects/O without/O warrants/O ,/O and/O ,/O just/O like/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O to/O break/O up/O gatherings/O and/O impose/O curfews/O ./O 
Yet/O the/O victims/O have/O the/O opportunity/O to/O pursue/O legal/O action/O and/O turn/O to/O the/O media/O to/O express/O their/O complaints/O ./O 
There/O is/O at/O least/O the/O possibility/O to/O punish/O authorities/O for/O an/O excessive/O use/O of/O force/O ,/O whereas/O in/O China/LOCATION there/O is/O no/O such/O recourse/O ./O 
This/O makes/O Beijing/LOCATION one/O of/O the/O most/O complicated/O allies/O in/O the/O fight/O against/O the/O so-called/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O alliance/O depends/O on/O how/O threatened/O China/LOCATION is/O by/O the/O IS/O and/O how/O long/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O West/O remain/O on/O the/O same/O page/O regarding/O terrorism/O ./O 
The/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION declared/O China/LOCATION as/O being/O one/O of/O the/O biggest/O enemies/O of/O Islam/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O end/O of/O last/O year/O ./O 
Ever/O since/O then/O ,/O more/O attacks/O have/O been/O carried/O out/O ./O 
Last/O summer/O there/O were/O knife/O attacks/O at/O a/O train/O station/O in/O Kunming/LOCATION and/O at/O a/O market/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O killing/O over/O 30/O people/O ./O 
Most/O of/O the/O victims/O ,/O just/O like/O those/O in/O Paris/LOCATION ,/O were/O killed/O for/O being/O at/O the/O wrong/O place/O at/O the/O wrong/O time/O ./O 
In/O October/O ,/O the/O Uyghur/O people/O were/O the/O victims/O ./O 
A/O knife/O attack/O killed/O 50/O employees/O and/O five/O policemen/O at/O a/O coal/O mine/O in/O the/O Aksu/PERSON prefecture/O ./O 
There/O is/O something/O Beijing/LOCATION can/O be/O upset/O about/O :/O the/O lack/O of/O solidarity/O shown/O by/O the/O West/LOCATION after/O the/O attacks/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
In/O both/O occasions/O ,/O innocent/O people/O were/O victims/O of/O barbaric/O terrorist/O actions/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O every/O right/O to/O be/O displeased/O ,/O especially/O as/O most/O Chinese/O are/O convinced/O that/O the/O West/LOCATION is/O responsible/O for/O the/O growth/O of/O IS/O after/O the/O wars/O in/O Iraq/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O military/O meddling/O in/O Libya/LOCATION ,/O Egypt/LOCATION and/O Syria/LOCATION ,/O and/O isolation/O of/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION regards/O the/O West/LOCATION 's/O military/O efforts/O to/O bring/O balance/O to/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION as/O dangerous/O and/O na茂ve/O ,/O an/O assessment/O which/O is/O not/O wrong/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O relied/O on/O negotiations/O and/O economic/O cooperation/O for/O years/O to/O stabilize/O the/O region/O ,/O making/O sure/O that/O no/O group/O gains/O too/O much/O power/O ./O 
An/O increasing/O number/O of/O politicians/O from/O the/O West/O are/O starting/O to/O see/O China/LOCATION 's/O approach/O as/O rational/O ./O 
The/O pressure/O to/O work/O along/O China/LOCATION has/O become/O stronger/O and/O the/O G-20/O summit/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION is/O just/O another/O example/O of/O it/O ./O 
Cooperating/O with/O China/LOCATION to/O combat/O terrorism/O would/O certainly/O be/O easier/O if/O China/LOCATION were/O to/O be/O more/O constitutional/O ./O 
