Pakistani/O PM/O Sharif/PERSON has/O inaugurated/O a/O two-day/O China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION summit/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O hailing/O the/O project/O as/O a/O milestone/O for/O his/O country/O ./O 
But/O opposition/O to/O the/O project/O is/O increasing/O amid/O new/O conflicts/O ./O 
Addressing/O the/O inaugural/O session/O of/O the/O two-day/O CPEC/O Summit/O in/O the/O Pakistani/O capital/O Islamabad/LOCATION on/O Monday/O ,/O August/O 29/O ,/O Prime/O Minister/O Nawaz/PERSON Sharif/PERSON said/O the/O project/O would/O be/O a/O ``/O game-changer/O ''/O for/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
He/O said/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION would/O also/O bring/O peace/O and/O prosperity/O to/O the/O entire/O region/O ./O 
Last/O year/O ,/O China/LOCATION announced/O an/O economic/O project/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION worth/O $/O 46/O billion/O -LRB-/O 41/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O ./O 
With/O Beijing/LOCATION aims/O to/O expand/O its/O influence/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O across/O Central/O and/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION in/O order/O to/O counter/O US/LOCATION and/O Indian/O influence/O ./O 
The/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION would/O link/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O southern/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ./O 
It/O also/O includes/O plans/O to/O create/O road/O ,/O rail/O and/O oil/O pipeline/O links/O to/O improve/O connectivity/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION is/O grappling/O with/O an/O acute/O economic/O crisis/O ./O 
Experts/O say/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION can/O certainly/O stir/O the/O much-needed/O economic/O activity/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
But/O the/O project/O has/O been/O strongly/O opposed/O by/O local/O communities/O ,/O ethnic/O groups/O and/O leaders/O of/O the/O smaller/O provinces/O who/O say/O that/O the/O bigger/O Punjab/LOCATION province/O want/O to/O reap/O all/O the/O benefits/O while/O using/O their/O lands/O and/O resources/O to/O implement/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION ./O 
From/O the/O northern/O Gilgit-Balitistan/LOCATION region/O to/O the/O western/O Balochistan/LOCATION and/O southern/O Sindh/O provinces/O ,/O the/O signs/O of/O an/O imminent/O conflict/O between/O Islamabad/LOCATION and/O local/O groups/O are/O already/O emerging/O ./O 
Syed/PERSON Masood/PERSON Alam/PERSON ,/O an/O expert/O based/O in/O the/O northwestern/O Waziristan/LOCATION region/O ,/O told/O DW/O that/O the/O military/O and/O civilian/O establishments/O had/O changed/O the/O route/O of/O the/O economic/O corridor/O for/O the/O benefit/O of/O the/O Punjab/LOCATION 鈥/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O most/O populous/O and/O politically/O strongest/O province/O ./O 
``/O The/O people/O of/O Khyber/O Pakhtunkhwa/O ,/O Gilgit-Baltistan/PERSON ,/O Balochistan/LOCATION and/O Sindh/O provinces/O are/O against/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION in/O its/O present/O form/O ./O 
We/O will/O go/O to/O any/O extent/O to/O oppose/O it/O ./O 
The/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION could/O even/O lead/O to/O violence/O and/O bloodshed/O in/O the/O country/O if/O the/O government/O did/O n't/O change/O its/O stance/O ,/O ''/O Alam/PERSON said/O ./O 
Ignoring/O the/O concerns/O of/O the/O local/O communities/O and/O their/O leaders/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION vowed/O to/O continue/O with/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION at/O all/O costs/O ./O 
The/O military/O says/O that/O those/O opposing/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION are/O against/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O economic/O prosperity/O and/O are/O ``/O traitors/O ./O ''/O 
``/O We/O -LSB-/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O security/O forces/O -RSB-/O will/O not/O stop/O unless/O we/O achieve/O our/O end/O objective/O of/O a/O terror-free/O Pakistan/LOCATION ''/O irrespective/O of/O the/O costs/O ./O 
These/O costs/O appeared/O not/O only/O in/O the/O form/O of/O remarkable/O human/O and/O material/O resources/O but/O also/O in/O the/O willingness/O of/O the/O soldiers/O to/O sideline/O with/O civilians/O and/O to/O scrutinize/O the/O latest/O achievements/O in/O democratic/O transitions/O for/O the/O sake/O of/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION implementation/O ,/O ''/O Pakistani/O army/O chief/O Raheel/PERSON Sharif/PERSON recently/O said/O ./O 
But/O experts/O say/O that/O the/O South/O Asian/O country/O 's/O in/O the/O implementation/O of/O the/O economic/O corridor/O plan/O ./O 
``/O The/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION will/O further/O entrench/O the/O military/O in/O the/O country/O 's/O politics/O and/O subsequently/O ,/O harm/O any/O attempt/O to/O bring/O the/O country/O back/O into/O the/O process/O of/O democratic/O transition/O ,/O ''/O wrote/O Brussels-based/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION scholar/O Siegfried/PERSON O./PERSON Wolf/PERSON in/O a/O paper/O on/O the/O China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O An/O example/O for/O autonomous/O decision-making/O by/O the/O military/O is/O the/O Karachi/LOCATION security/O operations/O ./O 
Here/O we/O have/O a/O similar/O situation/O like/O with/O the/O Zarb-e-Azb/LOCATION operation/O in/O the/O northwestern/O areas/O :/O the/O decision/O to/O carry/O out/O decisive/O measures/O against/O terrorists/O was/O made/O by/O the/O military/O and/O the/O rangers/O -LRB-/O a/O paramilitary/O force/O headed/O by/O the/O army/O -RRB-/O themselves/O ,/O ''/O O./PERSON Wolf/PERSON added/O ./O 
Sattar/PERSON Khan/PERSON ,/O DW/O 's/O correspondent/O ,/O says/O that/O the/O fight/O over/O the/O control/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O economic/O hub/O and/O port/O city/O Karachi/LOCATION is/O also/O intensifying/O as/O the/O security/O forces/O continue/O to/O the/O Muttahida/ORGANIZATION Qaumi/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O MQM/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION 's/O influence/O is/O not/O limited/O to/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O Pakistani/O authorities/O are/O doling/O out/O all/O kinds/O of/O business/O contracts/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Karachi/LOCATION is/O economically/O very/O important/O for/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O therefore/O it/O does/O n't/O want/O any/O challenge/O to/O the/O new/O economic/O initiatives/O in/O the/O city/O ./O 
The/O MQM/ORGANIZATION leadership/O ,/O particularly/O its/O exiled/O leader/O in/O London/LOCATION ,/O Altaf/PERSON Hussain/PERSON ,/O is/O challenging/O it/O ,/O ''/O Khan/PERSON said/O ./O 
But/O the/O trickiest/O part/O of/O the/O proposed/O Sino-Pakistani/O economic/O projects/O could/O be/O their/O implantation/O in/O the/O face/O of/O Islamist/O militancy/O and/O a/O protracted/O separatist/O insurgency/O in/O Balochistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Baloch/PERSON separatist/O groups/O have/O vowed/O to/O resist/O these/O projects/O ,/O claiming/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION is/O a/O further/O exploitation/O of/O their/O resources/O and/O rights/O ./O 
last/O year/O ,/O Brahamdagh/PERSON Bugti/PERSON ,/O leader/O of/O the/O Baloch/ORGANIZATION Republican/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION living/O in/O exile/O in/O Switzerland/LOCATION ,/O said/O that/O the/O multi-billion/O dollar/O economic/O corridor/O deal/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION could/O spur/O rights/O violations/O in/O Balochistan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O I/O think/O there/O will/O be/O massive/O human/O rights/O abuses/O in/O Balochistan/LOCATION because/O of/O this/O deal/O ./O 
To/O secure/O their/O financial/O interests/O in/O the/O province/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION is/O likely/O to/O intensify/O its/O military/O operation/O there/O ./O 
They/O will/O do/O so/O in/O the/O name/O of/O providing/O security/O to/O the/O multinational/O and/O Chinese/O companies/O that/O are/O investing/O in/O the/O project/O ./O 
They/O would/O not/O even/O allow/O peaceful/O demonstrations/O and/O protests/O against/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O said/O Bugti/PERSON ./O 
Development/O analyst/O Maqsood/PERSON Ahmad/PERSON Jan/PERSON told/O DW/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION would/O turn/O Pakistan/LOCATION into/O ``/O China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O colony/O ./O ''/O 
With/O money/O pouring/O in/O from/O China/LOCATION for/O the/O establishment/O of/O the/O economic/O corridor/O ,/O those/O demanding/O more/O transparency/O about/O the/O Balochistan/LOCATION province/LOCATION are/O likely/O to/O face/O the/O ire/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O security/O agencies/O ./O 
Analysts/O say/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O more/O than/O willing/O to/O support/O China/LOCATION in/O its/O regional/O ambitions/O and/O be/O a/O ``/O client/O state/O ,/O ''/O given/O that/O the/O US/LOCATION has/O very/O little/O to/O offer/O economically/O and/O geo-politically/O in/O the/O present/O circumstances/O ./O 
``/O Pakistan/LOCATION knows/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O going/O to/O be/O the/O superpower/O in/O ten/O years/O ./O 
Islamabad/LOCATION is/O getting/O closer/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O its/O alliance/O with/O Washington/LOCATION is/O slowly/O and/O gradually/O taking/O a/O back/O seat/O ,/O ''/O Ali/PERSON Shah/PERSON ,/O a/O Pakistani/O researcher/O in/O Karachi/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
For/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION has/O become/O more/O important/O than/O ever/O before/O ,/O said/O Jan./O ``/O Islamabad/LOCATION has/O no/O other/O option/O but/O to/O increase/O cooperation/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O do/O what/O it/O says/O ,/O ''/O Jan/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ca/O n't/O be/O as/O big/O an/O investor/O as/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O US/LOCATION is/O unreliable/O and/O the/O Pakistani/O government/O needs/O money/O urgently/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
Jan/O goes/O on/O to/O say/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION has/O sold/O out/O to/O China/LOCATION for/O $/O 46/O billion/O ./O 
``/O I/O think/O the/O Chinese/O aid/O is/O not/O for/O free/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O economy/O is/O not/O that/O big/O ,/O so/O Beijing/LOCATION will/O now/O take/O over/O most/O of/O our/O income-generating/O sectors/O ./O ''/O 
But/O Ahsan/PERSON Iqbal/PERSON ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O minister/O for/O planning/O and/O development/O ,/O believes/O the/O forthcoming/O economic/O deals/O with/O China/LOCATION would/O be/O beneficial/O for/O his/O country/O ./O 
``/O The/O real/O opportunity/O of/O this/O China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION is/O that/O it/O changes/O the/O scope/O of/O the/O relationship/O from/O geopolitics/O to/O geo-economics/O ,/O ''/O Iqbal/PERSON told/O journalists/O ,/O adding/O that/O the/O projects/O would/O have/O a/O ``/O significant/O transformative/O effect/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O economy/O ./O ''/O 
Jan/O ,/O however/O ,/O does/O not/O agree/O with/O Iqbal/PERSON 's/O assessment/O of/O Sino-Pakistani/O economic/O ties/O ./O 
``/O This/O will/O turn/O us/O into/O China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O colony/O instead/O ./O ''/O 
