The/O social/O media/O behemoth/O has/O reportedly/O developed/O a/O software/O tool/O that/O is/O able/O to/O suppress/O users鈥/O posts/O in/O China/LOCATION -/O a/O possible/O first/O step/O toward/O convincing/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O allow/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION to/O re-enter/O the/O Chinese/O market/O ./O 
According/O to/O a/O report/O in/O the/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION ,/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION developed/O software/O which/O suppresses/O posts/O from/O appearing/O in/O people/O 's/O news/O feeds/O in/O specific/O geographies/O ./O 
The/O tool/O was/O reportedly/O created/O with/O the/O support/O of/O Chief/O Executive/O Mark/PERSON Zuckerberg/PERSON ,/O who/O met/O with/O China/LOCATION 's/O propaganda/O chief/O Liu/PERSON Yunshan/PERSON in/O March/O to/O discuss/O a/O re-entry/O of/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION in/O China/LOCATION where/O it/O has/O been/O banned/O since/O 2009/O ./O 
The/O Times/ORGANIZATION noted/O that/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION had/O taken/O down/O posts/O in/O other/O countries/O around/O the/O world/O ,/O including/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION and/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
But/O the/O tool/O now/O in/O development/O would/O prevent/O the/O posts/O from/O ever/O surfacing/O in/O the/O News/O Feed/O at/O all/O ,/O the/O newspaper/O added/O ./O 
The/O report/O also/O said/O that/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION was/O planning/O to/O outsource/O censorship/O duties/O to/O a/O third-party/O company/O ./O 
Facebook/ORGANIZATION spokeswoman/O Arielle/PERSON Aryah/PERSON wrote/O in/O an/O emailed/O statement/O to/O the/O news/O agency/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION that/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION 's/O focus/O in/O China/LOCATION was/O on/O helping/O businesses/O and/O developers/O ``/O expand/O to/O new/O markets/O outside/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
``/O We/O have/O long/O said/O that/O we/O are/O interested/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O are聽spending/O time/O understanding/O and/O learning/O more/O about/O the聽country/O ./O 
However/O ,/O we/O have/O not/O made/O any/O decision/O on/O our/O approach/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
Like/O many/O US/LOCATION technology/O companies/O ,/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION is/O seeking/O a/O way/O back/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O seeing/O the/O country/O 's/O 1.3/O billion/O residents/O as/O a/O source/O of/O enormous/O potential/O growth/O ./O 
China/LOCATION banned/O the/O website/O following/O the/O under/O efforts/O to/O limit/O the/O flow/O of/O information/O about/O ethnic/O unrest/O ./O 
Earlier/O this/O month/O ,/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION CEO/O Mark/PERSON Zuckerberg/PERSON said/O the/O company/O was/O building/O new/O tools/O to/O address/O fake/O news/O ./O 
``/O I/O want/O what/O we/O do/O to/O have/O a/O good/O impact/O on/O the/O world/O ./O 
I/O want/O people/O to/O have/O a/O diversity/O of/O information/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O new/O censorship/O tool/O would/O allow/O censors/O to/O manipulate/O public/O opinion/O directly/O by/O essentially/O preventing/O users/O from/O posting/O articles/O that/O offended/O the/O state/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Times/ORGANIZATION report/O ,/O the/O software/O ,/O therefore/O ,/O caused/O a/O controversy/O within/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION ,/O with/O ``/O several/O employees/O ''/O quitting/O in/O protest/O after/O working/O on/O it/O ./O 
But/O the/O newspaper/O also/O cautioned/O that/O the/O tool/O was/O one/O of/O several/O approaches/O Facebook/ORGANIZATION had/O considered/O and/O that/O there/O was/O no/O indication/O that/O the/O software/O had/O been/O offered/O to/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O yet/O ./O 
uhe/jd/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 聽/O 
