Tens/O of/O thousands/O of/O Tibetan/O exiles/O are/O voting/O around/O the/O globe/O to/O elect/O a/O new/O prime/O minister/O and/O parliament/O ./O 
It/O is/O the/O second/O such/O election/O since/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON stepped/O down/O to/O focus/O on/O his/O role/O as/O a/O spiritual/O leader/O ./O 
Some/O 80,000/O registered/O Tibetans/O are/O in/O exile/O -/O 11,000/O of/O them/O in/O Dharmsala/LOCATION in/O India/LOCATION -/O were/O set/O to/O vote/O in/O Sunday/O 's/O daylong/O election/O ,/O to/O decide/O who/O will/O lead/O the/O parliament/O of/O the/O Central/O Tibetan/O Administration/O -LRB-/O CTA/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O in/O Dharamsala/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O n't/O recognized/O by/O any/O country/O ./O 
The/O result/O is/O expected/O next/O month/O ./O 
Running/O for/O office/O is/O current/O Prime/O Minister/O Lobsang/PERSON Sangay/PERSON and/O his/O opponent/O ,/O parliamentary/O speaker/O Penpa/PERSON Tsering/PERSON ./O 
Both/O continue/O to/O support/O ``/O a/O middle/O way/O ''/O proposed/O by/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O ,/O which/O calls/O for/O seeking/O regional/O autonomy/O under/O Chinese/O rule/O ./O 
The/O Dalai/O Lama/O has/O been/O living/O in/O exile/O in/O Dharmsala/LOCATION since/O he/O fled/O Tibet/LOCATION after/O a/O failed/O uprising/O against/O Chinese/O rule/O in/O 1959/O ./O 
He/O stepped/O down/O as/O head/O of/O the/O Tibetan/O government/O in/O 2011/O ./O 
Concerns/O after/O he/O was/O admitted/O to/O a/O US/LOCATION hospital/O ./O 
Some/O groups/O have/O been/O advocating/O full/O independence/O for/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O as/O little/O progress/O has/O been/O made/O in/O the/O dialogue/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O which/O does/O n't/O recognize/O the/O Tibetan/O government/O in/O exile/O ./O 
Representatives/O of/O the/O pro-independence/O groups/O failed/O to/O win/O enough/O support/O in/O the/O first/O round/O of/O elections/O to/O be/O in/O the/O running/O for/O the/O prime/O minister/O 's/O post/O ./O 
Exiled/O Tibetan/O officials/O say/O at/O least/O 114/O monks/O and/O laypeople/O have/O self-immolated/O to/O protest/O Chinese/O rule/O over/O their/O homeland/O over/O the/O past/O five/O years/O ,/O with/O most/O of/O them/O dying/O ./O 
According/O to/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Free/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION ,/O 144/O people/O have/O died/O by/O setting/O fire/O to/O themselves/O since/O 2009/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION blames/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON and/O others/O for/O inciting/O the/O immolations/O and/O says/O it/O has/O made/O vast/O investments/O to/O develop/O Tibet/LOCATION 's/O economy/O and/O improve/O quality/O of/O life/O ./O 
ksb/jlw/O -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 
