Ahead/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION congress/O next/O year/O ,/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON has/O begun/O to/O reinforce/O his/O position/O as/O party/O chief/O ./O 
There/O have/O already/O been/O 12/O changes/O out/O of/O 32/O provinces/O to/O the/O party/O secretaries/O in/O 2016/O ./O 
In/O little/O more/O than/O a/O year/O ,/O the/O 19th/O congress/O of/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION is/O to/O take/O place/O ,/O but/O experts/O say/O that/O party/O leader/O and/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON is/O already/O making/O personnel/O moves/O to/O ensure/O control/O of/O his/O top/O position/O ./O 
Earlier/O this/O week/O ,/O Xi/PERSON appointed/O three/O new/O provincial/O party/O chiefs/O ./O 
According/O to/O a/O report/O by/O China/LOCATION 's/O state/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION released/O Sunday/O ,/O in/O the/O southwestern/O province/O of/O Yunnan/LOCATION ,/O Chen/PERSON Hao/PERSON was/O appointed/O party/O chief/O and/O in/O the/O populous/O province/O of/O Hunan/LOCATION ,/O Du/PERSON Jiahao/PERSON was/O given/O the/O top/O position/O ./O 
According/O to/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O Chen/PERSON and/O Du/PERSON both/O worked/O with/O Xi/O in/O Shanghai/LOCATION when/O he/O was/O Communist/O party/O chief/O there/O for/O a/O short/O period/O in/O 2007/O ./O 
In/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O Wu/PERSON Yingjie/PERSON was/O appointed/O party/O chief/O ./O 
These/O appointments/O were/O quickly/O followed/O by/O further/O reshuffling/O in/O the/O autonomous/O regions/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION ,/O as/O well/O as/O in/O the/O Anhui/LOCATION province/O ./O 
By/O placing/O loyalists/O in/O key/O party/O positions/O ,/O Xi/O can/O ensure/O that/O he/O has/O support/O when/O the/O party/O congress/O meets/O next/O year/O ./O 
``/O It/O is/O definite/O that/O he/O wants/O to/O bring/O in/O people/O he/O can/O trust/O ,/O ''/O Matthias/PERSON Stepan/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O Domestic/ORGANIZATION Politics/ORGANIZATION Programs/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O Mercator/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
Stepan/PERSON added/O that/O this/O type/O of/O reshuffling/O is/O not/O unusual/O for/O leaders/O in/O Xi/O 's/O position/O but/O that/O there/O was/O a/O clear/O timing/O for/O the/O rearrangement/O of/O key/O positions/O on/O the/O provincial/O level/O ./O 
``/O This/O is/O a/O clear/O prelude/O to/O a/O bigger/O reshuffle/O of/O positions/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O the/O provinces/O ,/O ''/O said/O Stepan/PERSON ./O 
``/O It/O is/O only/O the/O tip/O of/O the/O iceberg/O ,/O ''/O said/O Stepan/PERSON ./O 
``/O We/O will/O see/O a/O larger/O number/O of/O people/O assuming/O office/O as/O governors/O or/O vice-governors/O in/O the/O provinces/O over/O the/O course/O of/O the/O year/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O many/O high/O level/O officials/O will/O transfer/O to/O positions/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
To/O rise/O in/O party/O ranks/O ,/O experience/O in/O the/O provinces/O is/O often/O necessary/O ./O 
``/O A/O number/O of/O people/O currently/O holding/O office/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION will/O need/O to/O gain/O experience/O in/O the/O provinces/O --/O even/O if/O it/O is/O only/O for/O a/O year/O ,/O ''/O underlined/O Stepan/PERSON ./O 
While/O Xi/O has/O progressively/O increased/O the/O authority/O of/O the/O party/O 's/O core/O since/O he/O became/O chief/O in/O 2012/O ,/O he/O still/O lacks/O support/O in/O the/O Central/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O comprises/O 205/O full/O members/O that/O are/O the/O leaders/O of/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
At/O the/O party/O congress/O in/O 2017/O ,/O Xi/O will/O have/O the/O chance/O to/O control/O the/O process/O and/O exercise/O influence/O over/O new/O members/O ./O 
According/O to/O figures/O published/O in/O ,/O the/O number/O of/O seats/O available/O will/O be/O 92/O ,/O an/O unusually/O high/O figure/O resulting/O from/O members/O retiring/O or/O being/O removed/O because/O of/O corruption/O ./O 
``/O For/O now/O Xi/O 's/O weakness/O is/O that/O many/O of/O his/O reform/O projects/O have/O stalled/O and/O this/O makes/O him/O a/O target/O for/O people/O around/O him/O who/O may/O criticize/O his/O approach/O to/O govern/O ,/O ''/O said/O Stepan/PERSON ./O 
``/O But/O I/O do/O n't/O detect/O anyone/O in/O the/O party/O who/O would/O directly/O challenge/O his/O power/O within/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
The/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION congress/O in/O China/LOCATION happens/O every/O five/O years/O and/O is/O where/O future/O leadership/O is/O chosen/O and/O where/O the/O direction/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O politics/O is/O determined/O ./O 
The/O seven-member/O core/O of/O political/O power/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION Standing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O Xi/O currently/O leads/O ,/O is/O also/O to/O be/O determined/O at/O next/O year/O 's/O conference/O ./O 
There/O is/O widespread/O speculation/O that/O Xi/O will/O seek/O to/O extend/O his/O power/O beyond/O 2022/O ,/O when/O he/O is/O due/O to/O step/O down/O ,/O however/O Stepan/PERSON disagrees/O with/O these/O assertions/O ./O 
``/O I/O do/O n't/O see/O any/O evidence/O that/O Xi/O will/O overstep/O this/O well/O established/O party/O rule/O ,/O and/O stay/O in/O office/O beyond/O 2022/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O that/O he/O seeks/O to/O solidify/O his/O control/O over/O power/O as/O a/O supreme/O leader/O like/O Mao/PERSON ./O ''/O 
