Wahid/PERSON Baloch/PERSON ,/O a/O prominent/O activist/O ,/O was/O allegedly/O detained/O by/O security/O forces/O earlier/O this/O year/O ./O 
Baloch/PERSON has/O now/O been/O reunited/O with/O his/O family/O but/O there/O 're/O thousands/O of/O other/O Baluchistan/LOCATION activists/O whose/O fate/O is/O unknown/O ./O 
Pakistani/O activist/O Wahid/PERSON Baloch/PERSON ,/O who/O ``/O disappeared/O ''/O four/O months/O ago/O ,/O has/O returned/O to/O his/O home/O in/O the/O southern/O city/O of/O Karachi/LOCATION ./O 
``/O The/O social/O activist/O ,/O writer/O and/O small-scale/O publisher/O is/O believed/O to/O have/O been/O detained/O by/O unidentified/O security/O officials/O on/O July/O 26/O on/O the/O outskirts/O of/O Karachi/LOCATION ,/O setting/O off/O a/O frightening/O ,/O though/O wearingly/O familiar/O ,/O process/O of/O recovery/O for/O his/O shocked/O family/O ,/O ''/O said/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O English/O daily/O ,/O Dawn/PERSON ,/O on/O Wednesday/O ,/O December/O 7/O ./O 
A/O number/O of/O activists/O from/O the/O South/O Asian/O country/O 's/O southwestern/O Baluchistan/LOCATION province/LOCATION have/O disappeared/O in/O the/O past/O few/O years/O ./O 
Rights/O groups/O claim/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O security/O agencies/O have/O kidnapped/O them/O because/O of/O their/O alleged/O support/O to/O a/O separatist/O movement/O in/O Baluchistan/LOCATION ./O 
Wahid/PERSON Baloch/PERSON is/O fortunate/O to/O have/O been/O reunited/O with/O his/O family/O ,/O thanks/O to/O the/O persistent/O efforts/O by/O many/O non-governmental/O organizations/O ,/O including/O the/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION of/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O an/O independent/O NGO/O ./O 
But/O thousands/O of/O Baloch/PERSON activists/O are/O still/O missing/O despite/O their/O families/O '/O complaints/O and/O protests/O ./O 
``/O Wahid/PERSON Baloch/PERSON 's/O abduction/O ,/O like/O thousands/O of/O other/O Baloch/PERSON kidnappings/O ,/O was/O illegal/O and/O unjust/O ./O 
But/O Pakistani/O authorities/O do/O not/O respect/O the/O law/O ,/O ''/O Mir/PERSON Mohammad/PERSON Ali/PERSON Talpur/PERSON of/O The/O Voice/ORGANIZATION for/O the/O Baloch/ORGANIZATION Missing/ORGANIZATION Persons/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O VBMP/O -RRB-/O group/O ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O The/O release/O of/O Wahid/PERSON Baloch/PERSON is/O certainly/O a/O victory/O for/O justice/O but/O thousands/O of/O people/O are/O still/O missing/O ,/O ''/O Talpur/PERSON underlined/O ./O 
Local/O rights/O groups/O have/O the/O details/O of/O at/O least/O 8,000/O people/O who/O they/O say/O have/O disappeared/O over/O the/O past/O 12/O years/O and/O have/O not/O been/O seen/O since/O ./O 
In/O 2012/O ,/O the/O Asian/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O AHRC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O said/O that/O 23/O bullet-riddled/O bodies/O of/O the/O missing/O persons/O were/O discovered/O in/O different/O parts/O of/O Baluchistan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Wahid/PERSON Baloch/PERSON 's/O release/O was/O a/O result/O of/O a/O sustained/O effort/O by/O his/O daughter/O ,/O Hani/PERSON ,/O his/O family/O and/O friends/O ,/O and/O the/O civil/O society/O ./O 
The/O international/O media/O also/O put/O pressure/O on/O the/O abductors/O ,/O who/O had/O to/O eventually/O free/O Baloch/PERSON ,/O ''/O said/O Talpur/PERSON ./O 
Baluchistan/LOCATION ,/O which/O borders/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O is/O rich/O in/O oil/O ,/O gas/O and/O minerals/O ,/O yet/O it/O remains/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O poorest/O province/O ./O 
Baloch/PERSON activists/O accuse/O Islamabad/LOCATION of/O usurping/O their/O wealth/O ,/O fueling/O a/O protracted/O separatist/O movement/O ./O 
The/O armed/O struggle/O for/O Baloch/PERSON independence/O intensified/O after/O the/O killing/O of/O influential/O Baloch/PERSON leader/O Akbar/PERSON Bugti/PERSON in/O 2006/O in/O a/O military/O operation/O ./O 
Rebel/O Baloch/PERSON groups/O like/O the/O Baluchistan/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION have/O repeatedly/O attacked/O security/O forces/O and/O state/O installations/O ./O 
Most/O of/O the/O rebel/O leadership/O is/O believed/O to/O be/O in/O exile/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Dubai/LOCATION ./O 
``/O According/O to/O the/O Asian/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O Pakistani/O army/O operates/O dozens/O of/O illegal/O underground/O torture/O cells/O in/O different/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O and/O various/O intelligence/O agencies/O do/O not/O share/O complete/O information/O with/O each/O other/O about/O their/O operations/O and/O torture/O cells/O ./O 
Rights/O groups/O believe/O these/O people/O are/O languishing/O in/O these/O cells/O ,/O ''/O Siraj/PERSON added/O ./O 
Asad/PERSON Butt/PERSON ,/O a/O vice/O chairperson/O of/O the/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION of/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/O that/O Wahid/PERSON Baloch/PERSON was/O tortured/O by/O his/O ``/O abductors/O ./O ''/O 
``/O I/O met/O him/O -LRB-/O Baloch/PERSON -RRB-/O after/O his/O release/O ./O 
He/O told/O me/O that/O he/O was/O kept/O in/O a/O small/O room/O ./O 
He/O was/O also/O tortured/O ,/O ''/O Butt/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O He/O said/O that/O most/O people/O in/O custody/O were/O from/O the/O Khyber/LOCATION Pakthunkwa/LOCATION province/O ./O 
Some/O belonged/O to/O the/O Karachi-based/O Muttahida/ORGANIZATION Qaumi/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O MQM/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O party/O ,/O ''/O Butt/O added/O ./O 
Pakistani/O authorities/O deny/O allegations/O that/O the/O security/O agencies/O detain/O people/O illegally/O ./O 
They/O say/O that/O many/O people/O from/O Baluchistan/LOCATION and/O other/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O have/O been/O arrested/O on/O terrorism/O charges/O ./O 
Pakistani/O authorities/O are/O taking/O the/O Baloch/PERSON insurgency/O even/O more/O seriously/O now/O ./O 
Last/O month/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O top/O civilian/O and/O military/O leaders/O inaugurated/O a/O new/O international/O route/O which/O connects/O the/O country/O 's/O renovated/O southwestern/O Gwadar/LOCATION port/O in/O Baluchistan/LOCATION to/O the/O Chinese/O city/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION as/O part/O of/O a/O joint/O multibillion-dollar/O initiative/O ,/O the/O China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ./O 
With/O the/O $/O 46/O billion/O -LRB-/O 41/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O project/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION aims/O to/O expand/O its/O clout/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O across/O Central/O and/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O while/O at/O the/O same/O time/O counter/O US/LOCATION and/O Indian/O influence/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
CPEC/ORGANIZATION also/O includes/O plans/O to/O create/O road/O ,/O rail/O and/O oil/O pipeline/O links/O to/O improve/O connectivity/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
But/O the/O success/O of/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION depends/O on/O the/O security/O situation/O in/O Baluchistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O that/O is/O why/O the/O military/O has/O beefed/O up/O its/O presence/O in/O the/O province/O ./O 
Pakistani/O officials/O also/O accuse/O India/LOCATION of/O backing/O the/O separatist/O movement/O in/O Baluchistan/LOCATION ,/O a/O claim/O denied/O by/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION ./O 
That/O puts/O even/O the/O pacifist/O Baloch/PERSON activists/O in/O the/O harms/O way/O ,/O as/O the/O authorities/O are/O now/O more/O suspicious/O of/O their/O activities/O than/O ever/O ./O 
The/O Baloch/PERSON separatists/O strongly/O oppose/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION ,/O saying/O that/O the/O bigger/O Punjab/LOCATION province/O want/O to/O reap/O all/O the/O benefits/O while/O using/O their/O lands/O and/O resources/O to/O implement/O the/O project/O ./O 
Ignoring/O the/O concerns/O of/O the/O local/O communities/O and/O their/O leaders/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION has/O vowed/O to/O continue/O with/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION at/O all/O costs/O ./O 
The/O military/O says/O that/O those/O opposing/O the/O economic/O corridor/O plan/O are/O against/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O economic/O prosperity/O and/O are/O ``/O traitors/O ./O ''/O 
``/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION 's/O success/O depends/O largely/O on/O regional/O stability/O ,/O security/O and/O rule/O of/O law/O ./O 
Without/O these/O guarantees/O ,/O Chinese/O companies/O will/O be/O hesitant/O to/O make/O more/O investments/O beyond/O the/O current/O agreements/O ,/O ''/O Siegfried/PERSON O/PERSON Wolf/PERSON ,/O a/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Heidelberg/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O Consequently/O ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O stepping/O up/O its/O security/O engagement/O regarding/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION -/O the/O deployment/O of/O an/O increased/O number/O of/O troops/O along/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION route/O and/O new/O counterterrorism/O policies/O accompanied/O by/O special/O laws/O to/O empower/O the/O military/O and/O its/O intelligence/O services/O are/O some/O examples/O ./O ''/O 
IS/O has/O claimed/O two/O attacks/O in/O Baluchistan/LOCATION in/O recent/O months/O ,/O and/O experts/O point/O to/O its/O expansion/O in/O the/O province/O ./O 
That/O development/O ,/O too/O ,/O poses/O a/O challenge/O for/O the/O Pakistani/O authorities/O to/O implement/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O There/O is/O no/O doubt/O that/O IS/O activities/O are/O increasing/O in/O the/O Afghanistan-Pakistan/O region/O ./O 
We/O must/O not/O forget/O that/O terrorist/O organizations/O like/O IS/O and/O al/O Qaeda/O are/O critical/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O handling/O of/O its/O Uighur/O Muslim/O population/O ./O 
There/O is/O a/O threat/O that/O these/O groups/O will/O identify/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION projects/O as/O potential/O targets/O in/O their/O so-called/O `/O jihad/O against/O China/LOCATION ,/O '/O ''/O Wolf/PERSON said/O ,/O adding/O that/O much/O will/O depend/O on/O how/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O security/O establishment/O deals/O with/O this/O new/O threat/O ./O 
