New/LOCATION York/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O 聳/O Chinese/O police/O tried/O to/O arrest/O the/O son/O of/O Muslim/O ethnic/O Uighur/O dissident/O ,/O Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON ,/O who/O emigrated/O to/O the/O USA/LOCATION ,/O and/O they/O have/O broken/O into/O her/O business/O and/O beaten/O and/O detained/O her/O staff/O ./O 
The/O ``/O reprisal/O ''/O was/O denounced/O by/O the/O non-governmental/O organisation/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O HRW/O -RRB-/O ./O 
``/O It/O looks/O as/O if/O the/O Chinese/O government/O is/O intent/O on/O ruining/O any/O legacy/O she/O may/O have/O left/O behind/O by/O destroying/O her/O business/O and/O silencing/O her/O children/O ,/O ''/O said/O Asia/LOCATION director/O for/O HRW/O ,/O Brad/PERSON Adams/PERSON ./O 
On/O Wednesday/O 11/O May/O ,/O two/O employees/O of/O the/O firm/O Kadeer/PERSON trade/O centre/O were/O arrested/O ./O 
``/O Two/O days/O later/O ,/O more/O than/O 100/O policemen/O entered/O the/O firm/O and/O took/O away/O all/O the/O documents/O they/O found/O ./O 
Police/O also/O tried/O to/O grab/O Kadeer/PERSON 's/O son/O Ablikim/PERSON Abdiriyim/PERSON ,/O but/O he/O evaded/O arrest/O and/O his/O whereabouts/O are/O unknown/O ./O 
A/O friend/O of/O his/O was/O beaten/O and/O detained/O because/O he/O did/O not/O know/O where/O Ablikim/PERSON was/O ;/O he/O was/O released/O only/O after/O he/O signed/O a/O statement/O that/O he/O would/O not/O visit/O the/O Kadeer/PERSON family/O or/O their/O business/O again/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
Ablikim/PERSON was/O arrested/O with/O his/O mother/O in/O 1999/O and/O detained/O for/O two/O years/O in/O a/O ``/O reeducation/O ''/O camp/O ./O 
Kadeer/PERSON was/O arrested/O in/O 1999/O for/O ``/O illegally/O providing/O state/O intelligence/O abroad/O ''/O after/O she/O sent/O newspaper/O clippings/O to/O her/O husband/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
She/O spent/O years/O in/O jail/O in/O solitary/O confinement/O and/O deprived/O of/O necessary/O medical/O care/O ./O ''/O 
She/O was/O released/O in/O March/O ``/O for/O health/O reasons/O ''/O and/O allowed/O to/O become/O an/O expatriate/O ,/O thanks/O to/O repeated/O international/O pleas/O and/O coinciding/O with/O the/O trip/O to/O China/LOCATION of/O US/LOCATION Secretary/O of/O State/ORGANIZATION Condoleeza/PERSON Rice/PERSON ./O 
She/O is/O involved/O in/O defending/O Uighur/O Muslims/O from/O persecution/O at/O the/O hands/O of/O Peking/O ,/O which/O fears/O their/O aspirations/O for/O autonomy/O :/O this/O ethnic/O group/O ,/O with/O its/O own/O language/O and/O traditions/O ,/O makes/O up/O the/O majority/O of/O the/O population/O of/O 19/O million/O of/O the/O oil-rich/O northern/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ,/O which/O was/O independent/O from/O China/LOCATION up/O until/O 1949/O -LRB-/O former/O eastern/O Turkestan/O -RRB-/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O persecuted/O this/O ethnic/O group/O for/O many/O years/O ,/O resorting/O to/O incarceration/O and/O systematic/O eradication/O of/O their/O identity/O -LRB-/O they/O even/O destroyed/O books/O in/O Uighur/O language/O in/O local/O libraries/O ,/O and/O people/O of/O other/O ethnicities/O are/O preferred/O for/O public/O appointments/O in/O all/O economic/O spheres/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Before/O release/O ,/O Kadeer/PERSON was/O threatened/O that/O ``/O her/O affairs/O and/O her/O children/O would/O be/O struck/O ''/O if/O she/O did/O not/O keep/O silent/O ./O 
On/O the/O contrary/O ,/O the/O woman/O has/O talked/O to/O journalists/O and/O politicians/O and/O she/O has/O continued/O her/O fight/O for/O human/O rights/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
-LRB-/O PB/O -RRB-/O 
