A/O report/O recently/O released/O by/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION provides/O evidence/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O repressive/O policies/O vis-à-vis/O ethnic/O Uighur/O Muslims/O ./O 
New/LOCATION York/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/HRW/O -RRB-/O --/O Chinese/O authorities/O are/O engaged/O in/O a/O violent/O campaign/O of/O religious/O and/O political/O repression/O against/O ethnic/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ,/O this/O according/O to/O a/O 114-page/O report/O released/O today/O by/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O document/O entitled/O Devastating/O Blows/O :/O Religious/O Repression/O of/O Uighurs/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION relies/O on/O previously/O undisclosed/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O government/O documents/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O local/O regulations/O ,/O official/O newspaper/O accounts/O ,/O and/O interviews/O conducted/O in/O the/O province/O ./O 
It/O unveils/O for/O the/O first/O time/O the/O complex/O system/O of/O laws/O ,/O regulations/O ,/O and/O policies/O enforced/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION that/O deny/O Uighurs/O religious/O freedom/O ,/O and/O by/O extension/O freedom/O of/O association/O ,/O assembly/O ,/O and/O expression/O ./O 
It/O shows/O how/O state/O authorities/O politically/O examine/O all/O imams/O on/O a/O regular/O basis/O requiring/O them/O to/O undergo/O `/O self-criticism/O '/O sessions/O ;/O impose/O surveillance/O on/O mosques/O ;/O purge/O schools/O of/O religious/O teachers/O and/O students/O ;/O screen/O literature/O and/O poetry/O for/O political/O allusions/O ;/O ban/O religious/O holidays/O ,/O studying/O religious/O texts/O ,/O or/O showing/O one/O 's/O religion/O through/O personal/O appearance/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O also/O vet/O who/O can/O be/O a/O cleric/O ,/O where/O religious/O gatherings/O may/O be/O held/O ,/O and/O what/O may/O be/O said/O ./O 
Openly/O expressing/O one/O 's/O religious/O identity/O in/O public/O places/O ,/O government/O buildings/O and/O school/O is/O also/O strictly/O forbidden/O ./O 
One/O official/O document/O goes/O so/O far/O as/O to/O say/O that/O ``/O parents/O and/O legal/O guardians/O may/O not/O allow/O minors/O to/O participate/O in/O religious/O activities/O ./O ''/O 
Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION condemns/O how/O the/O government/O equates/O religious/O freedom/O and/O any/O expression/O of/O dissatisfaction/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policies/O with/O `/O separatism/O '/O ./O 
People/O practicing/O their/O religion/O in/O ways/O that/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION and/O government/O deem/O unacceptable/O are/O arrested/O ,/O tortured/O ,/O and/O at/O times/O executed/O ./O 
The/O harshest/O punishments/O are/O reserved/O for/O those/O accused/O of/O so-called/O separatist/O activity/O ,/O which/O officials/O increasingly/O term/O `/O terrorism/O '/O ./O 
What/O is/O more/O ,/O half/O the/O detainees/O in/O re-education/O camps/O were/O arrested/O and/O detained/O without/O due/O process/O and/O ``/O the/O worldwide/O campaign/O against/O terrorism/O has/O given/O Beijing/LOCATION the/O perfect/O excuse/O to/O crack/O down/O harder/O than/O ever/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O Brad/PERSON Adams/PERSON ,/O Asia/LOCATION director/O for/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O Other/O Chinese/O enjoy/O a/O growing/O freedom/O to/O worship/O ,/O but/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O like/O the/O Tibetans/O ,/O find/O that/O their/O religion/O is/O being/O used/O as/O a/O tool/O of/O control/O ./O ''/O 
As/O Xinjiang/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Secretary/O Wang/PERSON Lequan/PERSON himself/O has/O stressed/O ,/O the/O ``/O major/O task/O ''/O facing/O the/O authorities/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O to/O ``/O manage/O religion/O and/O guide/O it/O in/O being/O subordinate/O to/O the/O central/O task/O of/O economic/O construction/O ,/O the/O unification/O of/O the/O motherland/O ,/O and/O the/O objective/O of/O national/O unity/O ./O ''/O 
The/O Uighurs/O ,/O a/O Turkish-speaking/O minority/O of/O some/O eight/O million/O people/O ,/O whose/O traditional/O homeland/O lies/O in/O the/O Xinjiang/LOCATION Uighur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION in/O northwest/O China/LOCATION ,/O have/O become/O increasingly/O fearful/O for/O their/O cultural/O survival/O and/O traditional/O way/O of/O life/O in/O the/O face/O of/O an/O intensive/O internal/O migration/O drive/O that/O saw/O more/O than/O 1.2/O million/O ethnic/O Chinese/O settlers/O arrive/O over/O the/O past/O decade/O and/O whose/O presence/O is/O radically/O changing/O local/O social/O structures/O ./O 
Most/O Uighurs/O desire/O greater/O autonomy/O than/O is/O currently/O allowed/O ;/O however/O ,/O in/O more/O recent/O years/O ,/O a/O small/O but/O growing/O minority/O is/O demanding/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
