PetroChina/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O mainland/O 's/O biggest/O oil/O company/O ,/O plans/O to/O invest/O 26.2/O billion/O yuan/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION to/O increase/O refining/O capacity/O to/O 10/O million/O tonnes/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O PetroChina/ORGANIZATION is/O the/O biggest/O oil/O company/O in/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION and/O it/O is/O currently/O planning/O investments/O up/O to/O September/O 2007/O in/O order/O to/O boost/O its/O refining/O capacity/O in/O the/O western-most/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O said/O Liu/PERSON Mingrong/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O Dushanzi/ORGANIZATION Petrochemical/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Estimated/O cost/O :/O 26.2/O billion/O yuan/O ./O 
``/O The/O project/O is/O built/O mainly/O to/O process/O oil/O imported/O from/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Mr/O Liu/PERSON said/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O also/O expected/O to/O start/O producing/O ethylene/O as/O early/O as/O the/O third/O quarter/O of/O 2008/O ./O 
Ethylene/O is/O used/O in/O making/O plastics/O ,/O food/O wrapping/O and/O electrical/O insulation/O ./O 
Mr/O Liu/PERSON said/O PetroChina/ORGANIZATION plans/O to/O increase/O refining/O capacity/O at/O the/O Dushanzi/ORGANIZATION Petrochemical/ORGANIZATION in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION to/O 10/O million/O tonnes/O a/O year/O by/O 2008/O from/O its/O current/O level/O of/O six/O million/O ./O 
The/O project/O will/O produce/O 1.2/O million/O tonnes/O of/O ethylene/O annually/O up/O from/O 220,000/O tonnes/O now/O ./O 
According/O to/O PetroChina/ORGANIZATION 's/O 2004/O report/O ethylene/O production/O rose/O 1.5/O per/O cent/O to/O 1.85/O million/O tonnes/O last/O year/O over/O the/O previous/O ./O 
PetroChina/ORGANIZATION drills/O for/O gas/O and/O oil/O at/O home/O but/O is/O also/O exploring/O abroad/O to/O compensate/O for/O the/O depletion/O of/O its/O biggest/O and/O oldest/O oil/O field/O in/O Daqing/O which/O started/O production/O back/O in/O 1959/O ./O 
The/O failure/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O oil/O companies/O to/O match/O increased/O demand/O from/O economic/O expansion/O sent/O imports/O soaring/O by/O 35/O per/O cent/O last/O year/O ./O 
PetroChina/ORGANIZATION 's/O crude/O oil/O production/O rose/O a/O mere/O 0.4/O per/O cent/O to/O 777.9/O million/O barrels/O ,/O compared/O with/O a/O 14/O per/O cent/O upsurge/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O demand/O over/O the/O same/O period/O ./O 
Natural/O gas/O output/O rose/O instead/O 21/O per/O cent/O to/O 839.4/O billion/O cubic/O feet/O over/O the/O same/O period/O ./O 
Production/O from/O Daqing/O fell/O to/O 46.4/O million/O tonnes/O last/O year/O from/O 48.4/O million/O tonnes/O in/O 2003/O ./O 
Output/O from/O Heilongjiang/LOCATION ,/O which/O accounts/O for/O 50/O per/O cent/O of/O PetroChina/ORGANIZATION 's/O production/O and/O 33/O per/O cent/O of/O the/O nation/O 's/O total/O ,/O is/O being/O cut/O to/O prolong/O Daqing/O 's/O life/O ./O 
