Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O 聳/O China/LOCATION 's/O security/O forces/O are/O on/O maximum/O alert/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
The/O government/O has/O ordered/O the/O suppression/O of/O any/O separatism/O or/O terrorism/O bids/O ,/O which/O may/O come/O from/O the/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uighurs/ORGANIZATION ,/O on/O the/O day/O marking/O the/O 50th/O anniversary/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O control/O over/O the/O autonomous/O region/O ./O 
This/O ethnic/O group/O ,/O with/O its/O own/O language/O and/O traditions/O ,/O accounts/O for/O the/O majority/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION 's/O 19/O million/O inhabitants/O ;/O the/O northern/O oil-rich/O region/O was/O independent/O until/O 1955/O under/O the/O name/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION ./O 
Alert/O levels/O shot/O up/O yesterday/O when/O Uighur/O Muslim/O activists/O in/O exile/O warned/O that/O they/O wanted/O to/O transform/O today/O 's/O celebrations/O into/O a/O ``/O day/O of/O mourning/O ''/O ./O 
Luo/PERSON Gan/PERSON ,/O a/O member/O of/O the/O permanent/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION party/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O yesterday/O that/O ``/O Xinjiang/LOCATION 's/O stability/O worries/O the/O whole/O country/O ./O 
We/O must/O continue/O to/O struggle/O hard/O against/O all/O criminal/O activities/O and/O to/O maintain/O social/O order/O ./O ''/O 
For/O many/O years/O ,/O China/LOCATION ,/O fearing/O autonomy/O bids/O ,/O has/O persecuted/O this/O ethnic/O group/O with/O imprisonment/O and/O the/O systematic/O annihilation/O of/O their/O identity/O ./O 
Yesterday/O ,/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION campaigners/O in/O exile/O 聳/O who/O came/O together/O for/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O WUC/O -RRB-/O 聳/O criticized/O China/LOCATION for/O oppressing/O and/O exploiting/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O and/O warned/O that/O the/O area/O could/O well/O become/O a/O ``/O time/O bomb/O ''/O ./O 
According/O to/O WUC/O ,/O ``/O the/O policies/O of/O political/O oppression/O ,/O cultural/O assimilation/O ,/O economic/O exploitation/O ,/O ecological/O destruction/O ,/O racial/O discrimination/O have/O gradually/O turned/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION into/O a/O time/O bomb/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O severe/O anti-Chinese/O sentiment/O has/O intensified/O throughout/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
According/O to/O the/O WUC/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O Chinese/O leader/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON established/O Xinjiang/LOCATION in/O 1955/O after/O having/O promised/O self-determination/O and/O full/O independence/O for/O the/O people/O of/O east/O Turkestan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION 's/O founder/O died/O three/O decades/O ago/O ,/O but/O China/LOCATION 's/O strategic/O ,/O political/O and/O economic/O objectives/O in/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION have/O remained/O unchanged/O ,/O ''/O the/O WUC/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O 
``/O The/O present/O Chinese/O leaders/O are/O continuing/O the/O same/O policy/O to/O transform/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION completely/O into/O a/O Chinese/O colony/O ,/O culturally/O assimilate/O the/O Uighur/O people/O ,/O and/O exploit/O their/O natural/O resources/O ./O ''/O 
For/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O crucial/O because/O of/O its/O strategic/O position/O close/O to/O central/O Asia/LOCATION and/O because/O of/O its/O large/O gas/O and/O oil/O reserves/O ./O 
In/O the/O last/O decade/O ,/O the/O area/O has/O seen/O a/O consistent/O influx/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
