Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agenzie/O -RRB-/O -/O In/O 2005/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION China/LOCATION arrestated/O 18.227/O Uygurs/O for/O ``/O threatening/O national/O security/O ''/O ./O 
The/O data/O was/O recently/O confirmed/O by/O a/O local/O authority/O newspaper/O ./O 
For/O more/O than/O a/O decade/O the/O Uygurs/O have/O been/O asking/O for/O autonomy/O for/O their/O mainly/O Islamic/O region/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION treats/O the/O activists/O as/O terrorists/O and/O arrests/O all/O those/O who/O speak/O with/O foreign/O press/O accusing/O them/O of/O revealing/O state/O secrets/O ./O ''/O 
``/O Uygurs/O are/O scared/O ./O 
They/O can/O be/O arrested/O even/O for/O a/O slip/O of/O the/O tongue/O ,/O ''/O said/O Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON ,/O of/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uygur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O German-based/O organisation/O seeking/O more/O freedom/O for/O the/O region/O they/O call/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O We/O have/O no/O rights/O ./O 
But/O we/O are/O also/O human/O beings/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O even/O more/O people/O -/O all/O Uygurs/O -/O were/O probably/O detained/O by/O police/O and/O not/O formally/O charged/O ''/O ./O 
In/O March/O 2005/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O under/O international/O pressure/O freed/O and/O exiled/O Uygurs/O activist/O Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON ,/O detained/O for/O years/O under/O the/O accusation/O of/O ``/O having/O revealed/O state/O secrets/O ''/O ,/O after/O he/O sent/O photocopies/O of/O newspaper/O articles/O abroad/O ./O ''/O 
If/O anything/O ,/O -/O accuses/O Raxit/O -/O the/O human/O rights/O situation/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O getting/O worse/O ./O 
The/O world/O is/O not/O putting/O enough/O pressure/O on/O China/LOCATION because/O they/O are/O scared/O of/O affecting/O economic/O ties/O ''/O ./O 
This/O ethnic/O group/O ,/O with/O their/O own/O traditions/O and/O language/O ,/O  /O makes/O up/O more/O than/O half/O of/O the/O 19/O million/O inhabitants/O of/O the/O oil/O rich/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ,/O independent/O until/O 1955/O -LRB-/O in/O October/O 2005/O the/O 50th/O anniversary/O of/O its/O '/O annexation/O was/O marked/O -RRB-/O which/O is/O known/O as/O eastern/O Turkestan/O ./O 
 The/O government/O maintains/O that/O there/O are/O active/O terrorists/O in/O the/O region/O citing/O 260/O terrorist/O acts/O had/O been/O committed/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION in/O the/O past/O two/O decades/O ,/O killing/O 160/O and/O wounding/O 440/O ./O ''/O 
In/O Xinjiang/O says/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION boss/O Wang/PERSON Lequan/PERSON ,/O -/O the/O separatists/O ,/O religious/O extremists/O and/O violent/O terrorists/O are/O all/O around/O us/O -/O they/O 're/O very/O active/O ./O 
We/O deal/O with/O these/O criminals/O using/O the/O law/O ./O 
In/O China/LOCATION ,/O endangering/O national/O security/O is/O the/O number/O one/O crime/O ./O 
We/O have/O to/O crack/O down/O on/O it/O severely/O ''/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION is/O promoting/O immigration/O of/O the/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O :/O  in/O 1950/O Urygurs/O were/O 94/O %/O of/O the/O population/O ,/O now/O they/O are/O less/O than/O half/O and/O benefit/O little/O from/O the/O natural/O wealth/O of/O their/O land/O ,/O the/O profits/O of/O which/O are/O destined/O for/O other/O regions/O ./O 
The/O annual/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION report/O ,/O published/O recently/O ,/O accuses/O China/LOCATION of/O carrying/O out/O systematic/O abuse/O against/O these/O people/O and/O their/O rights/O with/O a/O steep/O rise/O in/O persecution/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION denies/O the/O reports/O accuracy/O ,/O describing/O it/O as/O gossip/O mongering/O for/O political/O ends/O ./O 
Kong/PERSON Quan/PERSON ,/O spokes/O person/O for/O the/O foreign/O ministry/O comments/O that/O it/O 's/O not/O worth/O even/O reading/O ./O 
``/O If /O China/LOCATION considers/O this/O report/O to/O be/O worthless/O /O observes/O Raxit/O /O than/O it/O should/O allow/O international/O human/O rights/O group/O to/O come/O to/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O investigate/O these/O claims/O ,/O without/O limits/O ''/O ./O 
-LRB-/O PB/O -RRB-/O 
