Signs/O posted/O in/O mosques/O across/O the/O region/O say/O youth/O league/O members/O ,/O government/O officials/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O active/O and/O retired/O state/O employees/O are/O banned/O from/O entering/O ./O 
Urumqi/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/RFA/O -RRB-/O --/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O banned/O government/O officials/O ,/O state/O employees/O -LRB-/O on/O active/O duty/O or/O retired/O -RRB-/O ,/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O ,/O youth/O league/O members/O ,/O minors/O and/O women/O from/O entering/O mosques/O ./O 
Such/O signs/O ,/O written/O in/O Uyghur/O --/O a/O language/O which/O uses/O the/O Arabic/O alphabet/O and/O is/O frowned/O upon/O by/O the/O authorities/O --/O were/O first/O posted/O in/O mosques/O in/O the/O southern/O and/O poorest/O parts/O of/O the/O region/O ./O 
The/O measure/O is/O part/O of/O a/O vast/O campaign/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION against/O a/O local/O revival/O in/O religious/O practice/O ,/O especially/O amongst/O its/O members/O ./O 
An/O article/O published/O last/O November/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong-based/LOCATION social/O affairs/O journal/O Zhengming/PERSON -LRB-/O `/O Debates/O '/O -RRB-/O reported/O that/O across/O the/O country/O more/O than/O one/O in/O three/O Party/ORGANIZATION members/O have/O become/O involved/O in/O religious/O activities/O ,/O usually/O in/O secret/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION has/O almost/O 20/O million/O members/O ./O 
After/O denying/O that/O there/O was/O any/O ban/O ,/O an/O imam/O at/O the/O Heitkar/LOCATION mosque/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION confirmed/O that/O that/O it/O did/O exist/O ./O 
The/O imam/O ,/O who/O preferred/O not/O to/O reveal/O his/O identity/O ,/O said/O that/O it/O was/O the/O ``/O same/O here/O in/O our/O Heitkar/LOCATION mosque/O ./O 
Our/O policies/O are/O all/O same/O ''/O ./O 
Several/O Uyghur/O Muslims/O confirmed/O that/O members/O of/O certain/O groups/O were/O not/O allowed/O to/O go/O to/O the/O mosque/O even/O for/O major/O festivals/O such/O asEid/O al-Fitr/O at/O the/O end/O of/O the/O fasting/O month/O of/O Ramadan/O ,/O orEid/O al-Adha/O when/O sheep/O and/O goats/O are/O sacrificed/O to/O recall/O the/O sparing/O of/O Abraham/PERSON 's/O son/O Isaac/PERSON ./O 
A/O farmer/O added/O that/O government/O officials/O keep/O tight/O guard/O over/O mosques/O ,/O noting/O who/O comes/O and/O who/O leaves/O ,/O and/O issuing/O fines/O of/O up/O to/O 5,000/O yuan/O -LRB-/O US$/O 620/O ,/O $/O 500/O -RRB-/O to/O those/O who/O break/O the/O ban/O ./O 
He/O mentioned/O the/O case/O of/O a/O schoolteacher/O jailed/O for/O two/O years/O and/O fired/O after/O 20/O years/O '/O service/O for/O persisting/O in/O performing/O her/O five/O daily/O prayers/O as/O required/O of/O each/O Muslim/O ./O 
``/O If/O an/O imam/O does/O not/O do/O what/O the/O government/O says/O ,/O he/O is/O taken/O away/O and/O the/O government/O appoints/O a/O new/O one/O who/O will/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
Known/O as/O East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION till/O 1955/O ,/O Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O currently/O an/O Autonomous/O Region/O ./O 
Uyghurs/PERSON ,/O who/O are/O mostly/O Muslim/O ,/O are/O the/O largest/O ethnic/O group/O in/O a/O population/O of/O 19/O million/O ./O 
The/O oil-rich/O territory/O was/O independent/O until/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION takeover/O ./O 
