Expert/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION warns/O that/O if/O the/O government/O does/O not/O intervene/O against/O unrestricted/O mining/O ,/O the/O rare/O Khotan/LOCATION jade/O mines/O will/O be/O depleted/O in/O five/O years/O ./O 
Urumqi/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/SCMP/O -RRB-/O 聳/O China/LOCATION 's/O supplies/O of/O a/O rare/O jade/O ,/O mainly/O mined/O from/O a/O river/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O will/O soon/O be/O exhausted/O if/O excessive/O exploitation/O continues/O ,/O a/O gem/O expert/O warned/O ./O 
Wang/PERSON Shiqi/PERSON ,/O deputy/O director/O of/O Peking/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Gemstone/ORGANIZATION Appraisal/ORGANIZATION Centre/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O deposits/O of/O Khotan/LOCATION ,/O or/O Hotan/LOCATION ,/O jade/O would/O be/O depleted/O in/O five/O or/O six/O years/O if/O the/O government/O did/O not/O stop/O the/O indiscriminate/O use/O of/O heavy/O excavation/O machinery/O along/O Xinjiang/LOCATION 's/O Yurungkax/LOCATION River/LOCATION ,/O the/O main/O source/O of/O the/O stone/O ./O 
The/O jade/O is/O considered/O to/O be/O the/O highest/O quality/O because/O of/O its/O pure/O texture/O and/O tallow-like/O lustre/O ,/O and/O has/O been/O associated/O with/O emperors/O throughout/O Chinese/O history/O ./O 
Khotan/LOCATION jade/O can/O sell/O for/O up/O to/O 1,000/O yuan/O a/O gram/O -LRB-/O about/O 100/O euros/O or/O 120/O dollars/O US/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O and/O prices/O have/O rocketed/O in/O recent/O years/O because/O of/O a/O sharp/O decrease/O in/O output/O ./O 
The/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/ORGANIZATION agency/ORGANIZATION reports/O that/O prospectors/O with/O modern/O mining/O equipment/O have/O flooded/O into/O the/O region/O to/O capitalise/O on/O the/O gemstone/O 's/O high/O prices/O ./O 
According/O to/O one/O jade/O miner/O ,/O ``/O there/O are/O about/O 200,000/O people/O and/O about/O 2,000/O excavators/O working/O along/O the/O Yurungkax/LOCATION River/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Hotan/LOCATION jade/O trader/O Zheng/PERSON Shengli/PERSON said/O he/O thought/O the/O jade/O would/O be/O depleted/O in/O no/O more/O than/O three/O years/O ,/O noting/O that/O ``/O about/O half/O of/O the/O machines/O have/O stopped/O running/O now/O because/O no/O gemstones/O can/O be/O found/O ./O ''/O 
