The/O raid/O ,/O occurred/O Friday/O ,/O was/O publicized/O today/O by/O the/O police/O ./O 
According/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION separatists/O are/O linked/O with/O al/ORGANIZATION -/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION ./O 
But/O many/O critics/O accuse/O China/LOCATION of/O using/O the/O excuse/O of/O terrorism/O to/O suppress/O religion/O and/O Uighur/O identity/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 聽/O -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O Chinese/O police/O raided/O an/O alleged/O terrorist/O camp/O killing/O 18/O suspects/O and/O arresting/O 17/O in/O the/O western/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ,/O near/O the/O border/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
聽/O Police/O sources/O said/O the/O raid/O occurred/O Friday/O at/O a/O training/O camp/O run/O by/O the/O East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O ETIM/O -RRB-/O ./O 
One/O police/O officer/O was/O killed/O and/O another/O was/O injured/O in/O the/O shoot-out/O ./O 
Police/O are/O also/O searching/O for/O suspects/O who/O are/O believed/O to/O have/O escaped/O during/O the/O raid/O ./O 
They/O found/O 22/O grenades/O and/O material/O for/O 1,500/O more/O ./O 
聽/O The/O camp/O was/O located/O in/O the/O Pamir/LOCATION Plateau/LOCATION ,/O a/O sprawling/O high-altitude/O section/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Xinjiang/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION near/O the/O borders/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ./O 
聽/O According/O to/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O ,/O militants/O among/O the/O region/O 's/O dominant/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O are/O leading/O a/O violent/O Islamic/O separatist/O movement/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Uighurs/O are/O Turkic-speaking/O Muslims/O with/O a/O language/O and/O culture/O distinct/O from/O the/O majority/O of/O Chinese/O ./O 
聽/O But/O critics/O 鈥/O and/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION among/O them/O -/O accuse/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O using/O the/O excuse/O of/O terrorism/O to/O crack/O down/O on/O peaceful/O pro-independence/O sentiment/O and/O expressions/O of/O Uighur/O identity/O ./O 
聽/O China/LOCATION occupied/O Xinjiang/LOCATION at/O the/O end/O of/O the/O communist/O revolution/O in/O 1949/O ./O 
Since/O then/O millions/O of/O Chinese/O migrants/O have/O been/O moved/O to/O Xinjiang/LOCATION to/O colonize/O the/O society/O and/O the/O economy/O ./O 
聽/O The/O Religious/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION has/O put/O restrictions/O on/O the/O religious/O practice/O ./O 
Minors/O and/O women/O 聽are/O not/O allowed/O to/O go/O to/O mosques/O and/O Islamic/O schools/O are/O forbidden/O ./O 
Recently/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O put/O restrictions/O also/O on/O the/O number/O of/O pilgrims/O allowed/O to/O go/O to/O Mecca/LOCATION ./O 
聽/O China/LOCATION says/O ETIM/O is/O one/O of/O the/O region/O 's/O most/O violent/O groups/O ,/O labelling/O it/O a/O terrorist/O organization/O and/O alleging/O that/O it/O has/O links/O to/O al-Qaida/O ./O 
Two/O years/O ago/O ,/O China/LOCATION claimed/O that/O Muslim/O separatist/O groups/O and/O individuals/O in/O western/O China/LOCATION had/O carried/O out/O 260/O attacks/O since/O 1995/O ,/O killing/O 160/O people/O and/O injuring/O 440/O ./O 
聽/O According/O to/O a/O local/O newspaper/O ,/O in/O 2005/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION China/LOCATION arrested18/O .227/O Uygurs/O for/O ``/O threatening/O national/O security/O ''/O ./O 
