The/O Turkish/O premier/O wants/O to/O push/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION to/O address/O the/O crisis/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
But/O Beijing/LOCATION could/O block/O it/O ./O 
The/O Turkish/O foreign/O minister/O calls/O for/O a/O boycott/O of/O Chinese/O goods/O ./O 
Demonstrations/O of/O Uyghurs/LOCATION in/O Istanbul/LOCATION ,/O Canberra/LOCATION ,/O Holland/LOCATION ,/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
Nothing/O new/O from/O the/O Organisation/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Conferences/ORGANIZATION or/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
Ankara/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O The/O Islamic/O world/O feels/O little/O solidarity/O it/O seems/O ,/O with/O fellow/O believers/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Among/O governments/O ,/O however/O ,/O Turkey/LOCATION has/O distinguished/O itself/O ./O 
Yesterday/O ,/O Premier/O Recep/PERSON Tayyip/PERSON Erdo臒an/PERSON defined/O what/O is/O happening/O in/O China/LOCATION as/O ``/O nearly/O genocide/O ./O ''/O 
The/O Turkish/O prime/O minister/O made/O this/O statement/O at/O the/O end/O of/O the/O G8/O in/O L'Aquila/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O heads/O of/O nations/O did/O not/O mention/O events/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION at/O all/O ,/O though/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON cancelled/O his/O presence/O at/O the/O summit/O as/O a/O result/O of/O the/O demonstrations/O and/O subsequent/O clashes/O between/O Uyghurs/LOCATION and/O police/O and/O between/O Han/O and/O Uyghurs/O in/O recent/O days/O ./O 
``/O On/O the/O one/O hand/O -/O said/O Erdogan/PERSON -/O we/O talk/O about/O universal/O human/O rights/O ,/O but/O on/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O we/O have/O to/O witness/O something/O like/O this/O ./O ''/O 
Stating/O that/O he/O has/O expressed/O his/O concerns/O to/O the/O heads/O of/O state/O and/O ministers/O of/O the/O G8/O ,/O the/O Turkish/O premier/O added/O :/O ``/O I/O have/O used/O the/O word/O 鈥榓trocity鈥/O before鈥/O no/O other/O word/O can/O describe/O a/O situation/O which/O is/O nearly/O genocide/O in/O which/O hundreds/O have/O been/O killed/O and/O more/O than/O 1,000/O others/O wounded/O ''/O ./O 
Erdogan/PERSON also/O said/O that/O Turkey/LOCATION is/O considering/O putting/O the/O issue/O of/O the/O Uyghurs/O on/O the/O agenda/O of/O the/O Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O but/O it/O is/O almost/O certain/O that/O China/LOCATION would/O block/O the/O step/O ,/O it/O being/O a/O permanent/O member/O of/O the/O Council/ORGANIZATION and/O stating/O that/O Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O an/O internal/O problem/O ./O 
In/O the/O Islamic聽/O world/O there/O are/O some/O demonstrations/O in/O favour/O of/O the/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
Yesterday/O in/O Istanbul/LOCATION about/O 5/O thousand/O people/O demonstrated/O in/O front/O of/O the/O Fatih/O mosque/O after/O Friday/O prayers/O shouting/O ``/O No/O to/O ethnic/O cleansing鈥/O and/O burning/O Chinese/O products/O ./O 
Two/O days/O ago/O ,/O Nihat/PERSON Ergun/PERSON ,/O the/O Turkish/O trade/O minister/O called/O on/O his/O fellow/O countrymen/O to/O boycott/O Chinese/O goods/O ./O 
The/O population/O of/O Turkey/LOCATION has/O historical/O ,/O linguistic/O and/O ethnic/O bonds/O with/O the/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
The/O demonstrations/O and/O protests/O worldwide/O that/O have/O occurred/O in/O recent/O days/O are/O all/O due/O to/O the/O exiled/O Uyghur/O community.聽/O In/O Canberra/LOCATION -LRB-/O Australia/LOCATION -RRB-/O 200/O people/O gathered/O in/O front/O of/O the/O parliament/O shouting/O ``/O death/O to/O Chinese/O terrorists/O ''/O ./O 
聽/O 聽/O In/O Holland/LOCATION ,/O in/O The/LOCATION Hague/LOCATION other/O exiled/O Uyghurs/O launched/O stones/O against/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O ;/O other/O exiles/O in/O Berlin/LOCATION staged/O a/O sit-in/O in/O front/O of/O the/O embassy/O ./O 
Many/O ordinary/O Muslim/O people/O have/O expressed/O sorrow/O for/O what/O is/O happening/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O but/O governments/O are/O being/O lukewarm/O in/O their/O reactions/O ./O 
The/O Organization/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Conferences/ORGANIZATION has/O condemned/O the/O use/O of/O ``/O disproportionate/O ''/O force/O and/O called/O on/O China/LOCATION for/O an/O ``/O honest/O ''/O inquiry/O into/O the/O incidents/O ./O 
The/O Iranian/O foreign/O minister/O ,/O Manuchehr/PERSON Muttaki/PERSON said/O that/O he/O will/O telephone/O his/O Chinese/O counterpart/O to/O discuss/O the/O situation/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION with/O him/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O the/O main/O trading/O partner/O of/O the/O Arab/O countries/O ,/O surpassing/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Between/O 2004/O and/O 2008/O trade/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O Arab/O countries/O came/O to/O about/O 100/O billion/O dollars/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O also/O long/O secured/O the/O friendship/O of/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION and/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O increasingly/O large/O economic/O ties/O with/O them/O ,/O with/O its/O ever-growing/O need/O for/O oil/O ./O 
In/O return/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O become/O their/O advocate/O in/O the/O international/O community/O ,/O putting/O a/O stop/O to/O certain/O points/O of/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION embargo/O against/O Tehran/LOCATION and/O willingly/O closing/O a/O eye/O on/O the/O world鈥檚/O criticism/O of/O Saudi/O Arabia鈥檚/O human/O rights/O record/O ./O 
