The/O meeting/O is/O scheduled/O for/O mid-December/O in/O Taichung/LOCATION ./O 
Security/O measures/O are/O set/O to/O be/O tightened/O to/O prevent/O demonstrations/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION and/O Taipei/LOCATION are/O increasingly/O closer/O despite/O opposition/O by/O pro-independence/O groups/O ./O 
Chinese/O delegation/O will/O not/O travel/O to/O Kaohsiung/LOCATION in/O guided/O tour/O because/O it/O hosted/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O and/O screened/O a/O documentary/O on/O a/O Uyghur/O activist/O ./O 
Taipei/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O 鈥/O Double/O taxation/O ,/O agricultural/O products/O inspection/O ,/O fisheries/O co-operation/O and/O industry/O standards/O certification/O will/O be/O the/O top/O priorities/O in/O cross-trait/O talks/O that/O will/O take/O place/O in/O the/O middle/O of/O December/O in/O Taichung/LOCATION City/LOCATION -LRB-/O west-central/O Taiwan/LOCATION -RRB-/O ./O 
Relations/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O will/O be/O further/O strengthened/O by/O this/O round/O of/O talks/O ,/O now/O that/O they/O have/O air/O and/O maritime/O links.聽/O To/O prevent/O incidents/O ,/O 鈥淭aichung/O will/O beef/O up/O security/O arrangements/O ,/O 鈥/O said/O Jason/PERSON Hu/PERSON ,/O the/O city鈥檚/O Mayor/O ./O 
He/O did/O not/O reveal/O the/O exact/O venue/O where/O the/O two/O delegations/O will/O meet/O ./O 
Unfazed/O by/O Hu鈥檚/O promise/O of/O tight/O security/O during/O the/O upcoming/O talks/O ,/O Chen/PERSON Da-chun/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O the/O Democratic/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party鈥檚/ORGANIZATION Taichung/ORGANIZATION Office/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O he/O would/O petition/O DPP/ORGANIZATION headquarters/O to/O organise/O protests/O against/O the/O meeting/O because/O it/O jeopardises/O Taiwan鈥檚/O sovereignty/O ./O 
Chiang/PERSON Pin-kung/PERSON ,/O chairman/O of/O Taiwan/LOCATION 's/O quasi-official/O Straits/ORGANIZATION Exchange/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SEF/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O will/O meet/O the/O chairman/O of/O theAssociation/O for/O Relations/O Across/O the/O Taiwan/LOCATION Straits/O -LRB-/O ARATS/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O Chen/PERSON Yunlin/PERSON ./O 
The/O two/O will/O exchange/O views/O on/O a/O quasi-free-trade/O pact/O that/O the/O island/O hopes/O to/O sign/O with/O the/O mainland/O ,/O but/O official/O talks/O on/O the/O formation/O of/O this/O Economic/O Co-operation/O Framework/O Agreement/O will/O be/O held/O separately/O ./O 
Participants/O in/O the/O talks/O will/O avoid/O politically/O sensitive/O Kaohsiung鈥攁/O stronghold/O for/O pro-independence/O supporters/O in/O southern/O Taiwan/LOCATION ./O 
Tibet鈥檚/O spiritual/O leader/O ,/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ,/O recently/O travelled/O to/O the/O city/O to/O visit/O areas/O devastated/O by/O typhoon/O Morakot/PERSON ./O 
City/O authorities/O also/O allowed/O the/O screening/O of/O a/O controversial/O documentary/O on/O Uygur/O activist/O Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON at/O the/O city/O 's/O film/O festival聽/O Both/O decisions/O sparked/O protests/O in/O the/O mainland/O ,/O which/O has/O accused/O the/O local/O government/O of/O fuelling/O pro-independence/O claims/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
For/O this/O reason/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION decided/O its/O delegation/O would/O not/O visit/O the/O city/O in/O any/O guided/O tour/O ,/O probably/O fearful/O that/O it/O would/O be/O met/O by/O huge/O protests/O ./O 
