The/O identity/O of/O the/O three/O people/O is/O being/O withheld/O to/O avoid/O suggestions/O about/O possible/O motives/O ,/O like/O an/O extreme/O attempt/O to/O protest/O against/O rights/O violations/O ./O 
Yesterday/O in/O Shenzhen/LOCATION worker/O set/O himself/O on/O fire/O after/O he/O was/O sacked/O without/O severance/O pay/O ./O 
The/O life/O of/O imprisoned/O human/O rights/O Wang/PERSON Guilan/PERSON is/O danger/O because/O prison/O authorities/O are/O denying/O her/O medical/O care/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O The/O authorities/O are/O saying/O nothing/O about/O an/O attempt/O by/O three/O people/O ,/O two/O men/O and/O a/O woman/O ,/O to/O set/O themselves/O on/O fire/O inside/O a/O car/O at/O the/O intersection/O of/O Chang/PERSON '/O an/O Avenue/O and/O shopping/O street/O Wangfujing/O ,/O in/O downtown/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O about/O a/O kilometre/O from/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ./O 
The/O man/O ,/O 59/O ,/O and/O the/O woman/O ,/O 58/O ,/O were/O brought/O to/O Jishuitan/LOCATION Hospital/LOCATION in/O serious/O conditions/O ./O 
Nothing/O is/O known/O about/O the/O second/O man/O ,/O but/O eyewitnesses/O said/O he/O was/O young/O ./O 
It/O is/O believed/O he/O might/O be/O in/O police/O custody/O ./O 
They/O set/O themselves/O on/O fire/O when/O police/O stopped/O them/O for/O a/O check/O because/O their/O car/O had/O a/O non-Beijing/O license/O platewith/O three/O red/O flags/O on/O the/O roof/O ./O 
Police/O pulled/O all/O three/O out/O before/O the/O car/O exploded/O ./O 
In/O reporting/O the/O event/O state/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION only/O said/O that/O the/O three/O people/O came/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O submit/O ``/O personal/O petitions/O ''/O ./O 
It/O might/O be/O significant/O that/O the/O authorities/O did/O not/O release/O any/O names/O ,/O a/O detail/O that/O might/O suggest/O a/O possible/O motive/O ./O 
Eyewitnesses/O said/O in/O fact/O that/O the/O car/O had/O a/O Xinjiang/LOCATION licence/O plate/O and/O that/O the/O three/O people/O inside/O looked/O ethnic/O ``/O Uyghur/O ''/O ./O 
Extreme/O public/O protests/O are/O not/O rare/O in/O China/LOCATION given/O the/O country/O 's/O systematic/O lack/O of/O rights/O ./O 
Self-immolation/O in/O public/O is/O seen/O by/O many/O as/O the/O ultimate/O refusal/O of/O someone/O else/O 's/O unjust/O action/O and/O violence/O ;/O it/O is/O a/O way/O to/O highlight/O their/O reprehensible/O behaviour/O ./O 
In/O recent/O years/O at/O least/O ten/O people/O have/O set/O themselves/O on/O fire/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O in/O the/O heart/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O a/O place/O rich/O in/O history/O ./O 
On/O 20/O July/O 2006/O Wang/PERSON Congan/PERSON ,/O a/O migrant/O worker/O from/O Jiangsu/LOCATION ,/O soaked/O himself/O in/O gasoline/O and/O turned/O himself/O into/O a/O human/O torch/O in/O front/O of/O hundreds/O of/O tourists/O ./O 
Wang/PERSON ,/O who/O survived/O ,/O had/O not/O been/O paid/O for/O months/O by/O a/O construction/O firm/O in/O Yuanan/LOCATION County/LOCATION -LRB-/O Hubei/LOCATION -RRB-/O ./O 
He/O had/O come/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION seeking/O redress/O ,/O without/O getting/O it/O ./O 
Before/O that/O an/O elderly/O couple/O unjustly/O thrown/O out/O of/O their/O home/O also/O set/O themselves/O on/O fire/O ;/O so/O did/O workers/O who/O were/O cheated/O out/O of/O their/O wages/O ;/O or/O people/O just/O too/O tired/O of/O submitting/O petitions/O that/O got/O nowhere/O ./O 
The/O latest/O incident/O could/O also/O be/O connected/O to/O important/O upcoming/O events/O and/O anniversaries/O like/O the/O annual/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O 50th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O crushing/O of/O the/O Tibet/LOCATION uprising/O ,/O the/O 20th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION massacre/O ,/O the/O 10th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O banning/O of/O the/O Falun/ORGANIZATION Gong/ORGANIZATION spiritual/O movement/O ,/O and/O the/O 60th/O anniversary/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O occupation/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
But/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O not/O the/O only/O place/O where/O such/O incidents/O are/O taking/O place/O ./O 
Yesterday/O in/O Shenzhen/LOCATION a/O migrant/O worker/O ,/O Fang/PERSON Donglei/PERSON ,/O set/O himself/O on/O fire/O after/O he/O was/O sacked/O by/O his/O employer/O ,/O Welluxe/ORGANIZATION Technology/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Manufacturing/ORGANIZATION ,/O without/O motivation/O or/O severance/O pay/O ./O 
Mr/O Fang/PERSON 's/O wife/O ,/O Li/PERSON Xinxia/PERSON ,/O told/O the/O South/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Morning/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION that/O after/O another/O argument/O with/O the/O firm/O 's/O supervisor/O he/O set/O himself/O on/O fire/O in/O front/O of/O him/O ./O 
Now/O he/O is/O in/O hospital/O with/O burns/O covering/O 55/O per/O cent/O of/O his/O body/O ./O 
If/O survives/O he/O has/O to/O pick/O up/O the/O medical/O bill/O because/O the/O ``/O factory/O paid/O just/O 8,000/O yuan/O for/O the/O hospital/O deposit/O and/O we/O 're/O still/O waiting/O for/O enough/O money/O for/O skin-graft/O surgery/O ,/O ''/O Ms/O Li/PERSON said/O ./O 
Human/O rights/O group/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Defenders/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CHRD/O -RRB-/O recently/O reported/O that/O the/O life/O of/O Wang/PERSON Guilan/PERSON ,/O sentenced/O to/O 15/O months/O of/O re-education/O through/O labour/O in/O August/O 2008/O ,/O is/O in/O danger/O because/O prison/O authorities/O have/O denied/O her/O much/O needed/O medical/O treatment/O ./O 
In/O 2001/O Ms/O Wang/PERSON Guilan/PERSON was/O forced/O out/O of/O her/O business/O in/O an/O Enshi/LOCATION City/LOCATION mall/O by/O developers/O and/O never/O properly/O compensated/O ./O 
Unable/O to/O seek/O redress/O through/O legal/O avenues/O and/O abused/O by/O court/O officials/O when/O she/O went/O in/O search/O of/O justice/O ,/O she/O set/O herself/O on/O fire/O in/O protest/O and/O suffered/O traumatic/O injuries/O ./O 
Having/O survived/O this/O ordeal/O she/O became/O an/O activist/O for/O petitioners/O '/O rights/O ,/O organising/O a/O public/O letter/O to/O public/O officials/O on/O behalf/O of/O petitioners/O and/O exposing/O illegal/O police/O practices/O directed/O against/O petitioners/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
For/O her/O troubles/O she/O was/O arrested/O last/O year/O on/O charges/O of/O ``/O disturbing/O the/O social/O order/O ''/O and/O later/O sentenced/O to/O 15/O months/O in/O a/O forced/O labour/O camp/O because/O she/O had/O accepted/O a/O phone/O interview/O with/O a/O foreign/O journalist/O ./O 
Now/O she/O needs/O immediate/O medical/O attention/O because/O she/O suffers/O from/O hypertension/O and/O heart/O disease/O and/O her/O burn/O wounds/O are/O badly/O infected/O ./O 
