Increases/O to/O 12/O the/O number/O of/O death/O sentences/O imposed/O ./O 
Every/O year/O Beijing/LOCATION condemns/O hundreds/O of/O Uyghurs/LOCATION to/O capital/O execution/O ./O 
The/O World/O Uygur/O Congress/O :/O Stop/O China/LOCATION 's/O bloody/O repression/O against/O the/O Uyghur/O people/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O Six/O people/O today/O received/O the/O death/O sentence/O ,/O charged/O with/O being/O behind/O the/O riots/O that/O broke/O out/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION last/O July/O ./O 
Earlier/O in/O the/O week/O 6/O others/O were/O sentenced/O to/O death/O ./O 
The/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Urumqi/ORGANIZATION has/O ruled/O a/O stay/O of/O two/O years/O in/O the/O sentence/O for/O three/O of/O the/O condemned/O ./O 
In/O the/O trial/O of/O the/O 14/O defendants/O ,/O three/O were/O sentenced/O to/O life/O imprisonment/O and/O five/O to/O prison/O for/O several/O years/O ./O 
On/O 5/O July/O last/O ,/O peaceful/O demonstrations/O of/O protest/O by/O Uyghurs/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION degenerated/O into/O ethnic/O clashes/O between/O the/O Muslim/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O populations/O ./O 
The/O police/O and/O army/O repressed/O tensions/O carrying/O out/O thousands/O of/O arrests/O ./O 
Uyghurs/O accuse/O Han/PERSON of/O colonizing/O them/O ,/O having/O occupied/O all/O the/O top/O positions/O in/O business/O and/O public/O administration/O ./O 
For/O decades/O ,/O the/O Uyghur/O population/O has/O been/O suffering/O a/O heavy/O military/O control/O ,/O which/O has/O grown/O in/O recent/O months/O ,/O in/O the/O aftermath/O of/O the/O clashes/O ./O 
The/O Uyghurs/O in/O exile/O have/O condemned/O the/O death/O sentences/O ,/O calling/O them/O ``/O the/O first/O mass/O of/O a/O execution/O promised/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O ''/O 
According/O to/O international/O organizations/O for/O human/O rights/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION carries/O out/O an/O average/O of/O hundreds/O of/O executions/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION in/O a/O year/O ./O 
A/O statement/O by/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION confesses/O that/O they/O ``/O can/O only/O hope/O that/O the/O world/O will/O stop/O China/LOCATION in/O its/O ongoing/O bloody/O repression/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O people/O ./O ''/O 
