Seven/O thousand/O employees/O will/O explain/O government/O policy/O house/O by/O house/O ./O 
Li/PERSON Zhi/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Urumqi/LOCATION and/O Liu/PERSON Yaohua/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O security/O ,/O have/O been/O forced/O to/O resign/O ./O 
Wang/PERSON Lequan/PERSON ,/O regional/O head/O of/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION and/O friend/O of/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON is/O still/O in/O the/O saddle/O ./O 
Urumqi/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //ORGANIZATION Agencies/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O Seven/O thousand/O government/O employees/O will/O visit/O the/O population/O of/O Urumqi/LOCATION house/O to/O house/O to/O promote/O calm/O after/O recent/O clashes/O between/O Han/O Chinese/O and/O Uyghurs/LOCATION that/O left/O five/O dead/O and/O dozens/O wounded/O ./O 
The/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION secretary/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Wang/PERSON Lequan/PERSON said/O that/O these/O ``/O harmony/O makers/O ''/O will/O explain/O what/O the/O government/O is/O doing/O to/O bring/O peace/O to/O the/O region/O and/O ``/O resolve/O disputes/O ''/O ./O 
The/O tensions/O of/O last/O week/O were/O caused/O by/O a/O series/O of/O attacks/O by/O unknown/O assailants/O who/O injured/O 531/O people/O with/O hypodermic/O syringes/O ./O 
Police/O ,/O the/O public/O prosecutor/O and/O courts/O have/O declared/O that/O the/O perpetrators/O of/O syringe/O attacks/O will/O be/O judged/O according/O to/O the/O law/O ./O 
Whoever/O injected/O poisons/O ,/O harmful/O substances/O or/O drugs/O will/O be/O sentenced/O to/O three/O years/O imprisonment/O ,/O life/O imprisonment/O or/O even/O the/O death/O penalty/O ./O 
Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O capital/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O remains/O calm/O ,/O given/O the/O massive/O police/O presence/O in/O the/O city/O thanks/O since/O early/O July/O ,/O when/O peaceful/O demonstrations/O by/O Uyghurs/PERSON became/O open/O ethnic/O clashes/O between/O Han/O Chinese/O and/O Uyghur/O Muslims/O ./O 
In/O recent/O days/O the/O Chinese/O have/O shown/O their/O discontent/O taking/O to/O the/O streets/O ,/O accusing/O the/O party/O and/O government/O of/O failing/O to/O maintain/O order/O in/O the/O area/O and/O calling/O for/O the/O resignation/O of/O Li/PERSON Zhi/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O party/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION and/O Liu/PERSON Yaohua/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O security/O ./O 
Both/O have/O been/O forced/O to/O resign/O ./O 
Some/O sources/O also/O say/O that/O the/O party/O chief/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Wang/PERSON Lequan/PERSON was/O discharged/O ,/O but/O there/O has/O so/O far/O been/O no/O confirmation/O ./O 
Indeed/O ,/O the/O launch/O of/O the/O ``/O makers/O of/O harmony/O ''/O campaign/O ,/O widely/O covered/O byXinhua/O ,/O shows/O that/O he/O is/O still/O in/O office/O ./O 
Wang/PERSON ,/O 64/O ,/O has/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION and/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION since/O 1994/O ./O 
Having/O worked/O in/O the/O '80s/O in/O the/O Young/O Communist/O League/O ,/O he/O is/O considered/O a/O close/O ally/O of/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ./O 
His/O 鈥淢akers/O of/O Harmony鈥/O campaign/O recalls/O the/O slogan/O of/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON 's/O statement/O that/O China/LOCATION should/O build/O a/O ``/O harmonious/O society/O ''/O ./O 
The/O situation/O of/O minorities/O -/O particularly/O Tibetans/O and/O Uyghurs/O -/O is/O far/O from/O harmonious/O ./O 
Uyghurs/O seek/O autonomy/O in/O their/O territory/O now/O colonized/O by/O a/O majority/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O who/O have/O settled/O in/O the/O bureaucracy/O ,/O government/O and/O economy/O ,/O marginalizing/O the/O local/O population/O ./O 
The/O syringe/O attacks/O with/O first/O started/O August/O 17/O and/O continue/O to/O date/O ,/O targeting/O the/O majority/O Han/O ,/O but/O also/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
Doctors/O have/O excluded/O that/O the/O syringes/O contained/O radioactive/O substances/O ,/O anthrax/O or/O chemical/O poisons/O ./O 
