Sentences/O of/O up/O to/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O two/O men/O and/O a/O woman/O ./O 
The/O court/O did/O not/O issue/O their/O ethnicity/O ,/O but/O they/O appear/O to/O belong/O to/O the/O minority/O Uyghur/O ./O 
Eighty/O people/O awaiting/O trial/O for/O the/O violence/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O but/O authorities/O refuse/O to/O disclose/O the/O date/O of/O hearings/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //ORGANIZATION Agencies/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O A/O court/O has/O convicted/O three/O people/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION with/O penalties/O of/O up/O to/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O in/O the/O first/O trial/O against/O the/O alleged/O perpetrators/O of/O the/O attacks/O with/O hypodermic/O syringes/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O have/O not/O announced/O the/O ethnicity/O of/O the/O defendants/O ,/O but/O the/O names/O seem/O to/O belong/O to/O the/O minority/O Muslim/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
Earlier/O this/O week/O official/O sources/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION reported/O they/O had/O arrested/O 12/O suspects/O implicated/O in/O the/O mysterious/O attacks/O by/O unknown/O assailants/O armed/O with/O hypodermic/O syringes/O ,/O with/O which/O they/O ``/O stabbed/O ''/O passersby/O ./O 
According/O to/O Chinese/O media/O ,/O from/O mid-August/O there/O were/O hundreds/O of/O cases/O of/O injuries/O ,/O which/O has/O further/O helped/O to/O exacerbate/O tensions/O between/O the/O minority/O Muslim/O Uyghur鈥檚/O and/O Chinese/O Han/O ./O 
聽/O The/O court/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION sentenced/O to/O 15/O years/O in/O prison/O Yilipan/PERSON Yilihamu/PERSON ,/O a/O boy/O of/O 19/O years/O who/O is/O charged/O with/O having/O stabbed/O a/O woman/O while/O buying/O fruit/O in/O a/O market/O ./O 
Ten/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O Muhutaerjiang/PERSON Turda/PERSON ,/O 34/O ,/O and/O seven/O to/O Aimannisha/LOCATION Guli/LOCATION ,/O a/O young/O woman/O of/O 22/O ./O 
聽/O Both/O apparently/O threatened/O a/O taxi/O driver/O with/O a/O syringe/O ,/O stealing/O about/O 700/O Yuan/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O equivalent/O to/O U.S./LOCATION $/O 103/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O tension/O remains/O high/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ./O 
Last/O week/O five/O people/O died/O during/O a/O protest/O which/O brought/O together/O thousands/O of/O citizens/O demanding/O the/O resignation/O of/O the/O local/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION chief/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O have/O not/O wanted/O to/O clarify/O the/O causes/O of/O death/O ./O 
聽/O Since/O July/O Xinjiang/LOCATION has/O been/O the/O scene/O of/O violence/O and/O social/O tensions/O between/O the/O minority/O Muslim/O Uyghurs/O and/O Chinese/O Han/O ./O 
These/O are/O the/O worst/O ethnic/O clashes/O in/O decades/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O protests/O are/O mounting/O in/O the/O nation/O ,/O with/O the/O demand/O for/O stiff/O penalties/O for/O those/O found/O guilty/O ./O 
Police/O have/O charged/O about/O eighty/O persons/O awaiting/O trial/O ;/O so/O far/O the/O dates/O of/O hearings/O have/O not/O yet/O been/O made/O public/O ./O 
