Groups/O of/O Tibetans/O in/O exile/O underline/O the/O similarities/O between/O what/O is/O happening/O today/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O the/O crackdown/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION after/O the/O March/O 2008/O protests/O ./O 
Fear/O of/O disappearances/O ,/O death/O sentences/O and/O life/O imprisonment/O ,/O a/O constant/O fact/O of/O martial/O law/O ./O 
Dharamsala/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O -/O Tibetans/O in/O exile/O are/O in/O solidarity/O with/O the/O Uyghur/O population/O ,/O over/O the/O tragic/O events/O of/O recent/O days/O with/O the/O police/O firing/O on/O the/O crowd/O protesting/O in/O the/O capital/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O causing/O hundreds/O of/O deaths/O and/O an/O unknown/O number/O of/O wounded/O ./O 
An/O unreal/O calm/O is/O now/O maintained/O by/O over/O 20/O thousand/O soldiers/O who/O patrol/O the/O city/O ./O 
Last/O night/O the/O government/O updated/O the/O death/O toll/O from/O clashes/O between/O Uyghurs/LOCATION and/O police/O and/O between/O Uyghurs/LOCATION and/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
According/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION the/O dead/O were/O 184/O -LRB-/O up/O from/O 156/O -RRB-/O ,/O of/O which/O 137/O are/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O the/O injured/O over/O a/O thousand/O ./O 
But/O according/O to/O exiled/O Uyghurs/O there/O are/O thousands/O of/O Uyghurs/O victims/O ./O 
Five/O of/O the/O largest/O groups/O of/O exiled/O Tibetans/O have/O asked/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O release/O those/O who/O have/O been/O arrested/O for/O protesting/O in/O a/O peaceful/O manner/O ,/O to/O restore/O telephone/O and/O internet/O communications/O with/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O to/O allow/O media/O access/O ,/O to/O stop/O the/O propaganda/O campaign/O that/O lays/O the/O blame/O on/O the/O demonstrators/O ,/O thus/O encouraging/O further/O violence/O ,/O to/O allow/O an/O independent/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION investigation/O ./O 
The/O groups/O note/O how/O Beijing/LOCATION handles/O the/O situation/O with/O exactly/O the/O same/O procedures/O adopted/O against/O peaceful/O protests/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION in/O March/O 2008/O ./O 
Then/O as/O now/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O :/O clamped/O down/O on/O foreign/O press/O ,/O cut/O all/O communication/O via/O internet/O and/O mobile/O phones/O to/O prevent/O any/O spread/O of/O news/O from/O noon-official/O sources/O ,/O carried/O out/O continuous/O night/O raids/O with/O the/O arrest/O of/O hundreds/O of/O people/O for/O merely/O being/O outdoors/O ,/O flooded/O television/O with/O images/O and/O statements/O that/O show/O only/O violent/O protests/O in/O ethnic/O conflicts/O ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O in/O both/O cases/O the/O responsibility/O for/O the/O protests/O ,/O without/O any/O proof/O to/O back/O up/O the/O charge/O ,/O were/O laid/O at/O the/O feet/O of/O a/O ``/O hostile/O foreign/O forces/O ''/O :/O referring/O to/O the/O exiled/O leader/O Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON and/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O while/O in/O the/O case/O of/O the/O Tibetan/O revolt/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O was/O charged/O with/O the/O responsibility/O ./O 
Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON ,/O a/O wealthy/O entrepreneur/O ,/O spent/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O years/O because/O of/O her/O struggle/O for/O the/O freedom/O of/O the/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
Released/O for/O medical/O reasons/O ,/O she/O now/O lives/O in/O exile/O ./O 
Ngawang/PERSON Woeber/PERSON ,/O spokesman/O of/O the/O initiative/O ,/O echoes/O “Rebiya/O Kadeer/PERSON 's/O urgent/O call/O for/O peace/O ,/O justice/O and/O the/O end/O of/O all/O violence/O and/O appeal/O to/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O end/O its/O brutal/O suppression/O of/O Uyghurs/LOCATION throughout/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION ''/O -LRB-/O the/O Chinese/O Xinjiang/LOCATION -RRB-/O ./O 
He/O recalls/O how/O the/O president/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON left/O the/O G8/O summit/O taking/O place/O in/O Italy/LOCATION in/O a/O hurry/O ,/O “to/O avoid/O facing/O the/O international/O media/O and/O being/O swamped/O with/O questions/O ,/O projects/O utter/O failure/O in/O the/O policy/O adopted/O by/O Chinese/O government/O in/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION and/O for/O that/O matter/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION as/O well/O ./O ''/O 
The/O groups/O point/O out/O that/O the/O Uyghur/O and/O Tibetans/O have/O not/O accepted/O the/O domination/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O despite/O the/O hardships/O of/O the/O past/O 50/O years/O ,/O and/O continue/O to/O ask/O for/O essential/O freedoms/O and/O human/O rights/O ./O 
In/O this/O situation/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O policy/O undermines/O social/O stability/O :/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O 16/O months/O after/O the/O bloody/O suppression/O of/O protests/O ,/O there/O is/O still/O de/O facto/O martial/O law/O ,/O with/O more/O than/O 1,000/O people/O arrested/O whose/O fate/O is/O still/O unknown/O ./O 
In/O the/O Tibetan/O protests/O ,/O there/O were/O about/O 200/O dead/O and/O hundreds/O arrested/O ,/O at/O least/O 5/O of/O which/O were/O then/O sentenced/O to/O death/O ./O 
The/O Tibetans/O fear/O is/O that/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION more/O ``/O disappearances/O ''/O ,/O beatings/O of/O demonstrators/O arrested/O and/O harsh/O sentences/O are/O taking/O place/O ./O 
To/O avoid/O this/O ,/O they/O are/O appealing/O to/O the/O international/O community/O to/O intervene/O ./O 
 /O  /O  /O 
