Shows/O and/O perfect/O organization/O for/O the/O grand/O celebration/O of/O 60/O years/O of/O communism/O ./O 
The/O party/O celebrates/O the/O greatness/O of/O the/O country/O to/O assert/O its/O power/O ./O 
But/O its/O celebrations/O ignore/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O many/O unsolved/O problems/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //ORGANIZATION Agencies/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O China/LOCATION stopped/O for/O hours/O yesterday/O to/O watch/O the/O television/O and/O witness/O the/O clear/O message/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION wanted/O to/O send/O to/O the/O world/O :/O China/LOCATION has/O grown/O and/O claims/O its/O place/O among/O the/O world/O powers/O ,/O under/O the/O unquestioned/O leadership/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O ceremony/O perfectly/O organised/O down/O to/O the/O very/O last/O detail/O :/O  yesterday/O morning/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O was/O threatened/O by/O ominous/O clouds/O and/O immediately/O the/O sky/O was/O bombarded/O with/O 432/O rockets/O loaded/O with/O silver/O iodide/O ,/O which/O quickly/O gave/O a/O clear/O blue/O sky/O ,/O as/O had/O been/O done/O for/O the/O inauguration/O of/O the/O Olympics/O a/O year/O ago/O ./O 
The/O cost/O :/O about/O 2/O thousand/O Yuan/PERSON per/O skyrocket/O ,/O a/O little/O under/O one/O million/O Yuan/O -LRB-/O 100/O thousand/O euros/O -RRB-/O in/O total/O ./O 
For/O the/O military/O parade/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON donned/O a/O green-gray/O jacket/O -LRB-/O see/O photo/O -RRB-/O like/O that/O always/O worn/O by/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON ,/O tailored/O just/O for/O the/O event/O ./O 
Like/O Mao/PERSON ,/O he/O paraded/O aboard/O a/O 12-cylinder/O communist-red/O limousine/O in/O front/O of/O the/O deployed/O troops/O repeating/O :/O ``/O I/O greet/O you/O ,/O comrades/O ,/O ''/O and/O getting/O the/O answer/O :/O ``/O Hello/O ,/O Our/O Leader/O !/O ''/O 
Or/O even/O ``/O We/O serve/O the/O People/O !/O 
./O 
He/O even/O marched/O hand/O in/O hand/O with/O a/O Tibetan/O girl/O on/O one/O side/O and/O a/O Uyghur/O child/O on/O the/O other/O ,/O although/O his/O speech/O avoided/O all/O mention/O of/O the/O problems/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xiniang/LOCATION ./O 
A/O large/O screen/O in/O the/O square/O showed/O pictures/O of/O happy/O Tibetans/O ,/O but/O many/O commentators/O have/O wondered/O if/O they/O were/O not/O ,/O in/O reality/O ,/O ethnic/O Han/O in/O Tibetan/O costume/O ./O 
In/O a/O carefully/O orchestrated/O show/O ,/O the/O successes/O of/O China/LOCATION in/O every/O field/O were/O represented/O and/O several/O illustrious/O Chinese/O personalities/O took/O part/O in/O the/O march/O :/O from/O former/O Olympic/O champion/O Liu/PERSON Xiang/PERSON to/O the/O astronaut/O Zhai/PERSON Zhigang/PERSON who/O made/O the/O first/O Chinese/O space/O walk/O ./O 
The/O ceremony/O was/O attended/O by/O past/O and/O present/O leaders/O and/O the/O portrait/O of/O Hu/PERSON was/O exhibited/O alongside/O those/O of/O Mao/PERSON and/O his/O successors/O ,/O Deng/PERSON Xiaoping/PERSON and/O Jiang/PERSON Zemin/PERSON ,/O to/O signify/O the/O continuity/O of/O the/O Communist/O leadership/O and/O to/O give/O Hu/PERSON a/O place/O equal/O to/O those/O of/O his/O predecessors/O ./O 
The/O celebration/O of/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION ,/O however/O ,/O was/O devoid/O of/O its/O people/O :/O  Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION and/O along/O the/O route/O of/O the/O parade/O was/O filled/O by/O authorities/O and/O especially/O selected/O guests/O ,/O from/O among/O the/O 75/O million/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O who/O form/O the/O political/O leadership/O and/O who/O control/O the/O armed/O forces/O ./O 
Instead/O ,/O the/O people/O were/O ``/O invited/O ''/O by/O a/O relentless/O campaign/O to/O stay/O home/O and/O watch/O the/O parade/O along/O Changan/LOCATION Boulevard/LOCATION on/O television/O ./O 
The/O security/O measures/O were/O maximal/O and/O the/O many/O ,/O mostly/O foreign/O tourists/O ,/O who/O tried/O to/O ``/O infiltrate/O ''/O the/O celebrations/O uninvited/O met/O with/O little/O luck/O :/O as/O if/O the/O Great/LOCATION China/LOCATION that/O on/O a/O par/O with/O world/O power/O feels/O threatened/O by/O its/O own/O citizens/O having/O to/O keep/O them/O at/O a/O safe/O distance/O from/O its/O leaders/O celebrations. So/O much/O so/O ,/O it/O has/O had/O to/O arrest in/O the/O past/O year/O or/O so/O ,/O numerous/O pro-democracy/O activists/O and/O defenders/O of/O human/O rights/O ,/O to/O prevent/O them/O from/O organizing/O protests/O and/O demonstrations/O during/O this/O celebration. /O Still/O China/LOCATION proudly/O participated/O in/O the/O party/O and/O recalled/O the/O last/O 30/O years/O of/O rapid/O economic/O and/O international/O growth/O ,/O after/O 30/O years/O of/O isolationism/O and/O after/O having/O suffered/O repeated/O abuse/O in/O the/O previous/O 200/O years/O ./O 
But/O those/O who/O were/O around/O 60/O years/O ago/O remember/O the/O announcement/O of/O Mao/PERSON ,/O but/O also/O the/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O people/O persecuted/O during/O the/O Cultural/O Revolution/O and/O the/O millions/O of/O deaths/O from/O the/O Great/O Famine/O ,/O an/O event/O which/O the/O CCP/ORGANIZATION has/O never/O disavowed/O ,/O and/O of/O which/O it/O is/O still/O forbidden/O to/O speak/O in/O terms/O that/O deviate/O from/O the/O official/O version/O ./O 
 /O 
