The/O new/O gas/O pipeline/O will/O bring/O natural/O gas/O to/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
It/O represents/O a/O slap/O in/O the/O face/O of/O Russia鈥檚/O approach/O to/O energy/O politics/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
For/O months/O ,/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION were/O at/O loggerheads/O over/O gas/O prices/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O the/O big/O winner/O ./O 
Ashgabat/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O 鈥/O The/O Kremlin/LOCATION is/O in/O a/O tight/O spot/O and/O must/O rethink/O its/O approach/O to/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION energy/O ,/O this/O according/O to/O some/O Russia/LOCATION newspapers/O that/O commented/O Monday鈥檚/O inauguration/O of/O the/O new/O Turkmenistan-China/LOCATION gas/O pipeline/O ./O 
The/O new/O facility/O is/O crucial/O to/O the/O geopolitics/O of/O the/O Caspian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION and/O more/O broadly/O Asia/LOCATION ./O 
It/O reinforces/O China鈥檚/O presence/O in/O the/O region/O at/O the/O expense/O of/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O which/O hitherto/O had/O held/O a/O stranglehold/O over/O gas/O exported/O from/O the/O former/O Soviet/LOCATION republics/LOCATION ./O 
Once/O it/O is/O in/O full/O operation/O in/O 2013/O ,/O the/O US$/O 20/O billion/O pipeline/O will/O stretch/O 1,883/O kilometres/O ./O 
It/O will/O have/O a/O capacity/O to/O deliver/O 40/O billion/O cubic/O metres/O a/O year/O to/O China鈥檚/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ,/O through/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION and/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ./O 
A/O deal/O between/O China/ORGANIZATION National/ORGANIZATION Petroleum/ORGANIZATION Corporation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O and/O KazStroyService/O will/O however/O allow/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION to/O keep/O 10/O billion/O cubic/O metres/O ./O 
Chinese/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ,/O his/O Turkmen/O counterpart/O ,/O Gurbanguly/PERSON Berdymukhamedov/PERSON ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O Presidenta/O of/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ,/O Nursultan/PERSON Nazarbaev/PERSON ,/O and/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION ,/O 聽Islam/O Karimov/PERSON ,/O were/O present/O at/O the/O inauguration/O ceremony/O of/O the/O Trans/O Asian/O Gas/O Pipeline/O -LRB-/O TAGP/O -RRB-/O in/O Saman-Depe/LOCATION ./O 
This/O structure/O is/O a/O very/O important/O element/O in/O Asia鈥檚/O energy/O equation/O ,/O especially/O since/O it/O is/O the/O first/O to/O bypass/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
For/O Turkmen/O President/O Berdymukhamedov/PERSON himself/O ,/O the/O pipeline/O is/O more/O than/O about/O economics/O ,/O it/O is/O a/O signal/O to/O Russia/LOCATION that/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION wants/O closer/O ties/O to/O China/LOCATION ,/O one/O of/O the/O guarantors/O of/O global/O security/O ./O 
Why/O did/O Moscow鈥檚/O relations/O with/O its/O former/O satellites/O sour/O ?/O 
Its/O arrogance/O ./O 
In/O July/O 2008/O ,/O Gazprom/ORGANIZATION signed/O an/O agreement/O to/O buy/O Turkmen/O gas/O at/O higher/O ,/O European/O prices/O ,/O but/O in/O April/O of/O this/O year/O ,/O the/O Russian/O energy/O giant/O shut/O down/O Turkmen/O supplies/O after/O a/O gas/O pipeline/O exploded/O in/O that/O country/O ./O 
For/O the/O Turkmen/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION was/O behind/O the/O incident/O because/O it/O reduced/O pressure/O in/O the/O pipeline/O ,/O causing/O the/O explosion/O ./O 
This/O came/O after/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION increased/O gas/O prices/O and/O threatened/O to/O ban/O its/O resale/O ,/O which/O would/O have/O made/O the/O gas/O deal/O worthless/O from/O Gazprom鈥檚/O perspective/O ./O 
After/O months/O of/O tensions/O ,/O Moscow/LOCATION relented/O and/O allowed/O the/O gas/O to/O flow/O again/O ,/O but/O the/O atmosphere/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O was/O no/O longer/O the/O same/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O taking/O advantage/O of/O Russia鈥檚/O arrogance/O ,/O profiting/O from/O a/O softer/O but/O more/O incisive/O diplomacy/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION gave/O Ashgabat/LOCATION a/O US$/O 4/O billion/O loan/O this/O year/O ./O 
The/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION is/O the/O only/O foreign/O company/O with/O exploration/O rights/O in/O Turkmenistan鈥檚/O gas/O fields/O ./O 
Russia鈥檚/O Gazprom/ORGANIZATION has/O failed/O to/O invest/O in/O the/O country/O ,/O choosing/O instead/O to/O get/O cheap/O Turkmen/O gas/O in/O order/O to/O resell/O it/O at/O a/O higher/O price/O ./O 
Now/O however/O ,/O Moscow鈥檚/O approach/O is/O showing/O its/O limits/O ,/O Vitaly/PERSON Bushuyev/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O Energy/ORGANIZATION Strategy/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O ./O 
