Promises/O of/O grandiose/O infrastructure/O projects/O for/O over/O 100/O billion/O dollars/O ./O 
Experts/O :/O if/O Beijing/LOCATION replicates/O the/O model/O of/O the/O East/LOCATION ,/O it/O will/O find/O similar/O problems/O with/O pollution/O ,/O exploitation/O ,/O social/O protests/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O In/O early/O July/O China/LOCATION announced/O fresh/O investment/O to/O the/O tune/O of/O 100/O billion/O dollars/O for/O 23/O infrastructure/O projects/O ``/O to/O promote/O rapid/O and/O healthy/O development/O of/O western/O areas鈥/O ,/O which/O lag/O behind/O the/O rich/O eastern/O coastal/O regions/O ./O 
Experts/O are/O arguing/O over/O what/O model/O of/O development/O will/O be/O pursued/O ./O 
The/O gap/O between/O the/O two/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O also/O has/O recent/O historical/O reasons/O :/O in/O 1978/O the/O leader/O Deng/PERSON Xiaoping/PERSON opened/O China/LOCATION to/O the/O industrial/O development/O and/O trade/O especially/O favouring/O the/O coastal/O areas/O with/O roads/O ,/O railways/O ,/O and/O hydroelectric/O power/O stations/O ./O 
The/O western/O regions/O constitute/O 71/O %/O of/O the/O territory/O but/O are/O home/O to/O only/O 28/O %/O of/O the/O population/O ./O 
They/O have/O plenty/O of/O energy/O and/O precious/O minerals/O ,/O essential/O for/O the/O development/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
Now/O Beijing/LOCATION says/O it/O wants/O to/O achieve/O roads/O ,/O railways/O ,/O airports/O ,/O coal/O mines/O ,/O power/O stations/O in/O the/O West/LOCATION to/O attract/O foreign/O investment/O ,/O increase/O vocational/O education/O and/O encourage/O the/O return/O home/O of/O migrants/O who/O now/O have/O to/O seek/O work/O in/O Coastal/O cities/O ./O 
The/O Commission/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION National/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Reform/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O Csnr/O -RRB-/O explained/O that/O the/O projects/O will/O be/O developed/O primarily/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION but/O also/O in/O Yunnan/LOCATION and/O Sichuan/LOCATION ./O 
There/O are/O tax/O exemptions/O for/O projects/O involving/O coal/O ,/O oil/O and/O gas.聽/O Du/PERSON Ying/PERSON ,/O vice/O president/O of/O Csnr/O appearing/O on/O television/O to/O explain/O the/O project/O ,/O nevertheless/O stresses/O ,/O which/O a/O robust/O growth/O is/O already/O in/O place/O in/O the/O West/LOCATION ,/O reaching/O 11.9/O %/O in/O the/O last/O year.聽He/O adds/O that/O over/O the/O past/O 10/O years/O ,/O the/O railway/O capacity/O has/O increased/O by/O 160/O %/O ,/O 280/O %/O that/O of/O highways/O ,/O the/O energy/O capacity/O by/O 550/O %/O ./O 
Fixed/O investment/O came/O to/O 3,600/O billion/O yuan/O -LRB-/O 360/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Although/O the/O per/O capita/O gross/O domestic/O product/O rose/O in/O the/O west/O to1/O ,/O 933/O dollars/O per/O year/O in/O 2008/O ,/O just/O 41.9/O %/O compared/O to/O the/O east/O and/O accounts/O for/O only/O 17.8/O %/O of/O national/O GDP/O ./O 
The/O government/O also/O hopes/O ,/O ,/O to/O stem/O the/O autonomist/O aspirations/O and/O protests/O in/O areas/O like/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O Tibet/LOCATION through/O better/O economic/O wellbeing/O and/O continuing/O to/O encourage/O the/O mass/O immigration/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O ,/O who/O are/O often/O favoured/O in/O positions/O of/O power/O ./O 
Experts/O say/O that/O ,/O however/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION appears/O to/O want/O to/O replicate/O the/O development/O model/O implemented/O in/O the/O east/O ,/O which/O has/O brought/O prosperity/O but/O also/O serious/O social/O and/O environmental/O problems/O ,/O with/O tens/O of/O millions/O of/O migrants/O in/O cities/O forced/O to/O live/O as/O second-class/O citizens/O ,/O the/O widespread/O pollution/O of/O air/O and/O water/O ,/O poisoning/O of/O soil/O and/O desertification/O of/O entire/O areas/O ./O 
Above/O all/O ,/O China/LOCATION does/O not/O appear/O to/O have/O any/O plans/O to/O resolve/O ethnic/O tensions/O and/O seems/O to/O think/O that/O economic/O development/O will/O eliminate/O all/O other/O problems/O ./O 
Instead/O ,/O scholars/O explain/O that/O ,/O as/O in/O the/O case/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O development/O has/O benefited/O only/O small/O sections/O of/O the/O population/O ,/O mostly/O ethnic/O Han/O ,/O increasing/O the/O gap/O and/O contrasts/O with/O the/O local/O ethnic/O groups/O ./O 
