The/O Chinese/O central/O government/O and/O the/O administration/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION strongly/O attack/O the/O speech/O given/O yesterday/O by/O the/O Buddhist/ORGANIZATION leader/O :/O ``/O It/O distorts/O reality/O and/O foments/O separatism/O within/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //ORGANIZATION Agencies/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O In/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O ``/O there/O is/O no/O serious/O problem/O ,/O despite/O what/O the/O Dalai/O Lama聽says/O ./O ''/O 
This/O is/O the/O declaration/O of/O the/O new/O president/O of/O the/O Autonomous/ORGANIZATION Region/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Padma/ORGANIZATION Choling/ORGANIZATION ,/O refuting/O accusations/O made/O yesterday/O by/O the/O Tibetan/O leader/O in/O exile/O ,/O according/O to/O who/O Beijing/LOCATION 鈥渋s/O trying/O to/O wipe/O out/O Buddhism/O ./O 
``/O Yesterday/O ,/O on/O the/O 51st/O anniversary/O of/O the/O uprising/O of/O 1959/O and/O the/O second/O anniversary/O of/O the/O 2008/O protests/O that/O occurred/O in/O many/O parts/O of/O China/LOCATION that/O is/O home/O to/O Tibetan/O people/O ,/O there/O were/O no/O reported/O incidents/O ./O 
聽/O ``/O In/O Lhasa/LOCATION -/O said/O Padma/PERSON ,/O the/O so-called/O ''/O hawk/O ''/O of/O the/O Tibetan/O Administration/O -/O you/O can/O see/O monks/O and/O nuns/O everywhere/O ./O 
In/O Tibet/LOCATION there/O are/O about/O 1,700/O religious/O sites/O home/O to/O 46/O thousand/O monks/O ./O ''/O 
In/O his/O speech/O the/O Nobel/O Peace/O Laureate/O accused/O the/O Chinese/O central/O government/O of/O having/O reduced/O the/O monks/O to/O a/O state/O of/O ``/O semi-slavery/O ''/O and/O expressed/O his/O support/O for/O the/O peoples/O of/O Eastern/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION -/O the/O Uyghur/O ,/O considered/O a/O separatist/O group/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION -/O and/O for/O those/O intellectuals/O who/O criticize/O the/O regime/O ./O 
This/O is/O a/O clear/O reference/O to/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON ,/O the/O Chinese/O dissident/O author/O of/O ``/O Charter/O '/O 08/O ''/O who/O has/O been/O sentenced/O to/O 11/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O 
The/O regional/O president/O criticized/O the/O Dalai/LOCATION Lama/LOCATION for/O having/O called/O the/O Chinese/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ``/O East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION ''/O ,/O using/O the/O term/O coined/O by/O local/O anti-Chinese/O nationalists/O ./O 
鈥淗e/O should/O not/O foment/O rebellion/O in/O our/O country/O ''/O ,/O said/O the/O local/O leader/O ./O 
According/O to/O Tibetan/O exiles/O ,/O about/O 200/O people/O died/O in/O the/O 2008/O protests/O while/O the/O government/O says/O that/O the/O victims/O were/O ``/O little/O more/O than/O twenty/O ./O ''/O 
The/O central/O government/O has/O also/O attacked/O the/O Buddhist/ORGANIZATION leader/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Qin/PERSON Gan/PERSON ,/O ``/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O destorts/O ''/O the/O real/O situation/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
Furthermore/O ,/O according/O to/O Qin/PERSON ,/O his/O support/O for/O the/O Uyghur/O ``/O is/O a/O demonstration/O of/O his/O desire/O to/O harm/O the/O national/O unity/O of/O China/LOCATION and/O his/O separatism/O ''/O ./O 
