Former/O Czech/O president/O and/O co-author/O of/O Charter/O 77/O goes/O to/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Embassy/ORGANIZATION in/O Prague/LOCATION with/O two/O other/O prominent/O dissidents/O to/O demand/O China/LOCATION respect/O the/O human/O rights/O of/O the/O author/O of/O Charter/O 08/O and/O his/O right/O to/O a/O fair/O appeal/O ./O 
Prague/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O Former/O Czech/O dissident/O and/O Velvet/O Revolution/O leader/O Vaclav/PERSON Havel/PERSON and/O other/O Communist-era/O dissidents/O went/O to/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Embassy/ORGANIZATION in/O Prague/LOCATION to/O hand/O over/O a/O letter/O demanding/O the/O release/O of/O Chinese/O human/O rights/O activist/O Xiaobo/PERSON ./O 
Professor/O Liu/PERSON ,/O a/O co-author/O of/O Charter/O 08/O ,/O was/O sentenced/O to/O 11/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O ``/O inciting/O subversion/O of/O state/O power/O ./O ''/O 
Havel/PERSON was/O accompanied/O by/O actor/O Pavel/PERSON Landovsky/PERSON and/O bishop/O Vaclav/PERSON Maly/PERSON ,/O two/O major/O figures/O in/O the/O anti-Communist/O struggle/O of/O the/O 1980s/O ./O 
``/O We/O are/O here/O to/O ask/O the/O Chinese/O president/O and/O through/O him/O the/O Chinese/O government/O .../O not/O to/O persecute/O rights/O fighters/O who/O have/O their/O legitimate/O demands/O backed/O by/O international/O pacts/O ,/O ''/O Havel/PERSON told/O reporters/O ./O 
Havel/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O president/O of/O Czechoslovakia/LOCATION and/O then/O the/O Czech/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION between/O 1989/O and/O 2003/O ,/O was/O one/O of/O the/O authors/O of/O Charter/O 77/O ./O 
Published/O exactly/O 33/O years/O ago/O ,/O the/O manifesto/O called/O on/O the/O Communist/O regime/O in/O the/O Central/O European/O country/O to/O respect/O human/O rights/O ./O 
Liu/PERSON co-authored/O Charter/O 08/O ,/O a/O manifesto/O modelled/O on/O Charter/O 77/O that/O demands/O democracy/O and/O respect/O for/O human/O rights/O as/O the/O basis/O for/O a/O truly/O integrated/O development/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O letter/O ,/O the/O trio/O of/O former/O dissidents/O said/O Liu/PERSON 's/O trial/O was/O ``/O the/O result/O of/O a/O political/O order/O ''/O and/O that/O it/O was/O ``/O chiefly/O meant/O as/O a/O stern/O warning/O to/O others/O not/O to/O follow/O his/O path/O ./O ''/O 
The/O letter/O also/O called/O on/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON to/O ``/O secure/O a/O fair/O and/O genuinely/O open/O trial/O for/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON when/O the/O court/O hears/O his/O appeal/O ./O ''/O 
``/O We/O are/O also/O asking/O you/O and/O your/O government/O to/O end/O the/O house/O arrests/O and/O police/O surveillance/O which/O have/O been/O imposed/O on/O other/O Charter/O 08/O signatories/O ''/O and/O ¨/O to/O end/O the/O criminalisation/O of/O free/O speech/O ,/O and/O to/O release/O all/O prisoners/O of/O conscience/O ,/O ''/O the/O letter/O added/O ./O 
Last/O September/O ,/O the/O former/O dissident/O angered/O Beijing/LOCATION when/O he/O invited/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ,/O Tibet/LOCATION 's/O spiritual/O leader/O ,/O and/O Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON ,/O an/O exiled/O Uygur/O leader/O ,/O to/O a/O conference/O in/O Prague/LOCATION ./O 
After/O ringing/O the/O bell/O several/O times/O without/O getting/O a/O response/O ,/O Havel/PERSON put/O the/O letter/O in/O a/O letterbox/O ./O 
``/O I/O doubt/O the/O ambassador/O would/O have/O time/O -LSB-/O to/O meet/O us/O -RSB-/O ,/O but/O I/O would/O at/O least/O expect/O a/O doorman/O to/O be/O here/O and/O take/O the/O envelope/O ,/O ''/O Havel/PERSON said/O ./O 
