The/O visit/O by/O the/O Afghan/O president/O is/O designed/O to/O boost/O his/O country鈥檚/O reconstruction/O and/O stability/O ./O 
China/LOCATION makes/O the/O largest/O foreign/O investment/O ever/O in/O Afghan/O mining/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION wants/O to/O secure/O energy/O supply/O routes/O and/O increase/O its/O hold/O on/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O 鈥/O China/LOCATION is/O increasingly/O present/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION without/O sending/O a/O single/O soldier/O setting/O its/O foot/O on/O Afghan/O territory/O ./O 
This/O was/O made/O obvious/O in/O recent/O days/O by/O President/O Hamid/PERSON Karzai鈥檚/PERSON state/O visit/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O which/O began/O on/O Tuesday/O ./O 
Leading/O a/O high-ranking/O delegation/O ,/O the/O Afghan/O leader/O yesterday/O met/O his/O Chinese/O counterpart/O ,/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ,/O as/O well/O as/O Premier/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON ./O 
The/O two/O presidents/O signed/O a/O number/O of/O agreements/O to/O boost/O the/O Afghan/O economy/O and/O stabilise/O the/O country/O in/O a/O region/O where/O China/LOCATION has/O many/O vested/O interests/O ./O 
Nothing/O has/O been/O forthcoming/O for/O now/O as/O to/O the/O content/O of/O the/O talks/O ,/O but/O the/O deals/O signed/O should/O cover/O economic/O and/O technological/O cooperation/O as/O well/O as/O favourable/O tariffs/O for/O Afghan/O exports/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Hu/PERSON said/O that/O Karzai鈥檚/O 鈥渧isit/O will/O definitely/O help/O promote/O practical/O cooperation/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O take/O our/O comprehensive/O and/O cooperative/O partnership/O to/O a/O new/O level鈥/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O president/O called/O for/O closer/O cooperation/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O in/O a/O number/O of/O sectors/O ,/O like/O mining/O ,/O agriculture/O ,/O hydroelectric/O power/O and/O infrastructure/O ./O 
For/O his/O part/O ,/O Karzai/PERSON asked/O China/LOCATION for/O its/O support/O in/O building/O peace/O in/O his/O country/O ./O 
Security/O is/O the/O other/O major/O issue/O of/O interest/O to/O China/LOCATION in/O relation/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
Foreign/O ministry/O sources/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION said/O last/O week/O that/O the/O People鈥檚/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION was/O going/O to/O continue/O its/O reconstruction/O work/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O key/O areas/O like/O schools/O and/O hospitals/O and/O thus/O encourage/O a/O return/O to/O normal/O life/O ./O 
Equally/O important/O ,/O hungry/O for/O natural/O resource/O and/O energy/O ,/O China/LOCATION is/O developing/O gas/O fields/O in/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan鈥檚/O neighbour/O ./O 
In/O December/O ,/O a/O gas/O pipeline/O linking/O western/O China/LOCATION to/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION through/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION and/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION was/O inaugurated/O not/O far/O from/O the/O Afghan/O border/O ./O 
In/O 2007/O ,/O state-owned/O China/ORGANIZATION Metallurgical/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION Corp/ORGANIZATION won/O a/O bid/O to/O develop/O one/O of/O the/O world鈥檚/O largest/O unexploited/O copper/O reserves/O at/O Aynak/LOCATION in/O Afghanistan鈥檚/LOCATION Logar/LOCATION province/LOCATION ,/O south/O of/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O 
The/O US$/O 3/O billion/O project/O is/O the/O largest/O single/O foreign/O investment/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
China/LOCATION also/O wants/O a/O negotiated/O solution/O to/O the/O Afghan/O war/O that/O would/O include/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION as/O a/O way/O to/O achieve/O stability/O and/O peace/O ./O 
For/O this/O reason/O ,/O to/O find/O a/O resolution/O to/O the/O conflict/O it/O has/O focused/O on/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O of/O which/O it/O is/O a/O permanent/O member/O ,/O and/O on/O its/O close/O ties/O with/O key/O regional/O players/O like/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
With/O close/O ties/O to/O Kabul/LOCATION ,/O Moscow/LOCATION and/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION can/O control/O the/O situation/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O a/O key/O player/O in/O terms/O of/O energy/O -LRB-/O for/O its/O reserves/O and/O a/O transit/O for/O the/O region鈥檚/O gas/O and/O oil/O -RRB-/O and/O a/O base/O for/O Islamic/O extremism/O -LRB-/O with/O a/O great/O potential/O to/O destabilise/O China鈥檚/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ,/O home/O to/O a/O large/O Muslim/O population/O -RRB-/O ./O 
