Such/O a/O railway/O line/O would/O allay/O China鈥檚/O greatest/O fear/O ,/O a/O naval/O blockade/O that/O could/O stop/O oil/O shipments/O from/O Africa/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O major/O political/O ,/O technical/O and/O financial/O problems/O remain/O ,/O including/O India鈥檚/O opposition/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O 鈥/O Pakistani/O President/O Asif/PERSON Ali/PERSON Zardari/PERSON and/O Chinese/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON met/O last/O Wednesday/O during/O an/O official/O visit/O of/O the/O Pakistani/O leader/O to/O the/O mainland/O ./O 
They/O discussed/O plans/O to/O build/O a/O railway/O line/O from/O Kashgar/LOCATION in/O China鈥檚/LOCATION Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O to/O the/O Pakistani/O port/O of/O Gwadar/LOCATION ./O 
This/O could/O give/O China/LOCATION direct/O access/O to/O the/O Persian/LOCATION Gulf/LOCATION and/O make/O Pakistan/LOCATION an/O alternative/O route/O for/O Chinese/O goods/O and/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION and/O African/O oil/O ,/O which/O currently/O have/O to/O go/O around/O India/LOCATION ./O 
The/O ambitious/O plan/O has/O been/O on/O the/O drawing/O boards/O for/O many/O years/O ./O 
It/O has/O advantages/O for/O both/O parties/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION would/O have/O direct/O access/O to/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ;/O currently/O ,/O 80/O per/O cent/O of/O China鈥檚/O oil/O travels/O through/O the/O Indian/LOCATION Ocean/LOCATION and/O the/O Strait/LOCATION of/LOCATION Malacca/LOCATION ,/O an/O area/O plagued/O by/O piracy/O ./O 
More/O importantly/O ,/O in/O case/O of/O war/O ,/O China鈥檚/O enemies/O could/O easily/O block/O its/O oil/O supplies/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION would/O especially/O benefit/O from/O increased/O traffic/O in/O the/O Gwadar/LOCATION port/O ,/O which/O was/O built/O with/O Chinese/O capital/O and/O assistance/O and/O opened/O in/O 2008/O ./O 
Now/O the/O railway/O ,/O which/O until/O recently/O appeared/O to/O be/O technically/O impossible/O because/O of/O the/O difficult/O terrain/O ,/O at/O 5,000/O metres/O above/O sea/O level/O ,/O could/O be/O built/O thanks/O to/O the/O experience/O and/O knowledge/O China/LOCATION has/O accumulated/O during/O the/O construction/O of/O the/O Qinghai-Tibet/LOCATION railway/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Professor/O Wang/PERSON Mengshu/PERSON ,/O a/O rail/O expert/O at/O Beijing/ORGANIZATION Jiaotong/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O that/O the/O Kashgar-Gwadar/LOCATION project/O would/O be/O ``/O more/O difficult/O than/O the/O one/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ''/O because/O Chinese/O surveyors/O and/O mappers/O will/O not/O have/O as/O good/O an/O understanding/O of/O the/O local/O terrain/O as/O they/O did/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
This/O would/O also/O create/O uncertainties/O about/O the/O cost/O ,/O which/O Wang/PERSON estimates/O would/O be/O around/O 200/O million/O yuan/O -LRB-/O US$/O 30/O million/O -RRB-/O per/O kilometre/O ,/O a/O bill/O too/O great/O even/O for/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
In/O addition/O ,/O India/LOCATION is/O not/O going/O to/O look/O favourably/O at/O closer/O Sino-Pakistani/O relations/O ./O 
New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION has/O always/O regarded/O Islamabad/LOCATION as/O its/O main/O adversary/O and/O Beijing/LOCATION as/O its/O main/O rival/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O the/O proposed/O railway/O would/O have/O to/O pass/O through/O Pakistan-administered/O Kashmir/LOCATION ,/O a/O territory/O claimed/O by/O India/LOCATION ,/O and/O would/O thus/O undermine/O the/O latter鈥檚/O its/O claim/O ./O 
Indeed/O ,/O important/O Indian/O newspapers/O have/O described/O the/O project/O as/O a/O serious/O threat/O to/O India/LOCATION 's/O security/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O idea/O still/O has/O many/O supporters/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O many/O see/O its/O completion/O as/O only/O a/O matter/O of/O time/O ./O 
People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Liberation/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION Navy/ORGANIZATION Rear/O Admiral/O Yin/PERSON Zhuo/PERSON said/O China/LOCATION relied/O too/O heavily/O on/O sea/O transportation/O for/O its/O oil/O imports/O ./O 
Hence/O ,/O ``/O We/O must/O either/O build/O a/O much/O more/O powerful/O navy/O or/O find/O alternative/O transportation/O channels/O ./O ''/O 
