Rise/O in/O number/O of/O ``/O official/O ''/O victims/O in/O yesterday鈥檚/O clashes/O in/O Hotan/LOCATION between/O police/O and/O a/O group/O of/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O residents/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O government/O continues/O to/O talk/O about/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //ORGANIZATION Agencies/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O -/O The/O Chinese/O government/O this/O morning/O made/O a/O u-turn/O on/O yesterday/O 's/O clashes/O that/O rocked/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O has/O admitted/O that/O the/O death/O toll/O is/O ``/O at/O least/O 18/O ''/O ,/O 14/O ``/O violent/O offenders/O ''/O ,/O 2/O police/O and/O officers/O 2/O hostages/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION continues/O to/O define/O the/O fighting/O as/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O ,/O while/O for/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION -/O the/O non-governmental/O organization/O that/O follows/O the/O situation/O of/O ethnic/O group/O ,/O the/O once/O dominant/O majority/O in/O the/O province/O -/O it/O was/O a/O massacre/O orchestrated/O by/O the/O police/O ./O 
Chinese/O police/O opened/O fire/O on/O a/O group/O of/O Uyghur/O demonstrators/O who/O ,/O in/O the/O desert/O town/O of/O Hotan/LOCATION ,/O protested/O against/O the/O forced/O confiscation/O of/O their/O lands/O and/O indiscriminate/O arrests/O against/O members/O of/O the/O ethnic/O group/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O most/O feared/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
According/O to/O a/O report/O published/O today/O by/O the/O provincial/O government/O ,/O however/O ,/O ``/O a/O group/O of/O terrorists/O armed/O with/O explosives/O and/O axes/O tried/O to/O set/O fire/O to/O the/O local/O police/O station/O ./O ''/O 
Clashes/O in/O the/O province/O are/O a/O regular/O occurrence/O ,/O but/O yesterday/O was/O the/O worst/O last/O year/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION needs/O stability/O in/O the/O area/O ,/O rich/O in/O raw/O materials/O and/O in/O order/O to/O obtain/O this/O has/O promoted/O a/O massive/O immigration/O of/O Han/O ,/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
The/O Uyghurs/O ,/O the/O region/O 's/O Muslim/O Turkic-speaking/O indigenous/O constitute/O less/O than/O half/O the/O population/O ,/O after/O decades/O of/O immigration/O from/O other/O areas/O of/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION ./O 
Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON ,/O spokesman/O for/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O complains/O :/O ``/O China/LOCATION has/O strengthened/O repression/O and/O control/O over/O the/O population/O ,/O and/O this/O has/O greatly/O worsened/O the/O situation/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION uses/O brute/O force/O to/O suppress/O any/O protest/O by/O Uyghurs/O ,/O even/O the/O most/O peaceful/O ./O ''/O 
