Two/O others/O get/O 19/O year/O in/O prison/O ./O 
All/O of/O them/O are/O accused/O of/O terrorism/O ,/O murder/O and/O arson/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Uyghurs/PERSON say/O that/O the/O police/O crackdown/O transformed/O their/O peaceful/O demonstrations/O into/O a/O confrontation/O ./O 
The/O four/O sentenced/O to/O death/O were/O tortured/O and/O their/O lawyers/O allowed/O to/O see/O them/O only/O an/O hour/O before/O their/O trial/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/Agencies/O -RRB-/O 鈥/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O sentenced/O to/O death/O four/O ethnic/O Uygur/O accused/O of/O terrorism/O ,/O but/O activists/O believe/O the/O condemned/O did/O not/O receive/O a/O fair/O trial/O ./O 
The/O four/O were/O found/O guilty/O on/O Wednesday/O for/O allegedly/O setting/O up/O and/O running/O terrorist/O organisations/O ,/O illegally/O making/O explosives/O ,/O murder/O and/O arson/O ./O 
Two/O others/O were/O jailed/O for/O 19/O years/O ./O 
Sentences/O stem/O from/O three/O terrorist/O attacks/O following/O a/O harsh/O crackdown/O in/O July/O by/O Chinese/O authorities/O -LRB-/O see/O 鈥淴injiang/O ,/O Chinese/O police/O kill/O dozens/O of/O Uyghurs/LOCATION ,/O 鈥/O inAsiaNews/O ,/O 19/O July/O 2011/O ,/O and/O 鈥淢ore/O deaths/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION announces/O tough/O measures/O during/O Ramadan/O ,/O 鈥/O InAsiaNews/O ,/O 1/O August/O 2011/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION blamed/O such/O attacks/O on/O 鈥渢errorists鈥/O but/O according/O to/O the/O Uyghurs/O ,/O police/O violence/O transformed/O peaceful/O demonstrations/O into/O clashes/O with/O security/O forces/O ./O 
A/O spokesman/O for/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uygur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O Germany-based/O exile/O group/O ,/O said/O that/O the/O suspects/O did/O not/O receive/O a/O fair/O trial/O ./O 
He/O accuses/O Chinese/O authorities/O of/O torturing/O the/O prisoners/O and/O denying/O them/O the/O right/O to/O choose/O their/O own/O lawyers/O ./O 
Government/O assigned/O attorney/O were/O able/O to/O meet/O their/O clients/O just/O an/O hour/O before/O trial/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION continues/O to/O justify/O its/O iron/O fist/O in/O its/O westernmost/O region/O by/O accusing/O the/O Uyghurs/O of/O extremism/O ,/O separatism/O and/O terrorism/O ./O 
For/O Chinese/O authorities/O ,/O local/O radical/O Muslims/O are/O tied/O to/O al/O Qaeda/O ./O 
In/O reality/O ,/O Uyghurs/PERSON want/O political/O and/O economic/O autonomy/O ,/O accusing/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O colonising/O their/O region/O ./O 
The/O crackdown/O by/O China鈥檚/O central/O authorities/O extends/O to/O the/O practice/O of/O religion/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O minors/O are/O not/O allowed/O to/O go/O to/O the/O mosque/O ,/O whilst/O imams/O and/O Qur鈥榓nic/O schools/O are/O controlled/O ./O 
