For/O the/O first/O time/O the/O explosion/O of/O an/O SUVs/O in/O the/O heart/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O described/O as/O a/O ``/O terrorist/O attack/O ''/O on/O state/O television/O ./O 
The/O police/O announce/O first/O arrests/O ,/O but/O continues/O to/O look/O for/O vehicles/O with/O Xinjiang/LOCATION license/O plates/O ./O 
Uyghur/O leader/O calls/O for/O ``/O calm/O and/O transparency/O ''/O in/O investigations/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O -/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O arrested/O ``/O some/O suspects/O ''/O believed/O to/O have/O been/O involved/O in/O the/O crash/O and/O subsequent/O explosion/O of/O an/O SUV/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O the/O heart/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
The/O explosion/O ,/O defined/O by/O police/O for/O the/O first/O time/O as/O ``/O a/O terrorist/O attack/O ''/O ,/O killed/O 5/O people/O ,/O including/O a/O Chinese/O man/O from/O Guangdong/LOCATION and/O a/O Philippine/O doctor/O touring/O the/O capital/O ,/O wounding/O at/O least/O 38/O ./O 
The/O arrests/O ,/O announced/O on/O CCTV/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O China/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION Television/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O occurred/O 10/O hours/O after/O the/O incident/O ./O 
According/O to/O a/O police/O statement/O ,/O seven/O of/O wanted/O persons/O come/O from/O the/O autonomous/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O home/O to/O the/O Uyghur/O minority/O ,/O Turkish-speaking/O Muslims/PERSON ,/O who/O denounce/O a/O strict/O linguistic/O ,/O cultural/O and/O religious/O repression/O by/O the/O Chinese/O central/O government/O ./O 
The/O eighth/O is/O reportedly/O Han/O -LRB-/O ethnic/O majority/O in/O China/LOCATION -RRB-/O and/O comes/O from/O the/O Sichuan/LOCATION province/O in/O the/O southwest/O of/O the/O country/O ,/O but/O is/O resident/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
The/O age/O of/O the/O suspects/O range/O from/O 21/O to/O 70/O years/O ./O 
Investigators/O are/O also/O looking/O for/O five/O vehicles/O with/O license/O plate/O from/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O including/O a/O motorcycle/O :/O the/O police/O have/O ordered/O mechanics/O and/O auto-repair/O shops/O to/O report/O ``/O every/O car/O with/O these/O details/O ''/O ./O 
Check/O points/O have/O also/O been/O set/O up/O at/O airports/O ,/O with/O passengers/O travelling/O to/O Urumqi/LOCATION -/O the/O provincial/O capital/O -/O being/O questioned/O for/O hours/O by/O the/O security/O forces/O ./O 
The/O World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O an/O organization/O that/O brings/O together/O the/O ethnic/O diaspora/O led/O by/O Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON ,/O call/O for/O ``/O calm/O and/O transparency/O ''/O during/O the/O investigation/O ./O 
Kadeer/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O deputy/O to/O the/O Chinese/O people/O 's/O National/ORGANIZATION Assembly/ORGANIZATION for/O years/O and/O is/O now/O in/O exile/O ,/O added/O :/O ``/O I/O fear/O now/O more/O than/O ever/O for/O the/O fate/O of/O my/O people/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION will/O not/O hesitate/O to/O use/O this/O tragedy/O to/O crush/O Xinjiang/LOCATION even/O more/O ''/O ./O 
