The/O official/O version/O claims/O police/O looking/O for/O suspects/O and/O criminals/O were/O attacked/O by/O ``/O thugs/O ''/O and/O ``/O terrorists/O ./O ''/O 
Beijing/LOCATION responds/O to/O Uyghur/O desire/O for/O greater/O autonomy/O and/O justice/O with/O a/O ruthless/O military/O ,/O economic/O and/O religious/O control/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O At/O least/O 16/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O a/O violent/O clash/O near/O Kashgar/LOCATION ./O 
The/O news/O was/O reported/O today/O by/O Tianshan.net/O ,/O the/O official/O website/O of/O the/O Xinjiang/LOCATION government/O ./O 
Two/O of/O those/O killed/O were/O policemen/O ,/O while/O the/O other/O 14/O are/O defined/O as/O ``/O violent/O thugs/O ''/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O site/O ,/O the/O police/O were/O looking/O for/O criminal/O suspects/O in/O Shufu/LOCATION County/LOCATION ,/O when/O they/O were/O attacked/O by/O ``/O thugs/O ''/O armed/O with/O explosives/O and/O knives/O ./O 
While/O the/O police/O were/O trying/O to/O arrest/O one/O of/O the/O suspects/O ,/O the/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O went/O into/O action/O ./O 
Two/O of/O the/O attackers/O were/O arrested/O ./O 
Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O a/O very/O restless/O region/O ./O 
聽The/O Uyghur/O population/O that/O inhabits/O it/O ,/O Turkic/O speaking/O and/O Muslim/PERSON ,/O accuses/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O wanting/O to/O colonize/O them/O with/O a/O massive/O migration/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O and/O with/O stringent/O military/O and/O economic/O control/O ./O 
Uyghur/O groups/O are/O fighting/O for/O the/O independence/O of/O the/O region/O they/O call/O ``/O East/O Turkestan/O ./O ''/O 
China/LOCATION accuses/O them/O of/O being/O terrorists/O and/O keeps/O strict/O control/O of/O Islamic/O schools/O and/O religious/O practice/O ./O 
Last/O October/O ,/O a/O car/O bomb/O exploded/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O killing/O five/O people/O ./O 
According/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O the/O incident/O was/O a/O Uyghur/O ``/O terrorist/O attack/O ''/O ./O 
聽/O 
