A/O provincial/O court/O handed/O down/O the/O sentence/O against/O Musa/PERSON Hesen/PERSON and/O Rehman/PERSON Hupur/PERSON ,/O involved/O in/O the/O April/O riots/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION ,/O where/O 21/O people/O died/O ./O 
Judges/O rule/O they/O are/O also/O guilty/O of/O having/O founded/O a/O group/O ``/O that/O has/O carried/O on/O illegal/O religious/O activities/O for/O years/O with/O the/O aim/O of/O promoting/O extremism/O ./O ''/O 
Local/O population/O rally/O to/O their/O defense/O ./O 
Urumqi/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O -/O The/O government/O of/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION this/O morning/O sentenced/O to/O death/O two/O members/O of/O Uyghur/O ethnicity/O arrested/O in/O the/O aftermath/O ofclashes/O in/O April/O in/O the/O prefecture/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION ,/O during/O which/O 21/O people/O died/O ./O 
The/O courts/O ruled/O that/O Musa/PERSON Hesen/PERSON and/O Rehman/PERSON Hupur/PERSON are/O guilty/O of/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O and/O ``/O murder/O ./O ''/O 
Musa/PERSON also/O has/O been/O accused/O of/O having/O founded/O a/O group/O ``/O that/O has/O carried/O on/O illegal/O religious/O activities/O for/O years/O with/O the/O aim/O of/O promoting/O extremism/O ./O ''/O 
The/O province/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION :/O It/O is/O home/O to/O the/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O ,/O Turkic/O speaking/O peoples/O of/O the/O Islamic/O religion/O ,/O who/O have/O always/O sought/O to/O gain/O independence/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
The/O central/O government/O has/O sent/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O to/O the/O region/O to/O try/O to/O make/O them/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
It/O also/O imposes/O serious/O restrictions/O on/O freedom/O of/O religion/O ,/O Muslim/O practices/O ,/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O language/O and/O the/O local/O culture/O ./O 
Since/O 2009/O a/O special/O system/O of/O Chinese/O police/O and/O army/O control/O is/O in/O place/O ,/O imposed/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION after/O theriots/O in/O which/O nearly/O 200/O people/O lost/O their/O lives/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O the/O violence/O hundreds/O of/O custodial/O sentences/O and/O dozens/O of/O death/O sentences/O were/O meted/O out/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O authorities/O believe/O that/O the/O perpetrators/O of/O violence/O are/O Muslim/O extremists/O ,/O but/O exiles/O claim/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O ``/O exaggerating/O ''/O the/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O to/O justify/O the/O repression/O against/O the/O Uyghur/O population/O ./O 
Even/O the/O latest/O violence/O -LRB-/O in/O chronological/O order/O -RRB-/O was/O reported/O in/O different/O ways/O ./O 
According/O to/O police/O ,/O the/O clashes/O were/O born/O after/O an/O investigation/O carried/O out/O in/O the/O home/O of/O one/O of/O the/O convicts/O who/O ``/O hid/O explosives/O that/O could/O have/O been/O used/O to/O make/O 10/O bombs/O ./O ''/O 
The/O alleged/O terrorists/O reportedly/O kidnapped/O agents/O by/O deception/O ,/O then/O set/O fire/O to/O the/O house/O to/O kill/O them/O ./O 
The/O population/O however/O claims/O that/O the/O clashes/O were/O sparked/O by/O the/O police/O insisted/O that/O the/O men/O ``/O shave/O their/O beards/O and/O women/O take/O off/O their/O veils/O ''/O in/O the/O town/O of/O Selibuya/LOCATION ./O 
聽/O 
