The/O police/O have/O also/O identified/O the/O leader/O of/O the/O group/O behind/O the/O attack/O :/O he/O is/O Kurban/PERSON Abdurehim/PERSON ,/O but/O there/O is/O no/O news/O of/O his/O condition/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O continue/O to/O follow/O the/O trail/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION separatists/O ,/O but/O a/O spokesman/O for/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION calls/O for/O a/O ``/O more/O transparent/O investigation/O ''/O ./O 
Kunming/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O Chinese/O police/O have/O identified/O a/O man/O ,/O Abdurehim/PERSON Kurban/PERSON ,/O as/O the/O mastermind/O behind/O the/O massacre/O that/O took/O place/O on/O 1/O March/O in/O the/O Kunming/LOCATION railway/O station/O ,/O and/O has/O also/O arrested/O three/O suspects/O ./O 
The/O move/O was/O reported/O today/O toXinhua/O ,/O the/O official/O government/O agency/O ,/O citing/O the/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Public/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Eight/O people/O -/O including/O two/O women/O -/O were/O responsible/O for/O the/O attack/O ,/O which/O resulted/O in29/O deaths/O and/O more/O than/O 130/O injured/O ./O 
Four/O suspects/O were/O killed/O on/O the/O spot/O by/O police/O and/O one/O woman/O was/O injured/O and/O captured/O ./O 
The/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION has/O not/O clarified/O whether/O Kurban/PERSON is/O among/O those/O arrested/O or/O who/O dies/O at/O the/O scene/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION continues/O to/O insist/O that/O the/O Kunming/LOCATION attack/O was/O ``/O a/O terrorist/O attack/O organized/O by/O Xinjiang/LOCATION separatists/O ''/O ./O 
聽/O Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O the/O autonomous/O northern/O region/O that/O is/O home/O to/O the/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O ,/O Turkic/O speaking/O Muslims/O ./O 
Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Qin/PERSON Gang/PERSON said/O that/O the/O flags/O of/O the/O separatist/O forces/O of/O East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION -LRB-/O the/O independent/O region/O that/O the/O Uyghurs/O want/O to/O create/O -/O ed/O -RRB-/O were/O found/O at/O the/O scene/O yesterday/O ./O 
Yesterday/O ,/O at/O the/O opening/O of/O the/O Chinese/O People/O 's/O Political/O Consultative/O Conference/O -LRB-/O CPPCC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O about/O 2/O thousand/O delegates/O observed/O a/O minute/O of/O silence/O for/O the/O victims/O ./O 
There/O were/O only/O two/O other/O occasions/O in/O which/O the/O CPPCC/ORGANIZATION stopped/O to/O commemorate/O something/O :/O in/O 1949/O for/O the/O martyrs/O of/O the/O Revolution/O and/O in/O 1997/O on/O the/O death/O of/O Deng/PERSON Xiaoping/PERSON ./O 
Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON ,/O spokesman/O for/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O asked/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O be/O ``/O more/O transparent/O ''/O in/O its/O investigation/O and/O not/O to/O use/O it/O ``/O as/O an/O excuse/O to/O crack/O down/O on/O the/O Uyghur/O people/O ''/O ./O 
聽/O 
