Jailed/O in/O January/O ,/O the/O economist/O has/O never/O supported/O separatism/O ./O 
However/O ,/O he/O has/O called/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O talk/O with/O Uighurs/O and/O check/O its/O corrupt/O local/O government/O ,/O which/O angers/O both/O Uighurs/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Chinese/O government/O repression/O could/O generate/O a/O more/O unified/O and/O violent/O movement/O ./O 
Urumqi/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O -/O Economist/O and/O university/O professor/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON went/O on/O trial/O today/O ./O 
Accused/O of/O Uighur/O ``/O separatism/O ''/O ,/O he/O was/O arrested/O last/O January/O for/O criticising/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policy/O after/O anattack/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O in/O October/O 2013/O ,/O blamed/O on/O Uighurs.The/O government/O responded/O to/O the/O attack/O by/O increasing/O its/O repression/O in/O the/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ./O 
For/O years/O ,/O Tothi/PERSON has/O called/O on/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O open/O a/O real/O dialogue/O with/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
For/O this/O purpose/O ,/O he/O set/O up/O a/O website/O ,/O Uighur/O online/O ,/O to/O allow/O Uighurs/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O to/O talk/O ./O 
However/O ,/O for/O his/O accusers/O ,/O the/O website/O is/O evidence/O of/O the/O scholar/O 's/O ``/O separatism/O ''/O ./O 
In/O reality/O ,/O as/O the/O text/O below/O shows/O ,/O Tohti/PERSON only/O wants/O the/O two/O sides/O to/O hear/O each/O other/O out/O and/O greater/O checks/O on/O those/O who/O currently/O rule/O Xinjiang/LOCATION because/O their/O corruption/O is/O a/O source/O of/O problems/O for/O Uighurs/O and/O Han/O alike/O ./O 
For/O the/O Uighur/O scholar/O ,/O repression/O is/O not/O the/O answer/O and/O the/O violence/O associated/O with/O it/O explains/O the/O desperate/O response/O by/O Uighurs/O ./O 
Over/O the/O past/O few/O decades/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O tried/O to/O supress/O Xinjiang/LOCATION 's/O independence/O movement/O by/O bringing/O in/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O settlers/O ./O 
This/O has/O led/O to/O the/O political/O and/O social/O marginalisation/O of/O indigenous/O Uighurs/O ,/O a/O Turkic/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
What/O is/O more/O ,/O their/O religious/O practice/O has/O been/O severely/O curtailed/O ./O 
Mosques/O and/O Qur/O `/O anic/O schools/O are/O under/O tight/O control/O ;/O religious/O practices/O like/O fasting/O and/O praying/O have/O been/O mocked/O ;/O and/O jail/O time/O and/O the/O death/O penalty/O have/O been/O liberally/O meted/O out/O ./O 
Soon/O after/O Tohti/PERSON 's/O arrest/O ,/O his/O close/O friend/O Tibetan/O writer/O Tsering/PERSON Woeser/PERSON put/O together/O an/O outline/O of/O Tohti/PERSON 's/O ideas/O in/O February.AsiaNews/O is/O publishing/O them/O ,/O courtesy/O of/O China/ORGANIZATION Change/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O provided/O the/O original/O translation/O from/O Chinese/O ./O 
Currently/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O a/O developing/O tendency/O is/O that/O the/O authorities/O are/O over-extending/O anti-terrorism/O measures/O to/O conceal/O other/O problems/O in/O their/O name/O ,/O including/O the/O incompetence/O of/O both/O the/O local/O governments/O and/O the/O security/O maintenance/O apparatus/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O the/O biggest/O problem/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O not/O anti-terrorism/O ,/O nor/O is/O it/O terrorism/O ,/O but/O rather/O ,/O the/O problem/O is/O that/O political/O power/O is/O unrestrained/O ,/O unequal/O ,/O controlled/O and/O monopolized/O by/O the/O very/O groups/O that/O profit/O from/O it/O ./O 
--/O I/O 've/O seen/O this/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION :/O the/O more/O the/O authorities/O suppress/O religion/O ,/O the/O more/O the/O Uighur/O people/O embrace/O religion/O ./O 
What/O should/O the/O government/O do/O ?/O 
The/O government/O repeatedly/O applies/O pressure/O when/O in/O fact/O it/O should/O first/O examine/O itself/O ./O 
If/O they/O can/O not/O govern/O themselves/O ,/O then/O they/O can/O not/O govern/O the/O country/O ./O 
If/O they/O can/O not/O govern/O themselves/O ,/O if/O they/O do/O not/O change/O their/O way/O of/O dealing/O with/O and/O thinking/O about/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O if/O they/O do/O not/O respect/O the/O people/O 's/O right/O to/O speak/O ,/O including/O respecting/O the/O Uighurs/O '/O right/O to/O ethnic/O autonomy/O ,/O then/O the/O conflicts/O between/O the/O Uighurs/O and/O the/O government/O will/O become/O more/O and/O more/O pronounced/O ./O 
--/O In/O 2009/O when/O I/O was/O under/O house/O arrest/O ,/O I/O warned/O the/O Chinese/O government/O that/O future/O protests/O by/O the/O Uighurs/O could/O become/O a/O protest/O movement/O the/O scale/O of/O which/O would/O surpass/O anything/O seen/O in/O the/O past/O sixty/O years/O ./O 
The/O government/O would/O see/O the/O Uighurs/O become/O more/O and/O more/O united/O in/O this/O protest/O movement/O ./O 
I/O now/O boldly/O predict/O that/O ,/O if/O the/O government/O does/O not/O change/O its/O policies/O toward/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O the/O Uighurs/O will/O more/O and/O more/O choose/O to/O confront/O the/O government/O in/O order/O to/O make/O their/O appeals/O ./O 
--/O Some/O Han/O Chinese/O scholars/O say/O that/O the/O issues/O confronting/O the/O Uighur/O and/O the/O Han/O are/O fundamentally/O the/O same/O ./O 
I/O agree/O somewhat/O with/O this/O statement/O because/O ,/O from/O the/O perspective/O of/O human/O rights/O ,/O government/O ,/O and/O democracy/O ,/O the/O Uighur/O and/O the/O Han/O face/O the/O same/O issues/O ./O 
Nonetheless/O ,/O the/O Uighurs/O also/O face/O a/O particular/O problem/O :/O social/O resources/O ./O 
We/O Uighurs/O also/O face/O such/O problems/O as/O ethnic/O and/O religious/O discrimination/O ,/O and/O so/O on/O ,/O due/O to/O the/O great/O differences/O we/O Uighurs/O have/O with/O the/O mainstream/O Han/O culture/O ,/O including/O language/O ,/O physical/O appearance/O ,/O religious/O beliefs/O ,/O and/O so/O on/O ./O 
--/O At/O present/O ,/O Xinjiang/LOCATION is/O under/O the/O ``/O one/O village/O one/O police/O station/O ,/O one/O household/O one/O police/O officer/O ''/O campaign/O .1/O This/O campaign/O came/O into/O effect/O after/O Zhang/PERSON Chunxian/PERSON -LRB-/O 寮犳槬璐/O -RRB-/O took/O office/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
The/O campaign/O stipulates/O that/O one/O village/O will/O have/O one/O police/O station/O and/O each/O police/O officer/O will/O be/O responsible/O for/O a/O single/O household/O ./O 
The/O personnel/O making/O visits/O to/O the/O villages/O and/O households/O include/O cadres/O ,/O unemployed/O people/O whom/O the/O government/O hires/O ,/O even/O some/O young/O ruffians/O ,/O people/O on/O government/O subsidies/O ,/O police/O officers/O ,/O special/O weapons/O and/O tactics/O -LRB-/O SWAT/O -RRB-/O officers/O ,/O and/O so/O on/O ./O 
I/O absolutely/O could/O not/O put/O up/O with/O people/O like/O this/O randomly/O breaking/O into/O my/O house/O ./O 
--/O At/O present/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O the/O exclusion/O of/O and/O discrimination/O against/O Uighurs/O is/O quite/O systematic/O ,/O with/O the/O government/O leading/O the/O way/O .../O the/O Uighurs/O '/O dissatisfaction/O with/O the/O government/O is/O unanimous/O with/O no/O internal/O disagreements/O ./O 
After/O all/O these/O years/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O the/O government/O has/O failed/O to/O cultivate/O a/O Uighur/O vested/O interest/O group/O ./O 
There/O are/O some/O Uighurs/O with/O vested/O interests/O ,/O but/O they/O are/O few/O and/O far/O between/O ./O 
I/O believe/O that/O ,/O in/O this/O respect/O ,/O the/O government/O has/O failed/O miserably/O ;/O they/O failed/O even/O to/O achieve/O this/O ./O 
--/O I/O have/O always/O upheld/O the/O unity/O of/O the/O nation/O and/O opposed/O separatism/O ./O 
I/O have/O never/O had/O a/O thought/O of/O secession/O ,/O thus/O I/O have/O not/O participated/O in/O any/O separatist/O activities/O ,/O let/O alone/O organizing/O a/O so-called/O separatist/O organization/O ./O 
I/O advocate/O governing/O Xinjiang/LOCATION according/O to/O the/O law/O ,/O including/O implementing/O and/O improving/O the/O regional/O ethnic/O autonomy/O system/O ,/O respecting/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O ,/O respecting/O human/O rights/O ,/O allowing/O each/O ethnic/O group/O to/O share/O equitably/O the/O fruits/O of/O development/O ,/O equality/O in/O employment/O ,/O elimination/O of/O discrimination/O ,/O including/O discrimination/O based/O on/O locality/O ,/O ethnicity/O ,/O gender/O ,/O and/O personal/O status/O ./O ''/O 
-LSB-/O This/O paragraph/O is/O atweet/O of/O Ilham/PERSON 's/O lawyer/O @xiao_xiaoyuan/O ./O -RSB-/O 
--/O Right/O up/O to/O the/O present/O ,/O although/O I/O 've/O been/O in/O difficult/O circumstances/O ,/O I/O have/O never/O sought/O financial/O assistance/O from/O any/O country/O ./O 
I/O will/O not/O be/O anyone/O 's/O lackey/O ./O 
I/O am/O an/O independent/O person/O who/O thinks/O independently/O ./O 
I/O am/O a/O Uighur/O intellectual/O ./O 
My/O first/O responsibility/O is/O to/O my/O people/O ,/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O to/O my/O hometown/O ,/O and/O to/O my/O country/O ./O 
I/O will/O not/O be/O anyone/O 's/O lackey/O ./O 
--/O I/O admire/O the/O American/O system/O ,/O I/O like/O America/LOCATION 's/O academic/O freedom/O ,/O I/O like/O American/O values/O such/O as/O the/O protection/O of/O human/O rights/O ,/O respect/O for/O the/O opinions/O of/O political/O minorities/O ,/O freedom/O of/O religion/O ,/O freedom/O of/O the/O press/O ,/O democracy/O ,/O and/O so/O on/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O ,/O however/O ,/O an/O American/O ./O 
Nor/O do/O I/O believe/O that/O the/O Uighur/O issue/O can/O be/O solved/O by/O depending/O on/O the/O U.S./LOCATION ./O 
The/O issues/O facing/O Uighurs/O ultimately/O can/O only/O be/O solved/O through/O a/O mutual/O dialogue/O between/O the/O Han/O and/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
--/O I/O make/O no/O appeal/O whatsoever/O to/O the/O international/O community/O ./O 
What/O we/O need/O is/O for/O the/O Communist/O government/O to/O take/O a/O responsible/O attitude/O and/O to/O reflect/O on/O its/O Xinjiang/LOCATION policies/O ./O 
The/O government/O should/O not/O politicize/O individual/O criminal/O cases/O or/O make/O them/O ethnically/O specific/O ./O 
It/O must/O act/O based/O on/O evidence/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O Voice/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION America/ORGANIZATION video/O interview/O on/O November/O 07/O ,/O 2013/O -RRB-/O --/O I/O am/O not/O going/O anywhere/O ./O 
The/O issues/O facing/O the/O Uighur/O are/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O resolution/O of/O these/O issues/O is/O also/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
If/O I/O have/O to/O be/O imprisoned/O ,/O then/O I/O will/O remain/O in/O a/O Chinese/O prison/O ./O 
After/O my/O release/O from/O prison/O ,/O I/O will/O still/O be/O in/O China/LOCATION seeking/O a/O future/O for/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
If/O I/O die/O ,/O I/O have/O only/O one/O desire/O :/O to/O be/O buried/O in/O my/O hometown/O ./O 
It/O would/O be/O enough/O of/O a/O solace/O for/O me/O ./O 
聽/O Translator/O 's/O note/O :/O the/O ``/O one/O village/O one/O police/O station/O ,/O one/O household/O one/O police/O officer/O ''/O was/O a/O campaign/O initiated/O by/O Zhang/PERSON Chunxian/PERSON ,/O a/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION Member/O and/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION Secretary/O for/O the/O Uighur/ORGANIZATION Autonomous/ORGANIZATION Region/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O a/O means/O to/O more/O tightly/O control/O Uighur/O villages/O ./O 
聽/O 
