The/O penalties/O range/O from/O five/O to/O 16/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O 
Accusations/O include/O charges/O of/O separatism/O ,/O ethnic/O hatred/O and/O disturbing/O the/O peace/O ./O 
The/O verdict/O was/O read/O in/O public/O in/O Kashgar/LOCATION ./O 
Increasingly/O the/O provincial/O epicenter/O of/O inter-ethnic/O clashes/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O -/O Authorities/O in/O the/O western/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION have/O sentenced/O 22/O Islamic/O preachers/O in/O recent/O days/O to/O sentences/O ranging/O from/O five/O to/O 16/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O 
Charges/O against/O them/O include/O separatism/O ,/O ethnic/O hatred/O and/O disturbing/O the/O peace/O ./O 
The/O verdict/O was/O read/O in/O public/O at/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION of/O Kashgar/LOCATION ./O 
The/O area/O is/O known/O for/O its/O violent/O attacks/O in/O recent/O months/O ,/O which/O according/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION that/O are/O orchestrated/O by/O Muslim/O separatists/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O judiciary/O report/O the/O preachers/O include/O ``/O rogue/O imams/O ,/O ''/O or/O those/O already/O removed/O from/O their/O mosques/O and/O religious/O still/O in/O office/O ./O 
Ainiwaer/PERSON Tuerxun/PERSON ,/O mayor/O of/O Kashgar/LOCATION ,/O said/O the/O province/O is/O ``/O plagued/O by/O religious/O extremism/O ''/O which/O has/O ``/O fomented/O terrorism/O in/O the/O region/O ./O ''/O 
According/O to/O the/O politician/O ,/O reading/O the/O sentence/O in/O public/O ``/O is/O a/O powerful/O deterrent/O that/O will/O help/O stop/O those/O who/O break/O the/O law/O through/O religion/O ./O ''/O 
Meng/PERSON Caixia/PERSON ,/O a/O teacher/O ,/O told/O the/O South/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Morning/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION that/O the/O problem/O of/O religious/O extremism/O ``/O is/O serious/O ,/O and/O is/O having/O a/O profound/O impact/O in/O the/O area/O ./O 
Some/O preachers/O are/O involved/O in/O this/O activity/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O very/O difficult/O for/O them/O to/O be/O open-minded/O and/O accept/O what/O they/O are/O told/O ''/O ./O 
The/O province/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Its/O Uyghur/O Muslim/O minority/O ,/O who/O number/O about/O nine/O million/O ,/O have/O long/O sought/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O central/O government/O ,/O for/O its/O part/O ,/O has/O brought/O in/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O settlers/O to/O make/O Han/O Chinese/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O it/O has/O severely/O curtailed/O Muslim/O religious/O worship/O as/O well/O as/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O local/O language/O and/O culture/O ./O 
Since/O 2009/O Chinese/O police/O and/O the/O military/O have/O held/O the/O region/O under/O a/O special/O regime/O ,/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION imposed/O followingclashes/O that/O left/O nearly/O 200/O people/O dead/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O various/O episodes/O of/O violence/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O long/O prison/O sentences/O were/O imposed/O and/O dozens/O of/O death/O penalties/O were/O carried/O out/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O blame/O Muslim/O extremists/O for/O the/O wave/O of/O violence/O ./O 
Uyghur/O exiles/O claim/O instead/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O ``/O exaggerating/O ''/O the/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O to/O justify/O repression/O against/O indigenous/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
聽/O 
