The/O clash/O took/O place/O in/O Shache/LOCATION county/LOCATION ,/O but/O the/O details/O are/O unclear/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O government/O ,/O a/O group/O of/O ``/O terrorists/O ''/O attacked/O local/O government/O offices/O and/O police/O station/O ;/O another/O reported/O to/O have/O attacked/O the/O inhabitants/O of/O Huangdi/PERSON ./O 
Authorities/O respond/O immediatly/O :/O dozens/O of/O dead/O ,/O wounded/O and/O arrested/O ./O 
Urumqi/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O -/O Chinese/O police/O have/O responded/O to/O an/O alleged/O terrorist/O attack/O on/O government/O buildings/O ,/O killing/O and/O injuring/O dozens/O of/O people/O -/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O and/O Han/O -/O in/O the/O remote/O western/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
The/O operation/O took/O place/O yesterday/O morning/O ,/O but/O state/O media/O only/O reported/O the/O news/O in/O the/O late/O evening/O ./O 
According/O to/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O group/O of/O assailants/O ``/O armed/O with/O knives/O and/O axes/O ''/O attacked/O the/O government/O office/O and/O the/O police/O station/O Elixku/ORGANIZATION ,/O County/O Shache/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O another/O group/O attack/O the/O inhabitants/O of/O Huangdi/PERSON town/O near/O Elixku/LOCATION ./O 
Local/O police/O said/O they/O had/O ``/O shot/O and/O killed/O dozens/O of/O assailants/O ''/O in/O what/O it/O called/O a/O premeditated/O and/O organized/O ``/O terrorist/O attack/O ''/O ./O 
During/O the/O violence/O 6/O cars/O were/O torched/O and/O 25/O more/O nearly/O destroyed/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O have/O not/O provided/O data/O on/O the/O number/O of/O victims/O or/O injured/O ,/O and/O have/O accused/O the/O Uyghur/O minority/O -/O Turkic/O and/O Muslim/O -/O for/O what/O happened/O ./O 
Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON ,/O spokesman/O for/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION based/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O says/O that/O more/O than/O 20/O Uyghurs/O were/O killed/O by/O the/O police/O ,/O while/O 10/O others/O were/O seriously/O injured/O ./O 
13/O police/O officers/O were/O killed/O or/O wounded/O ,/O while/O ``/O about/O 67/O people/O ''/O were/O arrested/O after/O the/O attack/O ./O 
The/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Its/O Uyghur/O Muslim/O minority/O ,/O who/O number/O about/O nine/O million/O ,/O have/O long/O sought/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O central/O government/O ,/O for/O its/O part/O ,/O has/O brought/O in/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O settlers/O to/O make/O Han/O Chinese/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O it/O has/O severely/O curtailed/O Muslim/O religious/O worship/O as/O well/O as/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O local/O language/O and/O culture/O ./O 
Since/O 2009/O Chinese/O police/O and/O the/O military/O have/O held/O the/O region/O under/O a/O special/O regime/O ,/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION imposed/O followingclashes/O that/O left/O nearly/O 200/O people/O dead/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O various/O episodes/O of/O violence/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O long/O prison/O sentences/O were/O imposed/O and/O dozens/O of/O death/O penalties/O were/O carried/O out/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O blame/O Muslim/O extremists/O for/O the/O wave/O of/O violence/O ./O 
Uyghur/O exiles/O claim/O instead/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O ``/O exaggerating/O ''/O the/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O to/O justify/O repression/O against/O indigenous/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
For/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Uyghurs/PERSON are/O responsible/O for/O the/O recent/O spate/O of/O violent/O attacks/O ,/O including/O the/O 1/O March/O 2014attack/O at/O the/O Kunming/LOCATION railway/O station/O by/O knives-wielding/O men/O that/O left/O 29/O people/O dead/O and/O more/O than/O 150/O wounded/O ,/O and/O the/O 28/O October/O 2013/O incidentwhen/O a/O SUV/O plunged/O into/O a/O crowd/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O then/O burst/O into/O flames/O ,/O killing/O three/O people/O ./O 
Finally/O ,/O May/O 1/O ,/O 2014/O an/O attack/O onthe/O train/O station/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION -/O the/O Capital/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION -/O shortly/O after/O the/O departure/O from/O the/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON caused/O 3/O dead/O and/O 79/O wounded/O ./O 
