The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O revealed/O the/O identity/O of/O 7/O terrorists/O killed/O for/O crimes/O that/O range/O from/O terrorist/O attacks/O to/O having/O watched/O online/O video/O on/O religious/O extremism/O ./O 
Uyghur/O dissident/O :/O ``/O Clearly/O politically/O motivated/O executions/O to/O weaken/O the/O spirit/O of/O the/O province/O ''/O ./O 
Urumqi/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O carried/O out/O 8/O death/O sentences/O for/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O in/O the/O north-western/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
The/O prisoners/O who/O were/O executed/O include/O the/O 3/O held/O responsible/O for/O theattack/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION last/O October/O ,/O which/O killed/O 5/O people/O ./O 
The/O others/O were/O instead/O found/O guilty/O of/O crimes/O ranging/O from/O ``/O arson/O ''/O to/O the/O manufacture/O of/O explosive/O material/O for/O terrorist/O activities/O ./O 
At/O the/O time/O of/O their/O execution/O ,/O the/O state/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION disclosed/O the/O identity/O of/O the/O three/O Tiananmen/LOCATION attackers/O :/O Huseyin/PERSON Guxur/PERSON ,/O Yusup/PERSON Wherniyas/PERSON and/O Yusup/PERSON Ehmet/PERSON ./O 
Rozi/PERSON Eziz/PERSON was/O instead/O executed/O for/O attacking/O police/O officers/O in/O 2013/O ;/O Abdusalam/PERSON Elim/PERSON for/O leading/O an/O unspecified/O terrorist/O organization/O ;/O Memet/PERSON Tohtiyusup/PERSON for/O murder/O -LRB-/O the/O victim/O 's/O name/O unknown/O -RRB-/O and/O for/O watching/O online/O video/O on/O religious/O extremism/O ;/O Abdumomin/PERSON Imin/PERSON for/O being/O ``/O terrorist/O ringleader/O ''/O ./O 
The/O name/O of/O the/O eighth/O prisoner/O that/O was/O executed/O is/O unknown/O ./O 
Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON ,/O a/O spokesman/O for/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION exile/O group/O ,/O called/O the/O executions/O ``/O a/O typical/O case/O of/O the/O law/O serving/O political/O ends/O ''/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O dissident/O ,/O in/O fact/O ,/O the/O sentences/O are/O part/O of/O a/O campaign/O launched/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O weaken/O the/O strength/O of/O spirit/O in/O the/O province/O ,/O which/O has/O long/O been/O seeking/O ``/O genuine/O autonomy/O ''/O from/O the/O central/O government/O ./O 
The/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Its/O Uyghur/O Muslim/O minority/O ,/O who/O number/O about/O nine/O million/O ,/O have/O long/O sought/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O central/O government/O ,/O for/O its/O part/O ,/O has/O brought/O in/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O settlers/O to/O make/O Han/O Chinese/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O it/O has/O severely/O curtailed/O Muslim/O religious/O worship/O as/O well/O as/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O local/O language/O and/O culture/O ./O 
