Kunming/LOCATION and/O Urumqi/LOCATION attacks/O shake/O Chinese/O authorities/O ,/O who/O respond/O by/O stepping/O up/O arrests/O and/O repression/O ./O 
The/O accusation/O is/O that/O of/O ``/O divulging/O video/O material/O or/O violent/O ,/O terrorists/O ''/O ./O 
Experts/O divided/O over/O responsibility/O for/O attacks/O ,/O which/O have/O not/O yet/O been/O claimed/O ./O 
And/O increasing/O restrictions/O on/O religion/O will/O only/O make/O things/O worse/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O -/O Police/O in/O the/O remote/O western/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION have/O arrested/O more/O than/O 230/O people/O in/O the/O last/O 6/O weeks/O on/O charges/O of/O ``/O disclosing/O violent/O or/O terrorist/O videos/O ''/O ./O 
According/O to/O theGlobal/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O is/O close/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O authorities/O arrested/O 232/O people/O for/O who/O ``/O have/O circulated/O videos/O promoting/O terrorism/O through/O the/O internet/O and/O on/O portable/O devices/O ''/O ./O 
The/O arrests/O came/O close/O to/O a/O series/O of/O violent/O attacks/O that/O have/O rocked/O the/O province/O and/O other/O parts/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O province/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Its/O Uyghur/O Muslim/O minority/O ,/O who/O number/O about/O nine/O million/O ,/O have/O long/O sought/O independence/O from/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O central/O government/O ,/O for/O its/O part/O ,/O has/O brought/O in/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O settlers/O to/O make/O Han/O Chinese/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O it/O has/O severely/O curtailed/O Muslim/O religious/O worship/O as/O well/O as/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O local/O language/O and/O culture/O ./O 
Since/O 2009/O Chinese/O police/O and/O the/O military/O have/O held/O the/O region/O under/O a/O special/O regime/O ,/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION imposed/O followingclashes/O that/O left/O nearly/O 200/O people/O dead/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O various/O episodes/O of/O violence/O ,/O hundreds/O of/O long/O prison/O sentences/O were/O imposed/O and/O dozens/O of/O death/O penalties/O were/O carried/O out/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O blame/O Muslim/O extremists/O for/O the/O wave/O of/O violence/O ./O 
Uyghur/O exiles/O claim/O instead/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O ``/O exaggerating/O ''/O the/O threat/O of/O Islamic/O terrorism/O to/O justify/O repression/O against/O indigenous/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
For/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O Uyghurs/PERSON are/O responsible/O for/O the/O recent/O spate/O of/O violent/O attacks/O ,/O including/O the/O 1/O March/O 2014attack/O at/O the/O Kunming/LOCATION railway/O station/O by/O knives-wielding/O men/O that/O left/O 29/O people/O dead/O and/O more/O than/O 150/O wounded/O ,/O and/O the/O 28/O October/O 2013/O incident/O whena/O SUV/O plunged/O into/O a/O crowd/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION ,/O then/O burst/O into/O flames/O ,/O killing/O three/O people/O ./O 
Finally/O ,/O May/O 1/O ,/O 2014/O an/O attack/O on/O the/O train/O station/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION -/O the/O Capital/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION -/O shortly/O after/O the/O departure/O from/O the/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON caused/O 3/O dead/O and/O 79/O wounded/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O government/O ,/O these/O are/O the/O work/O of/O ''/O armed/O groups/O inspired/O by/O Al/ORGANIZATION Qaeda/ORGANIZATION ''/O ,/O for/O example/O the/O Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O attacks/O were/O inspired/O and/O even/O ``/O orchestrated/O ''/O from/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O which/O the/O province/O borders/O ./O 
However/O several/O anti-/O terrorism/O experts/O reject/O this/O scenario/O ,/O since/O the/O extremist/O leaders/O have/O never/O explicitly/O claimed/O attacks/O in/O recent/O months/O ./O 
What/O is/O certain/O is/O that/O ethnic-religious/O tensions/O in/O the/O area/O are/O playing/O an/O important/O role/O in/O increasing/O tensions/O ./O 
According/O to/O a/O recent/O study/O published/O by/O Brian/PERSON J./PERSON Grim/PERSON ,/O one/O time/O director/O of/O the/O Pew/ORGANIZATION Research/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION on/O religions/O and/O now/O chairman/O of/O the/O Religious/ORGANIZATION Freedom/ORGANIZATION &/ORGANIZATION Business/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O ''/O wrong/O ''/O in/O stepping/O up/O repression.聽/O The/O analyst/O writes/O ``/O data/O show/O that/O religious/O restrictions/O can/O increase/O episodes/O of/O violence/O ,/O instead/O of/O reducing/O them/O ''/O ./O 
聽/O 
