Beijing/LOCATION has/O signed/O a/O series/O of/O agreements/O with/O the/O countries/O of/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION to/O repatriate/O Uighur/O Muslims/O ./O 
In/O Chinese/O prisons/O ,/O convicts/O are/O sentenced/O to/O severe/O penalties/O ,/O including/O death/O ./O 
Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION and/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION have/O repatriated/O prisoners/O who/O had/O sought/O asylum/O on/O humanitarian/O grounds/O ./O 
Dushanbe/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O 鈥/O Tajikistan/LOCATION 's/O parliament/O has/O unanimously/O approved/O a/O Tajik-Chinese/O agreement/O on/O the/O mutual/O extradition/O of/O suspected/O and/O convicted/O felons/O ./O 
Presenting/O the/O bilateral/O agreement/O to/O lawmakers/O before/O the/O debate/O ,/O Tajik/O Prosecutor-General/O Yusuf/PERSON Rahmonov/PERSON -LRB-/O pictured/O -RRB-/O urged/O passage/O in/O order/O to/O safeguard/O the/O rights/O of/O Tajik/O nationals/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O give/O them/O a/O chance/O to/O serve/O their/O terms/O in/O Tajik/O penitentiaries/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O deal/O seems/O more/O useful/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O which/O has/O been/O cracking/O down/O on/O the/O Uighur/O community/O for/O a/O long/O time/O ./O 
China/LOCATION currently/O detains/O 16/O Tajik/O nationals/O ,/O including/O seven/O women/O ./O 
Four/O of/O those/O inmates/O ,/O including/O one/O woman/O ,/O are/O on/O death/O row/O and/O five/O more/O are/O serving/O life/O terms/O ./O 
In/O Tajikistan/LOCATION ,/O three/O Chinese/O nationals/O are/O currently/O serving/O prison/O terms/O ,/O one/O for/O rape/O and/O two/O for/O endangering/O public/O health/O and/O drug/O trafficking/O ./O 
Both/O Tajikistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION are/O members/O of/O the/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Organisation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SCO/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O which/O also/O includes/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ,/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
Ethnic/O Uighurs/O ,/O who/O are/O mostly/O Muslim/O and/O live/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ,/O have/O been/O particularly/O at/O risk/O in/O Chinese/O prisons/O ./O 
Uighurs/O ,/O who/O speak/O a/O Turkic/O language/O ,/O traditionally/O consider/O themselves/O much/O closer/O to/O the/O peoples/O of/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
Uighur/O nationalists/O dream/O of/O creating/O their/O own/O state/O ,/O East/LOCATION Turkestan/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O under/O Chinese/O rule/O ,/O all/O Uighurs/O have/O suffered/O discrimination/O and/O repression/O ,/O accused/O by/O Chinese/O authorities/O of/O terrorism/O ./O 
According/O to/O experts/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O signed/O extradition/O agreements/O with/O neighbours/O to/O get/O Uighurs/O exiles/O and/O inflict/O harsher/O punishment/O ./O 
Once/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O they/O are/O given/O long/O periods/O of/O imprisonment/O or/O even/O the/O death/O penalty/O ./O 
For/O example/O ,/O Kyrgyz/O officials/O said/O that/O they/O returned/O three/O Uighurs/O to/O China/LOCATION following/O a/O local/O court/O 's/O ruling/O based/O on/O a/O bilateral/O agreement/O ./O 
Kazakhstan/LOCATION too/O has/O repatriated/O several/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O who/O had/O demanded/O asylum/O in/O the/O Central/O Asian/O nation/O ,/O earning/O criticism/O from/O domestic/O and/O international/O human/O rights/O organisations/O ./O 
