Bangkok/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O -/O Bilal/PERSON Mohammed/PERSON ,/O the/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O who/O confessed/O to/O involvement/O in/O theattack/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION in/O August/O 2015/O ,/O was/O reportedly/O tortured/O and/O forced/O to/O admit/O his/O guilt/O ./O 
This/O was/O stated/O by/O his/O lawyer/O ,/O Schoochart/PERSON Kanpai/PERSON ,/O on/O the/O eve/O of/O the/O Mohammed/PERSON 's/O appearance/O before/O a/O military/O court/O ./O 
According/O to/O police/O ,/O Mohammed/PERSON and/O Yusufu/PERSON Mieraili/PERSON -LRB-/O only/O other/O suspect/O detained/O -RRB-/O ,/O spontaneously/O confessed/O their/O role/O in/O the/O explosion/O of/O the/O bomb/O which/O caused/O 20/O dead/O and/O 100/O wounded/O ,/O including/O many/O tourists/O ./O 
At/O the/O time/O of/O the/O confession/O -/O the/O lawyer/O said/O after/O visiting/O his/O client/O in/O prison/O -/O Mohammed/PERSON ``/O was/O tortured/O and/O put/O under/O pressure/O ./O 
This/O is/O why/O he/O confirmed/O the/O charges/O ./O 
He/O goes/O on/O to/O say/O that/O he/O had/O no/O involvement/O in/O the/O case/O ./O 
The/O only/O charge/O that/O he/O admits/O is/O that/O of/O illegal/O immigration/O ./O ''/O 
Through/O its/O spokesman/O ,/O the/O members/O of/O the/O ruling/O military/O junta/O said/O they/O were/O ``/O quite/O sure/O that/O nothing/O happened/O to/O the/O suspects/O while/O they/O were/O under/O arrest/O ./O ''/O 
Mihammed/O and/O Mieraili/PERSON were/O indicted/O in/O November/O 2015/O for/O 10/O counts/O -LRB-/O including/O premeditated/O murder/O and/O conspiracy/O -RRB-/O but/O not/O for/O terrorism/O ./O 
The/O Bangkok/LOCATION authorities/O ,/O although/O the/O investigation/O suggested/O it/O ,/O immediately/O discarded/O the/O hypothesis/O of/O terrorism/O to/O avoid/O affecting/O the/O tourism/O sector/O and/O damage/O the/O country/O 's/O economy/O ./O 
During/O the/O preliminary/O hearing/O he/O two/O neither/O confirmed/O nor/O denied/O the/O charges/O due/O to/O translation/O problems/O ./O 
Last/O August/O 's/O attack/O has/O never/O been/O claimed/O ./O 
The/O fact/O the/O two/O leading/O suspects/O were/O Uyghur/O increased/O suspicions/O that/O is/O was/O revenge/O for/O theforced/O extradition/O suffered/O by/O the/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O in/O July/O ./O 
Police/O investigations/O have/O repeatedly/O been/O criticized/O by/O the/O population/O and/O experts/O ./O 
While/O investigations/O were/O still/O ongoing/O ,/O the/O first/O of/O September/O ,/O police/O pocketed/O the/O reward/O -LRB-/O 85/O thousand/O dollars/O -RRB-/O ./O 
On/O September/O 29/O ,/O the/O former/O head/O of/O the/O department/O Gen./O Poompunmuang/PERSON declared/O the/O ``/O case/O closed/O ''/O and/O handed/O over/O another/O 82/O thousand/O dollars/O in/O prize/O money/O for/O his/O men/O ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O the/O alleged/O ``/O mastermind/O ''/O of/O the/O attack/O ,/O identified/O as/O Izaan/O ,/O is/O still/O at/O large/O along/O with/O 15/O other/O suspects/O -LRB-/O all/O Uyghurs/O -RRB-/O ./O 
For/O these/O reasons/O ,/O a/O BangkokAsiaNews/ORGANIZATION source/O described/O the/O entire/O investigation/O ``/O a/O joke/O ''/O ./O 
