Brussels/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/O -RRB-/O -/O The/O European/ORGANIZATION Parliament/ORGANIZATION has/O named/O 聽the/O well-known/O intellectual/O and/O Uighur/O activist/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON among/O finalists/O for/O the/O Sakharov/O Prize/O ./O 
The/O Professor/O ,/O who/O had/O taught/O for/O years/O in/O a/O university/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O was/O sentenced/O to/O life/O imprisonment/O in/O September/O 2014on/O charges/O of/O ``/O terrorism/O ''/O and/O ``/O inciting/O separatism/O ''/O ./O 
In/O reality/O he/O was/O targeted/O by/O authorities/O for/O his/O writings/O ,/O critical/O of/O the/O central/O government/O and/O ``/O erroneous/O communist/O policies/O ''/O in/O the/O western/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Tohti/PERSON ,/O 47/O ,/O is/O famous/O for/O his/O public/O interventions/O in/O favor/O of/O the/O Uighur/O ./O 
This/O ethnic/O group/O lives/O in/O the/O northern/O autonomous/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O is/O ethnically/O Turkish/O and/O Muslim/PERSON ,/O and/O suffering/O a/O strong/O linguistic/O ,/O economic/O ,/O cultural/O and/O religious/O repression/O at/O the/O hand/O s/O of/O the/O Chinese/O central/O government/O ./O 
However/O there/O is/O no/O evidence/O that/O Tohti/PERSON supports/O the/O separatist/O movement/O and/O since/O the/O day/O of/O his/O arrest/O he/O continues/O to/O proclaim/O himself/O innocent/O ./O 
``/O He/O believes/O he/O has/O always/O tried/O to/O work/O in/O the/O interest/O of/O the/O nation/O with/O words/O and/O with/O deeds/O -/O says/O his/O lawyer/O -/O and/O the/O organic/O integration/O of/O the/O majority/O Han/O and/O the/O Uighur/O ''/O minority/O ./O 
The/O Sakharov/O Prize/O for/O Freedom/O of/O Thought/O is/O an/O award/O dedicated/O to/O the/O scientist/O and/O Soviet/O dissident/O Andrei/PERSON Sakharov/PERSON ,/O set/O up/O by/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Parliament/ORGANIZATION in/O 1988/O to/O reward/O personalities/O or/O organizations/O who/O have/O dedicated/O their/O lives/O to/O defending/O human/O rights/O and/O individual/O freedoms/O ./O 
Recent/O winners/O included/O Raif/PERSON Badawi/PERSON -LRB-/O 2015/O -RRB-/O ,/O a/O blogger/O who/O opposes/O repression/O in/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ;/O Malala/PERSON Yousafzai/PERSON -LRB-/O 2013/O -RRB-/O ,/O a/O young/O Pakistani/O activist/O who/O is/O fighting/O for/O the/O right/O to/O education/O in/O her/O country/O ;/O Nasrin/PERSON Sotoudeh/PERSON and/O Jafar/PERSON Panahi/PERSON -LRB-/O 2012/O -RRB-/O ,/O opposed/O to/O the/O regime/O of/O the/O ayatollahs/O in/O Iran/LOCATION ;/O the/O association/O Memorial/O -LRB-/O 2009/O -RRB-/O active/O in/O Russia/LOCATION ;/O Hu/PERSON Jia/PERSON -LRB-/O 2008/O -RRB-/O ,/O the/O historical/O face/O of/O dissidents/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O point/O of/O contact/O among/O activists/O for/O human/O rights/O and/O the/O international/O community/O ./O 
Hu/PERSON Jia/PERSON commented/O on/O to/O this/O nomination/O Radio/O Free/O Asia/O :/O ``/O As/O a/O Chinese/O citizen/O ,/O and/O Sakharov/PERSON award/O winner/O ,/O I/O believe/O that/O if/O there/O is/O one/O person/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION who/O really/O deserves/O the/O award/O that/O 's/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON ./O 
He/O is/O a/O thorn/O in/O the/O side/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION :/O He/O is/O the/O consciousness/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O and/O for/O this/O has/O received/O the/O harshest/O punishment/O ./O 
The/O people/O he/O represents/O are/O persecuted/O ,/O and/O this/O has/O sparked/O a/O welter/O of/O hostility/O and/O confrontation/O ./O 
But/O the/O key/O to/O loosen/O this/O pressure/O is/O Ilham鈥檚/O release/O ''/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O same/O activist/O fears/O this/O nomination/O could/O lead/O to/O increased/O pressures/O on/O the/O detainee/O :/O ''/O In/O 2008/O ,/O I/O was/O sentenced/O to/O 3.5/O years/O in/O prison/O on/O charges/O of/O ``/O inciting/O subversion/O of/O state/O power/O ,/O ''/O because/O I/O engaged/O in/O activities/O to/O promote/O human/O rights/O and/O liberty/O before/O the/O Olympic/O Games/O ./O 
聽The/O European/O Parliament/ORGANIZATION awarded/O me/O the/O Sakharov/O Prize/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O also/O nominated/O for/O the/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O ./O 
When/O I/O was/O in/O prison/O ,/O the/O head/O of/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION municipal/O political/O police/O led/O a/O group/O of/O public/O security/O and/O foreign/O ministry/O officials/O to/O pay/O a/O visit/O to/O me/O in/O prison/O 鈥/O they/O were/O putting/O me/O under/O 聽intense/O pressure/O ,/O trying/O to/O force/O me/O to/O make/O a/O public/O announcement/O that/O I/O rejected/O both/O the/O Sakharov/O Prize/O and/O the/O nomination/O for/O a/O Nobel/O Peace/O Prize/O ./O 
In/O exchange/O ,/O these/O officials/O said/O that/O they/O would/O reduce/O my/O sentence/O by/O 2.5/O years/O ,/O and/O also/O pay/O me/O double/O the/O cash/O award/O of/O the/O Sakharov/O Prize/O ,/O as/O economic/O ``/O compensation/O ./O ''/O 
These/O secret/O political/O police/O ,/O and/O the/O jailers/O in/O their/O charge/O ,/O lobbied/O me/O with/O this/O proposal/O on/O up/O to/O seven/O occasions/O ./O 
I/O flatly/O rejected/O all/O of/O these/O despicable/O ,/O filthy/O political/O dealings/O ./O 
Thus/O ,/O I/O am/O deeply/O aware/O of/O how/O moral/O support/O ,/O and/O awards/O from/O the/O international/O community/O ,/O place/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION 's/O security/O organs/O and/O foreign/O affairs/O officials/O under/O enormous/O pressure/O ''/O ./O 
Hu/PERSON concluded/O ,/O that/O the/O jailed/O professor/O ``/O opposes/O all/O forms/O of/O violence/O and/O bloodshed/O ./O 
If/O he/O 's/O awarded/O the/O Sakharov/O Prize/O ,/O then/O his/O ideas/O ,/O what/O he/O advocates/O ,/O what/O he/O has/O attempted/O to/O realize/O ,/O his/O wish/O that/O we/O 're/O all/O able/O to/O live/O with/O dignity/O as/O part/O of/O a/O big/O family/O ,/O will/O be/O recognized/O by/O the/O entire/O world/O ./O 
The/O Xinjiang/LOCATION question/O will/O be/O looked/O at/O squarely/O by/O the/O world/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O question/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O ''/O 
