DaimlerChrysler-owned/O Mercedes-Benz/ORGANIZATION Trucks/ORGANIZATION is/O preparing/O to/O team/O up/O with/O its/O Chinese/O partners/O to/O produce/O a/O wider/O range/O of/O vans/O and/O trucks/O on/O the/O mainland/O ,/O state/O media/O reported/O Monday/O ./O 
The/O US-German/O auto/O giant/O is/O looking/O to/O locally/O produce/O its/O Mercedes-Benz/ORGANIZATION branded/O vans/O and/O trucks/O ,/O including/O the/O Actros/O ,/O Axor/ORGANIZATION ,/O Atego/LOCATION and/O Unimog/O series/O ,/O theChina/O Daily/O said/O ,/O citing/O DaimlerChrysler/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O China/LOCATION -RRB-/O Ltd/ORGANIZATION general/O manager/O Rainer/PERSON Schaefer/PERSON ./O 
The/O auto/O firm/O commanded/O 32/O percent/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O heavy-duty/O truck/O market/O last/O year/O and/O aims/O to/O increase/O its/O share/O to/O 40/O percent/O within/O a/O few/O years/O ,/O the/O newspaper/O said/O ./O 
``/O Through/O years/O of/O preparation/O ,/O from/O product/O introduction/O to/O dealership/O networks/O ,/O from/O technology/O updates/O to/O after-sales/O services/O improvement/O ,/O our/O solid/O business/O foundation/O in/O China/LOCATION has/O been/O established/O ,/O ''/O Schaefer/PERSON said/O ./O 
Mercedes-Benz/ORGANIZATION Trucks/ORGANIZATION has/O gradually/O expanded/O its/O business/O from/O western/O and/O coastal/O areas/O to/O regions/O in/O central/O China/LOCATION and/O along/O the/O transportation/O artery/O of/O northeast/O China/LOCATION ./O 
It/O recently/O won/O a/O bid/O for/O Xinjiang/PERSON Guanghui/PERSON 's/O liquefied/O natural/O gas/O transportation/O program/O ,/O the/O newspaper/O added/O ./O 
