The/O International/ORGANIZATION Olympic/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION made/O no/O deal/O with/O China/LOCATION on/O limited/O Internet/O access/O for/O the/O media/O at/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympics/LOCATION ,/O IOC/ORGANIZATION president/O Jacques/PERSON Rogge/PERSON said/O on/O Saturday/O in/O response/O to/O recent/O speculation/O ./O 
``/O There/O has/O absolutely/O been/O no/O deal/O ,/O no/O agreement/O with/O the/O Chinese/O ,/O ''/O Rogge/PERSON told/O DPA/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O around/O IOC/ORGANIZATION executive/O board/O meetings/O ahead/O of/O the/O August/O 8-24/O Games/O ./O 
Rogge/PERSON also/O said/O that/O ``/O we/O must/O improve/O the/O situation/O ,/O ''/O the/O day/O after/O several/O Web/O sites/O such/O as/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION were/O finally/O unblocked/O for/O the/O Olympic/O media/O after/O protests/O ./O 
IOC/ORGANIZATION spokeswoman/O Giselle/PERSON Davies/PERSON did/O not/O speak/O of/O ``/O uncensored/O ''/O Internet/O access/O like/O Rogge/PERSON in/O the/O past/O ,/O but/O spoke/O of/O ``/O furthest/O possible/O access/O ''/O and/O said/O the/O Chinese/O had/O made/O ``/O unprecedented/O moves/O ''/O by/O unblocking/O some/O Web/O sites/O for/O the/O Olympic/O media/O ./O 
IOC/ORGANIZATION press/O commission/O chief/O Kevan/PERSON Gosper/PERSON said/O on/O Saturday/O that/O a/O working/O group/O from/O the/O IOC/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION organizers/O BOCOG/O has/O been/O set/O up/O to/O deal/O with/O possible/O further/O problems/O on/O the/O issue/O ./O 
A/O number/O of/O Web/O sites/O are/O blocked/O by/O the/O Communist/O government/O for/O Chinese/O citizens/O but/O China/LOCATION promised/O that/O the/O Olympic/O media/O at/O least/O have/O better/O access/O ./O 
The/O international/O media/O was/O furious/O when/O it/O noticed/O this/O week/O that/O Web/O sites/O were/O blocked/O in/O the/O Olympic/O media/O center/O ,/O which/O prompted/O speculation/O of/O a/O possible/O deal/O or/O that/O the/O IOC/ORGANIZATION had/O caved/O in/O to/O the/O Chinese/O ./O 
``/O I/O was/O very/O unhappy/O on/O Tuesday/O ,/O ''/O Gosper/PERSON told/O a/O news/O conference/O ./O 
``/O Censorship/O was/O being/O applied/O ./O 
It/O was/O clarified/O at/O the/O most/O senior/O level/O ./O ''/O 
Gosper/PERSON said/O he/O met/O with/O Rogge/PERSON after/O the/O IOC/ORGANIZATION boss/O '/O arrival/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION on/O Friday/O and/O that/O IOC/ORGANIZATION top/O officials/O Hein/PERSON Verbruggen/PERSON and/O Gilbert/PERSON Felli/PERSON then/O met/O with/O the/O organizing/O committee/O BOCOG/O which/O resulted/O in/O the/O unblocking/O of/O Web/O sites/O ./O 
Journalists/O at/O the/O media/O center/O are/O now/O able/O to/O access/O sites/O for/O Amnesty/O ,/O US/LOCATION broadcaster/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Free/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION ,/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O China-critical/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION newspaper/O Apple/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O Human/O Rights/O Watch/O as/O well/O as/O the/O site/O of/O a/O group/O advocating/O Taiwan/LOCATION independence/O ./O 
But/O access/O to/O other/O Web/O sites/O were/O still/O barred/O ,/O including/O those/O for/O Human/O Rights/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O organizations/O advocating/O the/O end/O of/O Chinese/O rule/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O western/O China/LOCATION 's/O Muslim-populated/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ./O 
The/O Web/O sites/O for/O the/O outlawed/O spiritual/O group/O Falun/ORGANIZATION Gong/ORGANIZATION were/O also/O blocked/O ./O 
Gosper/PERSON also/O dismissed/O claims/O that/O the/O IOC/ORGANIZATION was/O to/O blame/O over/O the/O issue/O ./O 
``/O This/O came/O as/O a/O big/O surprise/O ,/O ''/O Gosper/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O There/O was/O uncertainty/O from/O BOCOG/O ./O 
The/O IOC/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O ineffective/O ./O ''/O 
``/O In/O the/O end/O ,/O BOCOG/O will/O fall/O in/O line/O with/O the/O IOC/ORGANIZATION ./O 
It/O has/O been/O a/O fairly/O rough/O week/O ./O 
We/O are/O back/O on/O track/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
