Ahead/O of/O a/O two-day/O EU-Asia/O summit/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION said/O Thursday/O China/LOCATION had/O to/O play/O its/O part/O in/O helping/O to/O resolve/O the/O current/O global/O economic/O crisis/O ./O 
European/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION President/O Jose/PERSON Manuel/PERSON Barroso/PERSON on/O Thursday/O ,/O Oct./O 23/O ,/O said/O China/LOCATION should/O have/O more/O say/O in/O international/O financial/O institutions/O ,/O but/O also/O urged/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O play/O its/O part/O in/O helping/O to/O resolve/O the/O global/O financial/O crisis/O ./O 
``/O We/O need/O a/O coordinated/O global/O response/O to/O reform/O the/O global/O financial/O system/O ./O 
We/O are/O living/O in/O unprecedented/O times/O ,/O and/O we/O need/O unprecedented/O levels/O of/O global/O coordination/O ,/O ''/O Barroso/PERSON told/O reporters/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
``/O I/O very/O much/O hope/O that/O China/LOCATION gives/O an/O important/O contribution/O to/O the/O solution/O of/O this/O financial/O crisis/O ./O 
It/O 's/O a/O great/O opportunity/O for/O China/LOCATION to/O show/O a/O sense/O of/O responsibility/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
``/O It/O 's/O very/O simple/O :/O we/O sink/O together/O or/O we/O swim/O together/O ./O ''/O 
Barroso/PERSON 's/O comments/O came/O ahead/O of/O a/O two-day/O summit/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION of/O the/O 27/O EU/ORGANIZATION member/O states/O and/O 16/O Asian/O countries/O covering/O the/O global/O downturn/O ,/O climate/O change/O and/O international/O security/O ./O 
Outlining/O the/O ``/O unprecedented/O ''/O challenges/O facing/O the/O global/O economy/O ,/O under/O threat/O of/O a/O looming/O worldwide/O recession/O ,/O Barroso/PERSON said/O :/O ``/O We/O need/O Asia/LOCATION to/O be/O on/O board/O ,/O and/O more/O particularly/O countries/O like/O China/LOCATION ,/O India/LOCATION -LRB-/O and/O -RRB-/O Japan/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
French/O President/O Nicolas/PERSON Sarkozy/PERSON ,/O whose/O country/O currently/O holds/O the/O rotating/O presidency/O of/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ,/O has/O already/O said/O he/O would/O use/O the/O ASEM/ORGANIZATION summit/O to/O seek/O Asian/O backing/O for/O his/O bid/O to/O rebuild/O the/O world/O 's/O financial/O system/O ./O 
European/O governments/O have/O already/O committed/O more/O than/O two/O trillion/O dollars/O to/O help/O bail/O out/O struggling/O banks/O and/O shore/O up/O plummeting/O stock/O markets/O in/O largely/O coordinated/O actions/O ./O 
Unlike/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O Asian/O banks/O have/O not/O responded/O to/O the/O crisis/O with/O coordinated/O action/O ,/O but/O rather/O have/O focused/O on/O cutting/O interest/O rates/O ,/O guaranteeing/O bank/O deposits/O and/O injecting/O money/O into/O credit/O markets/O ./O 
``/O The/O present/O gathering/O could/O not/O be/O more/O timely/O ./O 
We/O face/O challenges/O which/O do/O n't/O respect/O any/O borders/O ,/O ''/O Barroso/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O No/O one/O in/O Europe/LOCATION or/O Asia/LOCATION can/O seriously/O pretend/O to/O be/O immune/O ./O 
We/O are/O living/O in/O unprecedented/O times/O ,/O and/O we/O need/O unprecedented/O levels/O of/O global/O coordination/O ./O ''/O 
Barroso/PERSON also/O hinted/O that/O in/O return/O Beijing/LOCATION could/O be/O given/O greater/O clout/O on/O the/O world/O financial/O stage/O ./O 
China/LOCATION this/O year/O won/O a/O modest/O increase/O in/O its/O voting/O power/O at/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Monetary/ORGANIZATION Fund/ORGANIZATION but/O argues/O that/O it/O is/O still/O not/O being/O given/O adequate/O leverage/O as/O the/O world/O 's/O fourth-largest/O economy/O and/O the/O one/O that/O is/O growing/O fastest/O ./O 
``/O We/O think/O China/LOCATION could/O and/O should/O have/O a/O greater/O voice/O in/O international/O financial/O institutions/O ,/O ''/O Barroso/PERSON said/O in/O a/O speech/O at/O a/O school/O for/O civil/O servants/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O among/O the/O Group/O of/O 20/O industrial/O and/O emerging/O nations/O that/O US/LOCATION President/O George/PERSON W./PERSON Bush/PERSON invited/O to/O a/O finance/O summit/O in/O Washington/LOCATION on/O Nov./O 15/O ./O 
More/O concrete/O internationally/O coordinated/O action/O is/O expected/O to/O come/O out/O of/O the/O Washington/LOCATION conference/O that/O Friday/O and/O Saturday/O 's/O Asia-Europe/O Meeting/O -LRB-/O ASEM/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Speaking/O to/O reporters/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION after/O meeting/O Chinese/O Premier/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON ,/O German/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON said/O on/O Thursday/O that/O ``/O cooperation/O with/O China/LOCATION is/O of/O utmost/O importance/O ''/O for/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
``/O It/O is/O important/O to/O bring/O China/LOCATION into/O a/O new/O financial/O system/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O China/LOCATION was/O already/O making/O efforts/O ./O 
``/O With/O China/LOCATION 's/O strong/O economic/O growth/O ,/O China/LOCATION by/O itself/O is/O already/O making/O a/O contribution/O ,/O ''/O Merkel/PERSON said/O ./O 
In/O a/O speech/O ahead/O of/O his/O talks/O with/O Merkel/PERSON ,/O Wen/PERSON said/O cooperation/O with/O Germany/LOCATION was/O ``/O extremely/O important/O ''/O and/O that/O China/LOCATION ``/O counts/O on/O investment/O from/O Germany/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
German/O officials/O said/O the/O fact/O that/O Merkel/PERSON was/O one/O of/O the/O few/O foreign/O leaders/O making/O a/O formal/O state/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION for/O the/O ASEM/ORGANIZATION summit/O showed/O the/O importance/O of/O ties/O between/O the/O two/O nations/O ./O 
Merkel/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O scheduled/O to/O meet/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON Friday/O ,/O said/O she/O raised/O human/O rights/O issues/O ,/O including/O the/O situation/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Tibetan/O and/O Uighur/O minorities/O ,/O during/O her/O talks/O ,/O adding/O that/O Germany/LOCATION wanted/O to/O continue/O dialogue/O with/O China/LOCATION on/O human/O rights/O ./O 
She/O welcomed/O Thursday/O 's/O award/O of/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION 's/O Sakharov/O Prize/O for/O human/O rights/O to/O recently/O jailed/O Chinese/O dissident/O Hu/PERSON Jia/PERSON ./O 
``/O The/O German/O government/O has/O always/O called/O for/O the/O release/O of/O Hu/PERSON Jia/PERSON and/O will/O continue/O to/O do/O so/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O she/O did/O n't/O expect/O the/O issue/O to/O cast/O a/O cloud/O over/O the/O ASEM/ORGANIZATION summit/O ./O 
China/LOCATION expressed/O anger/O at/O the/O decision/O to/O award/O the/O prize/O to/O Hu/O ,/O 35/O ,/O who/O was/O imprisoned/O for/O three-and-a-half/O years/O in/O April/O on/O subversion/O charges/O ./O 
But/O experts/O say/O the/O incident/O is/O unlikely/O to/O seriously/O mar/O the/O summit/O or/O strain/O ties/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O EU/LOCATION ./O 
``/O The/O fact/O is/O ,/O in/O spite/O of/O all/O the/O political/O irritation/O and/O debates/O in/O the/O last/O few/O months/O about/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O and/O the/O Olympics/O ,/O the/O significance/O of/O bilateral/O economic/O relations/O between/O Germany/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION or/O Europe/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION was/O never/O denied/O by/O anyone/O ,/O ''/O Eberhard/PERSON Sandschneider/PERSON ,/O research/O director/O at/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION on/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Relations/ORGANIZATION told/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION ./O 
