Historic/O and/O short-term/O factors/O provoked/O recent/O unrest/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O and/O there/O is/O no/O quick/O solution/O to/O the/O conflict/O ./O 
More/O social/O justice/O and/O cultural/O integration/O is/O necessary/O ,/O experts/O at/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION say/O ./O 
Following/O the/O violent/O unrest/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION last/O year/O ,/O the/O most/O violent/O ethnic/O motivated/O upheaval/O in/O decades/O occurred/O earlier/O this/O month/O in/O the/O autonomous/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION in/O western/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O unexpected/O level/O of/O aggression/O demonstrated/O during/O this/O recent/O turmoil/O caused/O the/O death/O of/O nearly/O 200/O people/O and/O left/O more/O than/O 1,600/O people/O injured/O ./O 
The/O incident/O demonstrates/O the/O limitations/O of/O the/O concept/O of/O social/O harmony/O that/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O employed/O in/O recent/O years/O in/O order/O to/O glaze/O the/O social/O conflicts/O resulting/O from/O rapid/O ./O 
Arguably/O ,/O the/O harmonious/O society/O envisaged/O and/O idealized/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O never/O really/O materialized/O in/O the/O autonomous/O regions/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Uighurs/O are/O not/O the/O only/O ethnic/O minority/O in/O China/LOCATION The/O roots/O of/O the/O latest/O unrest/O go/O far/O back/O into/O history/O ,/O as/O Xinjiang/LOCATION for/O the/O longest/O time/O has/O been/O a/O multi-ethnic/O region/O ,/O influenced/O and/O ruled/O by/O changing/O forces/O before/O it/O became/O part/O of/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION ./O 
Consequently/O ,/O a/O major/O objective/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O been/O to/O stabilize/O the/O region/O and/O -/O especially/O in/O the/O course/O of/O the/O overall/O reform/O process/O -/O to/O stimulate/O economic/O development/O ./O 
However/O ,/O from/O the/O perspective/O of/O the/O local/O ``/O national/O minorities/O ,/O ''/O which/O do/O not/O only/O comprise/O Uighur/O people/O but/O a/O number/O of/O other/O ethnic/O groups/O ,/O the/O minorities/O never/O prospered/O from/O the/O success/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O rapid/O economic/O development/O in/O a/O way/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O population/O did/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O tried/O to/O counter/O this/O perception/O by/O means/O of/O its/O minority-related/O policies/O ./O 
Indeed/O ,/O during/O the/O 1990s/O ,/O the/O government/O -/O among/O other/O initiatives/O -/O extended/O the/O freedom/O of/O religion/O and/O eased/O access/O of/O the/O minority/O people/O to/O education/O and/O especially/O to/O universities/O ./O 
The/O ``/O go/O west/O ''/O policies/O of/O the/O second/O half/O of/O the/O 1990s/O were/O intended/O to/O enhance/O the/O development/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O areas/O and/O to/O reduce/O the/O development/O gap/O between/O the/O coastal/O regions/O and/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
Compared/O to/O other/O provinces/O and/O regions/O ,/O Xinjiang/LOCATION performed/O better/O economically/O and/O benefited/O from/O all/O kinds/O of/O direct/O and/O indirect/O subsidies/O ./O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O minority/O policies/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O Tibet/LOCATION failed/O in/O one/O crucial/O aspect/O :/O Since/O the/O early/O 1990s/O ,/O as/O a/O result/O of/O laxer/O birth/O controls/O for/O minority/O people/O ,/O the/O share/O of/O minorities/O in/O overall/O population/O grew/O in/O all/O autonomous/O regions/O or/O districts/O of/O China/LOCATION except/O for/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O Liaoning/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O minorities/O declined/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O the/O population/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION grew/O from/O about/O 15/O million/O people/O to/O more/O than/O 20/O million/O ./O 
In/O the/O urban/O agglomerations/O such/O as/O Urumqi/LOCATION the/O national/O minorities/O that/O used/O to/O dominate/O the/O local/O population/O literally/O became/O minorities/O ./O 
Julia/PERSON Bader/PERSON is/O a/O political/O scientist/O at/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION Against/ORGANIZATION this/O background/O of/O huge/O growth/O in/O population/O ,/O a/O shift/O in/O the/O relative/O weight/O of/O the/O minority/O population/O as/O well/O as/O a/O political/O system/O which/O grants/O rights/O but/O does/O not/O allow/O for/O substantial/O participation/O or/O autonomy/O ,/O any/O minor/O incident/O could/O have/O sparked/O an/O outbreak/O of/O the/O simmering/O conflict/O ./O 
In/O this/O case/O ,/O the/O trigger/O of/O the/O unrest/O has/O most/O likely/O been/O the/O economic/O downturn/O resulting/O from/O the/O global/O financial/O crisis/O ./O 
This/O is/O indicated/O by/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O Urumqi/LOCATION unrests/O followed/O a/O conflict/O among/O workers/O of/O different/O ethnic/O groups/O in/O a/O factory/O located/O in/O southern/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Also/O ,/O Han/O Chinese/O have/O repeatedly/O voiced/O their/O anger/O against/O unfair/O privileges/O Uighur/O people/O presumably/O enjoy/O due/O to/O their/O minority/O status/O ./O 
Such/O arguments/O arise/O in/O times/O of/O crisis/O when/O growth/O is/O limited/O and/O distribution/O conflicts/O prevail/O ./O 
Due/O to/O the/O specific/O mixture/O of/O historic/O and/O short-term/O factors/O that/O have/O provoked/O the/O recent/O unrest/O ,/O quick/O solutions/O to/O solve/O the/O conflicts/O clearly/O are/O not/O at/O hand/O ./O 
For/O sure/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O will/O not/O endanger/O national/O integrity/O ,/O thereby/O creating/O precedence/O for/O other/O provinces/O or/O minorities/O striving/O for/O independence/O ./O 
Similarly/O ,/O the/O fact/O that/O many/O Han/O Chinese/O families/O have/O already/O lived/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION for/O generations/O limits/O the/O options/O for/O a/O far-reaching/O ethnic-based/O autonomy/O ./O 
Any/O sustainable/O political/O solution/O for/O Xinjiang/LOCATION would/O have/O to/O respect/O the/O needs/O of/O Uighurs/O as/O well/O as/O those/O of/O the/O other/O minorities/O and/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
Doris/PERSON Fischer/PERSON is/O an/O economist/O at/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION To/O ease/O the/O conflict/O and/O to/O establish/O a/O literally/O harmonious/O society/O ,/O more/O social/O justice/O and/O cultural/O integration/O among/O the/O ethnic/O groups/O involved/O would/O be/O needed/O ./O 
This/O will/O hardly/O be/O achieved/O by/O the/O increased/O military/O forces/O that/O currently/O appease/O the/O situation/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ./O 
Future/O integration/O policies/O will/O have/O to/O be/O more/O inclusive/O and/O participatory/O ,/O integrating/O the/O indigenous/O population/O more/O actively/O in/O public/O and/O governmental/O institutions/O ./O 
In/O the/O long/O run/O ,/O political/O stability/O for/O Xinjiang/LOCATION can/O only/O be/O envisaged/O in/O the/O context/O of/O a/O changed/O national/O political/O environment/O based/O on/O institutions/O that/O guaranty/O far/O reaching/O transparency/O ,/O extended/O political/O rights/O as/O well/O as/O fair/O mechanisms/O of/O distribution/O and/O reconcilement/O of/O social/O interests/O ./O 
Authors/O :/O Julia/PERSON Bader/PERSON ,/O Dr./O Doris/PERSON Fischer/PERSON Editor/O :/O Sean/PERSON Sinico/PERSON Julia/PERSON Bader/PERSON is/O a/O political/O scientist/O in/O the/O ``/O Governance/O ,/O Statehood/O ,/O Security/O ''/O department/O at/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Dr./O Doris/PERSON Fischer/PERSON is/O an/O economist/O in/O the/O institute/O 's/O ``/O Competitiveness/O and/O Social/O Development/O ''/O department/O ./O 
Based/O in/O Bonn/LOCATION ,/O the/O German/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O Deutsches/ORGANIZATION Institut/ORGANIZATION für/O Entwicklungspolitik/O DIE/O -RRB-/O draws/O together/O the/O knowledge/O of/O development/O research/O available/O worldwide/O ,/O dedicating/O its/O work/O to/O key/O issues/O facing/O the/O future/O of/O development/O policy/O ./O 
It/O consults/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O independent/O research/O findings/O in/O Germany/LOCATION and/O worldwide/O and/O deals/O with/O current/O issues/O in/O cooperation/O between/O industrial/O and/O developing/O countries/O ./O 
