The/O US/LOCATION has/O issued/O a/O second/O request/O to/O Germany/LOCATION to/O take/O in/O prisoners/O from/O Guantanamo/LOCATION ./O 
But/O the/O government/O says/O it/O needs/O more/O details/O before/O it/O can/O make/O a/O decision/O ./O 
The/O interior/ORGANIZATION ministry/ORGANIZATION said/O on/O Thursday/O that/O it/O was/O unable/O to/O accept/O the/O US/LOCATION request/O based/O on/O the/O data/O provided/O ./O 
``/O We/O 're/O examining/O two/O new/O cases/O ,/O ''/O ministry/O spokesman/O Stefan/PERSON Paris/PERSON said/O in/O Berlin/LOCATION ./O 
``/O The/O information/O provided/O by/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION is/O not/O sufficient/O for/O now/O for/O us/O to/O give/O the/O green/O light/O for/O taking/O in/O the/O two/O men/O ./O ''/O 
The/O interior/ORGANIZATION ministry/ORGANIZATION would/O need/O to/O check/O whether/O the/O prisoners/O represented/O a/O security/O risk/O ,/O he/O said/O ./O 
Also/O ,/O Berlin/LOCATION needed/O to/O know/O why/O the/O men/O could/O not/O be/O taken/O in/O by/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O what/O ties/O they/O had/O to/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
Paris/LOCATION would/O not/O disclose/O the/O nationality/O of/O the/O two/O men/O ./O 
Security/O sources/O said/O one/O was/O Syrian/O ,/O the/O other/O Tunisian/O ./O 
Resistance/O at/O home/O and/O abroad/O In/O April/O ,/O the/O US/LOCATION made/O an/O initial/O request/O ,/O presenting/O the/O German/O government/O with/O a/O list/O of/O nine/O Chinese/O Uighur/O detainees/O for/O Berlin/LOCATION to/O ``/O consider/O ./O ''/O 
Palau/LOCATION is/O offering/O 17/O Uighers/ORGANIZATION a/O new/O temporary/O home/O Interior/ORGANIZATION Minister/O Wolfgang/PERSON Schaeuble/PERSON had/O also/O replied/O in/O that/O case/O that/O the/O information/O provided/O was/O insufficient/O to/O warrant/O a/O positive/O reply/O ./O 
US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON has/O pledged/O to/O close/O the/O facility/O at/O the/O US/LOCATION naval/O base/O at/O Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION ,/O Cuba/LOCATION by/O early/O next/O year/O ./O 
Many/O of/O the/O inmates/O have/O already/O been/O cleared/O for/O release/O ./O 
But/O US/LOCATION officials/O are/O having/O difficulty/O finding/O countries/O that/O will/O take/O them/O in/O ,/O and/O meeting/O resistance/O at/O home/O to/O housing/O them/O on/O US/LOCATION soil/O ./O 
The/O tiny/O Pacific/LOCATION nation/O Palau/LOCATION on/O agreed/O Wednesday/O to/O take/O in/O up/O to/O 17/O Uighur/O Guantanamo/O detainees/O ./O 
Four/O further/O Uighur/O men/O who/O had/O been/O held/O at/O the/O prison/O camp/O were/O sent/O to/O Bermuda/LOCATION on/O Thursday/O ./O 
Sharp/O political/O debate/O German/O politicians/O have/O disagreed/O on/O the/O issue/O ./O 
Foreign/O Minister/O Frank-Walter/PERSON Steinmeier/PERSON ,/O the/O Social/ORGANIZATION Democrat/ORGANIZATION candidate/O to/O challenge/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON in/O September/O 's/O federal/O election/O ,/O has/O spoken/O in/O favor/O of/O accepting/O inmates/O ./O 
But/O Interior/O Minister/O Schaeuble/PERSON has/O voiced/O skepticism/O ./O 
On/O a/O visit/O to/O Germany/LOCATION last/O week/O ,/O Obama/PERSON said/O after/O talks/O with/O Merkel/PERSON that/O he/O had/O neither/O asked/O for/O nor/O received/O any/O hard/O commitments/O from/O Berlin/LOCATION on/O taking/O Guantanamo/LOCATION detainees/O ./O 
He/O said/O Merkel/PERSON had/O been/O ``/O very/O open/O ''/O to/O discussions/O on/O the/O issue/O ./O 
Opposition/O politicians/O have/O been/O very/O critical/O of/O the/O government/O 's/O stance/O ./O 
Claudia/PERSON Roth/PERSON ,/O co-leader/O of/O the/O Green/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O Schaeuble/PERSON was/O using/O ``/O stalling/O tactics/O ./O ''/O 
``/O He/O 's/O acting/O on/O the/O maxim/O :/O we/O do/O n't/O know/O anything/O ,/O we/O have/O to/O check/O things/O first/O ,/O we/O have/O to/O deliberate/O so/O long/O until/O someone/O else/O takes/O this/O decision/O of/O our/O hands/O ,/O ''/O Roth/PERSON said/O in/O reference/O to/O the/O Uighur/O case/O ./O 
Michael/PERSON Leutert/PERSON ,/O the/O human/O rights/O spokesman/O for/O the/O Left/O party/O 's/O parliamentary/O group/O ,/O said/O accepting/O the/O inmates/O was/O ``/O a/O simple/O humanitarian/O act/O ./O ''/O 
``/O It/O is/O not/O plausible/O that/O two/O people/O proven/O innocent/O pose/O an/O uncalculated/O security/O risk/O for/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Leutert/PERSON said/O ./O 
He/O said/O the/O German/O government/O needed/O to/O promptly/O ``/O consider/O favorably/O ''/O the/O US/LOCATION request/O ./O 
sac/AFP/Reuters/O //O dpa/O Editor/O :/O Chuck/PERSON Penfold/PERSON 
