Italy/LOCATION has/O agreed/O to/O accept/O three/O Guantanamo/LOCATION detainees/O ./O 
The/O announcement/O came/O after/O talks/O between/O US/LOCATION President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON and/O Italian/O Prime/O Minister/O Silvio/PERSON Berlusconi/PERSON in/O Washington/LOCATION ./O 
``/O I/O thanked/O the/O prime/O minister/O for/O his/O support/O of/O our/O policy/O of/O closing/O Guantanamo/O ,/O ''/O Obama/PERSON said/O after/O the/O meeting/O at/O the/O White/LOCATION House/LOCATION ./O 
``/O This/O is/O not/O just/O talk/O ./O 
Italy/LOCATION has/O agreed/O to/O accept/O three/O specific/O detainees/O ./O ''/O 
The/O announcement/O comes/O after/O the/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION said/O earlier/O on/O Monday/O it/O agreed/O on/O a/O ``/O framework/O ''/O for/O its/O member/O states/O to/O accept/O released/O Guantanamo/LOCATION detainees/O ./O 
Washington/LOCATION said/O it/O would/O grant/O EU/ORGANIZATION member/O states/O acces/O to/O information/O on/O detainees/O cleared/O for/O release/O ,/O and/O added/O that/O it/O would/O consider/O -/O case/O for/O case/O -/O making/O a/O contribution/O towards/O the/O cost/O of/O receiving/O former/O prisoners/O ./O 
Obama/PERSON welcomed/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION deal/O ,/O saying/O that/O it/O paved/O the/O way/O for/O ``/O an/O opportunity/O to/O create/O a/O lasting/O and/O durable/O international/O legal/O framework/O for/O dealing/O with/O terrorism/O that/O I/O think/O is/O very/O important/O on/O both/O sides/O of/O the/O Atlantic/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Within/O days/O of/O taking/O office/O on/O January/O ,/O Obama/PERSON set/O a/O one-year/O deadline/O for/O closing/O the/O prison/O ,/O which/O now/O holds/O more/O than/O 220/O detainees/O ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION administration/O last/O week/O sent/O three/O Saudi/O prisoners/O ,/O one/O Iraqi/O and/O one/O Chadian/O back/O to/O their/O homelands/O ./O 
Four/O Uighurs/O were/O resettled/O on/O the/O Atlantic/LOCATION island/O of/O Bermuda/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O US/LOCATION is/O in/O talks/O to/O send/O another/O 13/O of/O the/O Chinese/O Muslims/O to/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION island/O of/O Palau/LOCATION ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION has/O refused/O to/O send/O them/O back/O to/O China/LOCATION over/O concerns/O they/O could/O be/O tortured/O ./O 
ai/dpa/Reuters/O Editor/O :/O Jennifer/PERSON Abramsohn/PERSON 
