The/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION is/O celebrating/O its/O 60th/O birthday/O on/O 1st/O October/O ./O 
Tens/O of/O thousands/O will/O attend/O a/O big/O military/O parade/O ./O 
It/O has/O all/O been/O orchestrated/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O has/O direct/O control/O of/O which/O events/O are/O celebrated/O and/O how/O China/LOCATION 's/O recent/O history/O is/O portrayed/O ./O 
``/O Social/O Progress/O in/O the/O Minority/O Regions/O ''/O :/O The/O exhibition/O in/O the/O Palace/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Nationalities/ORGANIZATION has/O drawn/O hordes/O of/O visitors/O ./O 
Big/O ,/O bright/O photos/O of/O happy/O people/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O Inner/LOCATION Mongolia/LOCATION adorn/O the/O walls/O ./O 
Young/O women/O wearing/O national/O dress/O guide/O the/O visitors/O through/O the/O exhibition/O ./O 
Harmony/O and/O economic/O progress/O are/O at/O the/O fore/O of/O the/O events/O to/O mark/O the/O 60th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O foundation/O of/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION China/LOCATION ./O 
Controversial/O themes/O are/O nowhere/O to/O be/O seen/O ./O 
There/O is/O no/O talk/O about/O the/O pro-autonomy/O movements/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION or/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
But/O the/O visitors/O are/O not/O complaining/O ./O 
``/O We/O can/O see/O the/O economic/O development/O of/O China/LOCATION in/O the/O past/O few/O years/O and/O it/O 's/O really/O very/O good/O ,/O ''/O one/O of/O them/O says/O ./O 
``/O As/O far/O as/O I/O know/O ,/O it/O 's/O only/O people/O outside/O China/LOCATION who/O want/O Tibet/LOCATION or/O Xinjiang/LOCATION to/O be/O independent/O ./O ''/O 
History/O as/O an/O instrument/O of/O party/O propaganda/O Controversial/O themes/O are/O also/O omitted/O in/O history/O books/O ./O 
Nowhere/O is/O the/O bloody/O suppression/O of/O the/O democracy/O movement/O in/O 1989/O mentioned/O ./O 
The/O Cultural/O Revolution/O might/O be/O mentioned/O fleetingly/O ./O 
The/O Great/O Leap/O Forward/O that/O triggered/O a/O catastrophic/O famine/O at/O the/O end/O of/O the/O 1950s/O gets/O a/O passing/O mention/O only/O but/O nowhere/O can/O the/O number/O of/O victims/O be/O found/O ./O 
Journalist/O Li/PERSON Datong/PERSON has/O nothing/O good/O to/O say/O about/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION although/O he/O was/O a/O member/O for/O years/O ./O 
``/O At/O the/O moment/O ,/O all/O depictions/O of/O history/O in/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Republic/ORGANIZATION are/O lies/O ./O 
There/O is/O not/O one/O ounce/O of/O truth/O ,/O ''/O Li/PERSON says/O ./O 
``/O The/O party/O controls/O every/O single/O aspect/O of/O the/O depiction/O of/O history/O in/O the/O media/O ./O 
This/O includes/O schoolbooks/O ,/O newspapers/O ,/O film/O ,/O radio/O and/O television/O ,/O literature/O and/O art/O --/O all/O media/O ./O ''/O 
Historians/O and/O journalists/O also/O conduct/O their/O own/O form/O of/O self-censorship/O ./O 
Especially/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O the/O state/O 's/O founder/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON ./O 
On/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION Online/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O milestones/O of/O the/O past/O 60/O years/O --/O including/O the/O so-called/O ``/O peaceful/O liberation/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION ''/O in/O 1951/O --/O have/O been/O listed/O but/O there/O is/O nothing/O about/O what/O happened/O on/O the/O domestic/O front/O until/O 1978/O --/O two/O years/O after/O Mao/PERSON 's/O death/O ./O 
Making/O ,/O not/O telling/O history/O Xiao/PERSON Yanzhong/PERSON from/O the/O Marxism/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Beijing/ORGANIZATION explains/O :/O ``/O History/O is/O not/O told/O here/O ,/O it/O is/O made/O ./O 
Anything/O that/O sheds/O a/O negative/O light/O on/O the/O government/O is/O left/O aside/O and/O everything/O positive/O is/O highlighted/O ./O 
Small/O things/O are/O turned/O into/O big/O events/O and/O other/O events/O are/O played/O down/O ./O ''/O 
A/O new/O film/O has/O been/O screened/O across/O the/O country/O for/O the/O past/O few/O days/O :/O ``/O The/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION of/O a/O Republic/O ''/O ./O 
The/O bombastic/O two-and-a-half-hour/O long/O drama/O depicts/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O the/O saviour/O of/O the/O Chinese/O people/O and/O Mao/PERSON Zedong/PERSON as/O a/O talented/O military/O strategist/O ./O 
It/O ends/O with/O the/O announcement/O of/O the/O People/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION on/O 1st/O October/O 1949/O ./O 
Critics/O say/O that/O the/O film/O serves/O only/O to/O idealise/O Mao/PERSON and/O the/O Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Nonetheless/O ,/O people/O are/O flocking/O to/O the/O cinemas/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Ruth/PERSON Kirchner/PERSON //O Anne/PERSON Thomas/PERSON Editor/PERSON :/O Thomas/PERSON Bärthlein/PERSON 
