Germany/LOCATION has/O resumed/O discussions/O with/O the/O US/LOCATION on/O the/O possibility/O of/O accommodating/O released/O Guantanamo/O detainees/O ./O 
The/O move/O comes/O as/O some/O other/O European/O nations/O have/O already/O opened/O their/O doors/O to/O former/O prisoners/O ./O 
According/O to/O an/O Interior/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O ,/O Berlin/LOCATION is/O talking/O to/O Washington/LOCATION about/O relocating/O suitable/O detainees/O after/O they/O get/O released/O from/O the/O US-owned/LOCATION Guantanamo/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION prison/LOCATION in/O Cuba/LOCATION ./O 
An/O unnamed/O Interior/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION official/O said/O on/O Saturday/O ,/O March/O 27/O ,/O that/O his/O ministry/O had/O ``/O opened/O talks/O anew/O with/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION on/O this/O matter/O ./O ''/O 
For/O some/O prisoners/O ,/O going/O home/O is/O not/O an/O option/O The/O discussions/O were/O taking/O place/O with/O the/O approval/O of/O the/O Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION and/O Chancellor/O Angela/PERSON Merkel/PERSON 's/O office/O ``/O on/O a/O case-by-case/O basis/O ,/O ''/O the/O official/O added/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O the/O German/O news/O magazine/O ``/O Der/ORGANIZATION Spiegel/ORGANIZATION ''/O reported/O that/O a/O delegation/O from/O Berlin/LOCATION recently/O visited/O Guantanamo/LOCATION to/O meet/O with/O several/O inmates/O ,/O including/O a/O Palestinian/O ,/O a/O Jordanian/O and/O a/O Syrian/O who/O are/O likely/O candidates/O for/O resettlement/O ./O 
Spiegel/PERSON said/O the/O delegation/O ,/O including/O police/O and/O immigration/O officials/O ,/O had/O interviewed/O the/O men/O to/O assess/O their/O suitability/O and/O any/O potential/O risks/O if/O they/O were/O to/O be/O taken/O in/O ./O 
Risk/O assessment/O Last/O year/O ,/O Germany/LOCATION had/O considered/O accepting/O prisoners/O but/O later/O backed/O off/O amid/O concerns/O that/O the/O men/O could/O prove/O dangerous/O ./O 
The/O Interior/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION said/O on/O Saturday/O that/O Berlin/LOCATION supported/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O efforts/O to/O close/O the/O prison/O camp/O and/O that/O this/O had/O been/O consistent/O German/O policy/O ./O 
Spiegel/ORGANIZATION said/O US/LOCATION special/O envoy/O Daniel/PERSON Fried/PERSON had/O had/O months/O of/O confidential/O talks/O last/O year/O with/O the/O Interior/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION ,/O culminating/O in/O the/O handing/O over/O of/O a/O list/O of/O nine/O candidates/O ./O 
Some/O of/O them/O have/O since/O found/O homes/O in/O other/O nations/O ./O 
The/O newspaper/O said/O the/O remaining/O candidates/O for/O resettlement/O included/O a/O Palestinian/O from/O the/O West/LOCATION Bank/LOCATION who/O was/O part/O of/O a/O conservative/O group/O of/O imams/O and/O had/O been/O arrested/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
A/O Jordanian/O who/O traveled/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O the/O summer/O of/O 2001/O was/O also/O on/O the/O list/O as/O was/O a/O Syrian/O ,/O who/O had/O been/O treated/O at/O a/O Kabul/LOCATION hospital/O at/O the/O end/O of/O 2001/O ,/O and/O was/O arrested/O shortly/O after/O his/O discharge/O ./O 
The/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION wants/O to/O release/O all/O three/O men/O ./O 
Prisoners/O who/O are/O no/O longer/O regarded/O as/O enemy/O combatants/O are/O eligible/O for/O release/O Missed/O deadline/O President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON 's/O administration/O has/O been/O reluctant/O to/O send/O some/O Guantanamo/LOCATION prisoners/O back/O to/O their/O home/O countries/O because/O they/O might/O suffer/O reprisal/O after/O being/O held/O in/O US/LOCATION custody/O ./O 
Obama/PERSON had/O pledged/O to/O close/O down/O the/O Guantanamo/LOCATION camp/O by/O January/O this/O year/O ,/O but/O some/O 200/O detainees/O continue/O to/O be/O held/O there/O as/O finding/O them/O new/O homes/O is/O proving/O difficult/O ./O 
European/O countries/O are/O divided/O over/O whether/O to/O accept/O freed/O Guantanamo/LOCATION detainees/O :/O while/O most/O appear/O reluctant/O ,/O some/O have/O openly/O expressed/O support/O ./O 
Last/O week/O ,/O two/O Chinese/O Uighur/O men/O who/O were/O released/O from/O the/O detention/O camp/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION arrived/O in/O Switzerland/LOCATION ./O 
In/O February/O ,/O the/O first/O of/O five/O inmates/O slated/O to/O be/O accepted/O by/O Spain/LOCATION arrived/O in/O Madrid/LOCATION ./O 
rb/dpa/AP/O Editor/O :/O Toma/PERSON Tasovac/PERSON 
