Two/O men/O have/O been/O found/O guilty/O of/O planning/O a/O bomb/O attack/O against/O a/O Danish/O newspaper/O that/O published/O cartoons/O depicting/O the/O Prophet/PERSON Muhammad/PERSON ./O 
The/O court/O heard/O that/O they/O plotted/O to/O explode/O a/O bomb/O in/O liaison/O with/O al/O Qaeda/O ./O 
A/O court/O in/O Oslo/LOCATION on/O Monday/O found/O two/O defendants/O guilty/O of/O hatching/O a/O bomb/O plot/O against/O the/O offices/O of/O a/O newspaper/O that/O published/O controversial/O cartoons/O depicting/O the/O Prophet/O Muhammad/PERSON ./O 
Norwegian/O national/O Mikael/PERSON Davud/PERSON ,/O 40/O ,/O a/O member/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Muslim/O Uighur/O community/O ,/O was/O sentenced/O to/O seven/O year/O in/O prison/O ./O 
Shawan/PERSON Sadek/PERSON Bujak/PERSON ,/O 38/O ,/O an/O Iraqi/O Kurd/O living/O in/O Norway/LOCATION ,/O received/O a/O three-and-a-half-year/O term/O ./O 
The/O prosecution/O had/O asked/O for/O sentences/O of/O 11/O and/O five/O years/O respectively/O for/O the/O two/O men/O ,/O who/O had/O pleaded/O not/O guilty/O ,/O on/O the/O grounds/O that/O they/O had/O plotted/O the/O attack/O in/O liaison/O with/O al/O Qaeda/O ./O 
The/O court/O had/O heard/O that/O the/O men/O planned/O to/O use/O explosives/O at/O the/O offices/O of/O Danish/O daily/O newspaper/O Jyllands-Posten/LOCATION ./O 
The/O paper/O had/O caused/O offense/O across/O the/O Muslim/O world/O with/O a/O series/O of/O 12/O cartoon/O drawings/O of/O the/O Muslim/O prophet/O in/O September/O 2005/O ./O 
Prosecutors/O said/O the/O men/O had/O later/O planned/O to/O murder/O Kurt/PERSON Westergaard/PERSON ,/O the/O artist/O responsible/O for/O the/O most/O controversial/O of/O the/O drawings/O ./O 
Accomplice/O is/O released/O A/O third/O man/O ,/O from/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION ,/O was/O acquitted/O of/O the/O most/O serious/O charges/O ./O 
David/PERSON Jakobsen/PERSON was/O sentenced/O to/O four/O months/O behind/O bars/O for/O helping/O the/O two/O other/O men/O to/O obtain/O materials/O for/O their/O plot/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O 33-year-old/O was/O freed/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O time/O served/O on/O remand/O ./O 
David/PERSON had/O confessed/O to/O planning/O an/O attack/O against/O Chinese/O interests/O in/O Norway/LOCATION ,/O but/O not/O against/O the/O Danish/O newspaper/O ./O 
He/O said/O the/O idea/O had/O been/O his/O own/O and/O that/O he/O had/O tried/O to/O manipulate/O both/O Bujak/PERSON and/O Jakobsen/PERSON ./O 
All/O three/O men/O were/O arrested/O in/O July/O 2010/O after/O Norwegian/O security/O services/O uncovered/O a/O plot/O to/O make/O bombs/O using/O hydrogen/O peroxide-based/O chemicals/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Richard/PERSON Connor/PERSON -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O Editor/O :/O Andrew/PERSON Bowen/PERSON 
