China/LOCATION 's/O parliamentary/O session/O closed/O with/O the/O prime/O minister/O calling/O for/O political/O and/O economic/O reforms/O ./O 
Experts/O doubt/O ,/O however/O ,/O that/O there/O will/O be/O much/O change/O in/O the/O run-up/O to/O the/O 18th/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O fall/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O growth/O was/O high/O on/O the/O agenda/O at/O this/O year/O 's/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
In/O his/O closing/O speech/O ,/O Premier/O Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON said/O on/O Wednesday/O that/O the/O country/O must/O embrace/O slower/O growth/O and/O bolder/O political/O reforms/O to/O keep/O its/O economy/O from/O faltering/O ,/O while/O spreading/O wealth/O more/O evenly/O ./O 
He/O had/O opened/O the/O parliamentary/O session/O on/O March/O 5/O by/O announcing/O a/O growth/O target/O of/O 7.5/O percent/O for/O this/O year/O compared/O to/O the/O 8/O percent/O that/O has/O been/O the/O goal/O for/O the/O past/O eight/O years/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O belief/O earlier/O that/O if/O growth/O were/O lower/O ,/O there/O would/O not/O be/O enough/O jobs/O created/O to/O preserve/O social/O stability/O ./O 
But/O the/O economy/O has/O continued/O to/O boom/O ./O 
Gu/PERSON Xuewu/PERSON from/O the/O Center/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Global/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION in/O Bonn/LOCATION says/O that/O the/O lucky/O ``/O Eight/O ''/O is/O being/O dropped/O ``/O to/O reduce/O overcapacities/O and/O optimize/O economic/O structures/O ,/O which/O are/O China/LOCATION 's/O most/O urgent/O challenges/O ./O ''/O 
``/O Eight/O percent/O growth/O is/O not/O needed/O at/O all/O to/O master/O the/O social/O challenges/O and/O create/O jobs/O ,/O ''/O he/O insists/O ./O 
What/O is/O important/O is/O the/O quality/O of/O growth/O and/O its/O sustainability/O ./O 
Hong-Kong/O based/O political/O commentator/O Willy/PERSON Lam/PERSON says/O that/O the/O lower/O target/O is/O ``/O realistic/O ''/O considering/O unfavorable/O economic/O growth/O in/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O which/O has/O led/O to/O a/O drop/O in/O Chinese/O exports/O ./O 
He/O also/O says/O that/O the/O state/O investment/O programs/O that/O have/O driven/O much/O of/O the/O growth/O since/O the/O 2008/O finance/O crisis/O are/O not/O ``/O a/O long-term/O solution/O ./O ''/O 
Beijing/LOCATION wants/O to/O boost/O domestic/O demand/O now/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O defense/O budget/O has/O been/O increased/O by/O 11.2/O percent/O for/O 2012/O ./O 
Analysts/O say/O China/LOCATION wants/O to/O expand/O its/O influence/O in/O Asia/LOCATION and/O to/O rival/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O 
``/O This/O is/O also/O true/O for/O military/O matters/O ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION has/O had/O to/O decrease/O its/O military/O expenditure/O because/O of/O its/O financial/O problems/O ./O 
This/O gives/O China/LOCATION a/O chance/O to/O catch/O up/O -/O especially/O regarding/O the/O navy/O and/O the/O air/O force/O ./O ''/O 
Lam/PERSON is/O worried/O about/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O budget/O for/O ``/O preserving/O the/O country/O 's/O stability/O ,/O namely/O for/O the/O police/O and/O security/O forces/O ,/O has/O been/O increased/O ./O 
He/O explains/O that/O 120,000/O protests/O and/O riots/O are/O registered/O in/O China/LOCATION every/O year/O -/O 300/O a/O day/O ./O 
He/O says/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O boosting/O its/O police/O apparatus/O to/O keep/O the/O situation/O under/O control/O ./O 
In/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O populated/O largely/O by/O Uighurs/O ,/O the/O situation/O is/O particularly/O tense/O ./O 
However/O ,/O this/O year/O 's/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION has/O not/O revised/O minority/O policies/O as/O some/O intellectuals/O had/O called/O for/O ./O 
Gu/PERSON Xuewu/PERSON points/O out/O that/O it/O is/O not/O so/O easy/O to/O solve/O these/O problems/O but/O if/O there/O are/O no/O attempts/O to/O introduce/O reforms/O the/O resentment/O will/O only/O grow/O ./O 
``/O At/O some/O point/O the/O disruption/O could/O be/O so/O great/O that/O the/O current/O system/O can/O not/O cope/O ./O 
The/O system/O is/O not/O as/O strong/O as/O it/O seems/O ./O ''/O 
It/O does/O not/O look/O as/O if/O the/O bold/O reforms/O that/O many/O have/O called/O for/O will/O be/O implemented/O however/O ./O 
Analysts/O do/O not/O expect/O many/O significant/O changes/O over/O the/O next/O months/O despite/O Wen/PERSON 's/O insistence/O he/O wants/O to/O drive/O forward/O reforms/O during/O his/O last/O year/O in/O office/O ./O 
The/O Hong-Kong/O based/O journalist/O Bao/PERSON Pu/PERSON says/O the/O past/O decade/O has/O been/O ``/O lost/O ./O ''/O 
``/O There/O have/O been/O no/O real/O reforms/O -/O only/O of/O the/O bureaucratic/O machine/O ,/O but/O not/O of/O the/O governmental/O system/O as/O a/O whole/O ./O ''/O 
In/O any/O case/O ,/O important/O decisions/O are/O not/O made/O by/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
All/O eyes/O are/O set/O on/O the/O 18th/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION later/O this/O year/O ./O 
Wen/PERSON Jiabao/PERSON and/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON are/O due/O to/O hand/O over/O power/O to/O their/O successors/O ,/O as/O are/O seven/O other/O members/O of/O the/O Politburo/ORGANIZATION Standing/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O fight/O for/O these/O positions/O is/O going/O on/O behind/O the/O scenes/O and/O is/O particularly/O heated/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Haiye/PERSON Cao/PERSON //O act/O Editor/O :/O Gregg/PERSON Benzow/PERSON 
