What/O kind/O of/O rock/O music/O is/O China/LOCATION making/O ,/O and/O what/O do/O hip-hop/O and/O old/O English/O dance/O styles/O have/O in/O common/O ?/O 
The/O 22nd/O edition/O of/O the/O TFF/O Rudolstadt/O festival/O had/O some/O answers/O -/O and/O much/O more/O ./O 
Joy/O ./O 
./O 
,/O devoting/O it/O to/O their/O colleague/O ./O 
nd/O -LRB-/O TFF/O Rudolstadt/O -RRB-/O ,/O which/O There/O are/O probably/O two/O and/O ,/O ./O 
Gong/PERSON Linna/PERSON also/O took/O part/O in/O an/O orchestral/O Even/O for/O are/O countless/O and/O play/O along/O ./O 
s/O ,/O percussion/O s/O street/O music/O Ruth/PERSON name/O of/O the/O presented/O ,/O at/O his/O age/O he/O prefers/O to/O write/O songs/O about/O death/O or/O women/O than/O about/O current/O political/O affairs/O ./O 
,/O ,/O -/O filled/O with/O backing/O from/O wind/O players/O ./O 
There/O are/O very/O few/O big/O names/O in/O Rudolstadt/O ,/O even/O among/O the/O prize-winners/O ,/O but/O the/O festival/O does/O n't/O live/O from/O star/O power/O ./O 
There/O are/O ,/O however/O ,/O a/O few/O exceptions/O in/O each/O year/O 's/O program/O ,/O like/O German/O reggae/O superstar/O Gentleman/O or/O American/O singer-songwriter/O Alison/PERSON Krauss/PERSON in/O 2012/O ./O 
The/O draw/O of/O Rudolstadt/O lies/O much/O more/O in/O the/O discovery/O of/O the/O new/O ,/O and/O in/O being/O part/O of/O a/O spring-up/O community/O that/O is/O singular/O in/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O festival/O season/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Matthias/PERSON Klaus/PERSON //O gsw/O Editor/O :/O Kate/PERSON Bowen/PERSON 
