The/O Syrian/O conflict/O has/O shifted/O allegiances/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION and/O forced/O members/O of/O the/O international/O community/O to/O take/O a/O stance/O ./O 
DW/O takes/O a/O close/O look/O at/O Syria/LOCATION 's/O friends/O and/O foes/O around/O the/O world/O ./O 
Bordering/O Lebanon/LOCATION ,/O Israel/LOCATION ,/O Jordan/LOCATION ,/O Turkey/LOCATION and/O Iraq/LOCATION ,/O Syria/LOCATION has/O a/O central/O geopolitical/O position/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
The/O region/O is/O of/O vital/O global/O importance/O for/O religious/O ,/O political/O and/O economic/O reasons/O ./O 
It/O is/O where/O the/O world/O 's/O three/O great/O monotheistic/O religions/O originated/O ,/O is/O a/O bridge/O between/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O Asia/LOCATION and/O Africa/LOCATION ,/O and/O has/O the/O largest/O fossil/O fuel/O reserves/O in/O the/O world/O ./O 
Many/O global/O trade/O routes/O converge/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O home/O of/O the/O Suez/LOCATION Canal/LOCATION ./O 
Under/O President/O Bashar/PERSON Assad/PERSON ,/O Syria/LOCATION has/O tried/O to/O stake/O out/O a/O position/O of/O leadership/O in/O the/O Arab/O world/O ./O 
The/O country/O saw/O itself/O leading/O efforts/O against/O the/O alleged/O ``/O colonial/O ''/O politics/O of/O the/O west/O ,/O especially/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O Israel/LOCATION ./O 
Assad/PERSON 's/O alliances/O with/O neighboring/O countries/O have/O made/O the/O Syrian/O uprising/O that/O started/O in/O spring/O 2011/O a/O problem/O for/O the/O region/O and/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O world/O ./O 
Syria/LOCATION is/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O only/O ally/O among/O the/O Arab/O nations/O ./O 
Religious/O ties/O underpin/O the/O relationship/O ./O 
The/O Assad/PERSON family/O belongs/O to/O the/O Alawite/O sect/O ,/O which/O is/O closely/O related/O to/O the/O Shiite/O branch/O of/O Islam/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O Shiites/O have/O their/O political/O and/O religious/O center/O in/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
There/O are/O also/O political/O considerations/O ./O 
Syria/LOCATION ,/O Iran/LOCATION and/O Lebanon/LOCATION form/O the/O so-called/O Shiite/O axis/O that/O works/O together/O against/O Israel/LOCATION ./O 
Lebanon/LOCATION is/O home/O to/O the/O militant/O Hezbollah/ORGANIZATION group/O ,/O which/O receives/O logistics/O support/O and/O weapons/O from/O Iran/LOCATION in/O the/O group/O 's/O fight/O against/O Israel/LOCATION ./O 
A/O change/O of/O government/O in/O Syria/LOCATION stands/O to/O alter/O the/O Shiite/O axis/O ./O 
With/O Assad/PERSON 's/O fall/O ,/O Iran/LOCATION would/O lose/O its/O most/O important/O ally/O ./O 
As/O the/O country/O where/O Islam/ORGANIZATION was/O born/O ,/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION is/O the/O center/O of/O the/O conservative/O Sunni/O denomination/O ./O 
In/O terms/O of/O religion/O ,/O it/O is/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O biggest/O rival/O ./O 
Both/O countries/O compete/O over/O political/O dominance/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION is/O also/O concerned/O about/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O nuclear/O ambitions/O ./O 
Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION stands/O to/O move/O even/O closer/O to/O its/O longtime/O ally/O the/O US/LOCATION in/O light/O of/O their/O common/O stance/O against/O Assad/PERSON ./O 
Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION has/O taken/O the/O lead/O among/O Arab/O countries/O calling/O for/O democracy/O and/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
But/O at/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION has/O helped/O neighboring/O Bahrain/LOCATION brutally/O suppress/O Shiite/O protests/O against/O the/O Sunni/O leadership/O there/O ./O 
Protests/O within/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION are/O also/O met/O with/O force/O ./O 
According/O to/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION ,/O serious/O human/O rights/O violations/O are/O an/O everyday/O occurrence/O ./O 
Dedication/O to/O freedom/O and/O democracy/O is/O not/O necessarily/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION 's/O true/O objective/O in/O supporting/O Syria/LOCATION 's/O opposition/O ./O 
Qatar/LOCATION is/O another/O close/O ally/O of/O the/O US/LOCATION ./O 
Just/O like/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ,/O it/O is/O worried/O that/O Iran/LOCATION could/O become/O too/O powerful/O ./O 
Critics/O have/O accused/O Qatar-based/O Al/ORGANIZATION Jazeera/ORGANIZATION of/O bias/O in/O its/O Arabic-language/O coverage/O of/O the/O Syrian/O crisis/O ./O 
The/O influential/O broadcaster/O is/O owned/O by/O the/O emir/O of/O Qatar/LOCATION ./O 
After/O the/O US/LOCATION invasion/O of/O Iraq/LOCATION in/O 2006/O ,/O Shiite/PERSON Nuri/PERSON Maliki/PERSON became/O the/O country/O 's/O prime/O minister/O ./O 
Maliki/PERSON spent/O his/O exile/O during/O the/O reign/O of/O deposed/O dictator/O Saddam/PERSON Hussein/PERSON in/O exile/O in/O Iran/LOCATION and/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
He/O has/O maintained/O his/O ties/O with/O the/O Assad/PERSON regime/O ./O 
About/O 60/O percent/O of/O Iraqis/O are/O Shiites/O ,/O making/O the/O country/O close/O with/O both/O Iran/LOCATION and/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
Baghdad/LOCATION sees/O them/O as/O allies/O against/O Sunni/O insurgents/O in/O Iraq/LOCATION ./O 
Developments/O in/O Syria/LOCATION have/O strongly/O affected/O its/O little/O neighbor/O Lebanon/LOCATION ./O 
Damascus/LOCATION actually/O sees/O Lebanon/LOCATION as/O an/O artificial/O construct/O that/O should/O become/O part/O of/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Lebanese/O civil/O war/O saw/O Syrian/O troops/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
Syrian/O forces/O stayed/O there/O even/O after/O the/O conflict/O ended/O ./O 
It/O was/O not/O until/O the/O murder/O of/O Lebanese/O Prime/O Minister/O Rafik/PERSON Hariri/PERSON -/O which/O was/O blamed/O on/O Damascus/LOCATION -/O that/O massive/O anti-Syrian/O protests/O led/O to/O a/O withdrawal/O of/O the/O troops/O ./O 
Hezbollah/ORGANIZATION is/O a/O strong/O Assad/PERSON ally/O ,/O with/O members/O of/O the/O militant/O group/O reportedly/O joining/O the/O fight/O against/O Syrian/O rebels/O ./O 
Northern/O Lebanon/LOCATION is/O a/O major/O conduit/O for/O arms/O going/O into/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O Lebanon/LOCATION 's/O Sunnis/O are/O lending/O support/O to/O Assad/PERSON 's/O opponents/O ./O 
The/O Syrian/O conflict/O has/O already/O sparked/O fighting/O between/O the/O two/O factions/O within/O Lebanon/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Lebanese/O government/O is/O trying/O to/O stay/O out/O of/O the/O Syria/LOCATION conflict/O ./O 
But/O it/O has/O to/O reckon/O with/O Hezbollah/ORGANIZATION 's/O representation/O in/O parliament/O ,/O among/O other/O factors/O ./O 
Israel/LOCATION has/O a/O twofold/O relationship/O with/O the/O Assad/PERSON regime/O ./O 
On/O the/O one/O hand/O ,/O Syria/LOCATION has/O been/O a/O reliable/O and/O predictable/O neighbor/O ./O 
Despite/O anti-Israeli/O sentiment/O in/O Damascus/LOCATION ,/O the/O Golan/LOCATION Heights/LOCATION border/O has/O remained/O calm/O ./O 
On/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O Syria/LOCATION has/O maintained/O close/O ties/O with/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O Israel/LOCATION 's/O biggest/O enemy/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
Assad/PERSON 's/O fall/O would/O present/O mixed/O possibilities/O for/O Israel/LOCATION ./O 
If/O he/O loses/O power/O ,/O a/O new/O Syrian/O regime/O could/O take/O a/O much/O more/O aggressive/O approach/O to/O Israel/LOCATION ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O Assad/PERSON 's/O ouster/O could/O weaken/O Iran/LOCATION and/O make/O Israel/LOCATION more/O secure/O ./O 
In/O recent/O years/O ,/O Turkey/LOCATION has/O worked/O to/O become/O a/O leader/O in/O its/O region/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Turkey/LOCATION is/O concerned/O about/O Syrian/O Kurds/O ,/O who/O have/O discussed/O forming/O an/O autonomous/O region/O since/O the/O beginning/O of/O the/O uprising/O ./O 
That/O could/O inspire/O Kurds/O in/O Turkey/LOCATION to/O step/O up/O their/O fight/O against/O Ankara/LOCATION ./O 
Turkey/LOCATION is/O also/O worried/O that/O Assad/PERSON 's/O fall/O could/O lead/O to/O armed/O conflict/O between/O Syria/LOCATION 's/O various/O opposition/O groups/O ./O 
A/O continued/O struggle/O could/O throw/O the/O entire/O region/O into/O turmoil/O ./O 
US/LOCATION military/O and/O economic/O strength/O has/O been/O greatly/O weakened/O by/O the/O wars/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Iraq/LOCATION ./O 
But/O Assad/PERSON 's/O fall/O would/O remove/O one/O of/O Washington/LOCATION 's/O biggest/O enemies/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION is/O backing/O the/O rebels/O in/O hopes/O of/O seeing/O a/O friendly/O Syrian/O government/O in/O the/O future/O ./O 
Washington/LOCATION is/O not/O supplying/O them/O weapons/O ,/O but/O is/O likely/O sending/O communications/O and/O other/O equipment/O through/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
Washington/LOCATION is/O also/O trying/O to/O limit/O Shiite/O influence/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O as/O the/O US/LOCATION generally/O has/O better/O relations/O with/O Sunnis/O ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION also/O has/O Israel/LOCATION 's/O interests/O in/O mind/O and/O hopes/O that/O Assad/PERSON 's/O ouster/O will/O weaken/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
So/O far/O ,/O Russia/LOCATION has/O vetoed/O every/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION resolution/O against/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
Russia/LOCATION has/O been/O an/O ally/O of/O Syria/LOCATION since/O the/O Soviet/O era/O ./O 
Damascus/LOCATION is/O Moscow/LOCATION 's/O last/O remaining/O ally/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
Working/O through/O Syria/LOCATION is/O the/O only/O way/O Russia/LOCATION can/O still/O try/O to/O influence/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Syrian/O port/O city/O of/O Tartus/LOCATION also/O hosts/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O only/O military/O port/O on/O the/O Mediterranean/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ./O 
Further/O ,/O Damascus/LOCATION is/O an/O important/O customer/O for/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O weapons/O industry/O ./O 
Russian/O energy/O companies/O also/O do/O business/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
Russia/LOCATION is/O also/O concerned/O about/O its/O standing/O in/O the/O Arab/O world/O ./O 
If/O Russia/LOCATION gives/O politicians/O in/O the/O region/O the/O impression/O that/O Russia/LOCATION will/O not/O aid/O its/O allies/O ,/O there/O will/O be/O little/O incentive/O to/O be/O on/O good/O terms/O with/O Moscow/LOCATION ./O 
Another/O reason/O for/O Russia/LOCATION support/O of/O Syria/LOCATION is/O Moscow/LOCATION 's/O fear/O that/O radical/O Islamists/O would/O dominate/O a/O post-Assad/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O pursued/O a/O course/O of/O economic/O expansion/O for/O years/O ./O 
It/O has/O been/O looking/O for/O ways/O to/O quench/O its/O thirst/O for/O resources/O ,/O including/O oil/O ,/O all/O over/O the/O world/O ./O 
That/O 's/O why/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O trying/O to/O increase/O its/O influence/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O strongest/O ties/O are/O with/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
But/O like/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION is/O banking/O that/O Assad/PERSON will/O stay/O in/O power/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O has/O justified/O its/O veto/O in/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION by/O saying/O it/O respects/O Syria/LOCATION 's/O right/O to/O handle/O its/O affairs/O without/O outside/O intervention/O ./O 
That/O 's/O a/O right/O China/LOCATION has/O striven/O to/O claim/O for/O itself/O in/O the/O cases/O of/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
If/O the/O Chinese/O government/O backed/O intervention/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ,/O it/O would/O likely/O face/O more/O criticism/O for/O its/O own/O policies/O back/O home/O ./O 
EU/ORGANIZATION member/O countries/O have/O maintained/O rather/O discrete/O ties/O with/O the/O Assad/PERSON regime/O over/O the/O years/O ./O 
The/O Syrian/O leadership/O tried/O to/O appear/O distant/O from/O the/O west/O ,/O but/O kept/O up/O pragmatic/O ,/O economic/O relations/O with/O the/O EU/LOCATION ./O 
Brussels/LOCATION also/O backed/O many/O civil/O society/O projects/O in/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
In/O light/O of/O the/O past/O year/O and/O a/O half/O of/O violence/O ,/O though/O ,/O EU/LOCATION member/O states/O have/O clearly/O distanced/O themselves/O from/O Damascus/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Assad/PERSON regime/O is/O no/O longer/O a/O viable/O candidate/O for/O European/O partnership/O ./O 
Author/O :/O Kersten/PERSON Knipp/PERSON //O ai/O Editor/O :/O Shant/PERSON Shahrigian/PERSON 
