More/O than/O two/O dozen/O people/O have/O died/O in/O clashes/O with/O police/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ./O 
The/O riots/O are/O the/O deadliest/O since/O the/O 2009/O clashes/O between/O Muslims/O and/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O population/O there/O ./O 
Clashes/O between/O armed/O gangs/O and/O police/O erupted/O Wednesday/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O far/O western/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ,/O home/O to/O a/O large/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION minority/O ,/O leaving/O 27/O dead/O ,/O the/O government/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION reported/O ./O 
The/O reasons/O for/O the/O attacks/O were/O not/O immediately/O clear/O ./O 
The/O agency/O said/O the/O unrest/O erupted/O at/O about/O 6/O a.m./O in/O the/O remote/O township/O of/O Lukqun/LOCATION ,/O about/O 200/O km/O -LRB-/O 120/O miles/O -RRB-/O southeast/O of/O the/O region/O 's/O capital/O Urumqi/LOCATION ./O 
Knife-wielding/O gangs/O reportedly/O attacked/O the/O township/O 's/O police/O stations/O ,/O and/O a/O local/O government/O building/O and/O set/O fire/O to/O several/O police/O vehicles/O ,/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION reported/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION officials/O as/O saying/O ./O 
At/O least/O nine/O policemen/O were/O killed/O along/O with/O eight/O civilians/O before/O police/O shot/O dead/O 10/O of/O the/O rioters/O ,/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION reported/O ./O 
The/O Muslim/O Uighur/O minority/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O who/O speak/O a/O Turkic/O language/O ,/O claim/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O put/O restrictions/O on/O their/O culture/O ,/O language/O and/O religion/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION says/O it/O grants/O Uighurs/O wide-ranging/O freedoms/O and/O accuses/O extremists/O of/O separatism/O ./O 
The/O clashes/O are/O the/O deadliest/O since/O July/O 2009/O ,/O when/O almost/O 200/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O riots/O between/O Uighurs/O and/O ethnic/O Chinese/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ./O 
hc/rg/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 
