China/LOCATION is/O considering/O cutting/O nine/O crimes/O from/O a/O list/O of/O 55/O offenses/O punishable/O by/O death/O ./O 
Rights/O groups/O estimate/O China/LOCATION puts/O more/O people/O to/O death/O than/O any/O other/O country/O ,/O although/O the/O number/O of/O executions/O is/O a/O state/O secret/O ./O 
The/O ruling/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION 's/O state/O parliament/O on/O Monday/O heard/O a/O proposal/O recommending/O lighter/O sentences/O for/O crimes/O such/O as/O smuggling/O weapons/O ,/O organizing/O prostitution/O and/O counterfeiting/O currencies/O ,/O the/O official/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION state/O news/O agency/O said/O ./O 
The/O draft/O amendment/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O criminal/O law/O is/O part/O of/O a/O review/O aimed/O to/O reform/O the/O country/O 's/O legal/O system/O ,/O and/O needs/O to/O be/O approved/O by/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O order/O to/O become/O legislation/O ./O 
Crimes/O that/O would/O be/O exempt/O from/O capital/O punishment/O under/O the/O amendment/O include/O arms/O smuggling/O ,/O fraudulent/O fund/O raising/O ,/O ``/O counterfeiting/O currencies/O .../O and/O arranging/O for/O or/O forcing/O another/O person/O to/O engage/O in/O prostitution/O ,/O ''/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION reported/O ./O 
The/O crimes/O of/O ``/O obstructing/O a/O commander/O or/O a/O person/O on/O duty/O from/O performing/O his/O duties/O ''/O and/O ``/O fabricating/O rumors/O to/O mislead/O others/O during/O wartime/O ''/O are/O also/O on/O the/O list/O ,/O the/O news/O agency/O said/O ./O 
The/O proposal/O recommended/O the/O maximum/O penalty/O for/O such/O offences/O be/O reduced/O to/O life/O in/O prison/O ./O 
A/O review/O in/O 2011/O that/O led/O to/O the/O death/O penalty/O for/O 13/O other/O crimes/O being/O scrapped/O had/O caused/O no/O ``/O negative/O effects/O for/O public/O security/O ,/O ''/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION quoted/O a/O government/O legal/O official/O ,/O Li/PERSON Shishi/PERSON ,/O as/O saying/O ./O 
The/O 55/O offences/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O including/O drug/O trafficking/O ,/O serious/O corruption/O and/O other/O non-violent/O crimes/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION keeps/O the/O number/O of/O executions/O a/O state/O secret/O ,/O but/O human/O rights/O groups/O estimate/O China/LOCATION kills/O more/O people/O than/O any/O other/O country/O ./O 
A/O recent/O report/O released/O by/O US-based/O human/O rights/O organization/O ,/O the/O Dui/ORGANIZATION Hua/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O China/LOCATION had/O ,/O and/O said/O it/O was/O likely/O to/O reach/O similar/O totals/O this/O year/O ./O 
The/O group/O said/O there/O had/O been/O a/O steady/O decline/O in/O executions/O since/O 2002/O ,/O when/O an/O estimated/O 12,000/O people/O were/O put/O to/O death/O ,/O but/O added/O this/O was/O likely/O to/O be/O ``/O offset/O ''/O this/O year/O ,/O amid/O a/O countrywide/O anti-corruption/O campaign/O and/O a/O in/O the/O largely/O Muslim/O northwestern/O province/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
In/O 2007/O ,/O it/O became/O mandatory/O for/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O review/O all/O death/O sentences/O -/O a/O move/O that/O has/O contributed/O to/O ``/O far/O fewer/O ''/O executions/O ,/O according/O to/O Dui/PERSON Hua/PERSON ./O 
In/O examining/O cases/O in/O 2013/O ,/O the/O top/O court/O sent/O around/O 39/O percent/O of/O death/O sentences/O back/O to/O provincial/O courts/O with/O a/O request/O for/O further/O evidence/O ,/O the/O group/O said/O ./O 
nm/mz/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O dpa/O -RRB-/O 
