It/O is/O still/O not/O clear/O who/O is/O responsible/O for/O the/O bloody/O attack/O at/O Kunming/LOCATION 's/O train/O station/O ./O 
But/O the/O tragedy/O shows/O that/O China/LOCATION 's/O policies/O on/O minorities/O needs/O an/O overhaul/O ,/O writes/O DW/O 's/O Matthias/PERSON von/PERSON Hein/PERSON ./O 
Until/O now/O ,/O Kunming/LOCATION has/O been/O known/O as/O ``/O the/O City/O of/O Eternal/O Spring/O ./O ''/O 
But/O after/O Saturday/O evening/O ,/O the/O capital/O of/O the/O southeastern/O province/O of/O Yunnan/LOCATION will/O be/O better/O known/O as/O the/O site/O of/O the/O bloodiest/O terror/O attack/O in/O recent/O Chinese/O history/O ./O 
Attackers/O wielding/O knives/O ran/O amok/O at/O Kunming/LOCATION train/O station/O ,/O creating/O a/O bloodbath/O that/O left/O over/O 30/O people/O dead/O and/O over/O 140/O wounded/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O did/O n't/O hesitate/O to/O blame/O ``/O separatist/O terrorists/O ''/O from/O northwestern/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O for/O the/O violence/O ./O 
The/O region/O -/O which/O is/O over/O 2,000/O kilometers/O from/O Kunming/LOCATION -/O has/O been/O the/O scene/O of/O bloody/O conflicts/O between/O the/O native/O Uighurs/O ,/O a/O Muslim/O minority/O ,/O and/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O majority/O a/O number/O of/O times/O in/O the/O past/O years/O ./O 
Whoever/O carried/O out/O the/O terrorist/O attack/O should/O know/O :/O nothing/O could/O ever/O justify/O such/O a/O blind/O act/O of/O aggression/O against/O innocent/O passengers/O ./O 
The/O international/O community/O has/O rightly/O condemned/O the/O attack/O and/O the/O German/O government/O has/O expressed/O its/O sympathy/O for/O the/O victims/O ./O 
This/O terrorist/O attack/O was/O carried/O out/O at/O a/O politically/O sensitive/O time/O ,/O just/O days/O before/O around/O 3,000/O delegates/O are/O scheduled/O to/O meet/O for/O the/O yearly/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Usually/O security/O forces/O are/O particularly/O vigilant/O during/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION to/O prevent/O anything/O from/O disturbing/O the/O strictly/O choreographed/O demonstration/O of/O national/O unity/O and/O prescribed/O harmony/O ./O 
It/O would/O be/O helpful/O if/O the/O Chinese/O leadership/O and/O the/O handpicked/O delegates/O at/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION thought/O about/O whether/O the/O dissatisfaction/O of/O national/O minorities/O such/O as/O Xinjian/PERSON 's/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O ,/O or/O the/O Tibetans/O and/O Mongolians/O ,/O should/O always/O simply/O be/O suppressed/O ./O 
But/O such/O a/O change/O in/O official/O attitudes/O is/O unlikely/O ./O 
Just/O last/O week/O ,/O the/O detained/O Uighur/O scientist/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON was/O accused/O of/O fostering/O separatism/O -/O a/O charge/O that/O can/O carry/O the/O death/O penalty/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
In/O his/O push/O for/O equality/O between/O Han/O Chinese/O and/O Uighurs/O ,/O Tohti/PERSON has/O actually/O been/O a/O moderate/O voice/O ./O 
Arresting/O people/O like/O him/O will/O only/O drive/O others/O into/O the/O arms/O of/O extremists/O ./O 
Last/O year/O ,/O there/O was/O a/O brief/O glimmer/O of/O hope/O that/O the/O treatment/O of/O national/O minorities/O in/O China/LOCATION might/O change/O when/O the/O head/O of/O an/O influential/O Beijing/LOCATION think/O tank/O for/O religious/O and/O ethnic/O questions/O commented/O on/O Tibet/LOCATION in/O an/O interview/O with/O a/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION magazine/O ./O 
In/O the/O interview/O ,/O she/O concluded/O that/O the/O current/O policy/O of/O economic/O development/O paired/O with/O continuing/O political/O repression/O does/O n't/O work/O and/O would/O have/O to/O change/O ./O 
The/O same/O conclusion/O applies/O when/O it/O comes/O to/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
