Over/O 700,000/O Hong/O Kongers/O have/O cast/O their/O ballots/O in/O an/O unofficial/O referendum/O on/O democratic/O reform/O which/O Beijing/LOCATION calls/O a/O farce/O ./O 
Analyst/O Joseph/PERSON Cheng/PERSON tells/O DW/O Beijing/LOCATION fears/O the/O vote/O may/O set/O a/O precedent/O for/O other/O regions/O ./O 
More/O than/O 700,000/O people/O have/O voted/O in/O an/O unofficial/O electoral/O reform/O poll/O which/O allows/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION residents/O to/O choose/O between/O three/O options/O on/O how/O the/O elections/O for/O the/O post/O of/O the/O chief/O executive/O in/O 2017/O should/O be/O carried/O out/O -/O each/O of/O which/O would/O allow/O voters/O to/O choose/O candidates/O for/O the/O top/O job/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O promised/O direct/O elections/O in/O 2017/O ,/O but/O has/O ruled/O out/O allowing/O voters/O to/O choose/O which/O candidates/O can/O stand/O ./O 
Participation/O in/O the/O unofficial/O voting/O -/O which/O began/O on/O Friday/O and/O is/O set/O to/O last/O until/O June/O 29/O -/O has/O beaten/O all/O expectations/O despite/O a/O major/O cyberattack/O that/O the/O organizers/O ,/O the/O Occupy/O Central/O movement/O ,/O have/O blamed/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
A/O state-run/O Chinese/O newspaper/O reacted/O on/O Monday/O ,/O June/O 23/O ,/O by/O slamming/O the/O referendum/O as/O an/O ``/O illegal/O farce/O ''/O that/O was/O ``/O tinged/O with/O mincing/O ludicrousness/O ./O ''/O 
Joseph/PERSON Cheng/PERSON ,/O Chair/O Professor/O of/O Political/O Science/O at/O the/O City/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Hong/ORGANIZATION Kong/ORGANIZATION says/O in/O a/O DW/O interview/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION may/O well/O choose/O to/O ignore/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION -LRB-/O HK/LOCATION -RRB-/O people/O 's/O demand/O for/O democracy/O ,/O but/O adds/O that/O this/O would/O come/O at/O a/O price/O as/O it/O would/O be/O extremely/O difficult/O for/O the/O city/O 's/O future/O government/O to/O achieve/O effective/O governance/O of/O a/O polarized/O society/O ./O 
DW/O :/O What/O is/O the/O purpose/O of/O this/O referendum/O ?/O 
The/O referendum/O is/O a/O platform/O for/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION people/O to/O articulate/O their/O views/O on/O political/O reform/O ./O 
There/O is/O a/O distrust/O of/O the/O HK/LOCATION government/O as/O to/O its/O objectivity/O in/O accepting/O public/O opinion/O ./O 
The/O pro-democracy/O movement/O would/O like/O to/O use/O this/O platform/O to/O demonstrate/O Hong/LOCATION Konger/LOCATION 's/O support/O of/O a/O democratic/O electoral/O system/O for/O the/O election/O of/O the/O chief/O executive/O in/O 2017/O ./O 
``/O The/O symbolic/O effect/O of/O the/O poll/O is/O simply/O that/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION people/O want/O to/O articulate/O their/O views/O ,/O ''/O says/O Cheng/PERSON There/O is/O a/O real/O fear/O that/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O may/O well/O allow/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION people/O to/O enjoy/O universal/O suffrage/O ,/O but/O Beijing/LOCATION also/O likes/O to/O control/O the/O list/O of/O candidates/O ./O 
This/O is/O why/O Hong/LOCATION Kongers/LOCATION would/O like/O to/O exercise/O the/O right/O to/O a/O civic/O nomination/O ,/O or/O nomination/O by/O one/O percent/O of/O the/O electorate/O ,/O to/O ensure/O that/O the/O people/O will/O have/O a/O meaningful/O choice/O and/O the/O vote/O will/O be/O genuinely/O competitive/O ./O 
Why/O is/O the/O referendum/O unofficial/O ?/O 
Because/O the/O poll/O is/O organized/O by/O the/O civic/O group/O Occupy/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O are/O extremely/O sensitive/O to/O the/O idea/O of/O a/O referendum/O and/O very/O worried/O about/O such/O a/O vote/O being/O carried/O out/O in/O Taiwan/LOCATION ,/O which/O may/O lead/O to/O a/O declaration/O of/O independence/O ./O 
They/O are/O also/O sensitive/O that/O the/O idea/O of/O holding/O a/O referendum/O may/O have/O a/O certain/O impact/O on/O volatile/O regions/O on/O the/O mainland/O such/O as/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
This/O is/O why/O Beijing/LOCATION considers/O the/O idea/O to/O be/O very/O dangerous/O ./O 
Over/O 700,000/O Hong/O Kongers/O out/O of/O five/O million/O eligible/O voters/O have/O already/O cast/O their/O ballots/O ./O 
What/O is/O your/O view/O on/O the/O turnout/O ?/O 
It/O is/O an/O incredibly/O high/O turnout/O which/O has/O exceeded/O the/O expectations/O of/O the/O organizers/O who/O had/O set/O a/O minimum/O target/O of/O 100,000/O voters/O ./O 
Let/O 's/O keep/O in/O mind/O that/O ,/O before/O the/O voting/O ,/O the/O ``/O Occupy/O Central/O ''/O campaign/O had/O stated/O that/O a/O turnout/O of/O some/O 300,000/O voters/O would/O be/O ``/O quite/O satisfactory/O ./O ''/O 
Now/O the/O poll/O is/O on/O its/O way/O to/O surpass/O the/O 800,000/O mark/O by/O June/O 29/O ./O 
The/O symbolic/O effect/O is/O simply/O that/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION people/O want/O to/O articulate/O their/O views/O ,/O want/O to/O say/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O to/O the/O whole/O world/O that/O they/O want/O democracy/O ,/O a/O genuinely/O competitive/O and/O democratic/O electoral/O system/O ,/O and/O that/O they/O can/O not/O accept/O the/O kind/O of/O electoral/O proposal/O put/O forward/O by/O Chinese/O authorities/O ./O 
DW/O recommends/O Beijing/LOCATION `/O seeking/O to/O intimidate/O '/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION democrats/O Protests/O have/O erupted/O in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION after/O Beijing/LOCATION issued/O a/O white/O paper/O stating/O its/O ``/O comprehensive/O control/O ''/O over/O the/O territory/O ./O 
Scholar/O Perry/PERSON Link/PERSON tells/O DW/O the/O move/O shows/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O intent/O to/O further/O ``/O digest/O ''/O the/O city/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 12.06.2014/O -RRB-/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION unofficial/O referendum/O extended/O after/O online/O voting/O problem/O A/O referendum/O for/O local/O government/O voting/O reform/O has/O been/O extended/O after/O organizers/O reported/O difficulties/O with/O their/O online/O voting/O system/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION and/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION officials/O have/O called/O the/O vote/O illegal/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 22.06.2014/O -RRB-/O China/LOCATION 's/O anti-graft/O drive/O '/O a/O testament/O of/O Xi/O 's/O power/O '/O Over/O 1,000/O people/O have/O been/O marked/O as/O ``/O naked/O officials/O ''/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O suspected/O of/O funneling/O illicit/O gains/O to/O overseas/O relatives/O ./O 
Analyst/O Rebecca/PERSON Liao/PERSON says/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O resolved/O to/O block/O any/O escape/O route/O for/O corrupt/O officials/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 10.06.2014/O -RRB-/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION :/O A/O dangerous/O memory/O As/O the/O 25th/O anniversary/O of/O the/O crackdown/O on/O student-led/O protests/O in/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION approaches/O ,/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O stepped/O up/O efforts/O to/O silence/O dissent/O by/O detaining/O lawyers/O ,/O activists/O and/O journalists/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 19.05.2014/O -RRB-/O The/O turnout/O also/O indicates/O that/O the/O people/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION resent/O the/O pressure/O exerted/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Before/O the/O referendum/O ,/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Information/ORGANIZATION Office/ORGANIZATION issued/O a/O white/O paper/O on/O June/O 9/O emphasizing/O the/O one/O country/O model/O and/O stressing/O that/O whatever/O power/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION has/O ,/O it/O comes/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O the/O document/O failed/O to/O mention/O both/O the/O two/O systems/O model/O and/O the/O rights/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION people/O ./O 
The/O online/O voting/O system/O for/O the/O unofficial/O referendum/O has/O reportedly/O witnessed/O one/O of/O the/O largest/O denial-of-service/O attacks/O in/O history/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O South/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Morning/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION newspaper/O ,/O more/O than/O 40/O percent/O of/O the/O attacks/O against/O the/O website/O came/O from/O computers/O registered/O to/O mainland/O firms/O in/O HK/LOCATION ./O 
Who/O could/O be/O behind/O the/O attacks/O ?/O 
There/O are/O suspicions/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION supporters/O are/O behind/O the/O attack/O ,/O but/O there/O is/O no/O evidence/O ,/O so/O we/O can/O not/O determine/O which/O parties/O are/O engaging/O in/O this/O kind/O of/O attack/O ./O 
Pro-democracy/O activists/O worry/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION will/O backtrack/O on/O its/O promise/O of/O universal/O suffrage/O ./O 
What/O are/O their/O fears/O based/O on/O ?/O 
The/O kind/O of/O proposal/O offered/O by/O the/O pro-Beijing/O group/O provides/O us/O with/O an/O important/O hint/O as/O to/O what/O is/O in/O the/O mind/O of/O Chinese/O authorities/O ,/O namely/O :/O ``/O Universal/O suffrage/O ,/O yes/O !/O 
,/O but/O only/O from/O an/O approved/O list/O of/O candidates/O ./O ''/O 
There/O is/O also/O a/O strong/O suspicion/O that/O ,/O given/O the/O nature/O of/O the/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O it/O will/O not/O allow/O a/O scenario/O in/O which/O a/O pro-democracy/O candidate/O becomes/O elected/O chief/O executive/O ./O 
What/O impact/O could/O the/O outcome/O of/O the/O vote/O have/O on/O the/O city/O 's/O pro-democratic/O aspirations/O ?/O 
Obviously/O ,/O we/O do/O n't/O know/O as/O yet/O ,/O but/O the/O general/O suspicion/O remains/O that/O it/O is/O rather/O difficult/O to/O persuade/O Beijing/LOCATION at/O the/O moment/O ./O 
One/O can/O only/O hope/O that/O Chinese/O authorities/O realize/O the/O consequences/O of/O rejecting/O the/O clearly/O articulated/O demand/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kongers/LOCATION ./O 
It/O appears/O that/O if/O Beijing/LOCATION decides/O to/O deny/O democracy/O to/O Hong/LOCATION Kongers/LOCATION ,/O it/O may/O well/O be/O able/O to/O do/O so/O ,/O but/O then/O the/O HK/LOCATION government/O will/O lose/O legitimacy/O in/O the/O eyes/O of/O many/O of/O the/O city/O 's/O residents/O ,/O leading/O to/O a/O very/O polarized/O society/O ./O 
It/O will/O be/O extremely/O difficult/O for/O the/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION government/O to/O achieve/O effective/O governance/O under/O such/O conditions/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O policy/O towards/O Taiwan/LOCATION will/O also/O be/O bankrupt/O ./O 
So/O the/O general/O scenario/O is/O that/O if/O Beijing/LOCATION chooses/O to/O ignore/O this/O ,/O they/O may/O well/O be/O able/O to/O impose/O its/O system/O on/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O but/O then/O the/O price/O will/O be/O high/O ./O 
Cheng/PERSON :/O ``/O The/O high/O turnout/O also/O indicates/O that/O the/O people/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION resent/O the/O pressure/O exerted/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ''/O How/O would/O Beijing/LOCATION react/O to/O potential/O massive/O pro-democracy/O demonstrations/O at/O the/O heart/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ?/O 
The/O Occupy/O Central/O movement/O intends/O to/O hold/O a/O peaceful/O rally/O ,/O but/O obviously/O the/O idea/O is/O considered/O dangerous/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O it/O is/O likely/O that/O there/O will/O be/O a/O crackdown/O ./O 
This/O would/O be/O a/O very/O sad/O situation/O for/O the/O city/O and/O I/O believe/O all/O parties/O involved/O would/O lose/O from/O such/O a/O scenario/O ./O 
The/O problem/O is/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION could/O view/O the/O demonstrations/O as/O a/O challenge/O to/O its/O authority/O and/O fear/O that/O this/O may/O have/O an/O impact/O on/O other/O people/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O something/O which/O would/O be/O considered/O dangerous/O from/O an/O authoritarian/O regime/O 's/O perspective/O ./O 
Joseph/PERSON Cheng/PERSON is/O Chair/O Professor/O of/O political/O science/O at/O the/O City/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Hong/ORGANIZATION Kong/ORGANIZATION ./O 
He/O has/O been/O the/O founding/O editor/O of/O the/O Hong/ORGANIZATION Kong/ORGANIZATION Journal/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Social/ORGANIZATION Sciences/ORGANIZATION and/O The/O Journal/O of/O Comparative/O Asian/O Development/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O founding/O President/O of/O the/O Asian/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ./O 
