After/O the/O sentencing/O of/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON ,/O a/O moderate/O government/O critic/O ,/O to/O life/O in/O prison/O ,/O the/O conflicts/O in/O western/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O are/O likely/O to/O get/O worse/O ,/O says/O DW/O columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON ./O 
With/O this/O week/O 's/O sentencing/O of/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON ,/O an/O academic/O who/O has/O been/O campaigning/O for/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION minority/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O -/O but/O explicitly/O not/O for/O the/O western/O region/O 's/O independence/O -/O the/O Chinese/O justice/O system/O made/O the/O wrong/O decision/O at/O the/O wrong/O time/O ./O 
Tohti/PERSON ,/O 44/O ,/O ran/O the/O website/O Uighur/ORGANIZATION Online/ORGANIZATION ,/O on/O which/O he/O has/O been/O accused/O of/O inciting/O his/O Uighur/O compatriots/O to/O violence/O ./O 
The/O economics/O professor/O last/O taught/O at/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O Minzu/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION and/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O charges/O against/O him/O ,/O also/O organized/O and/O led/O separatist/O groups/O ./O 
As/O ``/O proof/O ,/O ''/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O produced/O writings/O published/O by/O Tohti/PERSON on/O his/O website/O ,/O along/O with/O teaching/O material/O with/O which/O he/O ,/O according/O to/O state/O news/O agency/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O ``/O bewitched/O and/O compelled/O ''/O young/O students/O to/O work/O for/O his/O website/O ./O 
He/O is/O also/O said/O to/O have/O ``/O built/O up/O a/O criminal/O syndicate/O ./O ''/O 
Seven/O students/O were/O arrested/O along/O with/O Tohti/PERSON as/O part/O of/O his/O ``/O separatist/O group/O ./O ''/O 
In/O a/O trial/O that/O lasted/O just/O two/O days/O ,/O the/O highest/O court/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O the/O capital/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O sentenced/O Tohti/PERSON to/O life/O imprisonment/O ./O 
Apart/O from/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O trial/O was/O not/O transparent/O even/O by/O Chinese/O standards/O ,/O this/O case/O again/O makes/O it/O clear/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O still/O far/O from/O a/O stable/O and/O comprehensive/O rule/O of/O law/O ./O 
Radicalization/O fears/O DW/O columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON The/O possible/O consequences/O of/O this/O decision/O -/O whether/O dictated/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION or/O not/O -/O must/O not/O be/O underestimated/O ./O 
The/O ruling/O will/O drive/O liberal/O Uighurs/O underground/O and/O radicalize/O them/O ./O 
The/O conflict/O in/O the/O country/O 's/O far/O west/O will/O not/O ease/O any/O time/O soon/O ./O 
The/O Xinjiang/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION 's/O dealings/O with/O Tohti/PERSON are/O further/O proof/O that/O its/O strategy/O is/O deterrence/O ,/O at/O any/O cost/O -/O even/O if/O it/O means/O ratcheting/O up/O the/O pressure/O ./O 
Any/O type/O of/O platform/O ,/O any/O kind/O of/O role/O model/O for/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O is/O immediately/O stifled/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O lesson/O that/O the/O hardliners/O in/O the/O Chinese/O government/O have/O learned/O from/O the/O success/O of/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
But/O they/O 're/O acting/O like/O a/O doctor/O who/O has/O injected/O morphine/O ,/O only/O to/O believe/O the/O illusion/O that/O the/O patient/O has/O been/O cured/O ./O 
More/O than/O ever/O ,/O Uighurs/O are/O feeling/O discriminated/O against/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O fear/O that/O their/O culture/O is/O being/O increasingly/O stifled/O by/O the/O Han/O Chinese/O ,/O who/O are/O moving/O to/O the/O region/O from/O the/O east/O ./O 
It/O 's/O hard/O to/O say/O exactly/O how/O many/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O are/O secretly/O in/O solidarity/O with/O the/O terrorists/O ,/O who/O want/O to/O use/O ever/O increasing/O attacks/O to/O force/O the/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O relent/O ./O 
Since/O the/O 2009/O uprising/O ,/O battle/O lines/O have/O hardened/O ./O 
A/O car/O bomb/O that/O exploded/O in/O October/O 2013/O atBeijing/O 's/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION has/O been/O attributed/O to/O the/O Uighurs/O ./O 
Bloody/O attacks/O have/O been/O directed/O not/O only/O against/O Chinese/O institutions/O ,/O but/O also/O more/O unpredictable/O targets/O -/O in/O recent/O months/O ,/O a/O train/O station/O in/O Kunming/LOCATION and/O a/O market/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ./O 
Potential/O gateway/O for/O international/O terrorism/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O preparing/O itself/O for/O attacks/O that/O are/O more/O frequent/O and/O ``/O professional/O ./O ''/O 
Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ,/O which/O shares/O a/O border/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O has/O become/O a/O potential/O gateway/O for/O international/O terror/O ./O 
Recently/O ,/O the/O terrorist/O organization/O ``/O Islamic/O State/O ''/O -LRB-/O ``/O IS/O ''/O -RRB-/O singled/O out/O China/LOCATION as/O one/O of/O Islam/ORGANIZATION 's/O greatest/O enemies/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION should/O do/O everything/O possible/O to/O ensure/O that/O the/O number/O of/O supporters/O of/O ``/O IS/O ''/O and/O other/O foreign/O terrorist/O groups/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION remains/O as/O small/O as/O possible/O ./O 
But/O much/O of/O what/O has/O happened/O in/O recent/O months/O appears/O to/O be/O counterproductive/O to/O this/O goal/O ./O 
The/O local/O population/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION has/O been/O called/O on/O to/O report/O suspicious/O neighbors/O with/O long/O beards/O to/O the/O authorities/O ,/O while/O Muslim/O officials/O were/O prohibited/O from/O fasting/O during/O Ramadan/O ./O 
No/O wonder/O that/O activists/O are/O now/O comparing/O Tohti/PERSON to/O South/O African/O leader/O Nelson/PERSON Mandela/PERSON ,/O who/O spent/O 27/O years/O in/O prison/O under/O the/O apartheid/O regime/O before/O becoming/O president/O in/O 1994/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION has/O also/O taken/O steps/O in/O the/O right/O direction/O :/O a/O new/O project/O will/O provide/O financial/O support/O to/O Han/O Chinese/O and/O Uighurs/O who/O share/O a/O house/O or/O marry/O ./O 
These/O are/O measures/O that/O will/O actually/O strengthen/O mutual/O understanding/O -/O unless/O roommates/O or/O spouses/O find/O themselves/O at/O odds/O over/O Tohti/PERSON 's/O sentence/O ./O 
DW/O columnist/O Frank/PERSON Sieren/PERSON has/O lived/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O the/O last/O 20/O years/O ./O 
