A/O Chinese/O court/O has/O rejected/O the/O appeal/O of/O prominent/O Uighur/O scholar/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON against/O his/O life/O sentence/O for/O ``/O separatism/O ./O ''/O 
This/O comes/O as/O journalist/O Gao/PERSON Yu/PERSON is/O tried/O on/O charges/O of/O leaking/O state/O secrets/O ./O 
A/O court/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O on/O Friday/O upheld/O a/O life/O sentence/O imposed/O on/O a/O well-known/O Uighur/O scholar/O who/O was/O convicted/O on/O charges/O of/O fomenting/O unrest/O and/O advocating/O separatism/O ./O 
The/O harsh/O verdict/O handed/O down/O in/O September/O to/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON ,/O 45/O ,/O was/O the/O most/O severe/O in/O decades/O to/O be/O pronounced/O against/O a/O goverment/O critic/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Tohti/PERSON ,/O an/O economics/O professor/O ,/O has/O repeatedly/O criticized/O the/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O its/O policies/O toward/O the/O Uighur/O minority/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O but/O he/O has/O always/O denied/O promoting/O violence/O or/O separatism/O ./O 
Hearing/O set/O at/O short/O notice/O His/O lawyers/O ,/O Liu/PERSON Xiaoyuan/PERSON and/O Li/PERSON Fangping/PERSON ,/O said/O the/O appeal/O hearing/O at/O a/O detention/O center/O in/O the/O regional/O capital/O ,/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O was/O a/O violation/O of/O normal/O judicial/O procedure/O ,/O and/O that/O the/O date/O was/O set/O at/O such/O short/O notice/O that/O neither/O of/O them/O was/O able/O to/O attend/O ./O 
Tohti/PERSON would/O appeal/O the/O ruling/O at/O the/O High/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION ,/O Li/PERSON said/O ,/O adding/O that/O his/O client/O had/O been/O kept/O in/O leg/O irons/O for/O almost/O two/O months/O ./O 
Li/PERSON also/O said/O that/O Tohti/PERSON would/O request/O that/O his/O place/O of/O detention/O be/O shifted/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O where/O his/O wife/O and/O children/O live/O ./O 
Xianjing/PERSON has/O been/O hit/O by/O a/O wave/O of/O violence/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION blames/O on/O separatist/O groups/O from/O among/O the/O mostly-Muslim/O Uighur/O minority/O ./O 
Rights/O groups/O say/O repressive/O government/O policies/O have/O fueled/O the/O unrest/O ,/O in/O which/O 200/O people/O have/O died/O this/O year/O alone/O ./O 
Crackdown/O on/O dissidence/O In/O a/O second/O case/O that/O underlines/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON 's/O ongoing/O campaign/O to/O silence/O government/O critics/O ,/O a/O Beijing/LOCATION court/O on/O Fridaybegan/O its/O trial/O of/O outspoken/O journalist/O Gao/PERSON Yu/PERSON ./O 
She/O is/O accused/O of/O providing/O state/O secrets/O to/O foreign/O contacts/O ./O 
Gao/PERSON Yu/PERSON 's/O lawyers/O say/O she/O confessed/O under/O duress/O The/O journalist/O ,/O who/O suffers/O from/O heart/O problems/O ,/O had/O to/O pause/O to/O take/O medicine/O several/O times/O during/O the/O four-hour/O hearing/O ,/O her/O lawyer/O Mo/PERSON Shaoping/PERSON told/O the/O news/O agency/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O 70-year-old/O Gao/PERSON has/O contributed/O to/O Deutsche/ORGANIZATION Welle/ORGANIZATION along/O with/O other/O foreign/O media/O outlets/O ,/O and/O is/O known/O for/O her/O articles/O criticizing/O government/O leaders/O ./O 
Gao/PERSON has/O already/O served/O a/O prison/O sentence/O in/O the/O 1990s/O ./O 
She/O was/O arrested/O in/O April/O this/O year/O on/O charges/O of/O having/O illegally/O obtained/O a/O Communist/O party/O document/O and/O handing/O it/O to/O an/O overseas/O website/O for/O publication/O ,/O according/O to/O previous/O official/O reports/O ./O 
The/O internal/O party/O communiqué/O reportedly/O called/O for/O a/O harsh/O crackdown/O on/O dissent/O and/O warning/O against/O Western-style/O democracy/O ./O 
`/O Frontal/O assault/O '/O on/O freedom/O Sophie/PERSON Richardson/PERSON ,/O China/LOCATION director/O of/O the/O US-based/O activist/O group/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION ,/O called/O Gao/PERSON 's/O case/O ``/O a/O frontal/O assault/O on/O the/O freedom/O of/O expression/O and/O access/O to/O information/O ,/O ''/O adding/O that/O Chinese/O laws/O on/O ``/O state/O secrets/O ''/O were/O being/O abused/O to/O silence/O political/O dissent/O ./O 
Since/O coming/O to/O power/O in/O 2012/O ,/O President/O Xi/O has/O overseen/O the/O detention/O or/O imprisonment/O of/O hundreds/O of/O government/O critics/O ./O 
Among/O them/O are/O promiinent/O legal/O expert/O Xu/PERSON Zhiyong/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O sentenced/O to/O four/O years/O '/O imprisonment/O in/O January/O ,/O and/O well-known/O human/O rights/O lawyer/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O not/O been/O released/O after/O being/O detained/O in/O May/O ./O 
tj/ipj/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 
