Courts/O in/O the/O Chinese/O region/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION have/O jailed/O 39/O people/O after/O a/O special/O operation/O to/O counter/O Uighur/O separatist/O terrorism/O ,/O say/O judicial/O sources/O ./O 
The/O offences/O included/O the/O spread/O of/O ``/O terrorism/O audios/O and/O videos/O ./O ''/O 
The/O Xinjiang/ORGANIZATION Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION on/O Wednesday/O said/O 39/O people/O had/O been/O sentenced/O to/O prison/O after/O they/O were/O convicted/O of/O crimes/O that/O included/O organizing/O and/O leading/O Uighur/O separatist/O terror/O groups/O ./O 
Other/O offences/O included/O inciting/O ethnic/O hatred/O ,/O both/O verbally/O and/O through/O the/O distribution/O of/O audio/O and/O video/O material/O ./O 
``/O Violent/O terrorism/O has/O become/O a/O major/O threat/O to/O ethnic/O unity/O and/O social/O stability/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O ''/O the/O court/O said/O in/O a/O statement/O ./O 
``/O We/O must/O eliminate/O from/O the/O root/O the/O soil/O where/O violent/O terrorist/O thoughts/O should/O grow/O by/O severely/O cracking/O down/O on/O the/O criminal/O activities/O of/O spreading/O terrorism/O audios/O and/O video/O ./O ''/O 
Just/O over/O 40/O percent/O of/O people/O in/O the/O restive/O region/O are/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O ,/O a/O Turkic/O group/O the/O majority/O of/O which/O is/O Muslim/O ./O 
A/O similar/O proportion/O belong/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O majority/O ethnic/O Han/O group/O ./O 
`/O Spreading/O jihad/O '/O Among/O those/O convicted/O in/O a/O hearing/O on/O Tuesday/O was/O 25-year-old/O Maimaitiniyazi/PERSON Aini/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O sentenced/O to/O five/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O inciting/O ethnic/O hatred/O and/O discrimination/O through/O chat/O group/O comments/O ,/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O 
One/O Uighur/O man/O was/O also/O jailed/O for/O 15/O years/O after/O he/O preached/O jihad/O ,/O or/O holy/O war/O ,/O to/O his/O son/O and/O another/O young/O man/O ,/O the/O court/O said/O ./O 
Uighur/O separatists/O have/O been/O waging/O a/O low-level/O insurgency/O for/O decades/O ,/O but/O recent/O attacks/O have/O become/O increasingly/O bold/O and/O bloody/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O blamed/O several/O incidents/O ,/O including/O abomb/O and/O knife/O attack/O that/O killed/O 29/O in/O the/O southwestern/O city/O of/O Kunming/LOCATION ,/O on/O the/O Eastern/ORGANIZATION Turkistan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Uighur/O activists/O claim/O the/O violence/O has/O been/O fueled/O by/O discriminatory/O policies/O imposed/O by/O the/O ethnic/O Han/O ./O 
rc/lw/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 
