Turkish/O President/O Erdogan/PERSON is/O traveling/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O mend/O ties/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O ./O 
The/O Turkish/O leader/O is/O expected/O to/O discuss/O a/O number/O of/O contentious/O issues/O with/O the/O Chinese/O leadership/O ,/O including/O the/O Uighur/O crisis/O ./O 
Turkish/O President/O Recep/PERSON Tayyip/PERSON Erdogan/PERSON has/O a/O lot/O to/O discuss/O with/O his/O Chinese/O hosts/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION during/O his/O two-day/O official/O visit/O which/O ends/O on/O July/O 30/O ./O 
Recently/O ,/O thousands/O of/O Turkish/O people/O staged/O a/O demonstration/O outside/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O in/O Ankara/LOCATION against/O the/O treatment/O of/O the/O Muslim/O Uighur/O community/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ./O 
Prior/O to/O that/O ,/O the/O Turkish/O media/O reported/O that/O Chinese/O authorities/O were/O not/O allowing/O the/O Uighurs/O to/O fast/O during/O the/O Muslim/O holy/O month/O of/O Ramadan/O ,/O and/O that/O they/O were/O even/O forcing/O them/O to/O consume/O alcohol/O ./O 
The/O police/O used/O tear/O gas/O to/O disperse/O the/O angry/O protesters/O ,/O who/O also/O attacked/O Chinese/O tourists/O ./O 
The/O situation/O forced/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O in/O Ankara/LOCATION to/O send/O out/O a/O travel/O advisory/O to/O its/O citizens/O traveling/O to/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
Thousands/O protested/O outside/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O in/O Ankara/LOCATION Solidarity/LOCATION with/O the/O `/O Uighur/O brethren/O '/O The/O Uighurs/O ,/O a/O Turkic-speaking/O ethnic/O group/O ,/O live/O predominantly/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ./O 
The/O province/O has/O been/O volatile/O for/O decades/O ,/O as/O the/O Uighurs/O complain/O about/O being/O culturally/O ,/O socially/O and/O economically/O suppressed/O by/O the/O majority/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
The/O government/O denies/O these/O claims/O and/O says/O the/O Uighur/O community/O enjoys/O freedom/O and/O a/O good/O standard/O of/O living/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
The/O authorities/O ,/O at/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O accuse/O some/O Uighur/O groups/O of/O being/O involved/O in/O separatist/O activities/O ./O 
The/O Turkish/O people/O feel/O the/O Uighurs/O are/O culturally/O and/O religiously/O closer/O to/O them/O than/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O country/O 's/O leaders/O have/O repeatedly/O criticized/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O treatment/O of/O the/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O ./O 
In/O 2009/O ,/O Erdogan/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O then/O prime/O minister/O ,/O described/O the/O bloody/O riots/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O which/O left/O more/O than/O 180/O people/O dead/O ,/O as/O ``/O a/O kind/O of/O genocide/O ./O ''/O 
After/O a/O short/O tense/O period/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O ,/O relations/O have/O improved/O again/O ,/O although/O the/O Uighur/O issue/O continues/O to/O cause/O friction/O ./O 
Since/O last/O year/O ,/O thousands/O of/O Uighurs/O have/O fled/O to/O Turkey/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION claims/O that/O several/O hundred/O Chinese/O nationals/O ,/O predominantly/O Uighurs/O ,/O have/O also/O gone/O to/O Syria/LOCATION via/O Turkey/LOCATION to/O join/O the/O extremist/O ``/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION ''/O group/O ./O 
Chinese/O authorities/O fear/O the/O Uighurs/O '/O exposure/O to/O jihadist/O networks/O in/O the/O region/O could/O create/O more/O unrest/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Ups/O and/O downs/O ``/O Relations/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O have/O their/O ups/O and/O downs/O ,/O ''/O Umut/PERSON Erguns端/PERSON ,/O a/O political/O scientist/O at/O China-based/O Peking/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
But/O while/O the/O feeling/O of/O solidarity/O with/O the/O Uighurs/O is/O especially/O strong/O amongst/O nationalist/O Turks/O ,/O the/O debate/O is/O largely/O based/O on/O emotions/O rather/O than/O on/O actual/O knowledge/O about/O the/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ,/O Erguns端/PERSON explained/O ./O 
Turkey/LOCATION depends/O on/O imports/O from/O China/LOCATION On/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O Turkey/LOCATION needs/O China/LOCATION as/O an/O economic/O partner/O ./O 
China/LOCATION is/O the/O second-largest/O importer/O into/O Turkey/LOCATION after/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O with/O bilateral/O trade/O reaching/O $/O 28/O billion/O -LRB-/O 25/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O in/O 2014/O ./O 
But/O the/O trade/O volume/O is/O tilted/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O favor/O ,/O with/O China/LOCATION exporting/O eight/O times/O more/O to/O Turkey/LOCATION than/O vice/O versa/O ./O 
China/LOCATION ,/O hence/O ,/O accounts/O for/O a/O fourth/O of/O the/O total/O Turkish/O trade/O deficit/O ./O 
While/O imports/O from/O China/LOCATION can/O not/O be/O replaced/O by/O the/O Turkish/O industry/O ,/O China/LOCATION can/O choose/O whether/O it/O buys/O its/O products/O from/O Turkey/LOCATION or/O somewhere/O else/O ,/O said/O Erguns端/PERSON ,/O adding/O that/O ``/O despite/O the/O occasional/O aggressive/O rhetoric/O coming/O from/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O the/O fact/O of/O the/O matter/O is/O that/O Turkey/LOCATION must/O cooperate/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Turkey/LOCATION and/O the/O new/O Silk/O Road/O The/O analyst/O explains/O that/O China/LOCATION 's/O plans/O for/O a/O new/O Silk/O Road/O will/O play/O an/O important/O role/O in/O future/O bilateral/O relations/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O is/O seeking/O to/O build/O new/O ports/O ,/O railroads/O and/O airports/O along/O the/O ancient/O trade/O route/O and/O Turkey/LOCATION is/O expected/O to/O play/O a/O key/O part/O in/O the/O scheme/O given/O its/O geographic/O location/O ./O 
``/O Turkey/LOCATION will/O certainly/O become/O a/O distribution/O hub/O ,/O enabling/O not/O only/O the/O distribution/O of/O Chinese/O products/O across/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O but/O also/O the/O strengthening/O of/O Turkey/LOCATION 's/O ties/O with/O Central/O Asian/O states/O ,/O ''/O said/O Erguns端/PERSON ./O 
