Reports/O have/O emerged/O that/O along/O with/O the/O Afghan/ORGANIZATION Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O scores/O of/O Central/O Asian/O Islamists/O and/O Pakistani/O jihadists/O are/O fighting/O in/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
Are/O the/O militants/O becoming/O a/O multi-national/O movement/O ?/O 
It/O is/O true/O that/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION had/O to/O retreat/O from/O Kunduz/LOCATION ,/O only/O days/O after/O taking/O over/O large/O parts/O of/O the/O Afghan/O city/O ./O 
But/O the/O Islamists/O have/O opened/O war/O fronts/O in/O other/O parts/O of/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O which/O have/O never/O been/O their/O strongholds/O ./O 
They/O have/O effectively/O taken/O the/O battle/O to/O the/O northeastern/O provinces/O of/O Takhar/LOCATION ,/O Baghlan/LOCATION and/O Badakhshan/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION reportedly/O captured/O some/O areas/O ,/O including/O one/O close/O to/O Fayzabad/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O German/O military/O once/O had/O a/O base/O ./O 
The/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O offensive/O and/O their/O military/O prowess/O seems/O to/O have/O caught/O everyone/O by/O surprise/O ,/O particularly/O President/O Ashraf/PERSON Ghani/PERSON 's/O administration/O in/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Afghan/O government/O needed/O US/LOCATION air/O power/O to/O expel/O the/O insurgents/O from/O Kunduz/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O not/O only/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O fifth-largest/O city/O but/O also/O has/O a/O geo-political/O significance/O given/O its/O proximity/O to/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
The/O success/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION in/O Kunduz/LOCATION -/O albeit/O ephemeral/O -/O raises/O questions/O about/O the/O Afghan/O troops/O '/O ability/O to/O prevent/O another/O provincial/O capital/O from/O falling/O under/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION control/O ./O 
``/O Kunduz/LOCATION is/O actually/O a/O very/O small/O part/O of/O a/O bigger/O story/O ./O 
This/O story/O is/O an/O effort/O by/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION to/O carve/O out/O a/O large/O sphere/O of/O influence/O in/O a/O geo-strategically/O significant/O region/O ,/O ''/O Michael/PERSON Kugelman/PERSON ,/O a/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION expert/O at/O the/O Woodrow/ORGANIZATION Wilson/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Scholars/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
The/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O military/O prowess/O in/O Kunduz/LOCATION caught/O everyone/O by/O surprise/O The/O expert/O says/O that/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION have/O also/O proven/O their/O ability/O to/O seize/O territory/O across/O a/O vast/O swath/O of/O the/O northern/O region/O ./O 
``/O In/O the/O long/O term/O ,/O that/O is/O just/O as/O concerning/O as/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O takeover/O of/O Kunduz/LOCATION ,/O given/O that/O until/O relatively/O recently/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION was/O not/O a/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION stronghold/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ./O 
A/O multi-national/O force/O ?/O 
Experts/O say/O that/O one/O of/O the/O reasons/O behind/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O takeover/O of/O Kunduz/LOCATION is/O their/O acceptance/O of/O jihadists/O from/O non-Pashtun/O movements/O across/O the/O region/O ./O 
For/O the/O first/O time/O ,/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION are/O emerging/O as/O a/O multi-ethnic/O and/O multi-national/O force/O by/O aligning/O with/O Uzbek/O ,/O Uighur/O and/O even/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Punjabi/O Islamists/O ./O 
``/O The/O battle/O over/O Kunduz/LOCATION symbolizes/O a/O change/O in/O the/O overall/O political/O strategy/O and/O subsequently/O the/O recruitment/O patterns/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION :/O from/O a/O mainly/O Pashtun-focused/O composition/O of/O its/O ranks/O towards/O a/O more/O multi-ethnic/O force/O in/O order/O to/O improve/O their/O chances/O of/O controlling/O northern/O areas/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Siegfried/PERSON O./PERSON Wolf/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O research/O at/O the/O Brussels-based/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION Democratic/O Forum/O -LRB-/O SADF/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O and/O a/O researcher/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Heidelberg/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION South/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O It/O seems/O that/O besides/O Arabs/O ,/O Pakistanis/O and/O Bangladeshis/O -LRB-/O including/O Rohingya/O refugees/O from/O Myanmar/LOCATION recruited/O in/O Bangladesh/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O militants/O from/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION 's/O Xinjiang/LOCATION Uighur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION are/O joining/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION in/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O the/O expert/O added/O ./O 
DW/O recommends/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION take/O fight/O beyond/O Kunduz/LOCATION As/O government/O forces/O make/O progress/O in/O Kunduz/LOCATION ,/O there/O are/O indications/O the/O fight/O over/O the/O city/O was/O only/O part/O of/O a/O bigger/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION strategy/O designed/O to/O increase/O their/O clout/O in/O key/O areas/O of/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
DW/O examines/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 06.10.2015/O -RRB-/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION condemns/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O `/O reign/O of/O terror/O '/O in/O Kunduz/LOCATION Mass/LOCATION murder/O ,/O gang/O rapes/O and/O house-to-house/O searches/O by/O death/O squads/O :/O Based/O on/O civilian/O testimonies/O ,/O Amnesty/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION has/O catalogued/O a/O number/O of/O atrocities/O attributed/O to/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O embattled/O city/O of/O Kunduz/LOCATION ./O 
-LRB-/O 02.10.2015/O -RRB-/O Dashed/O hopes/O -/O A/O year/O into/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O unity/O government/O When/O Afghan/O politicians/O reached/O a/O deal/O to/O form/O a/O unity/O government/O last/O September/O ,/O many/O hoped/O for/O a/O future/O free/O of/O insecurity/O ,/O unemployment/O and/O corruption/O ./O 
But/O a/O year/O into/O the/O government/O ,/O what/O has/O changed/O on/O the/O ground/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O 29.09.2015/O -RRB-/O Ahmad/PERSON Saidi/PERSON ,/O a/O former/O Afghan/O diplomat/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O a/O security/O expert/O ,/O confirmed/O the/O participation/O of/O ethnically/O diverse/O Islamists/O in/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O latest/O offensive/O ./O 
``/O There/O are/O fighters/O from/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION ,/O Chechnya/LOCATION ,/O Kirgizstan/LOCATION ,/O Azerbaijan/LOCATION and/O some/O from/O Arab/O countries/O in/O Kunduz/LOCATION and/O other/O northern/O Afghan/O provinces/O ,/O ''/O Saidi/PERSON told/O DW/O ,/O adding/O that/O among/O them/O the/O Pakistani/O and/O Uzbek/O fighters/O had/O been/O the/O most/O active/O ./O 
What/O 's/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O role/O in/O it/O ?/O 
According/O to/O media/O reports/O ,/O some/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION commanders/O fighting/O in/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION were/O once/O incarcerated/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
And/O some/O of/O them/O played/O important/O roles/O in/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION regime/O ousted/O in/O 2001/O following/O a/O US-led/O invasion/O ./O 
Mullah/PERSON Abdul/PERSON Salam/PERSON Akhund/PERSON ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O was/O one/O of/O nine/O former/O Afghan/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION cabinet/O ministers/O arrested/O by/O Pakistani/O authorities/O in/O 2010/O as/O part/O of/O a/O US-driven/O crackdown/O on/O extremists/O ./O 
Akhund/PERSON ,/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O shadow/O governor/O for/O Kunduz/LOCATION ,/O was/O released/O in/O 2013/O by/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O along/O with/O several/O other/O of/O the/O group/O 's/O leaders/O ,/O to/O facilitate/O peace/O talks/O with/O Washington/LOCATION and/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O 
That/O same/O year/O ,/O Islamabad/LOCATION also/O released/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O former/O foreign/O minister/O ,/O Mullah/PERSON Mohammed/PERSON Hassan/PERSON ./O 
Analysts/O say/O it/O ca/O n't/O be/O a/O coincidence/O that/O the/O two/O commanders/O freed/O by/O Pakistan/LOCATION were/O in/O charge/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O Kunduz/LOCATION mission/O ./O 
``/O It/O is/O not/O clear/O on/O what/O terms/O they/O -LRB-/O Akhund/PERSON and/O Hassan/PERSON -RRB-/O were/O released/O and/O sent/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Arif/PERSON Jamal/PERSON ,/O a/O US-based/O journalist/O and/O author/O of/O several/O books/O on/O Islamic/O terrorism/O and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O However/O ,/O we/O know/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O supporting/O the/O Islamist/O takeover/O of/O parts/O of/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O ,/O eventually/O ,/O the/O capital/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Jamal/PERSON says/O there/O is/O enough/O evidence/O that/O the/O supply/O lines/O for/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O other/O extremist/O groups/O in/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION pass/O through/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O The/O Pakistani/O military/O is/O supporting/O different/O groups/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O Jamatud/PERSON Dawa/PERSON and/O `/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION '/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O goal/O is/O to/O send/O Ghani/PERSON 's/O government/O packing/O once/O the/O US/LOCATION forces/O completely/O withdraw/O ./O ''/O 
Can/O Afghan/O troops/O prevent/O another/O provincial/O capital/O from/O falling/O into/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION hands/O ?/O 
Islamabad/LOCATION denies/O allegations/O that/O it/O backs/O factions/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O other/O jihadist/O groups/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O says/O it/O wants/O a/O stable/O government/O in/O Kabul/LOCATION ./O 
Analyst/O Wolf/PERSON ,/O however/O ,/O does/O not/O agree/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O official/O stance/O :/O ``/O This/O has/O been/O a/O recurring/O part/O of/O an/O officially/O orchestrated/O `/O cat-and-mouse/O game/O '/O by/O Pakistani/O authorities/O to/O provoke/O the/O Afghan/O government/O and/O to/O lead/O astray/O the/O anti-terror/O engagement/O of/O the/O international/O community/O ./O 
The/O Pakistani/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION have/O been/O heading/O in/O remarkable/O numbers/O to/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O which/O has/O become/O a/O new/O sanctuary/O and/O area/O of/O operation/O for/O an/O array/O of/O militant/O groups/O ./O ''/O 
But/O there/O is/O also/O a/O flipside/O ,/O says/O Wolf/PERSON ./O 
``/O The/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION are/O taking/O a/O moderate/O approach/O towards/O non-Pashtuns/O and/O former/O combatants/O in/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION to/O reduce/O the/O intensity/O of/O the/O conflict/O between/O different/O ethnic/O groups/O ./O 
But/O this/O could/O be/O a/O worrying/O development/O for/O Pakistani/O policymakers/O as/O many/O of/O the/O new/O groups/O in/O the/O north/O are/O known/O for/O their/O deeply/O entrenched/O anti-Pakistan/O sentiments/O ./O ''/O 
Islamabad/LOCATION is/O rather/O interested/O in/O supporting/O the/O pro-Pakistan/O factions/O among/O the/O Afghan/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION in/O order/O to/O establish/O a/O friendly/O Pashtun/O government/O in/O its/O neighborhood/O ,/O said/O Wolf/PERSON ./O 
``/O All/O this/O could/O lead/O to/O an/O escalation/O of/O the/O armed/O conflict/O in/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O making/O the/O region/O unmanageable/O for/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O National/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Forces/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
Is/O there/O a/O diplomatic/O solution/O ?/O 
Former/O Afghan/O diplomat/O Ahmad/PERSON Saidi/PERSON hopes/O the/O situation/O can/O be/O brought/O under/O control/O as/O long/O as/O President/O Ghani/PERSON 's/O administration/O works/O with/O neighboring/O countries/O and/O persuades/O them/O to/O stop/O the/O flow/O of/O jihadists/O to/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
Is/O the/O rift/O between/O President/O Ghani/PERSON and/O Chief/O Executive/O Abdullah/PERSON affecting/O Kabul/LOCATION 's/O anti-terror/O strategy/O ?/O 
``/O The/O government/O should/O work/O together/O with/O the/O countries/O in/O the/O region/O to/O fight/O the/O insurgency/O ./O 
In/O order/O to/O do/O this/O ,/O Afghan/O politicians/O need/O to/O ignore/O their/O disputes/O and/O take/O a/O stronger/O stance/O against/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION when/O they/O engage/O in/O talks/O with/O other/O countries/O ,/O ''/O said/O Saidi/PERSON ,/O referring/O to/O political/O disputes/O among/O President/O Ghani/PERSON and/O his/O chief/O executive/O Abdullah/PERSON Abdullah/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O also/O from/O northern/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
But/O resolving/O the/O Afghan/O government/O 's/O internal/O crisis/O is/O probably/O easier/O said/O than/O done/O ./O 
The/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION 's/O latest/O offensive/O in/O the/O north/O has/O dealt/O a/O major/O blow/O to/O the/O one-year-old/O unity/O government/O of/O President/O Ashraf/PERSON Ghani/PERSON ,/O as/O it/O is/O yet/O again/O civilians/O who/O have/O borne/O the/O brunt/O of/O the/O escalating/O violence/O ./O 
``/O The/O crisis/O of/O confidence/O in/O the/O government/O was/O already/O there/O ,/O but/O the/O fall/O of/O Kunduz/LOCATION has/O exacerbated/O this/O ,/O and/O also/O brought/O international/O attention/O to/O the/O weakness/O of/O the/O Afghan/O government/O ,/O ''/O Omar/PERSON Hamid/PERSON ,/O Head/O of/O Asia/LOCATION Pacific/LOCATION Country/LOCATION Risk/LOCATION at/O global/O analytics/O firm/O IHS/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
Also/O ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O neighboring/O countries/O are/O not/O willing/O to/O help/O ,/O at/O least/O not/O now/O ./O 
Additional/O reporting/O by/O Gabriel/PERSON Domínguez/PERSON and/O Masood/PERSON Saifullah/PERSON ./O 
