Chinese/O journalist/O Gao/PERSON Yu/PERSON has/O been/O sentenced/O to/O seven/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O 
This/O again/O shows/O how/O the/O authorities/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION deal/O with/O critics/O of/O the/O regime/O ,/O writes/O the/O head/O of/O DW/O 's/O Chinese/O department/O ,/O Philipp/PERSON Bilsky/PERSON ./O 
Over/O the/O past/O few/O months/O it/O seemed/O like/O the/O Chinese/O government/O was/O delaying/O a/O decision/O in/O the/O ``/O Gao/PERSON Yu/PERSON case/O ./O 
``/O The/O verdict/O was/O postponed/O twice/O ,/O which/O is/O rather/O unusual/O for/O Chinese/O courts/O ./O 
``/O The/O political/O leadership/O has/O not/O decided/O yet/O ,/O ''/O one/O of/O the/O judges/O admitted/O in/O an/O informal/O conversation/O ./O 
Optimists/O took/O that/O to/O be/O a/O good/O sign/O ./O 
Their/O hope/O was/O that/O the/O verdict/O might/O not/O turn/O out/O as/O harsh/O as/O they/O feared/O ./O 
But/O not/O even/O the/O most/O optimistic/O observers/O saw/O a/O chance/O for/O acquittal/O ./O 
In/O April/O 2014/O the/O 71-year-old/O was/O arrested/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION police/O ./O 
She/O was/O accused/O of/O having/O leaked/O state/O secrets/O ./O 
But/O there/O were/O no/O details/O concerning/O which/O documents/O Gao/PERSON had/O allegedly/O actually/O provided/O ./O 
Observers/O conjectured/O that/O the/O file/O in/O question/O could/O be/O the/O so-called/O ``/O Document/O No./O 9/O ./O ''/O 
That/O document/O warns/O of/O Western/O ideas/O such/O as/O the/O concept/O of/O parliamentary/O democracy/O or/O freedom/O of/O the/O press/O as/O threats/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O suggesting/O a/O more/O rigorous/O ideological/O stance/O ./O 
Details/O from/O the/O text/O had/O appeared/O first/O on/O several/O foreign/O websites/O then/O on/O Chinese/O sites/O as/O well/O ./O 
Now/O the/O verdict/O has/O been/O issued/O :/O Gao/PERSON is/O to/O spend/O seven/O years/O in/O prison/O ./O 
The/O court/O confirmed/O the/O indictment/O that/O she/O had/O illegally/O passed/O on/O state/O secrets/O to/O foreigners/O ./O 
The/O defense/O 's/O arguments/O were/O discarded/O ,/O according/O to/O Gao/PERSON 's/O lawyers/O ./O 
The/O verdict/O is/O a/O clear/O signal/O to/O all/O those/O who/O are/O critical/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O 
For/O months/O Beijing/LOCATION repeatedly/O cracked/O down/O on/O critics/O ./O 
A/O recent/O example/O being/O the/O arrest/O offive/O feminists/O who/O had/O wanted/O to/O protest/O against/O sexual/O harassment/O on/O public/O transport/O ./O 
The/O protesters/O were/O released/O on/O bail/O ,/O but/O their/O legal/O cases/O are/O still/O pending/O ./O 
That/O case/O seemed/O particularly/O absurd/O because/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION likes/O to/O portray/O itself/O as/O a/O champion/O of/O women/O 's/O rights/O ./O 
Obviously/O only/O one/O thing/O counts/O for/O the/O Chinese/O government/O :/O Stifling/O any/O form/O of/O dissent/O ./O 
And/O there/O are/O many/O more/O examples/O :/O The/O arrest/O of/O human/O rights/O lawyer/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON ,/O for/O instance/O ./O 
In/O May/O 2014/O ,/O he/O was/O charged/O with/O ``/O agitation/O ./O ''/O 
Amongst/O other/O things/O ,/O Pu/PERSON Zhiqiang/PERSON had/O defended/O the/O artistAi/O Weiwei/O ./O 
Or/O the/O verdict/O against/O the/O Uighur/O academic/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON in/O September/O ./O 
He/O was/O one/O of/O the/O more/O moderate/O representatives/O of/O that/O ethnic/O minority/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ./O 
Now/O he/O is/O serving/O a/O life/O sentence/O in/O prison/O ./O 
The/O verdict/O against/O Gao/PERSON Yu/PERSON fits/O into/O this/O pattern/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O government/O clearly/O wants/O to/O quickly/O suppress/O everything/O that/O could/O be/O a/O challenge/O to/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinpin/PERSON 's/O ``/O Chinese/O Dream/O ./O ''/O 
The/O ice/O in/O China/LOCATION has/O become/O very/O thin/O for/O those/O who/O have/O a/O critical/O point/O of/O view/O ./O 
