As/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON makes/O his/O first/O state/O visit/O to/O Britain/LOCATION next/O week/O ,/O Professor/O Steve/PERSON Tsang/PERSON tells/O DW/O the/O most/O important/O aspect/O about/O the/O trip/O is/O the/O visual/O impact/O it/O will/O make/O back/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
This/O upcoming/O state/O visit/O will/O be/O an/O occasion/O for/O the/O host/O nation/O to/O roll/O out/O the/O red/O carpet/O and/O make/O sure/O that/O everything/O goes/O right/O ./O 
For/O President/O Xi/O ,/O the/O visit/O is/O about/O giving/O the/O impression/O back/O in/O China/LOCATION that/O he/O is/O achieving/O his/O objective/O of/O promoting/O the/O ``/O China/LOCATION dream/O ./O ''/O 
For/O President/O Xi/O ,/O the/O single/O most/O important/O thing/O is/O the/O visual/O impact/O the/O visit/O is/O likely/O to/O make/O back/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
And/O you/O can/O not/O get/O a/O more/O visually/O impressive/O state/O visit/O than/O being/O received/O by/O the/O British/O Queen/O Elizabeth/PERSON II/PERSON ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O a/O state/O visit/O is/O not/O an/O occasion/O when/O you/O expect/O serious/O negotiations/O on/O any/O subject/O ./O 
That/O said/O ,/O the/O UK/LOCATION government/O will/O be/O making/O joint/O announcements/O with/O China/LOCATION in/O terms/O of/O a/O few/O big/O projects/O that/O have/O already/O been/O agreed/O ./O 
No/O ,/O it/O is/O not/O ./O 
As/O finance/O minister/O ,/O Osborne/PERSON has/O an/O exceptionally/O strong/O influence/O over/O UK-China/O relations/O ./O 
When/O finance/O ministers/O deal/O with/O these/O issues/O ,/O they/O do/O it/O in/O a/O very/O peculiar/O way/O that/O does/O not/O fall/O in/O line/O with/O normal/O foreign/O policies/O even/O in/O a/O country/O such/O as/O the/O UK/LOCATION ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O the/O UK/LOCATION 's/O China/LOCATION policies/O are/O very/O different/O from/O those/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON has/O gone/O out/O of/O his/O way/O to/O try/O to/O accommodate/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Over/O the/O past/O 20/O years/O or/O so/O ,/O you/O can/O not/O find/O any/O US/LOCATION president/O who/O has/O been/O more/O accommodating/O to/O China/LOCATION than/O Obama/PERSON ./O 
You/O can/O say/O the/O same/O about/O British/O PM/O David/PERSON Cameron/PERSON ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O UK/LOCATION has/O gone/O much/O further/O than/O the/O US/LOCATION for/O two/O reasons/O :/O The/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION is/O an/O Asia-Pacific/LOCATION power/O whose/O strategic/O interests/O compete/O with/O those/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
But/O the/O United/LOCATION Kingdom/LOCATION has/O no/O regional/O conflicts/O of/O interest/O with/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O second/O important/O factor/O is/O the/O way/O George/PERSON Osborne/PERSON is/O seeking/O to/O shape/O UK-China/O ties/O ./O 
He/O seems/O to/O think/O that/O by/O going/O out/O of/O his/O way/O to/O accommodate/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O he/O will/O win/O the/O friendship/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ,/O which/O will/O then/O improve/O bilateral/O relations/O and/O put/O his/O country/O in/O a/O better/O position/O when/O dealing/O with/O China/LOCATION as/O compared/O to/O other/O western/O nations/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O that/O what/O Osborne/PERSON did/O necessarily/O received/O widespread/O support/O in/O the/O UK/LOCATION ./O 
While/O Xi/O 's/O upcoming/O visit/O may/O be/O seen/O as/O a/O positive/O response/O to/O Osborne/PERSON 's/O China/LOCATION policy/O ,/O in/O the/O long/O run/O ,/O such/O an/O approach/O will/O not/O do/O the/O UK/LOCATION any/O good/O given/O that/O it/O will/O only/O encourage/O the/O Chinese/O leadership/O to/O demand/O a/O higher/O price/O for/O cooperation/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O know/O that/O London/LOCATION is/O willing/O to/O pay/O a/O higher/O price/O under/O the/O influence/O of/O Chancellor/O Osborne/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O not/O limited/O to/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O the/O UK/LOCATION getting/O more/O investments/O from/O China/LOCATION for/O the/O construction/O of/O nuclear/O power/O plants/O ./O 
It/O could/O also/O refer/O to/O things/O such/O as/O British/O ministers/O visiting/O places/O like/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O sending/O the/O wrong/O signals/O that/O their/O country/O does/O not/O care/O about/O human/O rights/O issues/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
