After/O the/O terrorist/O attack/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ,/O which/O left/O more/O than/O 20/O people/O dead/O ,/O the/O search/O for/O the/O perpetrators/O is/O in/O full/O swing/O ./O 
The/O turbulent/O political/O situation/O in/O the/O country/O is/O now/O facing/O additional/O pressure/O ./O 
It/O was/O the/O deadliest/O attack/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION 's/O history/O ./O 
On/O Monday/O ,/O August/O 17/O ,/O a/O bomb/O was/O detonated/O in/O the/O center/O of/O the/O Thai/O capital/O ,/O which/O killed/O 20/O people/O and/O injured/O more/O than/O 120/O ./O 
``/O People/O are/O shocked/O and/O stunned/O ,/O ''/O Michael/PERSON Winzer/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O the/O Konrad/ORGANIZATION Adenauer/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O They/O are/O afraid/O that/O the/O violence/O might/O continue/O ./O ''/O 
The/O attack/O also/O broke/O a/O taboo/O ,/O because/O for/O the/O first/O time/O the/O foreigners/O were/O targeted/O ./O 
The/O head/O of/O the/O Thai/O military/O junta/O ,/O Prayut/PERSON Chan/PERSON Ocha/PERSON ,/O said/O Tuesday/O that/O surveillance/O cameras/O showed/O a/O male/O suspect/O ,/O who/O is/O now/O being/O searched/O ./O 
The/O speculation/O that/O he/O could/O be/O an/O opposition/O supporter/O ,/O however/O ,/O should/O be/O dealt/O with/O care/O ,/O says/O Winzer/PERSON :/O ``/O There/O are/O no/O concrete/O indications/O of/O a/O particular/O group/O involved/O in/O the/O attack/O ./O 
Everything/O is/O still/O open/O ./O ''/O 
The/O security/O forces/O are/O looking/O to/O restore/O peace/O after/O the/O attack/O Motives/O unclear/O The/O list/O of/O possible/O perpetrators/O could/O be/O long/O ./O 
In/O addition/O to/O the/O supporters/O of/O the/O previous/O government/O ,/O which/O was/O toppled/O by/O the/O military/O in/O May/O 2014/O ,/O the/O attackers/O could/O also/O be/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION separatists/O fighting/O for/O independence/O from/O Thailand/LOCATION for/O years/O ./O 
Even/O the/O Uighurs/O ,/O a/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O living/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwest/O ,/O could/O be/O accused/O ./O 
Just/O recently/O ,/O some/O 100/O Uighurs/O were/O deported/O from/O Thailand/LOCATION to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
``/O The/O government/O and/O the/O security/O forces/O have/O reacted/O sensibly/O so/O far/O ,/O ''/O Siegfried/PERSON Herzog/PERSON ,/O head/O of/O the/O Friedrich/ORGANIZATION Naumann/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O FNS/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
The/O government/O has/O advised/O the/O citizens/O to/O be/O vigilant/O ,/O but/O it/O has/O not/O deployed/O a/O large/O number/O of/O troops/O ./O 
``/O The/O authorities/O do/O not/O want/O to/O play/O in/O the/O hands/O of/O the/O terrorists/O and/O create/O more/O panic/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
Further/O destabilization/O ``/O Whoever/O is/O behind/O the/O attack/O ,/O it/O will/O continue/O to/O politically/O destabilize/O the/O country/O ,/O ''/O Winzer/PERSON is/O convinced/O ./O 
DW/O recommends/O Thai/O authorities/O seeking/O `/O identified/O '/O male/O bombing/O suspect/O The/O head/O of/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O junta/O says/O a/O suspect/O sought/O by/O authorities/O in/O connection/O with/O a/O deadly/O Bangkok/LOCATION blast/O has/O been/O identified/O ./O 
The/O man/O was/O seen/O on/O CCTV/ORGANIZATION footage/O taken/O prior/O to/O the/O explosion/O at/O the/O blast/O site/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 18.08.2015/O -RRB-/O Thailand/LOCATION seeks/O answers/O after/O bomb/O attack/O on/O shrine/O Experts/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION have/O been/O sifting/O through/O debris/O after/O at/O least/O 21/O people/O were/O killed/O and/O scores/O wounded/O in/O a/O blast/O said/O to/O have/O targeted/O foreigners/O ./O 
Officials/O say/O the/O attack/O has/O not/O yet/O been/O linked/O to/O any/O group/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 18.08.2015/O -RRB-/O A/O look/O at/O southern/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O smoldering/O insurgency/O A/O recent/O string/O of/O deadly/O attacks/O have/O turned/O the/O spotlight/O on/O the/O southern/O Thai/O insurgency/O ,/O a/O decade-long/O conflict/O over/O autonomy/O that/O has/O claimed/O some/O 6,500/O lives/O ./O 
DW/O examines/O the/O causes/O and/O implications/O of/O the/O unrest/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 20.07.2015/O -RRB-/O For/O several/O years/O ,/O Thailand/LOCATION has/O been/O facing/O a/O political/O crisis/O ./O 
The/O military/O is/O struggling/O with/O the/O government/O and/O the/O reorganization/O of/O institutions/O and/O is/O expected/O to/O take/O some/O major/O decisions/O in/O the/O coming/O days/O ./O 
On/O August/O 23/O ,/O a/O draft/O constitution/O will/O be/O discussed/O in/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Peace/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Order/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O new/O military/O officers/O will/O replace/O the/O old/O ones/O in/O key/O positions/O by/O the/O end/O of/O September/O ./O 
The/O Bangkok/LOCATION attack/O has/O further/O complicated/O the/O situation/O ./O 
``/O After/O the/O coup/O ,/O the/O military/O promised/O to/O bring/O back/O peace/O and/O order/O ./O 
Its/O legitimacy/O has/O naturally/O been/O undermined/O by/O the/O attack/O ,/O ''/O said/O Winzer/PERSON ,/O adding/O that/O the/O military/O would/O likely/O show/O even/O more/O power/O now/O ./O 
Herzog/PERSON ,/O however/O ,/O does/O not/O consider/O it/O a/O foregone/O conclusion/O that/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O political/O crisis/O has/O been/O aggravated/O by/O the/O attack/O ./O 
He/O said/O the/O attack/O would/O generate/O the/O feeling/O of/O solidarity/O in/O the/O society/O ,/O which/O has/O been/O split/O for/O many/O years/O ./O 
Economic/O impact/O However/O ,/O both/O experts/O say/O the/O attack/O bears/O economic/O consequences/O for/O the/O Southeast/O Asian/O nation/O ./O 
The/O country/O 's/O economy/O has/O weakened/O in/O the/O past/O years/O ./O 
Due/O to/O political/O infighting/O and/O chaos/O ,/O the/O much-needed/O economic/O reforms/O were/O not/O implemented/O before/O the/O coup.The/O situation/O has/O not/O improved/O even/O after/O the/O military/O took/O power/O ./O 
According/O to/O Winzer/PERSON ,/O ``/O the/O economy/O has/O not/O got/O back/O on/O its/O feet/O since/O the/O beginning/O of/O the/O political/O unrest/O in/O 2013/O ./O ''/O 
Since/O the/O coup/O in/O May/O 2014/O ,/O the/O military/O has/O the/O final/O say/O in/O all/O affairs/O of/O the/O state/O The/O bombing/O is/O also/O expected/O to/O harm/O the/O tourism/O industry/O ,/O which/O despite/O political/O turmoil/O did/O not/O really/O suffer/O ,/O Winzer/PERSON added/O ./O 
The/O site/O of/O the/O attack/O ,/O the/O Erawan/O Shrine/O ,/O is/O a/O tourist/O hub/O ./O 
``/O The/O Shrine/O is/O a/O major/O tourist/O attraction/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ./O 
Pretty/O much/O everyone/O who/O goes/O to/O Bangkok/LOCATION visits/O the/O Erawan/O Shrine/O ,/O ''/O said/O Winzer/PERSON ./O 
The/O attackers/O not/O only/O had/O the/O objective/O of/O creating/O fear/O and/O terror/O among/O the/O public/O but/O also/O wanted/O to/O generate/O the/O media/O coverage/O ./O 
``/O That/O 's/O obviously/O been/O achieved/O ,/O ''/O said/O Herzog/PERSON ./O 
