Thai/O authorities/O say/O international/O terrorists/O were/O probably/O not/O behind/O the/O attack/O on/O a/O religious/O shrine/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ./O 
At/O least/O 10/O people/O appear/O to/O have/O been/O involved/O in/O the/O bombing/O that/O killed/O 20/O people/O ./O 
``/O Security/O agencies/O have/O cooperated/O with/O agencies/O from/O allied/O countries/O and/O have/O come/O to/O the/O preliminary/O conclusion/O that/O the/O incident/O is/O unlikely/O to/O be/O linked/O to/O international/O terrorism/O ,/O ''/O Colonel/O Winthai/PERSON Suvaree/PERSON ,/O a/O spokesman/O for/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O ruling/O junta/O ,/O known/O as/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Peace/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Order/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O reporters/O on/O Thursday/O ./O 
National/O police/O chief/O Somyot/PERSON Poompanmoung/PERSON said/O the/O attack/O took/O at/O least/O one/O month/O to/O plan/O and/O that/O at/O least/O 10/O people/O were/O suspected/O of/O being/O involved/O in/O the/O bombing/O of/O the/O Erawan/O shrine/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O popular/O with/O locals/O and/O tourists/O ./O 
``/O This/O blast/O was/O made/O by/O teams/O ,/O ''/O he/O told/O reporters/O ./O 
``/O I/O believe/O this/O network/O links/O with/O people/O inside/O Thailand/LOCATION .../O more/O than/O 10/O people/O were/O involved/O ./O ''/O 
Observers/O have/O speculated/O that/O the/O bomb/O may/O have/O been/O planted/O by/O extremists/O of/O the/O Uighur/ORGANIZATION Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Thailand/LOCATION deported/O more/O than/O 100/O Uighurs/O back/O to/O China/LOCATION in/O July/O ./O 
Rights/O activists/O say/O they/O face/O persecution/O there/O ./O 
Another/O police/O spokesman/O said/O that/O the/O main/O suspect/O -/O who/O police/O desbribed/O as/O a/O tall/O ,/O fair-skinned/O foreigner/O speaking/O neither/O Thai/O nor/O English/O -/O may/O have/O left/O the/O country/O ,/O but/O that/O police/O were/O ``/O unsure/O ''/O of/O his/O whereabouts/O ./O 
Police/O have/O released/O CCTV/ORGANIZATION footage/O of/O a/O young/O man/O with/O glasses/O ,/O wearing/O a/O yellow/O t-shirt/O and/O leaving/O a/O rucksack/O at/O the/O shrine/O shortly/O before/O the/O blast/O ./O 
were/O seen/O standing/O next/O to/O the/O main/O suspect/O ./O 
On/O Thursday/O ,/O Thai/O police/O started/O investigating/O areas/O of/O interest/O around/O the/O capital/O ./O 
They/O have/O also/O asked/O Interpol/ORGANIZATION for/O help/O with/O the/O investigation/O ./O 
ng/jil/O -LRB-/O dpa/O ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/O -RRB-/O 
