Iran/LOCATION is/O arguably/O one/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O closest/O partners/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
And/O with/O economic/O sanctions/O on/O Tehran/LOCATION set/O to/O be/O eased/O ,/O DW/O examines/O China/LOCATION 's/O latest/O proposal/O to/O integrate/O Iran/LOCATION into/O its/O New/O Silk/O Road/O Initiative/O ./O 
Seeking/O to/O capitalize/O on/O the/O easing/O of/O international/O sanctions/O on/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O railway/O authority/O has/O proposed/O a/O high-speed/O rail/O line/O for/O both/O passengers/O and/O cargo/O connecting/O the/O country/O 's/O northwest/O region/O to/O West/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION via/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O according/O to/O state-run/O newspaperChina/O Daily/O ./O 
The/O proposed/O 3,200-kilometer/O long/O -LRB-/O nearly/O 2,000/O miles/O -RRB-/O rail/O link/O ,/O put/O forward/O last/O month/O by/O state-owned/O China/ORGANIZATION Railway/ORGANIZATION Corporation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CRC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O would/O begin/O in/O Urumqi/LOCATION ,/O the/O capital/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O western/O Xinjiang/LOCATION Province/LOCATION ,/O and/O end/O in/O the/O Iranian/O capital/O ,/O Tehran/LOCATION ./O 
Along/O the/O way/O it/O would/O stop/O in/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION -LRB-/O Almaty/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION -LRB-/O Bishkek/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION -LRB-/O Tashkent/LOCATION and/O Samarkand/LOCATION -RRB-/O and/O Turkmenistan/LOCATION -LRB-/O Ashgabat/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O said/O the/O paper/O ./O 
The/O line/O would/O be/O complementary/O to/O the/O existing/O railway/O network/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O which/O mostly/O runs/O southeast/O to/O northwest/O toward/O Moscow/LOCATION ,/O CRC/ORGANIZATION chief/O engineer/O He/PERSON Huawu/PERSON was/O quoted/O as/O saying/O ./O 
What/O 's/O more/O important/O ,/O he/O argued/O ,/O is/O that/O it/O could/O get/O rid/O of/O the/O incompatibility/O between/O the/O region/O 's/O wide-gauge/O track/O systems/O -LRB-/O 1.52/O meter/O -RRB-/O and/O the/O 1.435-meter/O standard/O track/O adopted/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O most/O other/O parts/O of/O the/O world/O ./O 
A/O single/O rail/O line/O relying/O on/O a/O uniform/O gauge/O would/O fix/O the/O problem/O of/O trains/O waiting/O for/O days/O at/O certain/O border/O crossings/O to/O have/O their/O gauges/O changed/O ,/O said/O the/O CRC/ORGANIZATION engineer/O ,/O adding/O that/O a/O passenger/O train/O using/O the/O suggested/O line/O could/O run/O at/O up/O to/O 300/O km/h/O -LRB-/O 186/O miles/O per/O hour/O -RRB-/O ,/O while/O a/O container/O train/O could/O run/O at/O 120/O km/h/O ./O 
The/O proposed/O high-speed/O rail/O line/O would/O be/O complementary/O to/O the/O existing/O railway/O network/O in/O the/O region/O One/LOCATION Belt/LOCATION ,/O One/LOCATION Road/LOCATION The/O CRC/ORGANIZATION proposal/O is/O just/O the/O latest/O in/O a/O series/O of/O plans/O designed/O to/O expand/O China/LOCATION 's/O economic/O connectivity/O -/O and/O political/O influence/O -/O across/O much/O of/O Eurasia/LOCATION through/O investment/O campaigns/O and/O infrastructure/O projects/O such/O as/O roads/O ,/O rail/O links/O ,/O airports/O and/O resource/O pipelines/O ./O 
``/O For/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O opportunity/O to/O build/O high-speed/O railways/O in/O other/O countries/O is/O strategically/O attractive/O as/O part/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O efforts/O to/O transform/O the/O economy/O away/O from/O low-cost/O manufacturing/O ,/O ''/O Rajiv/PERSON Biswas/PERSON ,/O Asia-Pacific/O Chief/O Economist/O at/O the/O analytics/O firm/O IHS/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
Such/O projects/O are/O part/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O One/LOCATION Belt/LOCATION ,/O One/LOCATION Road/LOCATION -LRB-/O OBOR/O -RRB-/O initiative/O ,/O namely/O the/O Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION Economic/LOCATION Belt/LOCATION and/O the/O 21st/ORGANIZATION Century/ORGANIZATION Maritime/ORGANIZATION Silk/ORGANIZATION Road/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O aims/O to/O enhance/O connectivity/O between/O China/LOCATION ,/O Central/O ,/O Southwest/ORGANIZATION and/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ,/O as/O well/O as/O Russia/LOCATION and/O Europe/LOCATION ./O 
While/O yet/O to/O be/O officially/O endorsed/O by/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O the/O CRC/ORGANIZATION proposal/O comes/O at/O a/O key/O moment/O as/O international/O economic/O sanctions/O on/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O one/O of/O world/O 's/O top/O oil/O producers/O ,/O are/O expected/O to/O be/O lifted/O in/O 2016/O ./O 
``/O With/O Iran/LOCATION being/O one/O of/O the/O world/O 's/O largest/O emerging/O market/O economies/O as/O well/O as/O a/O key/O economy/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O the/O strengthening/O of/O economic/O and/O logistical/O connectivity/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O will/O also/O boost/O China/LOCATION 's/O geopolitical/O influence/O on/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
DW/O recommends/O Eased/O sanctions/O will/O permit/O Iran/LOCATION to/O export/O oil/O to/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION :/O report/O Pyongyang/LOCATION may/O want/O to/O pay/O for/O much-needed/O energy/O supplies/O with/O weapons/O and/O nuclear/O technology/O ,/O analysts/O suggest/O ./O 
Julian/PERSON Ryall/PERSON reports/O from/O Tokyo/LOCATION ./O 
-LRB-/O 08.12.2015/O -RRB-/O How/O China/LOCATION 's/O rise/O is/O affecting/O Europe/LOCATION 's/O view/O of/O Japan/LOCATION Despite/O solid/O bilateral/O ties/O ,/O many/O Europeans/O see/O international/O cooperation/O between/O Japan/LOCATION and/O Europe/LOCATION as/O not/O making/O significant/O progress/O ,/O a/O new/O ECFR/ORGANIZATION survey/O found/O -/O a/O paradox/O partly/O linked/O to/O China/LOCATION 's/O ascent/O ,/O say/O experts/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 09.12.2015/O -RRB-/O India/LOCATION and/O Japan/LOCATION to/O deepen/O defense/O ,/O trade/O ties/O Amid/O China/LOCATION 's/O muscle-flexing/O in/O Asia/LOCATION ,/O Japan/LOCATION 's/O PM/O Shinzo/PERSON Abe/PERSON will/O embark/O on/O a/O three-day/O India/LOCATION visit/O ,/O hoping/O to/O seal/O key/O defense/O and/O trade/O deals/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O a/O civil/O nuclear/O pact/O ./O 
DW/O examines/O the/O Indo-Japanese/O partnership/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 08.12.2015/O -RRB-/O Why/O Russia/LOCATION needs/O China/LOCATION to/O buy/O its/O weapons/O Despite/O intellectual/O property/O concerns/O ,/O Russia/LOCATION recently/O agreed/O to/O sell/O 24/O Sukhoi/ORGANIZATION Su-35/O fighter/O jets/O to/O China/LOCATION -/O a/O deal/O worth/O $/O 2/O billion/O ./O 
But/O what/O is/O driving/O Moscow/LOCATION to/O seek/O deeper/O trade/O ties/O with/O Beijing/LOCATION ?/O 
DW/O examines/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 24.11.2015/O -RRB-/O ``/O From/O an/O energy/O security/O perspective/O ,/O Iran/LOCATION has/O an/O important/O role/O to/O play/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O future/O energy/O security/O ,/O as/O a/O major/O long-term/O source/O of/O supply/O of/O oil/O and/O gas/O ,/O ''/O said/O Biswas/PERSON ./O 
The/O oil/O factor/O In/O order/O to/O fully/O understand/O the/O potential/O impact/O of/O the/O proposal/O ,/O it/O 's/O worth/O taking/O a/O broader/O look/O at/O the/O state/O of/O Sino-Iranian/O ties/O ./O 
Iran/LOCATION is/O considered/O one/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O closest/O allies/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O with/O significant/O political/O and/O economic/O ties/O going/O back/O many/O years/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION has/O maintained/O its/O trading/O relations/O with/O Iran/LOCATION throughout/O the/O sanctions/O ,/O and/O Chinese/O companies/O are/O heavily/O invested/O in/O a/O number/O of/O industries/O ,/O ranging/O from/O consumer/O goods/O through/O auto/O to/O energy/O ,/O ''/O Michal/PERSON Meidan/PERSON ,/O a/O China/LOCATION expert/O at/O UK-based/O think/O tank/O Chatham/ORGANIZATION House/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
The/O energy/O factor/O has/O played/O an/O essential/O role/O in/O the/O relationship/O ./O 
Flynt/PERSON Leverett/PERSON ,/O a/O professor/O of/O international/O affairs/O at/O Penn/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O points/O out/O that/O while/O China/LOCATION has/O worked/O hard/O to/O diversify/O its/O foreign/O sources/O of/O oil/O ,/O Iran/LOCATION has/O remained/O one/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O top/O oil/O suppliers/O for/O over/O a/O decade/O -/O a/O development/O likely/O to/O continue/O as/O China/LOCATION 's/O demand/O for/O oil/O increases/O ./O 
Iran/LOCATION once/O accounted/O for/O up/O to/O 13/O percent/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O oil/O imports/O ./O 
But/O they/O dipped/O considerably/O under/O international/O sanctions/O ,/O causing/O Iran/LOCATION to/O slip/O from/O being/O China/LOCATION 's/O third-largest/O supplier/O to/O its/O fifth/O -/O after/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ,/O Angola/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION and/O Oman/LOCATION ./O 
Yet/O ever/O since/O the/O historic/O July/O 2015/O nuclear/O deal/O was/O announced/O ,/O imports/O have/O gradually/O risen/O ,/O currently/O representing/O around/O 9/O percent/O of/O total/O Chinese/O crude/O oil/O imports/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O so/O far/O this/O year/O ,/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O oil/O exports/O to/O China/LOCATION have/O averaged/O around/O 573,000/O barrels/O per/O day/O -LRB-/O bpd/O -RRB-/O -/O higher/O than/O the/O 2014/O average/O of/O roughly/O 555,000/O bpd/O ,/O said/O Leverett/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O also/O author/O of/O ``/O Going/O to/O Tehran/LOCATION :/O Why/O America/O Must/O Accept/O the/O Islamic/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION of/LOCATION Iran/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
More/O than/O just/O energy/O More/O recently/O ,/O a/O sizable/O portion/O of/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O earnings/O from/O oil/O exports/O to/O China/LOCATION have/O been/O deposited/O into/O Chinese/O banks/O ./O 
``/O Even/O with/O sanctions/O relief/O ,/O a/O significant/O share/O of/O these/O deposits/O -/O probably/O in/O the/O tens/O of/O billions/O of/O dollars/O -/O will/O not/O be/O repatriated/O to/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
Instead/O ,/O this/O money/O will/O remain/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O where/O it/O will/O fund/O ongoing/O Iranian/O purchases/O of/O Chinese/O goods/O ,/O ''/O said/O Leverett/PERSON ,/O referring/O to/O another/O significant/O aspect/O of/O Sino-Iranian/O ties/O ./O 
Besides/O becoming/O arguably/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O most/O important/O international/O economic/O partner/O in/O recent/O years/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O also/O emerged/O as/O the/O main/O great/O power/O alternative/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION in/O Tehran/LOCATION 's/O strategic/O calculations/O ,/O as/O Leverett/PERSON indicates/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O view/O of/O Iran/LOCATION as/O a/O historic/O and/O cultural/O power/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION has/O also/O contributed/O to/O both/O sides/O seeking/O to/O deepen/O relations/O ,/O including/O arms/O sales/O and/O strategic/O cooperation/O on/O an/O expanding/O range/O of/O issues/O such/O as/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Syria/LOCATION ./O 
Economic/O sanctions/O on/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O China/LOCATION 's/O fifth-largest/O oil/O supplier/O ,/O are/O set/O to/O be/O eased/O in/O 2016/O ``/O China/LOCATION has/O long/O been/O an/O important/O military/O supplier/O to/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O while/O China/LOCATION 's/O status/O as/O a/O permanent/O member/O of/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION makes/O it/O an/O essential/O diplomatic/O reference/O point/O for/O Tehran/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O the/O expert/O ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O once/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION sanctions/O are/O lifted/O ,/O Iran/LOCATION will/O be/O also/O eligible/O to/O apply/O for/O full/O membership/O in/O the/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Cooperation/ORGANIZATION Organization/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O Moritz/PERSON Rudolf/PERSON ,/O a/O research/O associate/O at/O the/O Germany-based/O Mercator/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O MERICS/O -RRB-/O ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
A/O balancing/O act/O However/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION seems/O to/O tread/O carefully/O when/O balancing/O its/O relationship/O with/O Middle/O Eastern/O states/O ./O 
``/O Despite/O a/O standing/O invitation/O ,/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON has/O yet/O to/O visit/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O partly/O because/O of/O the/O political/O sensitivities/O about/O heading/O to/O Tehran/LOCATION before/O a/O trip/O to/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Andrew/PERSON Small/PERSON ,/O a/O fellow/O with/O the/O Asia/LOCATION program/O of/O German/O Marshall/O Fund/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
China/LOCATION views/O Iran/LOCATION as/O strategic/O partner/O and/O a/O historic/O and/O cultural/O power/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION But/O the/O Iranians/O have/O also/O raised/O concerns/O ,/O particularly/O about/O a/O potential/O Chinese/O dominance/O of/O their/O economy/O as/O well/O as/O a/O ``/O flood/O ''/O of/O imported/O Chinese/O goods/O ,/O said/O Meidan/PERSON ./O 
``/O And/O since/O Chinese/O companies/O have/O slowed/O some/O of/O their/O investments/O in/O the/O energy/O sector/O to/O avoid/O US/LOCATION sanctions/O ,/O Iranian/O officials/O have/O also/O canceled/O a/O number/O of/O Chinese/O upstream/O projects/O ,/O ''/O added/O Meidan/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O also/O director/O of/O independent/O research/O consultancyChina/O Matters/O ./O 
A/O mixed/O blessing/O for/O China/LOCATION But/O the/O greatest/O challenge/O to/O the/O relationship/O yet/O may/O arise/O from/O ramifications/O of/O the/O nuclear/O deal/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION 's/O political/O and/O security/O links/O with/O Tehran/LOCATION had/O benefited/O from/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O long-standing/O hostile/O relations/O with/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O its/O tensions/O with/O Europe/LOCATION in/O more/O recent/O years/O ./O 
But/O there/O are/O fears/O that/O China/LOCATION 's/O position/O may/O now/O be/O undermined/O by/O a/O potential/O influx/O of/O Western/O companies/O in/O sectors/O where/O Iran/LOCATION 's/O isolation/O had/O given/O China/LOCATION privileged/O access/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION is/O keen/O to/O expand/O its/O investments/O in/O the/O country/O considerably/O as/O it/O opens/O up/O ,/O but/O Iran/LOCATION will/O be/O careful/O in/O choosing/O its/O partners/O -/O not/O least/O in/O the/O energy/O sector/O ,/O where/O more/O technically/O capable/O western/O energy/O majors/O are/O still/O often/O seen/O as/O preferable/O partners/O ,/O ''/O analyst/O Small/O told/O DW/O ./O 
Professor/O Leverett/PERSON has/O a/O similar/O view/O ./O 
``/O While/O sanctions/O relief/O will/O create/O more/O economic/O openings/O in/O Iran/LOCATION for/O China/LOCATION ,/O it/O will/O also/O generate/O more/O international/O competition/O for/O Chinese/O entities/O seeking/O opportunities/O to/O do/O business/O in/O or/O with/O Iran/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O this/O is/O why/O China/LOCATION and/O Iran/LOCATION are/O unlikely/O to/O develop/O a/O ``/O privileged/O ''/O relationship/O in/O the/O near/O future/O ./O 
Opening/O new/O markets/O So/O what/O role/O could/O the/O proposed/O high-speed/O rail/O link/O play/O ?/O 
China/LOCATION is/O looking/O to/O Iran/LOCATION as/O a/O location/O for/O investment/O ,/O transit/O ,/O and/O as/O an/O emerging/O market/O ./O 
And/O given/O the/O increasing/O levels/O of/O competition/O expected/O from/O 2016/O ,/O such/O a/O rail/O link/O would/O be/O a/O critical/O step/O towards/O integrating/O Iran/LOCATION into/O China/LOCATION 's/O ``/O New/O Silk/O Road/O ''/O initiative/O ,/O say/O experts/O ./O 
``/O Among/O China/LOCATION 's/O prospective/O partners/O ,/O Iran/LOCATION is/O comparatively/O unique/O in/O the/O sense/O that/O geography/O makes/O it/O important/O to/O realizing/O both/O the/O essentially/O land-based/O New/O Silk/O Road/O Economic/O Belt/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O Maritime/LOCATION Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION ,/O ''/O said/O Leverett/PERSON ./O 
Dr./O Hui/PERSON Ching/PERSON ,/O Research/O Director/O at/O the/O Hong/ORGANIZATION Kong/ORGANIZATION Zhi/ORGANIZATION Ming/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION agrees/O ./O 
In/O the/O long/O run/O ,/O he/O argues/O ,/O the/O construction/O and/O operation/O of/O the/O railway/O would/O meet/O not/O only/O China/LOCATION 's/O strategic/O goals/O ,/O but/O also/O its/O geopolitical/O interests/O and/O economic/O needs/O ./O 
``/O Given/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O its/O military/O alliance/O and/O its/O diplomatic/O collaborations/O in/O the/O Asia-Pacific/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O now/O looking/O for/O markets/O ,/O resources/O and/O strategic/O partners/O in/O both/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O western/O development/O is/O a/O logical/O choice/O ,/O and/O inevitable/O in/O the/O coming/O decades/O ,/O ''/O Hui/PERSON told/O DW/O ./O 
Analyst/O Meidan/PERSON is/O also/O of/O the/O view/O that/O the/O proposed/O rail/O link/O -/O which/O seeks/O to/O place/O China/LOCATION and/O its/O goods/O at/O the/O heart/O of/O an/O Eurasian/O sphere/O -/O would/O open/O new/O markets/O for/O Chinese/O companies/O and/O employees/O ./O 
And/O as/O economist/O Biswas/PERSON explains/O ,/O the/O rail/O line/O would/O also/O help/O accelerate/O economic/O development/O along/O the/O entire/O rail/O corridor/O by/O linking/O up/O the/O regional/O economies/O and/O trading/O commodities/O ,/O intermediate/O goods/O and/O finished/O products/O with/O both/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O EU/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Major/O hurdles/O ahead/O But/O the/O rail/O link/O proposal/O still/O has/O major/O hurdles/O to/O overcome/O ./O 
As/O analyst/O Hui/PERSON points/O out/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION first/O needs/O to/O demonstrate/O it/O is/O actually/O interested/O in/O building/O the/O rail/O line/O ./O 
In/O addition/O ,/O the/O suggested/O system/O is/O yet/O to/O be/O tested/O by/O commercial/O measures/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O Hui/PERSON warns/O that/O given/O the/O railway/O 's/O length/O along/O with/O its/O construction/O and/O running/O costs/O ,/O the/O number/O of/O passengers/O could/O be/O well/O below/O the/O acceptable/O level/O ./O 
The/O Urumqi-Tehran/O high-speed/O rail/O link/O proposal/O faces/O major/O hurdles/O And/O then/O there/O are/O security/O concerns/O ./O 
``/O The/O single-line/O railway/O could/O easily/O turn/O into/O a/O target/O for/O extremists/O or/O militia/O ./O 
It/O is/O still/O unknown/O whether/O China/LOCATION has/O the/O military/O strength/O and/O determination/O to/O protect/O such/O railways/O by/O the/O use/O of/O force/O ,/O ''/O Hui/PERSON said/O ./O 
MERICS/O analyst/O Rudolf/PERSON is/O also/O skeptical/O ./O 
``/O It/O will/O be/O very/O difficult/O to/O realize/O this/O project/O ,/O especially/O since/O it/O would/O stretch/O across/O many/O unstable/O countries/O in/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION like/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION and/O Uzbekistan/LOCATION ./O 
In/O addition/O ,/O relations/O among/O the/O Central/LOCATION Asian/LOCATION countries/O are/O very/O difficult/O ./O ''/O 
Analysts/O agree/O that/O if/O Beijing/LOCATION does/O go/O ahead/O with/O the/O project/O ,/O it/O will/O not/O be/O completed/O rapidly/O ,/O mainly/O due/O to/O the/O lead/O time/O for/O preparations/O -/O the/O need/O to/O wait/O for/O sanctions/O to/O ease/O as/O well/O as/O technical/O factors/O such/O as/O feasibility/O studies/O ,/O regulatory/O approvals/O and/O visas/O ./O 
In/O the/O end/O ,/O it/O seems/O that/O a/O lot/O will/O depend/O on/O how/O much/O high-level/O support/O the/O project/O attracts/O ./O 
``/O If/O President/O Xi/O actually/O travels/O to/O Iran/LOCATION in/O the/O near/O future/O and/O an/O initial/O agreement/O on/O high-speed/O rail/O connectivity/O becomes/O a/O key/O `/O deliverable/O '/O for/O his/O visit/O ,/O the/O project/O could/O gain/O momentum/O relatively/O quickly/O ./O 
Without/O such/O high-level/O attention/O ,/O it/O would/O surely/O take/O longer/O ,/O ''/O said/O Leverett/PERSON ./O 
