Thai/O authorities/O say/O the/O man/O arrested/O in/O connection/O with/O last/O week/O 's/O deadly/O bombing/O at/O a/O shrine/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION is/O not/O cooperating/O with/O investigators/O ./O 
Police/O believe/O he/O is/O part/O of/O a/O people-smuggling/O gang/O ./O 
The/O foreign/O suspect/O reportedly/O refused/O to/O answer/O any/O questions/O or/O provide/O details/O about/O whether/O he/O played/O a/O role/O in/O the/O bomb/O attack/O thatkilled/O 20/O people/O and/O left/O scores/O wounded/O ,/O Thai/O officials/O said/O Sunday/O ./O 
Police/O spokesman/O Prawuth/PERSON Thawornsiri/PERSON also/O said/O the/O detained/O suspect/O may/O have/O been/O part/O of/O a/O people-smuggling/O ring/O helping/O illegal/O migrants/O obtain/O forged/O documents/O ./O 
The/O spokesman/O added/O it/O was/O possible/O the/O attack/O was/O in/O retaliation/O for/O a/O recent/O Thai/O crackdown/O on/O the/O trade/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
``/O They/O -LRB-/O the/O gang/O -RRB-/O are/O unsatisfied/O with/O police/O arresting/O illegal/O entrants/O ,/O ''/O he/O told/O Channel/O 3/O in/O an/O interview/O ./O 
``/O The/O interrogation/O is/O not/O making/O progress/O because/O the/O suspect/O is/O not/O really/O giving/O useful/O information/O ,/O ''/O army/O chief/O General/O Udomdej/PERSON Sitabutr/PERSON told/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O We/O have/O to/O conduct/O further/O interrogations/O and/O make/O him/O better/O understand/O so/O he/O will/O be/O more/O cooperative/O -/O while/O we/O have/O to/O be/O careful/O not/O to/O violate/O the/O suspect/O 's/O rights/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
The/O 28-year-old/O foreigner/O was/O arrested/O on/O Saturday/O at/O a/O flat/O in/O Nong/PERSON Jok/PERSON on/O Bangkok/LOCATION 's/O eastern/O outskirts/O ./O 
Police/O allegedly/O found/O bomb-making/O materials/O as/O well/O as/O a/O stack/O of/O fake/O passports/O at/O the/O property/O ./O 
Police/O spokesman/O Prawuth/PERSON said/O the/O materials/O were/O similar/O to/O those/O used/O in/O the/O bomb/O that/O went/O off/O at/O the/O Erawan/O Shrine/O in/O the/O heart/O of/O the/O Thai/O capital/O on/O August/O 17/O ./O 
He/O added/O ,/O however/O ,/O that/O the/O detained/O man/O may/O only/O be/O linked/O to/O the/O attack/O ,/O not/O the/O bomber/O himself/O ./O 
Thais/O mourn/O victims/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O worst-ever/O bombing/O attack/O Identity/O unknown/O The/O suspect/O ,/O whose/O identity/O is/O yet/O to/O be/O verified/O ,/O is/O being/O held/O at/O an/O army/O base/O north/O of/O Bangkok/LOCATION on/O charges/O of/O possessing/O illegal/O explosives/O ./O 
Local/O reports/O suggested/O he/O could/O be/O from/O Turkey/LOCATION ,/O but/O the/O Turkish/O embassy/O has/O denied/O the/O claim/O ./O 
Following/O the/O blast/O ,/O images/O were/O circulated/O of/O a/O yellow-shirted/O individual/O who/O was/O captured/O on/O camera/O leaving/O a/O bag/O at/O the/O scene/O of/O the/O explosion/O ./O 
It/O 's/O not/O clear/O whether/O the/O man/O arrested/O Saturday/O is/O the/O same/O man/O in/O the/O video/O footage/O ./O 
Thai/O police/O on/O Sunday/O were/O monitoring/O about/O 1,000/O mobile/O phone/O numbers/O and/O checking/O photographs/O used/O in/O some/O 200/O seized/O passports/O to/O track/O down/O other/O people/O who/O may/O have/O been/O involved/O in/O orchestrating/O the/O strike/O ./O 
Who/O 's/O responsible/O ?/O 
But/O local/O officials/O and/O experts/O haveput/O forward/O a/O number/O of/O potential/O perpetrators/O and/O motives/O ./O 
Some/O experts/O have/O suggested/O southern/O ethnic/O Malay/O insurgents/O ,/O opponents/O of/O the/O military/O government/O and/O sympathizers/O of/O Uighur/O Muslims/O may/O be/O behind/O the/O bombing/O ./O 
Thailand/LOCATION forcibly/O repatriated/O more/O than/O 100/O Uighur/O refugees/O to/O China/LOCATION last/O month/O ,/O prompting/O an/O international/O outcry/O ./O 
nm/bk/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O dpa/O -RRB-/O 
