Once/O again/O ,/O secret/O talks/O with/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION representatives/O are/O said/O to/O have/O taken/O place/O -/O this/O time/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Given/O the/O string/O of/O deadly/O attacks/O in/O their/O country/O ,/O Afghans/O have/O reacted/O to/O the/O alleged/O meeting/O with/O skepticism/O ./O 
According/O to/O some/O Afghan/O and/O Western/O media/O outlets/O ,/O an/O Afghan/O peace/O delegation/O and/O former/O officials/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION regime/O held/O secret/O talks/O last/O week/O in/O the/O northwestern/O Chinese/O city/O of/O Urumqi/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Afghan/O delegation/O was/O reportedly/O headed/O by/O Masoom/PERSON Stanekzai/PERSON ,/O secretary/O of/O the/O Afghan/O government/O 's/O High/ORGANIZATION Peace/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O who/O has/O also/O been/O nominated/O as/O defense/O minister/O by/O President/O Ashraf/PERSON Ghani/PERSON ./O 
According/O to/O some/O reports/O ,/O three/O representatives/O of/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION -/O Mullah/PERSON Abdul/PERSON Jalil/PERSON ,/O Mullah/PERSON Abdul/PERSON Razaq/PERSON and/O Mullah/PERSON Hassan/PERSON Rahmani/PERSON -/O participated/O in/O the/O negotiations/O ./O 
Also/O present/O were/O officials/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O spy/O agency/O ,/O the/O Inter-Services/ORGANIZATION Intelligence/ORGANIZATION 's/O -LRB-/O ISI/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O who/O reportedly/O facilitated/O the/O talks/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O officially/O denied/O any/O knowledge/O of/O the/O alleged/O meeting/O ,/O but/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ,/O in/O the/O past/O ,/O has/O shown/O a/O great/O deal/O of/O interest/O in/O a/O peaceful/O settlement/O in/O neighboring/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
``/O Beijing/LOCATION should/O have/O known/O something/O about/O this/O meeting/O ,/O ''/O Wang/PERSON Lian/PERSON ,/O a/O political/O scientist/O at/O Beijing/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O Probably/O China/LOCATION does/O n't/O want/O to/O talk/O about/O it/O ,/O mainly/O because/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION are/O perceived/O as/O extremists/O and/O terrorists/O ,/O but/O eventually/O ,/O if/O the/O reconciliation/O process/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION succeeds/O ,/O it/O will/O be/O good/O for/O China/LOCATION ./O 
It/O is/O also/O about/O China/LOCATION 's/O own/O security/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
The/O alleged/O Urumqi/LOCATION talks/O are/O the/O latest/O in/O a/O series/O of/O similar/O unofficial/O meetings/O between/O Afghan/O officials/O and/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION in/O Qatar/LOCATION and/O Iran/LOCATION ./O 
Both/O parties/O deny/O that/O these/O talks/O have/O taken/O place/O ,/O and/O this/O time/O it/O is/O no/O different/O :/O ``/O We/O have/O received/O no/O information/O about/O a/O meeting/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O according/O to/O High/ORGANIZATION Peace/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION 's/O Shahzada/PERSON Shahid/PERSON ./O 
``/O These/O are/O only/O rumors/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
Afghan/O experts/O and/O lawmakers/O have/O criticized/O the/O secrecy/O over/O the/O talks/O because/O President/O Ghani/PERSON had/O promised/O that/O the/O discussions/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION would/O be/O transparent/O ./O 
``/O The/O Afghans/O are/O unhappy/O with/O the/O government/O ./O 
There/O have/O been/O no/O real/O peace/O talks/O to/O date/O ,/O ''/O said/O Haji/PERSON Abdulhai/PERSON Akhondzada/PERSON ,/O a/O parliamentarianfrom/O Helmand/LOCATION Province/LOCATION and/O deputy/O chairman/O of/O the/O parliament/O 's/O Commission/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Internal/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O Until/O now/O ,/O the/O talks/O have/O been/O only/O about/O how/O to/O start/O the/O talks/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
But/O the/O victims/O are/O the/O people/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Akhondzada/PERSON told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O The/O security/O situation/O in/O the/O country/O is/O getting/O worse/O by/O the/O day/O ./O 
There/O are/O no/O positive/O developments/O ,/O and/O there/O is/O fighting/O in/O each/O province/O ./O 
The/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION are/O in/O the/O midst/O of/O their/O spring/O offensive/O ,/O and/O they/O will/O only/O be/O willing/O to/O talk/O if/O their/O offensive/O fails/O ./O ''/O 
The/O parliamentarian/O added/O that/O the/O government/O in/O Kabul/LOCATION had/O made/O no/O progress/O in/O this/O regard/O ,/O and/O that/O the/O Pakistani/O leadership/O had/O failed/O to/O keep/O its/O promise/O of/O bringing/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION to/O the/O negotiating/O table/O ./O 
Afghan/O political/O analyst/O Ahmad/PERSON Saeedi/PERSON agrees/O and/O argues/O that/O it/O makes/O no/O sense/O to/O engage/O in/O talks/O with/O former/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION officials/O ./O 
``/O Those/O based/O in/O the/O Emirates/O and/O other/O Arab/O countries/O have/O almost/O no/O influence/O on/O the/O activities/O of/O today/O 's/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O he/O told/O DW/O ./O 
Experts/O agree/O that/O only/O if/O the/O ISI/ORGANIZATION genuinely/O cooperates/O with/O Kabul/LOCATION ,/O will/O any/O demands/O made/O on/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION carry/O some/O weight/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION recently/O announced/O it/O would/O support/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O the/O fight/O against/O common/O enemies/O ./O 
And/O last/O week/O ,/O Kabul/LOCATION announced/O that/O the/O Afghan/O and/O Pakistani/O governments/O had/O agreed/O to/O forge/O a/O partnership/O between/O their/O intelligence/O agencies/O ./O 
The/O agreement/O stipulates/O that/O both/O sides/O share/O information/O regarding/O future/O operations/O and/O the/O fight/O against/O insurgents/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O controversial/O deal/O has/O been/O criticized/O by/O a/O majority/O of/O Afghans/O ./O 
Saeedi/PERSON believes/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O pledge/O of/O support/O is/O only/O a/O game/O ./O 
``/O Pakistani/O Prime/O Minister/O Nawaz/PERSON Sharif/PERSON told/O the/O media/O on/O May/O 25/O that/O his/O government/O wanted/O to/O fight/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
One/O day/O later/O ,/O however/O ,/O we/O saw/O renewed/O attacks/O in/O the/O Afghan/O provinces/O of/O Kandahar/LOCATION ,/O Wardak/PERSON and/O Baghlan/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
According/O to/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O number/O of/O civilian/O casualties/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION has/O reached/O a/O new/O record/O ./O 
In/O the/O first/O four/O months/O of/O the/O year/O ,/O a/O total/O of/O 974/O Afghans/O were/O killed/O and/O 1,963/O others/O were/O injured/O -/O a/O 16/O percent/O rise/O compared/O to/O the/O same/O period/O last/O year/O ./O 
This/O is/O why/O Saeedi/PERSON believes/O that/O the/O Pakistani/O pledges/O are/O just/O empty/O words/O ./O 
``/O If/O they/O truly/O want/O to/O contribute/O ,/O they/O first/O need/O to/O banish/O the/O Haqqani/ORGANIZATION Network/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O Quetta/LOCATION Shura/O from/O the/O country/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O he/O doubts/O this/O would/O ever/O happen/O ./O 
