The/O British/O government/O and/O the/O Queen/O are/O receiving/O the/O Chinese/O president/O with/O honors/O ./O 
The/O most/O important/O aspect/O of/O his/O visit/O is/O monetary/O investment/O ;/O human/O rights/O issues/O are/O being/O discreetly/O swept/O under/O the/O red/O carpet/O ./O 
It/O has/O been/O 10/O years/O since/O a/O Chinese/O leader/O visited/O Great/LOCATION Britain/LOCATION ./O 
In/O 2005/O ,/O then/O Prime/O Minister/O Tony/PERSON Blair/PERSON welcomed/O Chinese/O President/O Hu/PERSON Jintao/PERSON ./O 
Now/O Hu/PERSON 's/O successor/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON will/O visit/O the/O United/LOCATION Kingdom/LOCATION for/O four/O days/O ./O 
He/O will/O be/O received/O by/O his/O hosts/O with/O full/O honors/O :/O a/O dinner/O with/O the/O Queen/O is/O scheduled/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O a/O visit/O to/O parliament/O and/O of/O course/O meetings/O with/O Prime/O Minister/O David/PERSON Cameron/PERSON at/O No./O 10/O Downing/LOCATION Street/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Chinese/O guest/O will/O be/O lodging/O at/O Buckingham/LOCATION Palace/LOCATION for/O the/O duration/O of/O his/O stay/O ./O 
``/O For/O Xi/O ,/O the/O images/O that/O his/O Chinese/O audience/O will/O see/O are/O especially/O important/O ,/O ''/O says/O Steve/PERSON Tsang/PERSON from/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Nottingham/ORGANIZATION in/O an/O interview/O with/O DW/O ./O 
``/O There/O is/O no/O more/O optically/O impressive/O state/O visit/O than/O a/O reception/O by/O Queen/O Elizabeth/PERSON II/PERSON ./O ''/O 
The/O reason/O for/O the/O British/O charm/O offensive/O :/O London/LOCATION is/O hoping/O to/O secure/O billions/O of/O euros/O in/O Chinese/O investment/O ./O 
During/O Xi/O 's/O visit/O ,/O the/O two/O nations/O are/O scheduled/O to/O sign/O an/O agreement/O paving/O the/O way/O for/O Chinese/O investment/O in/O a/O nuclear/O reactor/O in/O southern/O England/LOCATION ./O 
Thereafter/O ,/O China/LOCATION itself/O could/O begin/O building/O nuclear/O reactors/O in/O Great/LOCATION Britain/LOCATION ,/O as/O was/O recently/O hinted/O at/O by/O the/O Chancellor/O of/O the/O Exchequer/O ,/O George/PERSON Osborne/PERSON ./O 
However/O ,/O security/O experts/O have/O vehemently/O warned/O against/O turning/O over/O such/O strategically/O important/O infrastructure/O projects/O to/O the/O Chinese/O ./O 
The/O British/O are/O also/O soliciting/O Chinese/O investment/O for/O a/O high-speed/O rail/O project/O between/O the/O capital/O and/O the/O country/O 's/O north/O ./O 
Further/O ,/O the/O government/O seeks/O to/O establish/O London/LOCATION as/O the/O leading/O hub/O for/O Chinese/O financial/O transactions/O outside/O of/O China/LOCATION -/O a/O position/O that/O ,/O among/O others/O ,/O the/O German/O financial/O center/O of/O Frankfurt/LOCATION also/O seeks/O ./O 
According/O to/O Prime/O Minister/O Cameron/PERSON 's/O office/O ,/O Xi/PERSON 's/O visit/O represents/O the/O possibility/O of/O deals/O worth/O some/O 40/O billion/O euro/O -LRB-/O $/O 45/O billion/O -RRB-/O and/O the/O creation/O of/O nearly/O 4,000/O jobs/O ./O 
``/O This/O will/O be/O a/O very/O important/O moment/O for/O British-Chinese/O relations/O ,/O ''/O said/O Cameron/PERSON ahead/O of/O the/O visit/O ./O 
``/O It/O is/O a/O real/O opportunity/O to/O deepen/O our/O relationship/O ./O ''/O 
Relations/O between/O Great/LOCATION Britain/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION have/O been/O strained/O over/O the/O last/O few/O years/O ./O 
In/O 2012/O ,/O Prime/O Minister/O Cameron/PERSON met/O with/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ,/O much/O to/O the/O chagrin/O of/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O 
Cameron/PERSON was/O labelled/O persona/O non/O grata/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION for/O a/O year/O and/O a/O half/O after/O that/O ./O 
London/LOCATION was/O surprised/O at/O the/O magnitude/O of/O the/O chill/O in/O relations/O ./O 
A/O high-ranking/O government/O official/O was/O quoted/O by/O the/O BBC/ORGANIZATION as/O saying/O ,/O ``/O We/O were/O in/O the/O corner/O longer/O than/O the/O foreign/O office/O had/O predicted/O ./O ''/O 
Meanwhile/O ,/O the/O situation/O has/O relaxed/O ./O 
The/O Chinese/O ambassador/O in/O London/LOCATION ,/O Liu/PERSON Xiaoming/PERSON ,/O even/O speaks/O of/O the/O beginning/O of/O a/O new/O ``/O golden/O age/O ''/O in/O relations/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O ./O 
That/O has/O to/O do/O primarily/O with/O Chancellor/O Osborne/PERSON 's/O policies/O toward/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Great/LOCATION Britain/LOCATION was/O one/O of/O the/O first/O Western/O countries/O to/O become/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Asian/ORGANIZATION Infrastructure/ORGANIZATION Investment/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O AIIB/O -RRB-/O ./O 
By/O taking/O that/O step/O ,/O the/O British/O knowingly/O accepted/O the/O discontent/O of/O their/O most/O important/O ally/O ,/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
On/O his/O visit/O to/O China/LOCATION in/O September/O ,/O Osborne/PERSON said/O that/O Great/LOCATION Britain/LOCATION wanted/O to/O be/O ``/O China/LOCATION 's/O best/O partner/O in/O the/O West/O ./O ''/O 
Among/O other/O things/O ,/O the/O chancellor/O visited/O China/LOCATION 's/O turbulent/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ./O 
The/O region/O is/O often/O the/O scene/O of/O clashes/O between/O members/O of/O the/O Uighur/ORGANIZATION Muslim/ORGANIZATION minority/O community/O and/O Chinese/O security/O forces/O ./O 
The/O Uighurs/O see/O themselves/O as/O culturally/O ,/O socially/O and/O economically/O disadvantaged/O ,/O and/O increasingly/O marginalized/O by/O the/O systematic/O settlement/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
The/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION claims/O that/O they/O have/O afforded/O the/O Uighurs/O many/O freedoms/O and/O have/O elevated/O the/O standard/O of/O living/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O leadership/O accuses/O Uighur/O groups/O of/O fomenting/O separatism/O and/O terrorism/O ./O 
In/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O Osborne/PERSON said/O that/O Great/LOCATION Britain/LOCATION sought/O to/O support/O development/O in/O the/O region/O -/O in/O exactly/O the/O same/O year/O that/O moderate/O Uighur/O civil/O rights/O activist/O Ilham/PERSON Tohti/PERSON was/O sentenced/O to/O life/O imprisonment/O by/O a/O Chinese/O court/O ./O 
However/O ,/O he/O refrained/O from/O criticizing/O the/O Chinese/O government/O on/O the/O matter/O ./O 
Osborne/PERSON himself/O then/O had/O to/O suffer/O very/O loud/O criticism/O from/O human/O rights/O organizations/O ./O 
The/O British/O media/O spoke/O of/O kowtowing/O to/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ./O 
Downing/O Street/O is/O also/O being/O criticized/O ahead/O of/O Xi/O 's/O visit/O ./O 
Media/O outlets/O ,/O human/O rights/O groups/O and/O the/O Labour/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION are/O accusing/O the/O government/O of/O not/O making/O an/O issue/O of/O injustice/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O ``/O Times/O ''/O commented/O that/O ``/O Closer/O economic/O relations/O with/O China/LOCATION are/O in/O Great/LOCATION Britain/LOCATION 's/O interest/O ./O 
Yet/O ,/O no/O relationship/O is/O worth/O betraying/O British/O values/O ./O ''/O 
Various/O protests/O are/O planned/O to/O take/O place/O during/O Xi/PERSON 's/O visit/O ./O 
Prince/PERSON Charles/PERSON ,/O a/O friend/O of/O the/O Dalai/O Lama/O ,/O will/O not/O attend/O the/O state/O banquet/O ./O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O side/O has/O self-confidently/O made/O it/O clear/O that/O criticism/O is/O unwanted/O ./O 
After/O Labour/O Party/O Leader/O Jeremy/PERSON Corbyn/PERSON announced/O that/O he/O would/O broach/O the/O subject/O of/O human/O rights/O at/O the/O state/O banquet/O ,/O he/O was/O promptly/O invited/O to/O meet/O with/O Ambassador/O Liu/PERSON Xiaoming/PERSON ./O 
In/O an/O interview/O with/O the/O BBC/ORGANIZATION ,/O Liu/PERSON said/O :/O ``/O I/O think/O the/O British/O are/O gentlemen/O and/O are/O very/O clever/O ./O 
They/O know/O how/O to/O behave/O at/O such/O events/O ./O 
Do/O you/O believe/O that/O the/O Labour/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION will/O bring/O up/O human/O rights/O at/O a/O state/O banquet/O ?/O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O so/O ./O ''/O 
