China/LOCATION 's/O education/O minister/O has/O called/O for/O strict/O adherence/O to/O communist/O ideology/O in/O university/O teaching/O ./O 
His/O remarks/O come/O after/O a/O number/O of/O academics/O have/O been/O dismissed/O or/O even/O imprisoned/O for/O their/O views/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O education/O minister/O Yuan/PERSON Guiren/PERSON has/O vowed/O to/O ban/O university/O textbooks/O seen/O as/O promoting/O Western/O values/O ,/O state/O media/O said/O on/O Friday/O ,/O in/O another/O sign/O of/O an/O Universities/O must/O not/O allow/O any/O remarks/O directed/O against/O party/O leaders/O or/O socialist/O ideology/O ,/O Yuan/PERSON was/O quoted/O as/O saying/O by/O the/O official/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/ORGANIZATION agency/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Yuan/PERSON also/O said/O that/O professors/O should/O ``/O not/O complain/O ,/O vent/O personal/O grievances/O or/O convey/O negative/O emotions/O to/O their/O students/O ,/O ''/O according/O to/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION ,/O but/O instead/O ``/O promote/O the/O ideas/O of/O Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON in/O teaching/O materials/O ,/O classrooms/O and/O our/O minds/O ./O ''/O 
The/O ruling/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O China/LOCATION often/O describes/O concepts/O such/O as/O mulitparty/O elections/O and/O the/O separation/O of/O powers/O as/O ``/O Western/O ./O ''/O 
The/O minister/O 's/O comments/O were/O made/O at/O an/O academic/O conference/O on/O Thursday/O ,/O attended/O by/O the/O heads/O of/O leading/O institutions/O including/O Peking/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION and/O Tsinghua/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION said/O ./O 
They/O come/O amid/O a/O widening/O crackdown/O on/O dissidents/O under/O President/O Xi/O that/O has/O led/O to/O a/O number/O of/O academics/O suffering/O sacking/O or/O even/O imprisonment/O for/O espousing/O views/O critical/O of/O government/O policy/O ./O 
Last/O year/O ,/O outspoken/O economics/O professor/O Xia/PERSON Yeliang/PERSON was/O expelled/O from/O Peking/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION after/O calling/O for/O democratic/O reforms/O ./O 
Another/O economics/O professor/O ,/O was/O sentenced/O to/O life/O imprisonment/O in/O September/O on/O separatism/O charges/O after/O he/O championed/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uighur/ORGANIZATION minority/O during/O lectures/O at/O Minzu/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION in/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Seven/O of/O his/O students/O were/O also/O sentenced/O to/O jail/O terms/O of/O between/O three/O to/O eight/O years/O on/O separatism/O charges/O ./O 
China/LOCATION 's/O universities/O are/O all/O run/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O keeps/O a/O close/O watch/O on/O any/O discussions/O or/O teaching/O that/O it/O sees/O as/O a/O potential/O threat/O to/O its/O power/O ./O 
tj/gb/O -LRB-/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O dpa/O -RRB-/O 
