Residents/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Muslim-majority/LOCATION Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O must/O provide/O DNA/O samples/O when/O applying/O for/O travel/O documents/O ,/O according/O to/O new/O rules/O ./O 
Local/O authorities/O have/O also/O put/O restrictions/O on/O fasting/O during/O Ramadan/O ./O 
The/O Muslim/O holy/O month/O of/O Ramadan/O ,/O which/O began/O this/O week/O ,/O is/O a/O sensitive/O period/O of/O the/O year/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION blames/O the/O Muslim-majority/LOCATION region/O 's/O Uighur/O militants/O for/O attacks/O in/O the/O country/O that/O have/O left/O hundreds/O of/O people/O dead/O in/O recent/O years/O ./O 
Now/O the/O authorities/O have/O mandated/O that/O the/O residents/O of/O the/O Ili/LOCATION Kazakh/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Prefecture/LOCATION provide/O DNA/O samples/O ,/O fingerprints/O ,/O voiceprints/O and/O a/O ``/O three-dimensional/O image/O ''/O in/O order/O to/O apply/O for/O passports/O ./O 
Separate/O documents/O will/O be/O issued/O to/O the/O residents/O for/O travel/O to/O the/O Chinese/O territories/O of/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION and/O Macao/LOCATION ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O self-ruled/O Taiwan/LOCATION ,/O according/O to/O the/O official/O newspaper/O ``/O IIi/O Daily/O ./O ''/O 
The/O new/O policy/O came/O into/O effect/O just/O before/O Ramadan/O with/O rights/O activists/O accusing/O Chinese/O authorities/O of/O a/O discriminatory/O attitude/O towards/O the/O country/O 's/O minority/O group/O ./O 
Those/O who/O fail/O to/O fulfill/O the/O requirements/O will/O be/O refused/O documents/O ./O 
Ili/LOCATION Prefecture/LOCATION is/O part/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION and/O borders/O Mongolia/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION and/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION ./O 
A/O Xinjiang/LOCATION government/O website/O also/O called/O on/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O ,/O government/O officials/O ,/O students/O and/O minors/O to/O not/O fast/O during/O Ramadan/O ./O 
``/O During/O the/O Ramadan/O month/O ,/O food/O and/O drink/O businesses/O must/O not/O close/O ,/O ''/O a/O report/O in/O ``/O The/O Wall/O Street/O Journal/O ''/O cited/O a/O local/O government/O website/O as/O saying/O ./O 
`/O Colonizing/O power/O '/O In/O 2014/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O blamed/O Xinjiang/LOCATION Islamists/O and/O separatists/O for/O aspate/O of/O violent/O attacks/O at/O transport/O hubs/O throughout/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON vowed/O to/O follow/O a/O ``/O strike-first/O approach/O against/O terrorists/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O ''/O stating/O that/O long-term/O stability/O in/O the/O region/O was/O ``/O vital/O to/O the/O whole/O country/O 's/O reform/O ./O ''/O 
``/O The/O Chinese/O policies/O targeting/O Islamic/O customs/O seem/O to/O reflect/O a/O misdiagnosis/O of/O the/O problem/O of/O Uighur/O discontent/O and/O separatism/O ./O 
It/O is/O clear/O to/O many/O outside/O observers/O ,/O and/O stated/O resoundingly/O by/O Uighur/O exile/O groups/O ,/O that/O extremist/O religion/O is/O only/O one/O element/O in/O Uighur/O discontent/O ,/O ''/O James/PERSON Millward/PERSON ,/O a/O US-based/O China/LOCATION expert/O and/O historian/O ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
Experts/O have/O said/O that/O Uighur/PERSON Muslims/PERSON ,/O a/O Turkic-speaking/O minority/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ,/O have/O long/O facedpersecution/O by/O the/O country/O 's/O Communist/O authorities/O ./O 
They/O are/O a/O distinct/O and/O mostly/O Sunni/O Muslim/O community/O and/O one/O of/O the/O 55/O recognized/O ethnic/O minorities/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O Uighurs/O feel/O increasingly/O oppressed/O and/O view/O Beijing/LOCATION as/O a/O ``/O colonizing/O power/O ''/O attempting/O to/O undermine/O their/O cultural/O identity/O ,/O political/O rights/O and/O religion/O and/O to/O exploit/O their/O region/O 's/O natural/O resources/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O raised/O its/O security/O budget/O for/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ``/O Uighurs/O identify/O themselves/O as/O the/O original/O inhabitants/O of/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ,/O which/O they/O describe/O as/O `/O East/LOCATION Turkistan/LOCATION ./O '/O 
Many/O of/O the/O Turkic-speaking/O Uighurs/O feel/O closer/O to/O Central/O Asian/O states/O and/O are/O in/O favor/O of/O separating/O from/O China/LOCATION or/O receiving/O greater/O autonomy/O ,/O ''/O Siegfried/PERSON O./PERSON Wolf/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O research/O at/O the/O Brussels-based/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION Democratic/O Forum/O -LRB-/O SADF/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O Therefore/O ,/O it/O does/O not/O come/O as/O a/O surprise/O that/O Chinese/O security/O officials/O are/O dealing/O with/O them/O very/O strictly/O and/O want/O to/O have/O Xinjiang/LOCATION under/O their/O tight/O control/O ,/O for/O both/O economic/O and/O geo-strategic/O reasons/O ,/O ''/O the/O expert/O added/O ./O 
Radicalization/O and/O militancy/O In/O the/O past/O few/O years/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O acted/O strictly/O against/O the/O separatists/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
This/O haspushed/O many/O Uighurs/O towards/O radicalization/O and/O militancy/O ./O 
The/O situation/O has/O also/O been/O aggravated/O as/O Uighur/O separatism/O is/O not/O only/O an/O ethnic/O movement/O but/O also/O has/O a/O religious/O dimension/O ./O 
The/O Uighur/O issue/O is/O generally/O viewed/O as/O an/O internal/O Chinese/O security/O problem/O ,/O but/O some/O experts/O argue/O it/O should/O also/O be/O looked/O at/O in/O the/O context/O of/O global/O jihad/O and/O Islamic/O fundamentalism/O ./O 
The/O crucial/O point/O ,/O the/O analysts/O say/O ,/O is/O that/O the/O Uighur/O case/O is/O being/O increasingly/O hijacked/O by/O the/O jihadi/O movements/O ,/O particularly/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O where/O a/O number/O of/O Uighur/O militants/O are/O reportedly/O fighting/O alongside/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O al/O Qaeda/O ./O 
``/O Militant/O group/O `/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION '/O -LRB-/O IS/O -RRB-/O has/O declared/O jihad/O against/O China/LOCATION on/O the/O grounds/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O mistreating/O the/O Uighur/O Muslim/O population/O ./O 
This/O classic/O Sunni/O jihadist/O propaganda/O based/O on/O the/O persecution/O of/O the/O Uighurs/O is/O evident/O in/O videos/O and/O other/O jihadist/O material/O in/O which/O IS/O has/O called/O for/O global/O jihad/O and/O an/O uprising/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O ''/O Wolf/PERSON explained/O ./O 
Watch/O video/O 05:12/O Violence/O in/O North-Western/LOCATION China/LOCATION :/O Why/O Uighurs/O exiled/O in/O Germany/LOCATION are/O worried/O 
