A/O car/O has/O exploded/O near/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION killing/O at/O least/O one/O person/O ,/O according/O to/O media/O reports/O ./O 
Three/O people/O have/O also/O been/O wounded/O ./O 
The/O Kyrgyz/O state/O security/O authority/O GKNB/ORGANIZATION said/O on/O Tuesday/O that/O it/O was/O carrying/O out/O an/O investigation/O after/O a/O car/O blew/O up/O near/O the/O Chinese/O embassy/O in/O the/O capital/O ,/O Bishkek/LOCATION ,/O killing/O at/O least/O one/O person/O and/O wounding/O several/O others/O ./O 
The/O Russian/O news/O agency/O Interfax/ORGANIZATION cited/O a/O representative/O of/O the/O emergency/O minister/O as/O saying/O that/O the/O exact/O death/O toll/O was/O being/O verified/O ./O 
According/O to/O local/O medics/O ,/O the/O driver/O of/O the/O car/O was/O killed/O while/O two/O Kyrgyz/O embassy/O staff/O and/O a/O woman/O were/O slightly/O wounded/O in/O the/O incident/O ,/O which/O occurred/O around/O 10/O am/O local/O time/O -LRB-/O 0400/O UTC/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Interfax/ORGANIZATION quoted/O Deputy/O Prime/O Minister/O Zhenish/PERSON Razakov/PERSON as/O saying/O it/O was/O a/O suicide/O attack/O and/O that/O the/O car/O had/O rammed/O the/O gate/O of/O the/O embassy/O before/O exploding/O ./O 
Condemnation/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION The/O Chinese/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Ministry/ORGANIZATION called/O the/O incident/O a/O ``/O serious/O terrorist/O attack/O ,/O ''/O stating/O that/O China/LOCATION would/O ``/O resolutely/O strike/O against/O all/O forms/O of/O terrorism/O ./O ''/O 
Authorities/O in/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION ,/O a/O former/O Soviet/O republic/O with/O a/O mostly/O Muslim/O population/O of/O 6/O million/O people/O ,/O have/O detained/O a/O number/O of/O suspected/O Islamist/O militants/O accused/O of/O having/O links/O to/O the/O extremist/O group/O ``/O Islamic/O State/O ''/O -LRB-/O IS/O -RRB-/O ./O 
The/O jihadists/O are/O known/O to/O recruit/O from/O Central/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
The/O region/O has/O also/O seen/O activity/O by/O an/O anti-Chinese/O group/O comprised/O of/O ethnic/O Uighurs/O ./O 
In/O 2014/O ,/O alleged/O members/O of/O the/O group/O illegally/O crossed/O into/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION from/O neighboring/O China/LOCATION and/O were/O intercepted/O by/O Kyrgzyz/PERSON border/O guards/O ./O 
Eleven/O Uighurs/O were/O killed/O ./O 
The/O attack/O comes/O a/O day/O before/O Kyrgyzstan/LOCATION celebrates/O the/O 25th/O anniversary/O of/O its/O independence/O from/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ./O 
tj/jm/O -LRB-/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION ,/O AFP/O -RRB-/O 
