German/O Foreign/O Minister/O Frank-Walter/PERSON Steinmeier/PERSON has/O arrived/O in/O China/LOCATION on/O a/O two-day/O official/O visit/O ./O 
In/O a/O DW/O interview/O ,/O China/LOCATION expert/O Moritz/PERSON Rudolf/PERSON discusses/O Germany/LOCATION 's/O China/LOCATION policy/O and/O bilateral/O relations/O ./O 
DW/O :/O What/O are/O the/O most/O important/O foreign/O and/O security/O issues/O for/O China/LOCATION and/O Germany/LOCATION ?/O 
Moritz/PERSON Rudolf/PERSON :/O Germany/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION want/O political/O stability/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O especially/O in/O Syria/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O conflicts/O in/O these/O countries/O indirectly/O affect/O Berlin/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O and/O that/O is/O the/O reason/O why/O both/O these/O countries/O are/O involved/O in/O Syrian/O talks/O ./O 
Germany/LOCATION has/O an/O interest/O in/O resolving/O the/O Syrian/O crisis/O as/O it/O is/O facing/O an/O influx/O of/O refugees/O from/O the/O war-torn/O country/O ./O 
China/LOCATION wants/O a/O stable/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION so/O that/O it/O can/O proceed/O with/O its/O Silk/LOCATION Road/LOCATION plans/O ./O 
China/LOCATION fears/O that/O an/O escalation/O of/O the/O civil/O war/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION could/O destabilize/O its/O western/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O China/LOCATION supports/O the/O US/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION in/O their/O efforts/O to/O engage/O in/O peace/O talks/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Germany/LOCATION has/O long/O been/O engaged/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O it/O is/O in/O Berlin/LOCATION 's/O interest/O that/O the/O Afghan/O government/O does/O n't/O fail/O ./O 
Both/O countries/O are/O also/O concerned/O about/O their/O radicalized/O citizens/O receiving/O militant/O training/O in/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O threat/O they/O could/O pose/O when/O they/O return/O to/O Germany/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Rudolf/PERSON :/O `/O Germany/LOCATION wants/O China/LOCATION to/O increase/O its/O involvement/O in/O international/O peace/O efforts/O '/O Germany/LOCATION wants/O China/LOCATION to/O increase/O its/O involvement/O in/O the/O ``/O international/O security/O architecture/O ./O ''/O 
Its/O aim/O is/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION accepts/O more/O political/O responsibility/O to/O deal/O with/O global/O security/O challenges/O ./O 
On/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O China/LOCATION wants/O to/O be/O seen/O as/O a/O responsible/O actor/O in/O world/O politics/O ,/O but/O without/O raising/O its/O stakes/O ./O 
However/O ,/O in/O the/O case/O of/O North/LOCATION Korea/LOCATION 's/O belligerence/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O proven/O it/O is/O fully/O capable/O to/O take/O over/O security/O responsibilities/O ./O 
Is/O the/O fight/O against/O Islamic/O terrorism/O a/O new/O element/O of/O cooperation/O between/O Berlin/LOCATION and/O Beijing/LOCATION ?/O 
So/O far/O ,/O the/O West/LOCATION has/O been/O critical/O ,/O and/O has/O seen/O China/LOCATION 's/O fight/O against/O Islamists/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION as/O repressive/O ./O 
It/O would/O be/O welcomed/O if/O Germany/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION could/O find/O a/O way/O to/O separate/O the/O conflict/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION from/O the/O terrorism/O discourse/O ./O 
This/O is/O precisely/O what/O had/O failed/O in/O the/O past/O --/O a/O common/O approach/O to/O combat/O Islamic/O extremism/O ./O 
I/O expect/O that/O China/LOCATION would/O be/O willing/O to/O compromise/O on/O this/O issue/O and/O acknowledge/O that/O cooperation/O in/O combating/O terrorism/O does/O not/O imply/O endorsement/O of/O its/O minority/O policies/O ./O 
The/O far-reaching/O infrastructure/O projects/O in/O Eurasia/LOCATION draw/O China/LOCATION into/O areas/O where/O Islamist/O terrorism/O is/O a/O major/O threat/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O Chinese/O nationals/O are/O a/O potential/O target/O for/O Islamic/O terrorists/O who/O do/O not/O have/O direct/O connections/O to/O the/O conflict/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
Both/O sides/O want/O -/O as/O evident/O by/O statements/O released/O after/O their/O first/O ``/O strategic/O dialogue/O ''/O in/O November/O last/O year/O --/O a/O dialogue/O on/O international/O law/O and/O regional/O issues/O ./O 
In/O this/O respect/O ,/O tensions/O in/O the/O East/O and/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION come/O to/O mind/O ./O 
Japan/LOCATION ,/O which/O hosts/O the/O G7/O meeting/O this/O year/O ,/O is/O directly/O involved/O in/O the/O conflict/O ./O 
What/O role/O could/O Berlin/LOCATION play/O in/O this/O regard/O ?/O 
Germany/LOCATION should/O work/O towards/O finding/O a/O legal/O solution/O to/O the/O territorial/O conflicts/O ./O 
A/O tribunal/O recognized/O by/O all/O parties/O could/O resolve/O the/O disputes/O ,/O but/O Beijing/LOCATION prefers/O bilateral/O solutions/O ./O 
Berlin/LOCATION could/O assume/O the/O role/O of/O a/O mediator/O in/O the/O East/O and/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION conflicts/O ./O 
But/O Germany/LOCATION would/O first/O have/O to/O be/O a/O part/O of/O the/O conflict/O in/O order/O to/O be/O recognized/O as/O a/O serious/O mediator/O ./O 
For/O this/O to/O happen/O ,/O Germany/LOCATION could/O initially/O increase/O pressure/O on/O China/LOCATION by/O providing/O ,/O for/O example/O ,/O military/O equipment/O to/O countries/O bordering/O the/O South/LOCATION China/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION ./O 
Berlin/LOCATION would/O then/O certainly/O find/O its/O place/O at/O the/O negotiating/O table/O ./O 
This/O scenario/O is/O quite/O possible/O in/O light/O of/O the/O worsening/O situation/O ./O 
What/O chances/O for/O cooperation/O could/O arise/O from/O the/O fact/O that/O China/LOCATION chairs/O the/O G20/O group/O this/O year/O and/O Germany/LOCATION will/O take/O over/O next/O year/O ?/O 
What/O could/O be/O the/O possible/O outcomes/O ?/O 
China/LOCATION has/O increased/O foreign/O investments/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O and/O is/O also/O proposing/O to/O finance/O land/O and/O sea/O passages/O -LRB-/O known/O as/O the/O ``/O New/O Silk/O Road/O ''/O -RRB-/O to/O Europe/LOCATION for/O an/O increase/O in/O economic/O exchange/O ./O 
The/O ``/O economic/O connectivity/O ''/O between/O Asia/LOCATION and/O Europe/LOCATION could/O serve/O as/O a/O link/O between/O the/O Chinese/O and/O German/O chairmanships/O of/O the/O G20/O bloc/O ./O 
As/O chairman/O of/O the/O Organization/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION and/O Cooperation/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O Germany/LOCATION has/O demonstrated/O that/O it/O understands/O the/O importance/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O Silk/O Road/O initiative/O ./O 
A/O major/O obstacle/O to/O this/O is/O that/O the/O Chinese/O initiative/O is/O not/O concrete/O enough/O to/O convince/O other/O countries/O of/O its/O merits/O ./O 
Germany/LOCATION could/O contribute/O to/O the/O Eurasian/O economic/O connectivity/O by/O creating/O an/O institutional/O framework/O and/O protecting/O its/O own/O interests/O at/O the/O same/O time/O ./O 
For/O example/O ,/O Berlin/LOCATION wants/O the/O Chinese/O initiative/O to/O be/O more/O sustainable/O ,/O with/O the/O keywords/O being/O ``/O Green/O Silk/O Roads/O ./O ''/O 
Moritz/PERSON Rudolf/PERSON is/O a/O researcher/O at/O the/O Berlin-based/O Mercator/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION China/ORGANIZATION Studies/ORGANIZATION ./O 
He/O focuses/O on/O China/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O policy/O and/O geo-strategy/O ./O 
