A/O series/O of/O coordinated/O blasts/O has/O been/O carried/O in/O in/O several/O of/O Thailand/LOCATION 's/O popular/O resorts/O ,/O leaving/O four/O dead/O and/O dozens/O wounded/O ./O 
Local/O authorities/O said/O the/O attacks/O were/O ``/O local/O sabotage/O ''/O and/O not/O of/O a/O ``/O terrorist/O ''/O nature/O ./O 
Thai/O authorities/O reported/O on/O Friday/O that/O a/O series/O of/O coordinated/O explosions/O had/O been/O detonated/O in/O at/O least/O four/O cities/O over/O the/O past/O 24/O hours/O ,/O including/O the/O popular/O seaside/O resort/O of/O Hua/PERSON Hin/PERSON and/O the/O tourist/O beach/O town/O of/O Patong/LOCATION on/O Phuket/LOCATION Island/LOCATION ./O 
Several/O of/O the/O attacks/O were/O twin/O blasts/O ./O 
National/O police/O deputy/O spokesman/O Piyapan/PERSON Pingmuang/PERSON confirmed/O that/O four/O people/O were/O killed/O in/O the/O blasts/O ./O 
Foreigners/O are/O believed/O to/O be/O among/O the/O dead/O ./O 
Dozens/O of/O others/O were/O injured/O ,/O including/O three/O Germans/O ./O 
It/O was/O not/O immediately/O clear/O who/O was/O behind/O for/O the/O attacks/O ,/O although/O authorities/O ruled/O out/O international/O terrorists/O ./O 
Twin/O blasts/O such/O as/O those/O seen/O on/O Thursday/O and/O Friday/O are/O common/O in/O the/O three/O Muslim-majority/LOCATION southernmost/O provinces/O of/O Thailand/LOCATION ,/O where/O a/O bloody/O insurgency/O has/O killed/O more/O than/O 6,500/O people/O since/O 2004/O ./O 
Thai/O authorities/O dismissed/O speculation/O ,/O however/O ,/O that/O Muslim/O rebels/O were/O responsible/O for/O the/O most/O recent/O blasts/O ./O 
``/O It/O is/O just/O local/O sabotage/O that/O is/O restricted/O to/O limited/O areas/O and/O provinces/O ,/O ''/O Pingmuang/PERSON told/O reporters/O in/O Bangkok/LOCATION ./O 
Sensitive/O timing/O The/O bombings/O on/O Thursday/O and/O Friday/O came/O at/O a/O sensitive/O time/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ,/O with/O this/O weekend/O marking/O Queen/O Sirikit/PERSON 's/O 84th/O birthday/O ./O 
A/O contentious/O referendum/O put/O forward/O by/O the/O military/O junta/O was/O also/O approved/O last/O week/O ,/O paving/O the/O way/O for/O a/O new/O constitution/O and/O elections/O next/O year/O ./O 
Opponents/O of/O the/O military-drafted/O constitution/O argue/O that/O it/O is/O laced/O with/O undemocratic/O principles/O and/O was/O designed/O to/O keep/O the/O military/O in/O power/O for/O five/O more/O years/O ./O 
The/O coordinated/O explosions/O were/O also/O carried/O out/O just/O days/O before/O the/O one-year/O anniversary/O of/O the/O last/O major/O attack/O on/O tourists/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O 
A/O bomb/O in/O the/O Thai/O capital/O ripped/O through/O a/O Hindi/O shrine/O on/O August/O 17/O ,/O last/O year/O ,/O killed/O 20/O people/O most/O of/O whom/O were/O foreigners/O ./O 
Thai/O authorities/O accused/O two/O Uighur/O men/O from/O western/O China/LOCATION of/O the/O bombing/O ,/O the/O deadliest/O attack/O of/O its/O kind/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION in/O recent/O years/O ./O 
The/O two/O accused/O have/O denied/O involvement/O in/O the/O attack/O and/O their/O trial/O is/O set/O to/O begin/O later/O this/O month/O ./O 
ksb/rs/O -LRB-/O AFP/ORGANIZATION ,/O AP/ORGANIZATION ,/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O 
