The/O US/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION have/O agreed/O to/O bolster/O defense/O and/O trade/O ties/O with/O an/O aim/O to/O minimize/O China/LOCATION 's/O influence/O in/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION and/O Islamabad/LOCATION are/O forging/O their/O own/O alliance/O ,/O which/O could/O increase/O tension/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
US/LOCATION Secretary/O of/O State/O John/PERSON Kerry/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O currently/O on/O a/O trip/O to/O India/LOCATION ,/O has/O made/O it/O clear/O that/O Washington/LOCATION wants/O to/O see/O India/LOCATION in/O a/O more/O powerful/O role/O in/O the/O South/O Asian/O region/O ./O 
Not/O only/O is/O the/O US/LOCATION moving/O ahead/O on/O a/O nuclear/O deal/O with/O India/LOCATION ,/O it/O is/O also/O aiming/O to/O increase/O the/O bilateral/O trade/O to/O around/O $/O 500/O billion/O -LRB-/O 448/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O annually/O ./O 
``/O I/O 'm/O very/O ,/O very/O confident/O that/O we/O will/O continue/O to/O strengthen/O what/O President/O Obama/PERSON has/O called/O the/O defining/O partnership/O of/O the/O 21st/O century/O ,/O ''/O Kerry/PERSON said/O in/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION ,/O adding/O that/O cooperation/O on/O trade/O and/O security/O had/O ``/O room/O to/O be/O able/O to/O further/O grow/O ./O ''/O 
``/O We/O also/O hope/O to/O see/O our/O civil/O nuclear/O cooperation/O take/O shape/O in/O the/O form/O of/O new/O reactors/O that/O will/O deliver/O reliable/O electricity/O to/O tens/O of/O millions/O of/O Indian/O households/O ,/O ''/O Kerry/PERSON said/O ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION is/O actively/O supporting/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION 's/O bid/O for/O the/O Nuclear/ORGANIZATION Suppliers/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O NSG/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O which/O has/O been/O opposed/O by/O India/LOCATION 's/O archrivals/O China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
Indian/O Foreign/O Minister/O Sushma/PERSON Swaraj/PERSON said/O the/O India-US/O military/O cooperation/O would/O also/O get/O a/O boost/O as/O her/O country/O wanted/O to/O build/O more/O sophisticated/O hardware/O at/O home/O with/O US/LOCATION cooperation/O ./O 
``/O We/O want/O to/O take/O our/O expanding/O defense/O cooperation/O to/O the/O next/O stage/O of/O co-production/O and/O co-development/O ,/O ''/O Swaraj/PERSON said/O at/O a/O conference/O alongside/O Kerry/PERSON ./O 
Experts/O say/O that/O the/O US/LOCATION wants/O India/LOCATION to/O play/O a/O greater/O role/O in/O the/O region/O to/O counter/O China/LOCATION 's/O growing/O strategic/O and/O military/O assertiveness/O ./O 
Amit/PERSON Cowshish/PERSON ,/O a/O former/O Financial/O Advisor/O -LRB-/O Acquisition/O -RRB-/O for/O India/LOCATION 's/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Defense/ORGANIZATION ,/O says/O it/O is/O logical/O and/O understandable/O that/O the/O US/LOCATION considers/O India/LOCATION a/O committed/O ally/O in/O the/O South/LOCATION Asian/LOCATION region/O :/O ``/O Shared/O democratic/O values/O and/O common/O interests/O in/O fields/O other/O than/O defense/O are/O the/O main/O drivers/O of/O the/O India-US/O relationship/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O India/LOCATION 's/O role/O as/O a/O stabilizing/O factor/O in/O the/O region/O and/O convergence/O between/O the/O two/O countries/O on/O US/LOCATION policy/O of/O Rebalance/O in/O Asia-Pacific/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION 's/O Act/O East/O policy/O that/O drives/O close/O defense/O ties/O ,/O ''/O Cowshish/PERSON told/O DW/O ./O 
The/O changing/O geopolitics/O in/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION has/O prompted/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O forge/O closer/O ties/O with/O its/O long-time/O ally/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION is/O expanding/O trade/O and/O military/O cooperation/O with/O Islamabad/LOCATION keeping/O in/O view/O the/O New/LOCATION Delhi-Washington/LOCATION maneuvers/O ./O 
Last/O year/O ,/O China/LOCATION announced/O an/O economic/O project/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION worth/O $/O 46/O billion/O -LRB-/O 41/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O ./O 
With/O the/O China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION aims/O to/O expand/O its/O influence/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O across/O Central/O and/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION in/O order/O to/O counter/O US/LOCATION and/O Indian/O influences/O ./O 
The/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION would/O link/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O southern/O Gwadar/LOCATION port/O on/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION to/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ./O 
It/O also/O includes/O plans/O to/O create/O road/O ,/O rail/O and/O oil/O pipeline/O links/O to/O improve/O connectivity/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION is/O currently/O grappling/O with/O an/O acute/O economic/O crisis/O ./O 
Experts/O say/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION can/O certainly/O stir/O the/O much-needed/O economic/O activity/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
``/O Pakistan/LOCATION knows/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O going/O to/O be/O the/O superpower/O in/O ten/O years/O ./O 
Islamabad/LOCATION is/O getting/O closer/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION and/O its/O alliance/O with/O Washington/LOCATION is/O slowly/O and/O gradually/O taking/O a/O back/O seat/O ,/O ''/O Ali/PERSON Shah/PERSON ,/O a/O Pakistani/O researcher/O in/O Karachi/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
The/O conflicting/O interests/O of/O the/O US/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION in/O Asia/LOCATION and/O the/O new/O strategic/O formations/O have/O already/O spiked/O tensions/O in/O the/O region/O ./O 
The/O Indian-Pakistani/O ties/O are/O at/O their/O worst/O with/O both/O neighboring/O countries/O accusing/O each/O other/O of/O sponsoring/O terrorism/O ./O 
Since/O July/O 8/O ,/O the/O Indian/O part/O of/O Kashmir/LOCATION has/O been/O in/O a/O grip/O of/O violence/O ./O 
New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION has/O accused/O Islamabad/LOCATION of/O supporting/O separatist/O groups/O in/O the/O valley/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O in/O turn/O ,/O has/O alleged/O that/O Indian/O intelligence/O agencies/O have/O been/O backing/O an/O insurgent/O movement/O in/O its/O western/O Balochistan/LOCATION province/LOCATION ./O 
Kerry/PERSON acknowledged/O that/O the/O deteriorating/O ties/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION were/O having/O a/O negative/O impact/O on/O the/O security/O situation/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O particulary/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O where/O American/O troops/O are/O stationed/O ./O 
The/O top/O US/LOCATION diplomat/O chose/O to/O be/O tough/O with/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O 
``/O It/O is/O clear/O that/O Pakistan/LOCATION has/O work/O to/O do/O in/O order/O to/O push/O harder/O against/O its/O indigenous/O groups/O that/O are/O engaged/O in/O extremist/O terrorist/O activities/O ,/O ''/O Kerry/PERSON said/O in/O an/O address/O to/O students/O in/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION ./O 
``/O They/O must/O work/O with/O us/O to/O help/O clear/O the/O sanctuaries/O of/O bad/O actors/O who/O are/O affecting/O not/O only/O relations/O between/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O India/LOCATION but/O also/O our/O ability/O to/O achieve/O peace/O and/O stability/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
The/O warming/O ties/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O the/O US/LOCATION have/O alarmed/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O analysts/O say/O ./O 
``/O The/O US-India/O security/O agreements/O will/O have/O an/O impact/O on/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
Islamabad/LOCATION is/O rightly/O worried/O ./O 
Why/O should/O Pakistan/LOCATION then/O work/O for/O the/O US/LOCATION interests/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ?/O ''/O 
Talat/PERSON A./PERSON Wazarat/PERSON ,/O an/O International/O Relations/O expert/O from/O Karachi/LOCATION ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O The/O new/O strategy/O is/O aimed/O at/O containing/O China/LOCATION 's/O influence/O ,/O but/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O also/O bearing/O the/O brunt/O ./O 
China/LOCATION ,/O Iran/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION should/O also/O take/O the/O US-India/O deals/O very/O seriously/O and/O do/O something/O about/O it/O ,/O ''/O she/O added/O ./O 
Shuakat/PERSON Qadir/PERSON ,/O a/O security/O analyst/O and/O former/O brigadier/O in/O the/O Pakistani/O army/O ,/O told/O DW/O that/O Islamabad/LOCATION would/O take/O action/O against/O the/O militants/O on/O its/O own/O volition/O ./O 
``/O We/O are/O already/O fighting/O terrorists/O ./O 
The/O US/LOCATION needs/O to/O review/O its/O policies/O also/O ,/O ''/O Qadir/PERSON said/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O military/O and/O civilian/O establishment/O ,/O analysts/O say/O ,/O still/O consider/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION an/O important/O strategic/O ally/O ,/O who/O they/O think/O should/O be/O part/O of/O the/O Afghan/O government/O after/O the/O NATO/ORGANIZATION pullout/O ./O 
Observers/O say/O that/O the/O Pakistani/O military/O hopes/O to/O regain/O the/O influence/O in/O Kabul/LOCATION it/O once/O enjoyed/O before/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O its/O allies/O toppled/O the/O pro-Pakistan/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION government/O in/O 2001/O ./O 
``/O Kabul/LOCATION is/O friendlier/O towards/O New/LOCATION Delhi/LOCATION now/O ,/O whereas/O Islamabad/LOCATION continues/O to/O back/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION wishes/O to/O change/O this/O scenario/O and/O turn/O Afghanistan/LOCATION into/O its/O political/O backyard/O once/O again/O ,/O ''/O London-based/O journalist/O and/O researcher/O Farooq/PERSON Sulehria/PERSON told/O DW/O ./O 
Nonetheless/O ,/O some/O experts/O blame/O the/O growing/O US-China/O rivalry/O for/O the/O worsening/O state/O of/O security/O in/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O believe/O it/O could/O trigger/O new/O conflicts/O and/O plunge/O the/O region/O into/O a/O deeper/O turmoil/O ./O 
India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O they/O say/O ,/O are/O only/O adjusting/O to/O changing/O geopolitics/O ./O 
