Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Tajikistan/LOCATION have/O joined/O a/O security/O alliance/O headed/O by/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Concerned/O about/O an/O Islamist/O insurgency/O in/O its/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O seeking/O to/O increase/O regional/O cooperation/O ./O 
Military/O leaders/O from/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Tajikistan/LOCATION met/O with/O their/O Chinese/O counterparts/O in/O the/O Muslim-majority/LOCATION Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O Wednesday/O to/O announce/O the/O formation/O of/O the/O Quadrilateral/O Cooperation/O and/O Coordination/O Mechanism/O alliance/O ./O 
The/O four/O countries/O pledged/O to/O work/O together/O to/O counter/O terrorism/O and/O share/O intelligence/O ./O 
``/O All/O parties/O reaffirmed/O they/O would/O cooperate/O to/O respond/O to/O these/O -LRB-/O terrorist/O -RRB-/O forces/O ,/O and/O safeguard/O all/O member/O countries/O '/O peace/O and/O stability/O ,/O ''/O the/O official/O Xinhua/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O said/O Thursday/O ./O 
The/O Uighur/O problem/O In/O the/O past/O few/O years/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O has/O acted/O strictly/O against/O the/O Muslim/ORGANIZATION separatists/O in/O Xinjiang/LOCATION ./O 
In/O 2014/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O blamed/O Xinjiang/LOCATION Islamists/O and/O separatists/O for/O a/O spate/O of/O violent/O attacks/O at/O transport/O hubs/O throughout/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON vowed/O to/O follow/O a/O ``/O strike-first/O approach/O against/O terrorists/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O ''/O stating/O that/O long-term/O stability/O in/O the/O region/O was/O ``/O vital/O to/O the/O whole/O country/O 's/O reform/O ./O ''/O 
Beijing/LOCATION is/O equally/O worried/O about/O the/O expansion/O of/O ``/O Islamic/O State/O ''/O -LRB-/O IS/O -RRB-/O in/O neighboring/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O a/O surge/O in/O violence/O in/O the/O war-torn/O country/O ./O 
It/O believes/O that/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION and/O other/O radical/O groups/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION are/O providing/O assistance/O to/O Xinjiang/LOCATION militants/O ./O 
Uighur/O Muslims/O have/O long/O faced/O persecution/O by/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O ``/O China/LOCATION is/O worried/O about/O IS/O gaining/O a/O permanent/O foothold/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O and/O establishing/O links/O to/O Uighur/O militants/O ,/O ''/O Wahid/PERSON Mazhdah/PERSON ,/O a/O former/O employee/O of/O the/O ousted/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION regime/O ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
Uighur/O Muslims/O ,/O a/O Turkic-speaking/O minority/O in/O China/LOCATION 's/O northwestern/O Xinjiang/LOCATION province/O ,/O have/O long/O faced/O persecution/O by/O the/O country/O 's/O communist/O authorities/O ./O 
They/O are/O a/O distinct/O and/O mostly/O Sunni/O Muslim/O community/O and/O one/O of/O the/O 55/O recognized/O ethnic/O minorities/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
However/O ,/O Uighurs/O feel/O increasingly/O oppressed/O and/O view/O Beijing/LOCATION as/O a/O ``/O colonizing/O power/O ''/O attempting/O to/O undermine/O their/O cultural/O identity/O ,/O political/O rights/O and/O religion/O and/O to/O exploit/O their/O region/O 's/O natural/O resources/O ./O 
Faiz/PERSON Mohammad/PERSON Zaland/PERSON ,/O a/O Kabul/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION lecturer/O who/O recently/O met/O with/O a/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION delegation/O in/O Qatar/LOCATION ,/O has/O a/O similar/O view/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION wants/O to/O make/O sure/O Uighur/O militants/O do/O not/O have/O sanctuaries/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION wants/O this/O issue/O to/O be/O part/O of/O the/O negotiations/O ,/O ''/O Zaland/PERSON told/O DW/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION assuming/O a/O bigger/O regional/O role/O Experts/O say/O these/O are/O the/O reasons/O behind/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O offer/O to/O support/O the/O Afghan/O government/O inreconciling/O with/O the/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Media/O reports/O said/O a/O Taliban/ORGANIZATION delegation/O had/O held/O talks/O with/O Chinese/O officials/O on/O two/O occasions/O in/O June/O ./O 
Chinese/O Foreign/O Minister/O Wang/PERSON Yi/PERSON said/O last/O year/O in/O December/O that/O his/O country/O was/O seeking/O a/O leading/O role/O for/O Islamabad/LOCATION to/O resolve/O conflicts/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ,/O pointing/O out/O that/O ``/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O an/O important/O nation/O for/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ''/O and/O ``/O has/O a/O special/O reach/O there/O ./O ''/O 
``/O Broad-based/O and/O inclusive/O national/O reconciliation/O ''/O was/O necessary/O to/O ensure/O Afghanistan/LOCATION 's/O durable/O stability/O ,/O Yi/PERSON commented/O ,/O and/O the/O country/O would/O need/O international/O support/O in/O the/O process/O ./O 
What/O does/O China/LOCATION want/O from/O the/O Afghan/O peace/O process/O ?/O 
China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION are/O close/O allies/O ,/O and/O with/O the/O Islamic/O country/O 's/O frayed/O ties/O with/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O exerting/O its/O influence/O on/O Pakistani/O authorities/O ./O 
``/O Obviously/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O want/O to/O challenge/O the/O American/O hegemony/O in/O the/O region/O and/O this/O looks/O like/O their/O stamp/O of/O authority/O on/O some/O sensitive/O matters/O ,/O ''/O Talat/PERSON Masood/PERSON ,/O a/O retired/O Pakistani/O army/O general/O and/O security/O expert/O ,/O told/O the/O DPA/ORGANIZATION news/O agency/O ./O 
Economic/O interests/O Experts/O say/O that/O another/O important/O reason/O behind/O the/O diplomatic/O push/O may/O be/O China/LOCATION 's/O level/O of/O economic/O engagement/O in/O these/O two/O countries/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O China/LOCATION signed/O deals/O worth/O $/O 46/O billion/O -LRB-/O 41.3/O billion/O euros/O -RRB-/O with/O Pakistan/LOCATION last/O year/O ./O 
President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON also/O inaugurated/O theChina-Pakistan/O Economic/O Corridor/O designed/O to/O create/O a/O network/O of/O roads/O ,/O railways/O and/O pipelines/O linking/O China/LOCATION 's/O restive/O west/O to/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION through/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
According/O to/O Afghan/O experts/O ,/O Chinese/O officials/O are/O striving/O to/O keep/O the/O situation/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O Afghanistan/LOCATION under/O control/O so/O Beijing/LOCATION can/O implement/O its/O economic/O projects/O and/O protect/O its/O investments/O ./O 
``/O China/LOCATION 's/O primary/O goal/O for/O its/O increased/O involvement/O in/O the/O Afghan/O peace/O process/O is/O to/O secure/O its/O economic/O interests/O in/O the/O region/O ,/O ''/O analyst/O Zaland/PERSON said/O ./O 
