Despite/O much-vaunted/O Chinese-Pakistani/O development/O projects/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Gwadar/LOCATION city/O ,/O the/O locals/O still/O have/O no/O access/O to/O clean/O water/O ./O 
And/O separatists/O have/O vowed/O to/O resist/O what/O they/O say/O is/O Sino-Pakistani/O colonization/O ./O 
Last/O year/O ,/O China/LOCATION announced/O an/O economic/O project/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION worth/O $/O 46/O billion/O -LRB-/O about/O 41/O billion/O euro/O -RRB-/O ./O 
With/O the/O China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION aims/O to/O expand/O its/O influence/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O across/O Central/O and/O South/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION in/O order/O to/O counter/O US/LOCATION and/O Indian/O influence/O ./O 
The/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION would/O link/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O southern/O Gwadar/LOCATION port/O on/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION to/O China/LOCATION 's/O western/O Xinjiang/LOCATION region/O ./O 
It/O also/O includes/O plans/O to/O create/O road/O ,/O rail/O and/O oil/O pipeline/O links/O to/O improve/O connectivity/O between/O China/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION is/O grappling/O with/O an/O acute/O economic/O crisis/O ./O 
Experts/O say/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION can/O certainly/O stir/O the/O much-needed/O economic/O activity/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
But/O the/O much-vaunted/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION has/O not/O impressed/O residents/O of/O Gwadar/LOCATION who/O believe/O they/O should/O be/O the/O main/O stakeholder/O of/O development/O projects/O in/O their/O port/O city/O ./O 
Gwadar/LOCATION lacks/O fundamental/O necessities/O of/O life/O like/O clean/O water/O ``/O Just/O look/O at/O the/O condition/O of/O our/O roads/O ,/O our/O homes/O and/O towns/O ;/O we/O still/O lack/O basic/O necessities/O of/O life/O ,/O ''/O Farhad/PERSON Baloch/PERSON ,/O a/O Gwadar/LOCATION resident/O ,/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O Even/O drinking/O water/O is/O a/O rare/O commodity/O in/O the/O area/O ./O 
We/O are/O facing/O a/O drought-like/O situation/O ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
K./PERSON B./PERSON Firaq/PERSON ,/O president/O of/O the/O Gwadar/ORGANIZATION Educational/ORGANIZATION Welfare/ORGANIZATION Society/ORGANIZATION ,/O complains/O that/O the/O locals/O are/O being/O driven/O out/O of/O the/O city/O 's/O port/O area/O to/O make/O way/O for/O Chinese/O workers/O and/O engineers/O ./O 
``/O The/O Gwadar/LOCATION fishermen/O are/O not/O allowed/O near/O the/O port/O boundaries/O ./O 
Thousands/O of/O fishermen/O have/O been/O asked/O to/O leave/O the/O harbor/O ,/O ''/O Firaq/PERSON claimed/O ./O 
Exploitation/O of/O economic/O resources/O Balochistan/LOCATION remains/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O poorest/O and/O least/O populous/O province/O ,/O despite/O a/O number/O of/O development/O projects/O initiated/O by/O the/O government/O in/O Islamabad/LOCATION ./O 
Rebel/O groups/O have/O waged/O a/O separatist/O insurgency/O in/O the/O province/O for/O decades/O ,/O complaining/O that/O Islamabad/LOCATION and/O the/O richer/O Punjab/LOCATION province/O unfairly/O exploit/O their/O resources/O ./O 
Islamabad/LOCATION reacted/O to/O the/O insurgency/O by/O launching/O a/O military/O operation/O in/O the/O province/O in/O 2005/O ./O 
There/O have/O since/O been/O reports/O of/O grave/O human/O rights/O abuses/O committed/O by/O the/O military/O and/O its/O intelligence/O agencies/O in/O the/O province/O ./O 
DW/O recommends/O Activist/O 's/O murder/O spotlights/O army/O 's/O abuses/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O Balochistan/LOCATION Pakistani/O military/O 's/O alleged/O rights/O abuses/O in/O western/O Balochistan/LOCATION province/O have/O come/O under/O scrutiny/O after/O the/O killing/O of/O activist/O Sabeen/PERSON Mahmud/PERSON in/O Karachi/LOCATION ./O 
Mahmud/PERSON held/O a/O talk/O on/O the/O issue/O right/O before/O she/O was/O shot/O dead/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 26.04.2015/O -RRB-/O Brahamdagh/PERSON Bugti/PERSON :/O `/O China-Pakistan/O deal/O usurps/O Balochistan/LOCATION 's/O resources/O '/O In/O an/O interview/O with/O DW/O ,/O Baloch/PERSON leader/O Brahamdagh/PERSON Bugti/PERSON says/O the/O recent/O multi-billion/O dollar/O economic/O corridor/O deal/O between/O Pakistan/LOCATION and/O China/LOCATION is/O aimed/O at/O colonizing/O the/O Balochistan/LOCATION province/O ,/O and/O must/O be/O resisted/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 24.04.2015/O -RRB-/O China/LOCATION expands/O influence/O in/O `/O economic/O colony/O '/O Pakistan/LOCATION Xi/O Jinping/PERSON 's/O visit/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION promises/O to/O boost/O the/O Islamic/O country/O 's/O struggling/O economy/O ,/O but/O experts/O warn/O there/O are/O many/O strings/O attached/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O aid/O ./O 
Why/O does/O Pakistan/LOCATION need/O to/O be/O careful/O in/O dealing/O with/O China/LOCATION ?/O 
-LRB-/O 20.04.2015/O -RRB-/O Senator/O Mushahid/PERSON Ullah/PERSON Khan/PERSON ,/O leader/O of/O the/O ruling/O Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Muslim/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION party/O ,/O admits/O that/O the/O people/O of/O Balochistan/LOCATION are/O unhappy/O with/O some/O of/O the/O government/O 's/O policies/O ,/O but/O he/O denies/O that/O Islamabad/LOCATION is/O usurping/O the/O province/O 's/O economic/O resources/O ./O 
``/O Prime/O Minister/O Nawaz/PERSON Sharif/PERSON 's/O government/O allowed/O a/O Baloch/PERSON nationalist/O to/O become/O the/O chief/O minister/O of/O the/O province/O ./O 
Our/O administration/O has/O also/O launched/O a/O number/O of/O development/O projects/O for/O the/O benefit/O of/O the/O locals/O ,/O ''/O Senator/O Khan/PERSON told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O An/O international/O airport/O in/O Gwadar/LOCATION is/O being/O built/O ./O 
We/O are/O also/O constructing/O a/O 90-kilometer/O long/O road/O connecting/O Gwadar/LOCATION to/O the/O coastal/O highway/O ,/O and/O establishing/O economic/O zones/O in/O the/O cities/O of/O Khuzdar/LOCATION and/O Zhob/LOCATION ./O 
Ultimately/O ,/O the/O Gwadar/LOCATION port/O will/O benefit/O the/O whole/O Balochistan/LOCATION ,/O ''/O he/O added/O ./O 
Fear/O and/O optimism/O But/O nationalist/O leader/O Abdul/PERSON Hai/PERSON Baloch/PERSON is/O skeptical/O about/O the/O government/O 's/O claims/O ,/O as/O he/O says/O the/O issue/O is/O more/O political/O than/O economic/O ./O 
He/O believes/O the/O Gwadar/LOCATION residents/O resent/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION because/O they/O fear/O that/O with/O the/O arrival/O of/O workers/O from/O China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O other/O provinces/O ,/O they/O will/O soon/O become/O a/O minority/O in/O their/O own/O town/O ./O 
Dr./O Abdul/PERSON Aziz/PERSON ,/O a/O Gwadar/LOCATION resident/O ,/O echoes/O Hai/PERSON Baloch/PERSON 's/O sentiments/O ./O 
``/O Our/O resources/O are/O being/O plundered/O ,/O and/O we/O are/O being/O deprived/O of/O our/O livelihood/O ./O 
Many/O people/O had/O to/O move/O to/O remote/O areas/O after/O the/O government/O started/O the/O construction/O work/O on/O Gwadar/LOCATION port/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ,/O adding/O that/O non-locals/O were/O already/O buying/O land/O in/O the/O city/O ./O 
``/O More/O dislocations/O are/O on/O the/O horizon/O ./O ''/O 
``/O We/O should/O be/O the/O masters/O of/O our/O resources/O ,/O but/O we/O are/O being/O treated/O like/O slaves/O ./O 
This/O will/O have/O catastrophic/O consequences/O ,/O ''/O he/O continued/O ./O 
Last/O year/O ,/O China/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION signed/O deals/O related/O to/O energy/O and/O infrastructure/O projects/O worth/O $/O 46/O billion/O A/O Gwadar/ORGANIZATION Port/ORGANIZATION Authority/ORGANIZATION official/O dismissed/O these/O fears/O ./O 
``/O Two/O dams/O are/O being/O constructed/O to/O deal/O with/O the/O water/O crisis/O in/O the/O area/O ./O 
The/O locals/O will/O be/O given/O jobs/O ./O 
A/O 50-bed/O hospital/O is/O being/O upgraded/O to/O a/O 300-bed/O facility/O ,/O and/O roads/O and/O other/O infrastructure/O work/O is/O being/O done/O ./O 
Who/O will/O benefit/O from/O these/O projects/O ?/O 
Of/O course/O ,/O the/O residents/O of/O Gwadar/LOCATION !/O ''/O 
The/O Lahore/LOCATION and/O Karachi-based/O real/O estate/O companies/O appear/O to/O be/O cashing/O in/O on/O the/O situation/O in/O Gwadar/LOCATION ./O 
Ali/PERSON Masood/PERSON ,/O a/O Karachi-based/O real/O estate/O agent/O ,/O reports/O that/O business/O is/O booming/O with/O housing/O projects/O in/O Gwadar/LOCATION ./O 
``/O In/O some/O areas/O ,/O a/O residential/O plot/O that/O was/O worth/O 12/O million/O Pakistani/O rupees/O -LRB-/O $/O 114,600/O -RRB-/O last/O year/O is/O now/O being/O sold/O for/O around/O 20/O million/O -LRB-/O $/O 191,000/O -RRB-/O ,/O ''/O Masood/PERSON told/O DW/O ./O 
Security/O concerns/O But/O the/O trickiest/O part/O of/O the/O proposed/O Sino-Pakistani/O economic/O projects/O could/O be/O their/O implentation/O in/O the/O face/O of/O Islamist/O militancy/O and/O a/O protracted/O separatist/O insurgency/O in/O Balochistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Baloch/PERSON separatist/O groups/O have/O vowed/O to/O resist/O these/O projects/O ,/O claiming/O the/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION is/O a/O further/O exploitation/O of/O their/O resources/O and/O rights/O ./O 
Rights/O groups/O accuse/O the/O military/O of/O committing/O grave/O human/O rights/O abuses/O in/O Balochistan/LOCATION Ruzhn/PERSON Baloch/PERSON ,/O a/O senior/O leader/O of/O the/O Baloch/ORGANIZATION Student/ORGANIZATION Organization/ORGANIZATION ,/O an/O independent/O group/O that/O advocates/O Balochistan/LOCATION 's/O separation/O from/O Pakistan/LOCATION ,/O says/O the/O new/O projects/O in/O Balochistan/LOCATION will/O not/O be/O any/O different/O from/O the/O ones/O that/O the/O Pakistani/O government/O had/O launched/O in/O the/O past/O ./O 
``/O Today/O ,/O Balochistan/LOCATION is/O the/O poorest/O province/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION despite/O being/O rich/O in/O natural/O resources/O ,/O ''/O she/O told/O DW/O ./O 
``/O We/O are/O against/O this/O colonization/O ./O ''/O 
