The/O province/O is/O rich/O in/O oil/O and/O gas/O hitherto/O held/O in/O reserve/O ./O 
Now/O authorities/O announce/O greater/O investments/O in/O exploration/O and/O refining/O capacity/O ./O 
But/O there/O is/O also/O greater/O fear/O about/O police/O repression/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O Beijing/LOCATION wants/O to/O develop/O the/O rich/O oil/O reserves/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Uygur/LOCATION Autonomous/LOCATION Region/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
For/O much/O of/O the/O history/O of/O the/O Chinese/O oil/O industry/O ,/O fields/O in/O eastern/O China/LOCATION have/O been/O the/O main/O contributors/O to/O production/O ,/O whilst/O those/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> took/O the/O role/O of/O a/O strategic/O substitutive/O zone/O ./O 
But/O as/O oil/O prices/O and/O imports/O -LRB-/O now/O standing/O at/O 45/O per/O cent/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O needs/O -RRB-/O grow/O ,/O the/O time/O has/O come/O for/O full/O developing/O domestic/O oil/O and/O gas/O resources/O ./O 
In/O late/O June/O ,/O Vice-Premier/O Zeng/PERSON Peiyan/PERSON and/O officials/O from/O the/O State/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Reform/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Land/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Resources/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O China/LOCATION 's/O top/O oil/O giants/O China/ORGANIZATION National/ORGANIZATION Petroleum/ORGANIZATION Corporation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O and/O China/ORGANIZATION Petrochemical/ORGANIZATION Corporation/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O SINOPEC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O attended/O an/O oil/O and/O gas/O seminar/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O where/O they/O agreed/O to/O speed/O up/O construction/O of/O facilities/O to/O develop/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O oil/O and/O gas/O resources/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O <U_LOCATION>Tarim/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O <U_LOCATION>Junggar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O <U_LOCATION>Turpan-Hami/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> basins/O are/O home/O to/O 20.9/O billion/O tons/O of/O oil/O resources/O and/O 10.85/O trillion/O cubic/O meters/O of/O natural/O gas/O ,/O respectively/O accounting/O for/O 25.5/O per/O cent/O of/O China/LOCATION 's/O inland/O oil/O resources/O and/O 27.9/O per/O cent/O of/O the/O country/O 's/O inland/O gas/O resources/O ./O 
In/O 2004/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> produced/O 22.60/O million/O tons/O of/O crude/O oil/O ./O 
According/O to/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION 's/O and/O SINOPEC/ORGANIZATION 's/O preliminary/O plans/O ,/O the/O region/O 's/O oil/O and/O natural/O gas/O output/O will/O hit/O 30/O million/O tons/O and/O 18/O billion/O cubic/O meters/O ,/O respectively/O ,/O by/O 2010/O ./O 
Combined/O with/O the/O 20/O million/O tons/O of/O crude/O oil/O imported/O from/O Kazakhstan/LOCATION via/O pipelines/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> will/O become/O the/O country/O 's/O largest/O oil/O and/O gas/O supply/O base/O by/O then/O ./O 
Earlier/O ,/O CNPC/ORGANIZATION and/O SINOPEC/ORGANIZATION announced/O that/O they/O would/O invest/O 20.85/O billion/O yuan/O this/O year/O in/O upstream/O oil/O and/O gas/O prospecting/O and/O exploration/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
Similarly/O ,/O the/O authorities/O are/O also/O speeding/O up/O the/O construction/O of/O facilities/O for/O transmitting/O oil/O and/O gas/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> to/O other/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
Expansion/O of/O the/O local/O oil/O and/O gas/O industry/O has/O been/O matched/O by/O statements/O made/O in/O the/O last/O few/O months/O by/O the/O central/O authorities/O that/O local/O ``/O separatism/O and/O religious/O extremism/O ''/O would/O be/O treated/O with/O greater/O ``/O severity/O ''/O ./O
