Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O 58/O ,/O an/O ethnic/O Uighur/O -LRB-/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION Muslim/O</U_ORGANIZATION> group/O -RRB-/O was/O freed/O today/O and/O allowed/O to/O leave/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Prior/O to/O her/O arrest/O in/O 1999/O ,/O she/O was/O involved/O in/O legal/O defence/O work/O for/O on/O behalf/O of/O her/O ethnic/O group/O and/O women/O ./O 
She/O was/O found/O guilty/O in/O 2000/O of/O ``/O illegally/O sending/O state/O documents/O ''/O and/O sentenced/O to/O eight/O years/O in/O jail/O to/O be/O purged/O in/O a/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> prison/O ./O 
According/O the/O <LOCATION>San/O Francisco/O</LOCATION> -/O based/O Dui/ORGANIZATION Hua/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O has/O been/O involved/O in/O the/O case/O from/O the/O beginning/O ,/O Ms/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> was/O allowed/O to/O leave/O China/LOCATION and/O should/O be/O on/O her/O way/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
In/O her/O recent/O trip/O to/O China/LOCATION US/LOCATION Secretary/O of/O State/O Condoleezza/PERSON Rice/PERSON had/O raised/O the/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> case/O with/O her/O Chinese/O counterparts/O ./O
