<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O --/O The/O authorities/O of/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> yesterday/O arrested/O a/O Korean-born/O Protestant/O pastor/O and/O 35/O unofficial/O Christians/O of/O Yongfeng/PERSON who/O had/O gathered/O for/O bible/O study/O ./O 
This/O was/O reported/O by/O the/O China/ORGANIZATION Aid/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CAA/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O ,/O a/O US-based/O non-governmental/O organization/O lobbying/O for/O religious/O freedom/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
The/O police/O raided/O `/O <U_LOCATION>Mountain/O Villa/O</U_LOCATION> '/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Qilin/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O a/O suburb/O of/O the/O provincial/O capital/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Uramqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O when/O some/O Christians/O were/O attending/O a/O bible/O training/O program/O by/O a/O Korean/O pastor/O from/O America/LOCATION ./O 
During/O the/O raid/O ,/O the/O police/O confiscated/O bibles/O and/O ``/O other/O Christian/O material/O ''/O ./O 
The/O detainees/O are/O being/O kept/O in/O an/O unknown/O location/O ./O 
CAA/ORGANIZATION said/O the/O names/O of/O some/O of/O the/O arrested/O were/O Zhou/PERSON Li/PERSON ,/O Xia/PERSON Lingzhi/PERSON ,/O Bao/PERSON Lin/PERSON ,/O Ren/PERSON Baolan/PERSON ,/O Feng/PERSON Yan/PERSON ,/O Hu/PERSON Ying/PERSON ,/O adding/O that/O the/O first/O two/O had/O already/O been/O arrested/O and/O fined/O last/O year/O ``/O for/O attending/O a/O Christian/O service/O ''/O ./O 
The/O association/O said/O :/O ``/O Xia/PERSON Lingzhi/PERSON is/O 66/O years/O old/O ./O 
She/O suffers/O from/O coronary/O heart/O disease/O and/O high/O blood/O pressure/O and/O thus/O should/O not/O be/O detained/O again/O as/O her/O life/O would/O be/O at/O risk/O ./O ''/O
