A/O plan/O announced/O yesterday/O will/O fund/O the/O economic/O development/O of/O ethnic/O minorities/O ,/O often/O among/O the/O nations/O poorest/O peoples/O ./O 
But/O there/O will/O also/O be/O a/O system/O of/O social/O control/O of/O minorities/O to/O prevent/O protests/O ./O 
Particular/O attention/O is/O paid/O to/O the/O Uyghurs/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O The/O central/O government/O has/O issued/O a/O development/O programme/O for/O to/O improve/O conditions/O for/O 55/O minorities/O ./O 
They/O are/O among/O the/O nations/O poorest/O social/O groups/O ,/O and/O often/O their/O discontent/O has/O exploded/O into/O violent/O street/O protest/O ./O 
But/O analysts/O maintain/O that/O Beijing/LOCATION merely/O wants/O to/O install/O greater/O control/O mechanisms/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O first/O time/O the/O government/O has/O issued/O 11th/O five-year/O development/O programme/O for/O its/O 55/O minorities/O separately/O from/O the/O nation/O 's/O overall/O five-year/O plan/O ./O 
The/O programme/O sets/O goals/O to/O improve/O infrastructure/O and/O the/O environment/O ,/O support/O the/O development/O of/O specialised/O economies/O ,/O relieve/O poverty/O ,/O create/O better/O welfare/O conditions/O and/O make/O ethnic/O relations/O ``/O more/O harmonious/O ''/O ./O 
Speaking/O at/O a/O press/O conference/O yesterday/O ,/O Danzhu/PERSON Angben/PERSON ,/O a/O deputy/O director/O of/O the/O State/ORGANIZATION Ethnic/ORGANIZATION Affairs/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O the/O 22/O small/O minorities/O with/O populations/O below/O 100,000/O ,/O would/O receive/O 112/O million/O Yuan/O from/O the/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Finance/ORGANIZATION every/O year/O to/O relieve/O poverty/O for/O a/O total/O population/O of/O 630,000/O ./O 
He/O insisted/O that/O ``/O in/O China/LOCATION the/O ethnic/O groups/O are/O equal/O in/O status/O and/O live/O in/O harmony/O ./O 
There/O is/O no/O discrimination/O ''/O ./O 
The/O rapid/O economic/O development/O of/O the/O country/O has/O not/O stopped/O poverty/O from/O spreading/O in/O rural/O areas/O where/O a/O lack/O of/O social/O services/O and/O grave/O pollution/O has/O worsened/O it/O 's/O effects/O ./O 
Now/O Beijing/LOCATION is/O claiming/O that/O social/O unrest/O ,/O which/O has/O increased/O over/O recent/O years/O transforming/O itself/O into/O violent/O street/O protests/O ,/O is/O due/O to/O the/O lack/O of/O economic/O development/O in/O some/O areas/O ./O 
But/O experts/O observe/O that/O the/O protests/O are/O generally/O in/O reaction/O to/O violations/O of/O human/O rights/O which/O happen/O in/O the/O same/O areas/O were/O the/O population/O is/O from/O the/O Han/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
Such/O as/O in/O Yunnan/LOCATION where/O protests/O by/O the/O ethnic/O minority/O were/O against/O the/O building/O of/O a/O dam/O ./O 
Moreover/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O long/O favoured/O the/O migration/O of/O the/O Han/O -LRB-/O which/O constitutes/O over/O 90/O %/O of/O the/O population/O -RRB-/O to/O areas/O of/O different/O traditional/O and/O cultural/O ethnic/O origins/O ,/O for/O example/O Tibet/LOCATION and/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O often/O promoting/O the/O Han/O in/O business/O and/O to/O positions/O of/O authority/O and/O even/O banning/O the/O use/O of/O local/O languages/O ./O 
To/O stave/O off/O inevitable/O protests/O the/O government/O ,/O while/O it/O promises/O economic/O relief/O for/O these/O areas/O ,/O now/O says/O that/O by/O 2010/O it/O will/O create/O a/O specific/O control/O system/O for/O these/O minorities/O ,/O to/O ``/O avoid/O separatist/O activities/O and/O maintain/O national/O stability/O ''/O ./O 
Meanwhile/O for/O the/O first/O time/O Beijing/LOCATION it/O will/O ``/O increase/O ''/O the/O number/O of/O bilingual/O teachers/O in/O the/O schools/O ,/O who/O will/O speak/O both/O mandarin/O as/O well/O as/O the/O local/O language/O ./O 
China/LOCATION claims/O that/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> represents/O a/O possible/O source/O of/O extremist/O violence/O as/O it/O is/O home/O to/O over/O 8/O million/O Islamic/O Uyghurs/O who/O are/O linguistically/O and/O traditionally/O linked/O to/O central/O Asia/LOCATION rather/O than/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION also/O claims/O that/O it/O fears/O secession/O attempts/O by/O Tibet/LOCATION ,/O under/O the/O guidance/O of/O the/O exiled/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON ,/O and/O punishes/O those/O who/O even/O carry/O his/O photo/O ./O
