An/O eight-name/O list/O of/O alleged/O Xingjian/O terrorists/O is/O released/O ./O 
They/O are/O accused/O with/O carrying/O out/O attacks/O during/O the/O Olympics/O ./O 
But/O for/O experts/O Beijing/LOCATION has/O failed/O so/O far/O to/O come/O with/O any/O evidence/O ./O 
The/O Uyghurs/O living/O in/O the/O oil/O -/O and/O mineral-rich/O region/O have/O been/O victims/O of/O a/O virtual/O cultural/O genocide/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O In/O an/O unprecedented/O move/O Chinese/O authorities/O today/O released/O a/O wanted/O list/O of/O eight/O <U_LOCATION>Xingjian/O</U_LOCATION> ``/O terrorists/O ''/O it/O said/O had/O carried/O out/O attacks/O aimed/O at/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympics/O ,/O calling/O on/O the/O international/O community/O for/O help/O in/O capturing/O them/O ./O 
``/O The/O eight/O are/O all/O key/O members/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>ETIM/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O and/O all/O participated/O in/O the/O planning/O ,/O deployment/O and/O execution/O of/O all/O kinds/O of/O violent/O terrorist/O activities/O targeting/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympics/O ''/O and/O foreign/O objectives/O ,/O said/O Wu/PERSON Heping/PERSON ,/O a/O spokesman/O with/O the/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Public/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION ,/O who/O did/O not/O however/O go/O into/O details/O about/O they/O are/O supposed/O to/O have/O done/O ./O 
The/O <U_ORGANIZATION>ETIM/O</U_ORGANIZATION> stands/O for/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>East/ORGANIZATION Turkestan/ORGANIZATION Islamic/ORGANIZATION Movement/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> and/O ,/O according/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O is/O linked/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>al-Qaeda/O</ORGANIZATION> ./O 
One/O of/O the/O suspects/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Memetiming/PERSON Memeti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O is/O considered/O the/O ETIM/O leader/O ./O 
A/O police/O statement/O said/O that/O he/O received/O help/O from/O ``/O certain/O western/O Asian/O countries/O ''/O ,/O including/O explosives/O to/O carry/O out/O terror/O attacks/O on/O targets/O in/O China/LOCATION and/O overseas/O ./O 
The/O other/O suspects/O were/O involved/O in/O attacks/O as/O well/O as/O training/O and/O recruiting/O terrorists/O ./O 
Strategically/O located/O resource-rich/O <U_LOCATION>Xingjian/O</U_LOCATION> has/O been/O rocked/O by/O attacks/O this/O year/O ,/O including/O the/O killing/O of/O 16/O armed/O police/O just/O before/O the/O August/O Olympics/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION blames/O Islamic/O militants/O for/O the/O incident/O ./O 
In/O April/O mainland/O authorities/O also/O arrested/O tens/O of/O alleged/O terrorists/O accusing/O them/O of/O being/O involved/O in/O terror/O plots/O targeting/O the/O Olympics/O ,/O including/O suicide/O bomb/O attacks/O and/O the/O kidnapping/O of/O athletes/O ./O 
None/O of/O these/O claims/O could/O be/O independently/O verified/O ./O 
China/LOCATION has/O in/O turn/O been/O accused/O of/O carrying/O out/O cultural/O genocide/O in/O the/O region/O by/O trying/O to/O eliminate/O the/O language/O and/O culture/O of/O indigenous/O Uyghur/O to/O the/O benefit/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O immigrants/O who/O hold/O positions/O of/O power/O and/O privilege/O ./O 
The/O end/O result/O of/O this/O policy/O has/O turned/O the/O Uyghurs/O into/O a/O minority/O ,/O eight/O million/O of/O the/O region/O 's/O 19/O million/O people/O or/O 46/O per/O cent/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION has/O also/O issued/O a/O series/O of/O edicts/O that/O have/O made/O life/O difficult/O for/O <OTHER>Muslim/PERSON Uyghurs/PERSON</OTHER> ./O 
For/O example/O ,/O sermons/O at/O Friday/O prayers/O can/O not/O run/O longer/O than/O a/O half-hour/O ./O 
Prayers/O in/O public/O areas/O outside/O the/O mosque/O are/O forbidden/O ./O 
Government/O workers/O and/O non-religious/O people/O can/O not/O be/O ``/O forced/O ''/O to/O attend/O mosque/O services/O --/O a/O generous/O wording/O of/O a/O law/O that/O prohibits/O government/O workers/O and/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O from/O going/O at/O all/O ./O 
Imams/O may/O not/O teach/O the/O Qur/O '/O an/O in/O private/O ./O 
Studying/O Arabic/O is/O allowed/O only/O at/O special/O government/O schools/O ./O 
Students/O and/O government/O workers/O are/O compelled/O to/O eat/O during/O Ramadan/O ./O 
Passports/O have/O been/O confiscated/O to/O force/O Uyghurs/O to/O join/O government-run/O hajj/O tours/O rather/O than/O travelling/O illegally/O to/O Makkah/LOCATION ./O 
And/O when/O they/O can/O travel/O official/O trips/O can/O cost/O US$/O 3,700/O ./O 
And/O last/O but/O not/O least/O ,/O anyone/O applying/O for/O Hajj/O must/O be/O vetted/O by/O police/O and/O show/O that/O they/O have/O the/O means/O to/O go/O ./O 
For/O <U_PERSON>Dilxat/PERSON Raxit/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O spokesperson/O for/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O the/O terrorist/O ``/O list/O has/O political/O motives/O -LSB-/O .../O -RSB-/O ./O 
They/O -LSB-/O Chinese/O authorities/O -RSB-/O have/O produced/O no/O evidence/O to/O support/O these/O claims/O ./O ''/O 
For/O the/O same/O reason/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION has/O refused/O to/O repatriate/O about/O 255/O Chinese/O Muslim/O Uyghur/O who/O fled/O Afghanistan/LOCATION to/O Pakistan/LOCATION after/O the/O US/LOCATION attacked/O it/O in/O October/O 2001/O ./O 
After/O their/O capture/O they/O were/O sent/O to/O Guantanamo/LOCATION where/O they/O have/O been/O held/O for/O years/O ./O 
But/O now/O they/O are/O on/O the/O verge/O of/O being/O freed/O but/O will/O not/O be/O repatriated/O for/O fear/O that/O China/LOCATION might/O jail/O them/O without/O cause/O ./O
