<U_PERSON>Jamal/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O 24/O ,/O sent/O via/O mobile/O phone/O sounds/O and/O comments/O about/O a/O shopkeepers/O '/O protest/O against/O local/O authorities/O ./O 
He/O was/O eventually/O arrested/O for/O separatism/O and/O leaking/O state/O secrets/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O On/O 28/O February/O 2008/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Intermediate/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION in/O <U_LOCATION>Turpan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> sentenced/O <U_PERSON>Ekberjan/PERSON Jamal/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O 24/O and/O a/O member/O of/O the/O region/O 's/O mostly/O <OTHER>Muslim/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> minority/O ,/O to/O ten/O years/O in/O prison/O for/O alleged/O separatism/O and/O leaking/O state/O secrets/O ./O 
Using/O a/O mobile/O phone/O <U_PERSON>Jamal/PERSON</U_PERSON> had/O sent/O some/O friends/O in/O the/O Netherlands/LOCATION the/O sounds/O of/O a/O November/O 2007/O protest/O by/O local/O shopkeepers/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Turpan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O 180/O kilometres/O east/O of/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Xingjian</U_LOCATION>/O regional/O capital/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
The/O shopkeepers/O had/O taken/O to/O the/O streets/O against/O local/O authorities/O on/O 1/O ,/O 17/O and/O 18/O November/O for/O the/O latter/O 's/O failure/O to/O restore/O their/O businesses/O and/O compensate/O them/O for/O lost/O income/O after/O a/O fire/O on/O 3/O October/O 2007/O at/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Turpan/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> <U_LOCATION>Grand/LOCATION Bazaar/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O pictured/O -RRB-/O ./O 
The/O fire/O killed/O one/O person/O and/O destroyed/O about/O 1/O million/O yuan/O worth/O of/O merchandise/O ./O 
The/O sounds/O <U_PERSON>Jamal/PERSON</U_PERSON> shared/O by/O cell/O phone/O were/O of/O police/O sirens/O ,/O voices/O ,/O and/O his/O own/O voice/O explaining/O what/O he/O was/O witnessing/O ./O 
<ORGANIZATION>Radio/O Free/O Asia/LOCATION</ORGANIZATION> 's/O Uyghur/O service/O received/O the/O tape/O of/O the/O phone/O conversation/O and/O used/O it/O in/O its/O broadcast/O ./O 
On/O 25/O December/O 2007/O Chinese/O authorities/O arrested/O <U_PERSON>Jamal/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O accusing/O him/O of/O trying/O to/O break/O up/O the/O country/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Jamal/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O who/O lost/O his/O father/O ,/O is/O the/O main/O support/O for/O his/O mother/O and/O two/O younger/O sisters/O ./O 
Now/O his/O mother/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Ibadethan/PERSON Jamal/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O said/O she/O wants/O to/O launch/O an/O appeal/O on/O her/O son/O 's/O behalf/O and/O explain/O ,/O even/O via/O websites/O ,/O that/O ``/O Our/O family/O is/O not/O anti-government/O ./O 
We/O do/O n't/O have/O any/O complaints/O about/O the/O government/O ./O ''/O 
She/O added/O that/O her/O son/O was/O not/O tortured/O and/O that/O she/O can/O see/O him/O once/O a/O month/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xingjian/O</U_LOCATION> is/O home/O to/O some/O eight/O million/O Uyghurs/O who/O are/O mostly/O Muslim/O ./O 
Exiled/O Uyghur/O groups/O have/O criticised/O the/O Chinese/O state/O for/O heavily/O discriminating/O against/O the/O indigenous/O population/O and/O favouring/O the/O mass/O immigration/O of/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
What/O is/O more/O ,/O not/O only/O are/O <OTHER>Uyghurs/PERSON</OTHER> already/O a/O minority/O in/O their/O own/O country/O ,/O but/O they/O have/O to/O endure/O restrictions/O on/O their/O religion/O as/O well/O as/O their/O language/O and/O traditions/O ./O 
Many/O have/O protested/O against/O this/O kind/O of/O treatment/O ./O 
Recently/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O in/O fact/O reported/O an/O increase/O in/O the/O number/O of/O attacks/O ./O 
They/O also/O announced/O police/O reinforcement/O and/O a/O tougher/O crackdown/O against/O all/O activities/O they/O deem/O dangerous/O to/O ``/O state/O security/O ''/O ./O
