They/O had/O come/O to/O present/O a/O petition/O ./O 
Today/O the/O group/O ``/O Tiananmen/ORGANIZATION Mothers/ORGANIZATION ''/O asked/O the/O government/O to/O reveal/O whether/O 127/O people/O who/O disappeared/O in/O the/O massacre/O on/O June/O 4/O ,/O 1989/O ,/O are/O alive/O or/O dead/O ./O 
Experts/O :/O the/O government/O is/O not/O resolving/O the/O problems/O ,/O and/O there/O are/O more/O and/O more/O protests/O ,/O some/O of/O them/O with/O extreme/O actions/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O The/O three/O Chinese/O who/O set/O themselves/O on/O fire/O in/O a/O car/O when/O the/O police/O stopped/O them/O in/O downtown/O Beijing/LOCATION were/O Uyghurs/O ./O 
Experts/O expect/O numerous/O protests/O this/O year/O ,/O because/O the/O government/O is/O preaching/O social/O harmony/O ,/O but/O is/O not/O resolving/O the/O problems/O ./O 
The/O police/O are/O responding/O by/O patrolling/O Beijing/LOCATION with/O helicopters/O ./O 
It/O appears/O that/O the/O three/O ,/O who/O were/O members/O of/O the/O same/O family/O ,/O had/O come/O to/O the/O capital/O to/O present/O a/O petition/O about/O a/O property/O dispute/O ./O 
The/O parents/O are/O still/O being/O treated/O in/O the/O hospital/O for/O their/O burns/O ,/O but/O there/O is/O no/O information/O about/O their/O son/O ,/O who/O was/O taken/O away/O by/O the/O police/O ./O 
The/O reason/O behind/O their/O action/O is/O unknown/O ;/O it/O may/O have/O been/O an/O extreme/O protest/O against/O a/O situation/O of/O injustice/O ./O 
Next/O week/O ,/O the/O annual/O session/O of/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Assembly/ORGANIZATION begins/O ,/O and/O for/O the/O occasion/O many/O Chinese/O go/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O present/O petitions/O ,/O asking/O for/O justice/O ./O 
Today/O the/O group/O ``/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Tiananmen/O Mothers/O</U_ORGANIZATION> ''/O presented/O a/O petition/O to/O find/O out/O what/O happened/O to/O 127/O people/O who/O disappeared/O during/O the/O massacre/O on/O June/O 4/O ,/O 1989/O ,/O when/O the/O army/O brought/O in/O tanks/O and/O fired/O on/O thousands/O of/O unarmed/O demonstrators/O who/O were/O occupying/O Tiananmen/LOCATION Square/LOCATION and/O calling/O for/O democratic/O reforms/O ./O 
20/O years/O later/O ,/O it/O is/O still/O unknown/O whether/O these/O 127/O people/O are/O dead/O or/O in/O prison/O ./O 
The/O group/O ,/O which/O unites/O the/O parents/O of/O young/O people/O who/O died/O or/O disappeared/O that/O June/O 4/O ,/O is/O asking/O the/O government/O to/O verify/O all/O of/O the/O deaths/O ,/O compensate/O families/O ,/O and/O punish/O ``/O those/O responsible/O for/O the/O killings/O ./O ''/O 
According/O to/O Human/O Rights/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O the/O petition/O claims/O that/O ``/O China/LOCATION has/O become/O like/O an/O airtight/O iron/O chamber/O and/O all/O the/O demands/O of/O the/O people/O about/O June/O 4/O ,/O all/O the/O anguish/O ,/O lament/O and/O moaning/O of/O the/O victims/O '/O relatives/O and/O the/O wounded/O have/O been/O sealed/O off/O ./O ''/O 
The/O request/O for/O official/O recognition/O of/O the/O killings/O has/O long/O been/O headed/O by/O Ding/PERSON Zilin/PERSON ,/O a/O retired/O professor/O whose/O 17-year-old/O son/O died/O in/O the/O square/O ./O 
At/O the/O time/O ,/O China/LOCATION limited/O itself/O to/O describing/O the/O demonstrators/O as/O ``/O counterrevolutionaries/O ,/O ''/O and/O still/O speaks/O of/O it/O as/O a/O period/O of/O ``/O political/O tumult/O ,/O ''/O avoiding/O further/O comments/O ./O 
Another/O protest/O took/O place/O yesterday/O ,/O when/O ,/O in/O front/O of/O more/O than/O 100/O journalists/O ,/O in/O front/O of/O the/O press/O office/O of/O the/O State/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O man/O climbed/O a/O street/O sign/O ,/O shouting/O ``/O give/O back/O my/O political/O rights/O ''/O and/O displaying/O a/O placard/O -LRB-/O in/O the/O photo/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Finally/O ,/O the/O police/O forced/O him/O down/O ./O 
This/O year/O ,/O there/O are/O many/O anniversaries/O of/O questions/O that/O are/O still/O open/O ,/O and/O the/O police/O have/O begun/O to/O patrol/O Beijing/LOCATION with/O helicopters/O ahead/O of/O next/O week/O 's/O session/O ,/O to/O better/O control/O the/O situation/O ./O 
The/O analyst/O Zhang/PERSON Dajun/PERSON observes/O that/O last/O year/O ,/O the/O Beijing/LOCATION Olympics/O drew/O Chinese/O public/O opinion/O ,/O but/O he/O expects/O that/O this/O year/O there/O will/O be/O many/O public/O protests/O ,/O because/O ``/O people/O 's/O problems/O have/O not/O been/O solved/O ./O 
When/O people/O become/O desperate/O ,/O they/O try/O extreme/O measures/O ,/O like/O the/O burning/O incident/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O to/O have/O their/O voices/O heard/O ./O ''/O
