Trials/O were/O held/O on/O 22/O and/O 23/O December/O but/O were/O not/O reported/O by/O Chinese/O media/O ./O 
Eight/O people/O got/O life/O in/O prison/O and/O four/O were/O sentenced/O to/O ten/O years/O and/O more/O ./O 
The/O authorities/O announce/O more/O trials/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION wants/O to/O pursue/O its/O crackdown/O on/O Uyghurs/O but/O keep/O it/O a/O secret/O from/O the/O world/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O Five/O more/O Uyghurs/O have/O been/O sentenced/O to/O death/O for/O their/O role/O in/O protests/O that/O broke/O out/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O but/O Chinese/O authorities/O have/O tried/O to/O keep/O the/O news/O from/O both/O domestic/O and/O international/O media/O ./O 
``/O Altogether/O 22/O defendants/O in/O five/O cases/O went/O on/O trial/O December/O 22/O -/O 23/O ,/O ''/O Hou/PERSON Hanmin/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>Xinjiang/ORGANIZATION Government/ORGANIZATION Information/ORGANIZATION Office/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> ,/O was/O quoted/O as/O saying/O ./O 
Ma/PERSON Xinchun/PERSON ,/O a/O representative/O for/O the/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> city/O government/O ,/O confirmed/O that/O five/O people/O were/O handed/O death/O sentences/O -LRB-/O with/O a/O two-year/O suspension/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Eight/O defendants/O were/O given/O life/O in/O prison/O ,/O whilst/O four/O more/O were/O handed/O sentences/O of/O 10/O years/O or/O longer/O ./O 
There/O is/O no/O information/O about/O who/O these/O people/O are/O but/O ,/O according/O to/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Free/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION ,/O their/O names/O appear/O to/O be/O Uyghur/O ./O 
Hou/PERSON did/O not/O elaborate/O on/O the/O charges/O that/O led/O to/O the/O convictions/O and/O sentencing/O ,/O but/O they/O all/O appear/O related/O to/O the/O July/O 2009/O unrest/O ./O 
He/O did/O say/O that/O they/O were/O published/O by/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> newspapers/O ;/O however/O ,/O since/O July/O internet/O has/O been/O blocked/O in/O the/O province/O and/O local/O newspaper/O websites/O can/O not/O be/O accessed/O from/O outside/O ./O 
Protests/O broke/O in/O the/O capital/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> on/O 5/O July/O as/O a/O result/O of/O rising/O interethnic/O frustrations/O between/O indigenous/O Uyghurs/O and/O Han/O Chinese/O settlers/O ./O 
The/O latter/O have/O become/O a/O majority/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O monopolise/O key/O political/O and/O economic/O positions/O thanks/O to/O an/O immigration/O policy/O pursued/O by/O the/O central/O government/O that/O provides/O them/O with/O a/O number/O of/O incentives/O ,/O economic/O or/O otherwise/O ,/O in/O order/O to/O move/O to/O the/O province/O ./O 
Protests/O started/O out/O peacefully/O -LRB-/O pictured/O ,/O the/O 5/O July/O demonstration/O -RRB-/O but/O turned/O into/O interethnic/O clashes/O that/O pitted/O Muslim/O Uyghurs/O against/O Han/O Chinese/O ./O 
This/O was/O followed/O by/O two/O days/O of/O retaliatory/O attacks/O by/O ethnic/O Chinese/O ./O 
The/O official/O death/O toll/O stands/O at/O about/O 200/O dead/O and/O thousands/O of/O wounded/O ./O 
With/O the/O latest/O sentences/O ,/O the/O number/O of/O death/O penalties/O handed/O down/O in/O connection/O with/O the/O riots/O has/O risen/O to/O 22/O ,/O of/O which/O at/O least/O nine/O have/O already/O been/O carried/O out/O ./O 
In/O the/O meantime/O ,/O official/O sources/O announced/O more/O trials/O against/O people/O accused/O of/O masterminding/O the/O protests/O ./O 
Similarly/O ,/O Cambodia/LOCATION announced/O last/O week/O that/O it/O was/O going/O to/O send/O 20/O Uyghurs/O back/O to/O China/LOCATION ./O 
They/O had/O fled/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> after/O the/O protests/O and/O applied/O for/O refugee/O status/O at/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION representative/O 's/O office/O in/O Phnom/LOCATION Penh/LOCATION ./O 
This/O decision/O meets/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O demands/O but/O has/O been/O severely/O criticised/O by/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Last/O week/O ,/O Chinese/O Vice/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON signed/O a/O number/O of/O agreements/O worth/O US$/O 1.2/O billion/O during/O a/O visit/O to/O Cambodia/LOCATION ./O 
They/O include/O money/O for/O road/O building/O and/O the/O restoration/O of/O Buddhist/O temples/O ./O
