A/O law/O is/O approved/O that/O punishes/O those/O who/O discuss/O it/O on/O the/O internet/O ./O 
Three/O months/O after/O the/O protests/O ,/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> remains/O occupied/O by/O police/O and/O subjected/O to/O tight/O controls/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O AsiaNews/ORGANIZATION //O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O The/O government/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> last/O week/O approved/O a/O law/O that/O punishes/O as/O a/O crime/O mere/O talk/O of/O separatism/O on/O the/O internet/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O government/O ,/O the/O ``/O Information/O Promotion/O Bill/O ''/O aims/O to/O prevent/O the/O Internet/O from/O being/O used/O to/O foment/O ethnic/O separatism/O or/O disrupt/O social/O stability/O ./O 
Now/O internet/O cafes/O are/O under/O police/O surveillance/O ,/O with/O officers/O ready/O to/O arrest/O those/O who/O dare/O to/O even/O discusses/O the/O ethnic/O protests/O that/O erupted/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> on/O July/O 5/O ,/O in/O which/O there/O were/O 197/O deaths/O ./O 
During/O the/O fighting/O and/O in/O the/O following/O weeks/O ,/O the/O authorities/O blocked/O all/O communication/O with/O the/O area/O via/O internet/O or/O phone/O and/O even/O blocked/O access/O to/O global/O sites/O such/O as/O <ORGANIZATION>Facebook/O</ORGANIZATION> ,/O <ORGANIZATION>Twitter/O</ORGANIZATION> and/O YouTube/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Local/O sources/O report/O that/O many/O mobile/O phones/O used/O in/O the/O region/O have/O received/O polite/O text/O messages/O in/O recent/O weeks/O ,/O probably/O for/O having/O sent/O messages/O containing/O words/O ``/O forbidden/O ''/O by/O the/O government/O ./O 
The/O police/O also/O prohibit/O pictures/O and/O videos/O of/O the/O July/O protests/O from/O being/O taken/O out/O of/O the/O region/O arresting/O those/O who/O are/O caught/O with/O them/O in/O their/O possession/O ./O 
Footage/O of/O the/O violence/O is/O still/O circulating/O on/O sites/O like/O YouTube/O ,/O posted/O by/O Uyghurs/O in/O exile/O ./O 
The/O engineer/O Pu/PERSON Fei/PERSON commented/O to/O <ORGANIZATION>Radio/O Free/O Asia/O</ORGANIZATION> that/O he/O is/O pessimistic/O about/O ``/O freedom/O of/O speech/O in/O the/O country/O ''/O ./O 
``/O Until/O now/O ,/O the/O law/O had/O only/O banned/O the/O use/O of/O certain/O words/O ''/O and/O had/O criticized/O the/O use/O on/O the/O internet/O ,/O but/O this/O is/O the/O first/O time/O that/O the/O mere/O use/O of/O certain/O terms/O or/O discussion/O of/O certain/O topics/O is/O considered/O in/O itself/O a/O crime/O ./O 
Youjin/PERSON Wang/PERSON ,/O a/O Chinese/O University/O professor/O of/O political/O science/O and/O law/O ,/O notes/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O deals/O severely/O with/O every/O ``/O subversive/O ''/O action/O but/O the/O term/O is/O generic/O and/O authorities/O can/O apply/O it/O to/O literally/O all/O forms/O of/O protest/O and/O dissent/O ./O 
The/O danger/O is/O that/O ,/O for/O security/O reasons/O ,/O the/O authorities/O will/O keep/O Uyghur/O population/O in/O isolation/O ./O 
After/O more/O than/O two/O months/O ,/O the/O situation/O remains/O tense/O ./O 
Over/O the/O last/O months/O unidentified/O persons/O ``/O stabbed/O ''/O with/O syringes/O hundreds/O of/O citizens/O ,/O causing/O panic/O ./O 
Now/O the/O police/O stop/O and/O search/O anyone/O who/O has/O a/O purse/O ,/O especially/O at/O night/O ,/O looking/O for/O syringes/O ./O 
Local/O sources/O report/O that/O these/O continuous/O checks/O ,/O rather/O than/O intimidate/O attackers/O ,/O exacerbate/O the/O population/O ./O
