Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION releases/O a/O damning/O report/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION increased/O its/O persecution/O of/O dissidents/O and/O activists/O last/O year/O ./O 
The/O West/O instead/O toned/O down/O its/O criticism/O and/O its/O defence/O of/O human/O rights/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O <ORGANIZATION>HRW/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O --/O Human/O rights/O protection/O in/O China/LOCATION faced/O significant/O setbacks/O in/O 2009/O as/O the/O Chinese/O government/O ,/O emboldened/O by/O increasingly/O weak/O international/O criticism/O of/O its/O rights/O record/O ,/O failed/O to/O reform/O the/O legal/O system/O and/O instead/O pursued/O politically-motivated/O attacks/O ,/O including/O long-term/O prison/O sentences/O ,/O against/O dissidents/O ,/O human/O rights/O defenders/O ,/O civil/O society/O advocates/O ,/O Tibetans/O and/O Uyghurs/O as/O well/O as/O ordinary/O people/O with/O complaints/O ,/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION said/O in/O its/O annual/O World/O Report/O ,/O released/O yesterday/O ./O 
Just/O in/O December/O of/O last/O year/O ,/O the/O Chinese/O government/O showed/O how/O much/O it/O disregarded/O human/O rights/O ,/O both/O at/O home/O and/O abroad/O ./O 
On/O 19/O December/O ,/O as/O a/O result/O of/O its/O pressure/O on/O the/O Cambodian/O government/O ,/O Beijing/LOCATION received/O 20/O Uighur/O asylum/O seekers/O forcibly/O repatriated/O ./O 
The/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION High/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION <ORGANIZATION>for/O Refugees/O</ORGANIZATION> voiced/O deep/O concern/O because/O of/O the/O high/O risk/O of/O torture/O ,/O disappearance/O ,/O and/O arbitrary/O detention/O they/O faced/O upon/O return/O ./O 
On/O 25/O December/O ,/O the/O Beijing/ORGANIZATION Intermediate/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION sentenced/O veteran/O dissident/O Liu/PERSON Xiaobo/PERSON -LRB-/O pictured/O -RRB-/O to/O an/O 11/O -/O year/O prison/O term/O for/O ``/O incitement/O to/O subvert/O state/O power/O ''/O because/O of/O his/O contribution/O to/O the/O drafting/O of/O ``/O Charter/O 08/O ,/O ''/O a/O political/O manifesto/O that/O calls/O for/O human/O rights/O and/O the/O rule/O of/O law/O in/O China/LOCATION ./O 
Liu/PERSON has/O been/O in/O prison/O since/O 8/O December/O 2008/O ./O 
On/O 28/O December/O ,/O the/O Xining/ORGANIZATION Intermediate/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION sentenced/O Tibetan/O filmmaker/O Dhongdup/PERSON Wangchen/PERSON to/O six/O years/O behind/O bars/O on/O charges/O of/O ``/O inciting/O separatism/O ''/O for/O producing/O a/O documentary/O film/O ,/O Leaving/O Fear/O Behind/O ,/O which/O criticised/O Chinese/O government/O policies/O in/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
Police/O arrested/O <PERSON>Wangchen/O</PERSON> in/O March/O 2008/O and/O judicial/O authorities/O arbitrarily/O replaced/O his/O attorney/O ,/O Li/PERSON Dunyong/PERSON ,/O with/O a/O government-appointed/O lawyer/O ./O 
Wangchen/PERSON was/O allowed/O to/O meet/O with/O Li/PERSON only/O once/O ,/O in/O July/O 2009/O ,/O who/O reported/O that/O his/O client/O had/O been/O tortured/O ./O 
On/O 31/O December/O ,/O a/O Sichuan/LOCATION court/O sentenced/O Phurbu/PERSON Tsering/PERSON ,/O a/O senior/O Tibetan/O cleric/O ,/O to/O an/O eight-year/O prison/O term/O on/O politically/O motivated/O charges/O of/O illegal/O weapons/O possession/O ./O 
Phurbu/PERSON stated/O in/O court/O that/O his/O confession/O was/O extorted/O whilst/O in/O prison/O --/O police/O interrogated/O him/O continuously/O for/O four/O days/O and/O nights/O ,/O and/O threatened/O to/O arrest/O his/O wife/O and/O son/O ./O 
Despite/O Phurbu/PERSON 's/O statement/O ,/O the/O court/O admitted/O the/O confession/O without/O making/O any/O inquiry/O ./O 
In/O February/O 2009/O ,/O US/LOCATION Secretary/O of/O State/O Hillary/PERSON Clinton/PERSON said/O that/O human/O rights/O ``/O should/O n't/O interfere/O ''/O in/O the/O US-China/O relationship/O ./O 
Similarly/O ,/O President/O Barack/PERSON Obama/PERSON decided/O not/O to/O meet/O the/O Dalai/PERSON Lama/PERSON prior/O to/O his/O November/O visit/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
Whilst/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O Obama/PERSON raised/O human/O rights/O broadly/O in/O his/O public/O statements/O but/O did/O not/O directly/O engage/O pressing/O issues/O of/O freedom/O of/O expression/O ,/O religious/O minorities/O ,/O the/O disbarment/O of/O civil/O rights/O lawyers/O ,/O or/O ongoing/O crackdowns/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O Tibet/LOCATION ./O 
The/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION gave/O in/O to/O Chinese/O pressure/O and/O limited/O NGO/O participation/O in/O an/O EU-China/O Human/O Rights/O Seminar/O ''/O ./O 
``/O That/O the/O Chinese/O government/O this/O year/O released/O a/O national/O action/O plan/O on/O human/O rights/O is/O ironic/O ,/O as/O its/O real/O plan/O seems/O to/O entail/O steadily/O curtailing/O --/O not/O protecting/O --/O rights/O ,/O ''/O said/O Sophie/PERSON Richardson/PERSON ,/O Asia/LOCATION advocacy/O director/O for/O Human/ORGANIZATION Rights/ORGANIZATION Watch/ORGANIZATION ./O 
In/O the/O meantime/O ,/O the/O list/O of/O abuses/O gets/O longer/O by/O the/O day/O ./O 
On/O 25/O December/O ,/O a/O court/O in/O Jiangsu/LOCATION sentenced/O in/O a/O closed/O hearing/O dissident/O Guo/PERSON Quan/PERSON to/O ten/O years/O in/O prison/O on/O subversion/O charges/O because/O he/O organised/O a/O political/O party/O in/O Xinmin/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Shanghai/ORGANIZATION Intermediate/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION upheld/O the/O ``/O light/O ''/O sentence/O of/O one/O and/O half/O year/O inflicted/O on/O activist/O Duan/PERSON Chunfang/PERSON for/O ``/O obstructing/O official/O business/O ''/O after/O police/O alleged/O she/O attacked/O an/O officer/O ./O 
Her/O lawyer/O said/O instead/O that/O the/O conviction/O stems/O from/O efforts/O by/O officials/O to/O punish/O her/O for/O persistent/O petitioning/O and/O organising/O other/O petitioners/O to/O defend/O their/O rights/O ./O 
On/O 17/O December/O ,/O the/O Fujian/ORGANIZATION Provincial/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Justice/ORGANIZATION suspended/O lawyer/O Lin/PERSON Hongnan/PERSON 's/O licence/O to/O practice/O for/O a/O year/O ./O 
He/O had/O defended/O many/O pro-rights/O activists/O and/O had/O been/O repeatedly/O threatened/O ./O
