According/O to/O the/O leader/O of/O the/O ethnic/O minority/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O the/O democratic/O wave/O across/O Africa/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ``/O terrifies/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O wants/O at/O all/O costs/O to/O destroy/O anything/O that/O does/O not/O conform/O ''/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O China/LOCATION has/O launched/O a/O new/O campaign/O of/O repression/O against/O the/O Uyghur/O ethnic/O minority/O to/O oppose/O any/O separatist/O movement/O and/O keep/O the/O democratic/O wave/O that/O is/O passing/O through/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION and/O North/LOCATION Africa/LOCATION ,/O out/O of/O its/O territory/O ./O 
The/O warning/O comes/O from/O well/O known/O Chinese/O dissident/O <U_PERSON>Rebiya/PERSON Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> who/O ,/O during/O a/O meeting/O with/O Australian/O parliamentarians/O ,/O denounced/O ``/O new/O violent/O and/O repressive/O measures/O ''/O against/O the/O minority/O ,/O which/O lives/O in/O the/O northern/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
According/O to/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> -/O invited/O to/O speak/O at/O a/O parliamentary/O committee/O in/O Canberra/LOCATION despite/O objections/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION -/O China/LOCATION ``/O is/O afraid/O of/O what/O 's/O happening/O in/O the/O world/O ./O 
What/O happened/O in/O Egypt/LOCATION and/O Tunisia/LOCATION sent/O shock/O waves/O through/O the/O Chinese/O leadership/O that/O people/O 's/O patience/O could/O run/O out/O and/O that/O people/O will/O one/O day/O rise/O up/O and/O challenge/O the/O authority/O of/O the/O regime/O ''/O It/O should/O be/O also/O considered/O that/O the/O Uyghur/O are/O a/O Turkic-speaking/O Muslim/O minority/O ,/O who/O define/O themselves/O as/O ``/O almost/O Middle/O Eastern/O ''/O and/O refer/O to/O their/O own/O territory/O as/O ``/O East/O Turkestan/O ''/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O by/O language/O ,/O appearance/O ,/O religion/O and/O customs/O ,/O the/O Uyghur/O have/O absolutely/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O the/O Han/O ethnic/O group/O that/O predominates/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O arrested/O several/O times/O and/O even/O sentenced/O to/O death/O by/O the/O central/O government/O in/O Beijing/LOCATION ,/O refutes/O charges/O that/O she/O is/O a/O separatist/O ,/O instead/O claiming/O that/O she/O is/O fighting/O for/O the/O preservation/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O language/O and/O culture/O ,/O that/O China/LOCATION is/O bent/O on/O wiping/O out/O ./O 
The/O visit/O to/O Australia/LOCATION has/O angered/O the/O government/O of/O China/LOCATION ,/O which/O in/O 2009/O had/O asked/O Canberra/LOCATION not/O to/O grant/O the/O activist/O a/O visa/O labelling/O her/O ``/O a/O dangerous/O separatist/O ./O ''/O 
According/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O she/O is/O behind/O the/O riots/O of/O July/O 2009/O ,/O when/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -/O the/O capital/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -/O the/O Uyghur/ORGANIZATION launched/O protests/O asking/O for/O more/O autonomy/O ./O 
For/O <U_PERSON>Kadeer/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O ``/O Although/O China/LOCATION has/O changed/O its/O tactics/O ,/O China/LOCATION has/O not/O changed/O its/O assaults/O upon/O Uygur/O people/O 's/O religious/O beliefs/O ,/O cultural/O identities/O ,/O freedom/O of/O speech/O and/O economic/O life/O ,/O which/O are/O central/O to/O the/O Chinese/O government/O 's/O project/O of/O speedy/O assimilation/O of/O our/O people/O in/O China/LOCATION ''/O ./O
