It/O is/O revealed/O by/O his/O lawyer/O ,/O who/O could/O meet/O him/O for/O the/O first/O time/O after/O his/O detention/O last/O January/O ./O 
The/O academic/O was/O denied/O food/O after/O an/O attack/O on/O a/O Kunming/LOCATION train/O station/O in/O March/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION blames/O Uyghur/O separatists/O for/O the/O attack/O ./O 
Beijing/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O -/O <U_PERSON>Ilham/PERSON Tothi/PERSON</U_PERSON> was/O denied/O food/O for/O more/O than/O a/O week/O and/O his/O legs/O have/O been/O shackled/O for/O the/O past/O few/O weeks/O ,/O his/O lawyer/O says/O ./O 
Mr./O <U_PERSON>Tothi/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O an/O economics/O professor/O and/O well-known/O ethnic/O Uyghur/O activist/O for/O the/O rights/O of/O minorities/O living/O in/O China/LOCATION ,/O has/O been/O detained/O since/O January/O ./O 
His/O lawyer/O Li/PERSON Fangping/PERSON met/O him/O for/O the/O first/O time/O this/O week/O ./O 
The/O academic/O was/O denied/O food/O after/O an/O attack/O on/O a/O Kunming/LOCATION train/O station/O in/O March/O that/O killed/O 29/O people/O ./O 
The/O attack/O was/O blamed/O on/O Uyghur/O separatists/O by/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O 45/O ,/O is/O famous/O for/O his/O public/O speeches/O in/O favor/O of/O the/O Uyghur/O cause/O ./O 
This/O ethnic/O group/O lives/O in/O the/O northern/O autonomous/O region/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O is/O of/O the/O Turkish/O language/O and/O the/O Muslim/O faith/O ,/O and/O denounces/O a/O strong/O linguistic/O ,/O cultural/O and/O religious/O repression/O by/O the/O Chinese/O central/O government/O ./O 
However/O there/O is/O no/O record/O of/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> 's/O support/O the/O cause/O of/O separatism/O and/O he/O maintains/O his/O innocence/O ./O 
``/O He/O believes/O that/O in/O his/O words/O and/O deeds/O ,/O he/O has/O always/O sought/O to/O work/O for/O the/O country/O 's/O national/O interests/O and/O the/O organic/O integration/O of/O the/O Han/O Majority/O and/O Uyghur/O minority/O ,/O ''/O said/O Li/PERSON ./O 
The/O lawyer/O added/O that/O <U_PERSON>Tohti/PERSON</U_PERSON> went/O on/O a/O hunger/O strike/O in/O January/O for/O 10/O days/O to/O protest/O against/O being/O served/O food/O that/O did/O not/O follow/O Islamic/O dietary/O laws/O ./O 
Authorities/O force-fed/O him/O milk/O when/O his/O organs/O started/O bleeding/O ./O
