This/O is/O confirmed/O by/O local/O sources/O in/O the/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> and/O the/O Uyghur/O World/O Congress/O :/O police/O officers/O go/O to/O homes/O of/O local/O Muslims/O to/O monitor/O compliance/O with/O the/O ban/O ./O 
The/O head/O of/O the/O -LRB-/O state/O controlled/O -RRB-/O Council/O for/O Islamic-Chinese/O relations/O denies/O central/O government/O involvement/O :/O ``/O I/O know/O nothing/O of/O this/O ban/O ,/O but/O even/O if/O it/O were/O in/O force/O ,/O it/O is/O a/O local/O authority/O initiative/O ''/O ./O 
The/O province/O is/O at/O the/O center/O of/O a/O violent/O ethnic/O conflict/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews/O</ORGANIZATION> -RRB-/O -/O Different/O government/O departments/O in/O the/O western/O province/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> have/O banned/O its/O officials/O and/O national/O school/O students/O from/O fasting/O during/O the/O Muslim/O holy/O month/O of/O Ramadan/O ./O 
The/O decision/O was/O apparently/O taken/O by/O the/O local/O government/O with/O the/O support/O of/O Beijing/LOCATION after/O a/O series/O of/O terrorist/O attacks/O that/O have/O rocked/O China/LOCATION in/O recent/O months/O ./O 
The/O central/O authorities/O have/O blamed/O Uyghur/O separatists/O -/O formerly/O the/O ethnic/O majority/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -/O of/O having/O planned/O the/O attacks/O in/O <LOCATION>Beijing/O</LOCATION> ,/O <U_LOCATION>Urumqi/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O Kunming/LOCATION andGuangzhou/O ./O 
For/O their/O part/O ,/O the/O ethnic/O leaders/O have/O always/O denied/O any/O involvement/O in/O acts/O of/O violence/O ./O 
<U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> province/O is/O one/O of/O the/O most/O turbulent/O in/O all/O of/O China/LOCATION ./O 
It/O is/O the/O homeland/O of/O ethnic/O Uyghurs/O ,/O a/O Turkic-speaking/O ,/O mostly/O Muslim/O people/O that/O has/O always/O sought/O independence/O from/O Beijing/LOCATION ./O 
The/O central/O government/O has/O sent/O hundreds/O of/O thousands/O of/O Han/O Chinese/O to/O the/O region/O to/O try/O to/O make/O them/O the/O dominant/O ethnic/O group/O ./O 
It/O has/O also/O imposed/O serious/O restrictions/O on/O freedom/O of/O religion/O ,/O Muslim/O practices/O ,/O the/O teaching/O of/O the/O indigenous/O language/O and/O the/O local/O culture/O ./O 
Bozhou/ORGANIZATION Radio/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION TV/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION -/O both/O government/O media/O -/O have/O stated/O that/O the/O fasting/O ban/O applies/O to/O Party/ORGANIZATION members/O ,/O teachers/O and/O young/O people/O :/O ''/O We/O remind/O everyone/O that/O they/O are/O not/O permitted/O to/O observe/O a/O Ramadan/O fast/O ''/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O local/O Met/ORGANIZATION Office/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O has/O also/O adopted/O the/O ban/O ,/O the/O norm/O ``/O was/O enacted/O in/O accordance/O with/O the/O instructions/O that/O come/O from/O the/O highest/O authorities/O ./O ''/O 
A/O spokesman/O for/O the/O <U_ORGANIZATION>World/ORGANIZATION Uyghur/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION</U_ORGANIZATION> -/O an/O Organization/O based/O in/O Germany/LOCATION that/O represents/O the/O ethnic/O diaspora/O and/O monitors/O the/O situation/O in/O the/O province/O -/O has/O confirmed/O the/O restrictions/O and/O added/O that/O authorities/O ``/O have/O posted/O security/O officers/O in/O Muslim/O homes/O to/O check/O that/O the/O categories/O involved/O do/O not/O observe/O the/O fast/O ./O 
These/O restrictions/O on/O our/O freedom/O of/O religion/O will/O only/O worsen/O the/O situation/O ''/O ./O 
<U_PERSON>Isaaq/PERSON Yousef/PERSON</U_PERSON> ,/O head/O of/O the/O Council/O for/O the/O Islamic-Chinese/O relations/O -LRB-/O a/O state/O controlled/O organization/O that/O regulates/O the/O lives/O of/O Chinese/O Muslims/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> -RRB-/O ,/O however/O denies/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O involvement/O :/O ''/O If/O such/O a/O ban/O is/O in/O effect/O ,/O it/O 's/O an/O initiative/O of/O lower/O level/O state/O employees/O and/O not/O a/O directive/O from/O higher/O authorities/O There/O is/O no/O interest/O for/O the/O state/O in/O banning/O anyone/O who/O wants/O to/O practice/O his/O religion/O ./O 
But/O if/O this/O happens/O ,/O it/O is/O usually/O those/O state/O employees/O who/O are/O behind/O this/O ''/O ./O
