Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON and/O Nawaz/PERSON Sharif/PERSON signed/O 51/O agreements/O for/O projects/O related/O to/O the/O ``/O New/O Silk/O Road/O ''/O ./O 
A/O China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION linking/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> to/O the/O Arabian/LOCATION Sea/LOCATION and/O the/O Karot/LOCATION dam/O are/O among/O the/O ambitious/O goals/O ./O 
Agreements/O include/O roads/O ,/O port/O facilities/O and/O power/O stations/O ./O 
Islamabad/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O China/LOCATION has/O promised/O Pakistan/LOCATION investments/O worth/O US$/O 45/O billion/O to/O have/O a/O more/O direct/O route/O to/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O Africa/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION ./O 
Chinese/O President/O Xi/PERSON Jinping/PERSON and/O Pakistani/O Prime/O Nawaz/PERSON Sharif/PERSON yesterday/O signed/O 51/O agreements/O to/O build/O a/O China-Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Economic/ORGANIZATION Corridor/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O CPEC/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O --/O a/O network/O of/O roads/O ,/O railway/O and/O pipelines/O between/O the/O long-time/O allies/O ./O 
<PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> ,/O whose/O visit/O lasted/O only/O two/O days/O -LRB-/O 20-21/O April/O -RRB-/O ,/O was/O the/O first/O Chinese/O president/O to/O travel/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION in/O more/O than/O ten/O years/O ./O 
For/O China/LOCATION ,/O Pakistan/LOCATION is/O strategically/O located/O ,/O providing/O access/O to/O the/O Indian/LOCATION Ocean/LOCATION over/O land/O and/O a/O boost/O to/O trade/O with/O Europe/LOCATION ,/O Africa/LOCATION and/O the/O Middle/LOCATION East/LOCATION China/LOCATION is/O also/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O top/O trading/O partner/O ,/O and/O both/O have/O a/O mutual/O distrust/O of/O India/LOCATION ,/O seen/O as/O the/O main/O obstacle/O to/O `/O New/O Silk/O Road/O '/O ./O 
As/O part/O of/O the/O new/O partnership/O ,/O two/O countries/O plan/O to/O build/O a/O 3,000-km/O corridor/O stretching/O from/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ,/O in/O western/O China/LOCATION ,/O to/O Gwadar/LOCATION ,/O on/O the/O <LOCATION>Arabian/O Sea/O</LOCATION> ./O 
They/O also/O agreed/O to/O build/O the/O Karot/LOCATION Dam/LOCATION in/O Rawalpindi/LOCATION ,/O near/O the/O capital/O Islamabad/LOCATION ,/O in/O northern/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O 720-megawatt/O structure/O would/O take/O about/O six/O years/O to/O build/O ,/O according/O to/O project/O documents/O filed/O by/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Bank/ORGANIZATION <OTHER>'s/ORGANIZATION</OTHER> International/ORGANIZATION Finance/ORGANIZATION Corp/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O is/O investing/O US$/O 125/O million/O in/O China/ORGANIZATION Three/ORGANIZATION Gorges/ORGANIZATION South/ORGANIZATION Asia/ORGANIZATION Investment/ORGANIZATION ./O 
It/O is/O expected/O to/O generate/O 75/O per/O cent/O of/O its/O energy/O during/O the/O summer/O months/O when/O water/O flow/O in/O the/O Jhelum/LOCATION River/LOCATION is/O at/O its/O highest/O ./O 
China/ORGANIZATION Three/ORGANIZATION Gorges/ORGANIZATION Corp/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O Beijing-based/O developer/O of/O the/O world/O 's/O largest/O dam/O ,/O is/O expected/O to/O become/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O biggest/O clean-energy/O company/O with/O plans/O for/O US$/O 5.5/O billion/O of/O hydropower/O ,/O solar/O and/O wind/O projects/O totalling/O more/O than/O 2,000/O megawatts/O in/O capacity/O ./O 
Pakistan/LOCATION requires/O as/O much/O as/O US/LOCATION billion/O in/O investments/O over/O the/O next/O five/O years/O to/O overcome/O a/O 10,000-megawatt/O shortfall/O in/O power/O capacity/O ./O 
<PERSON>Xi/O</PERSON> and/O Sharif/PERSON signed/O deals/O valued/O at/O US$/O 28/O billion/O to/O build/O roads/O ,/O ports/O and/O power/O plants/O --/O nearly/O equal/O to/O the/O amount/O of/O foreign/O aid/O the/O US/LOCATION has/O provided/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION over/O the/O past/O decade/O to/O support/O its/O war/O in/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O 
The/O investments/O ,/O if/O realised/O ,/O will/O help/O Sharif/PERSON revive/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O economy/O ,/O which/O suffers/O from/O chronic/O power/O failures/O and/O an/O insurgency/O that/O has/O killed/O more/O than/O 50,000/O people/O since/O 2001/O ./O 
China/LOCATION also/O pledged/O to/O fight/O terrorism/O and/O help/O bring/O peace/O to/O Afghanistan/LOCATION ./O
