The/O leading/O Sunni/O institution/O slams/O the/O ban/O on/O fasting/O and/O religious/O activities/O imposed/O on/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> ./O 
It/O appeals/O to/O the/O international/O community/O ,/O the/O UN/ORGANIZATION and/O human/O rights/O groups/O to/O end/O violations/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O in/O the/O province/O ./O 
Cairo/LOCATION -LRB-/O <ORGANIZATION>AsiaNews</ORGANIZATION> /O Agencies/O -RRB-/O --/O Al-Azhar/LOCATION ,/O the/O leading/O Muslim/O seat/O of/O learning/O ,/O condemned/O China/LOCATION for/O imposing/O restrictions/O on/O fasting/O in/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/O</U_LOCATION> during/O the/O holy/O month/O of/O Ramadan/O ./O 
Based/O in/O Egypt/LOCATION ,/O the/O Sunni/O institution/O has/O called/O on/O Beijing/LOCATION to/O allow/O the/O Muslim/O community/O in/O the/O province/O to/O observe/O the/O fast/O and/O participate/O in/O religious/O activities/O during/O the/O holy/O month/O ./O 
Out/O of/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> 's/O 22/O million/O people/O ,/O almost/O nine/O million/O are/O indigenous/O Muslim/O Uighurs/O ./O 
Deemed/O a/O hotbed/O of/O terrorism/O ,/O the/O region/O has/O seen/O rising/O tensions/O due/O to/O Beijing/LOCATION 's/O restrictive/O ethnic/O and/O religious/O policies/O ./O 
Over/O the/O years/O ,/O clashes/O and/O violent/O incidents/O have/O broken/O out/O between/O native/O Uighurs/O and/O ethnic/O Han/O Chinese/O settlers/O brought/O in/O by/O the/O Chinese/O government/O to/O swamp/O the/O indigenous/O population/O ./O 
``/O <LOCATION>Al-Azhar/ORGANIZATION</LOCATION> and/O its/O grand/O imam/O ,/O <U_PERSON>Ahmed/PERSON Al-Tayeb/PERSON</U_PERSON> -LRB-/O pictured/O -RRB-/O ,/O condemn/O the/O Chinese/O authorities/O '/O ban/O on/O Muslims/O from/O fasting/O and/O practicing/O their/O religious/O rituals/O during/O Ramadan/O in/O some/O parts/O of/O the/O western/O <U_LOCATION>Xinjiang/LOCATION</U_LOCATION> region/O ,/O ''/O said/O a/O statement/O from/O the/O Cairo-based/O <LOCATION>Al-Azhar/ORGANIZATION</LOCATION> ./O 
``/O <LOCATION>Al-Azhar/ORGANIZATION</LOCATION> rejects/O all/O forms/O of/O oppression/O practiced/O against/O Uighur/O Muslims/O in/O China/LOCATION that/O affect/O their/O religious/O rights/O and/O personal/O freedoms/O ,/O ''/O said/O the/O prestigious/O institution/O ,/O which/O called/O on/O the/O international/O community/O ,/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION and/O human/O rights/O groups/O to/O end/O these/O violations/O ./O
